okay let's continue our discussion of
learning
before i do that though one
clarification
arms apologize for any confusion that
was caused by the aren't by the mail and
i sent out over the weekend about the
review slides
though a little caption
indicated that the uh... exam was
scheduled for sometime in september
that was last year
on
i've corrected at the story for the
confusion
just like to make it clear that the
examines going to be held as scheduled
on wednesday october third
with the review session as scheduled on
monday or cover first
what's up on the course website now is a
new set of slides all that you can use
for review and what's coming in about a
day or so
is a narrative that accompanies those
flights that'll give you some more
information
about what to focus on
and what you can't ignore
especially you know
img whiteman
so there's an exam scheduled for
wednesday october third review session
monday
october first
next week will be arm
talking about uh...
sensation perception
okay last time i talk to you about a
major forum of learning
i discovered more than a hundred years
ago by russian all of the physiologist
even pablo
all
and the significance of this flood
warning notice classical conditioning
is that
classical conditioning
extends
the range of stimuli deccan evoke
involuntary reflex of responses
what classical conditioning does is
attached to these reflexive behaviors
to stimuli
that ordinarily wouldn't be able to them
usually dog celebrate when there's food
put in their miles mel pavlov's dogs
elevated
when a battle all rangel
all right as i point out last time
the phenomenon of classical conditioning
are basically ubiquitous lien
nature
every organism virtually every organism
with a nervous system in fact every
organism with a nervous system
our shows that we thought were the
phenomenal of classical conditioning
pablo believed
along that all learning
was
classical
on your nature of that is that
classical conditioning on drill a hole
alba warning that
organisms can do
but we now know that is very
too strong a position to take but it
does seem to be the case
that are by virtue of something very
much like classical conditioning
we acquire a lot of our a motion all
responses to events
some of our emotional responses to
events art
reflex
but others are acquired through
something like classical conditioning
so the become too like something was
fears some things
avoid all or be averse to some things
and so on
all by virtue of the attachment
an association between a previously
neutral object and psalm
home formal motion will stimulus
at the same time as pavlov was studying
classical conditioning in his laboratory
in saint petersburg russia
another a psychologist an american
psychologist are ever tell thorndike was
studying in another form of learning
in his laboratory at columbia university
in art in new york
and this is our diagram of thorndike's
are apparatus
known as a puzzle box and what ford bike
was doing have not worked with barbs
thorndike work with cats
are in for dikes method it was too
on dalton uh...
put cuts in this puzzle box
and let them
learn how to out to get out
and the way the puzzle boxes of his own
constructed
here's the cage
here's a door with the latch on it
that's connected by a string to a paddle
that's inside all of the cage
and when thorndike first put the cat
include the uh... puzzle box
cat did what cats ordinarily do but have
you ever have cats you take a minute
reluctance to prevent or whatever
they want to get out
so thorndike's cats would meow where
made scrabble around the cajun they
engage in all sorts of sort of random
behavior
in the course of which
they would just accidentally press on
this panel
which would pull on the string which
would open the latch which will allow
the door to open in the cat would
with expecting about there was
thorndike pick up the cat bump it back
in a cage close the door
capitol around inside the box
accidentally trip on the paddle
polled accord open the latch open the
door the cat would come out there before
and i can
i kept on the cat back in a box
orlando and so on
although what thorndike noticed
was that on repeated trials
the cats
pressed the
vault lover more quickly here is foreign
dikes actual
data data from his experiment
or if you're a number of trials up to
sixty here's the latency
all up to three minutes
author action after six minutes three
hundred sixty seconds
all of that it took though i'll be at
the cat to too
or open the door
and you can see that there is a clearer
downward trend so that on the first
trial it took the cat
for five minutes on average to open the
door
on successive trials
tube progressively last time
so that on the sixteen th trial
the cat was opd was
got would go in the cage press the lever
and all of the media lee
come out a cage and of course there
before and i could to killed the cat
back in a cage while for another trial
but the point here is
that over successive trial's
well wait and see all of the escape
responds
are diminished soul apparently
the other mls the cats were learning how
to open the door
and thorndike concluded
that this learning was although it was
produced
by the fact that
the behavior
had some consequence for the animal
he was able to escape from the puzzle
box
at least on at least momentarily
also of load for indict argued
that this was a form of learning
that was motivated by reward
on the basis all of his studies are
katzen puzzle boxes
thorndike formulated a set of laws of
learning there were about eight of these
but three of them are primary though the
most important ones for our purposes and
they're the ones i'm going to focus on
here
the first of these with what or and i
called on welcome reading this
and what the wall of reading this
state's is that lure name is motivated
alright the organisms internal state
so that
motivational states whether the cat is
hungry
or thirsty
or wants to flee or wants to get out or
whatever
those motivational states
activate whole sequence of behaviors
the cats confined in a puzzle box
it doesn't want to begin their and so
would engage isn't all sorts of well all
sorts of behaviors
the second of these all laws
is all they have a fact which basically
says
that responses that lead to reward up
are strengthened
responses to lead to reward are
strengthened
and by the same token
responses that do not lead to reward
weakened
so what happens is it may take
for five minutes
for the animal to press the paddle the
first on the first trial
that pat oppressing response that title
pressing behavior leads to the
possibility of a skate so pressing the
paddle is gradually
strengthened over time
whereas the other things the cat's doing
this scene
scratching at though that the other side
of the cage
or whatever else it's going
that's both behaviors are not rewarded
and they gradually dropout all of the
animals response behavior
so responses that are rewarded or
strengthen
responses that are not rewarded to or
weakened and then finally
alm for our purposes the law of exercise
which basically says
that connections between stimuli and
responses
are strengthened by practice
okay strengthened by repetition
and weakened
disuse
connections between stimuli and
responses or strengthened by practice
and weakened by distance as i say there
were five other subsidiary was
but we don't have to worry about the use
of a little
what's going on here
part of basic are the basic because
illustration
of what we now have come to call
instrumental conditioning
or what some psychologist notably b_f_
skinner calls operant conditioning
there's a technical difference between
instrumental in operant conditioning but
it
doesn't matter for us at this level of
the chorus
we're going to use these terms
interchangeably
and the idea behind although at the
general principle of instrumental
conditioning
is that animals
law-abiding acquire
all adaptive behaviors
through the experience of success or a
failure
sometimes called operant conditioning
because in the form of conditioning
the organism operates on the environment
in some way
the cat presses a paddle okay that's a
operant
like a kind of response
whereas in classical conditioning
the edible doesn't operate on the
response in any way that you must
celebrates or whatever it's going to do
it's also called instrumental
conditioning
because this conditioned response is
instrumental
in getting for the organism something
that once okay
are so that's the general idea here the
organism is operating on the environment
changing it in some way
and the behavior is instrumental the end
of
i
getting for the or organism
some desired all
the state of affairs
whereas in classical conditioning
we see organisms forming associations
among stimuli
between battles
and food between conditioned stimuli and
unconditional stimulus
in instrumental conditioning
we see on the walls forming responses
between their behaviors
and the i'll calms
of those behaviors between patil
pressing and getting old of the auto
oh out of the yarn oppose a box
so again
by virtue although instrumental
conditioning
what happens is that
all voluntary behaviors
not involuntary reflex of behaviors
but so-called voluntary behaviors like
paddle pressing that's not all
nodded innate reflex
these kinds of behaviors
come under the control ald environmental
events
and again the phenomenal all
instrumental conditioning or nearly
ubiquitous in nature
all vertebrate organisms at any rate all
birder bird organisms and many
invertebrate organisms
control
saw the phenomenal of instrumental
condition so that's a lot of organisms
are a lot of species
that could spill or instrumental
conditioning
just as parable off the lot
that older teen was a kind of variant on
classical conditioning
so thorndike and scatter
thought that all learning was org
was a very into bondage mental
conditioning
we now know that
that viewpoint is also too extreme
however
it's very clear now
that home
the laws of instrumental conditioning
appeared with carol
for much of the uh... acquisition
maintenance and display
of lots of adaptive behavior for what
ever happened
of it or behaviors
or acquired through hardness terminal
condition basically
anything that organisms learn to do
under conditions of incentive
the are week at once to get out
followed the animal wants to get federal
once globe water or whatever
instrumental conditioning
is what seems to be uh... seems to be
going on there
let us know
terror
classical and instrumental conditioning
on a number of salient dimensions there
are a least four differences between
these two forms of learning
and i think going over them will help
you to understand what's going on here
are all the love that better
in the first place
in classical conditioning
reinforcement
is not does not depend on the animal's
behavior
think about pavlov's dog for a second
dole installed by food
bell food
dole food
and it doesn't matter what the adult
dogs
okay
the adults just sitting there section
not doing anything it's in this harness
it can move around it's not parking
that's not doing anything
health food bell food dole food
the reinforcement
all of the presentation of the food
following that the bell
doesn't depend on anything that the
animal does
all by comparison
in instrumental conditioning
reinforcement is precisely dependent
army or army cats behavior
if it acted and press the paddle in the
puzzle box and never get out
and gave out as the reinforcement for
the paddle pressing behavior
so the animals got to engage in some
kind of behavior for reinforcement ought
to be presented
alm another difference between classical
and instrumental conditioning is that in
classical conditioning
the behavior that you're interested in
is if you listed as a reflex
by the on condition stimulus
what problem wants to do
is to condition the dog so that it's
elevates in response to the barrel
okay but the celebration izzy elicited
as a reflex by the meat power
by contrast
in the instrumental conditioning
behavior is even edited
freely
by the organism
all there's nothing that you can do to
make the cat
press the pedal okay
is just got to do it
and its own on its own sweet time
so there's nothing you can do to elicit
this people's patil pressing behavior
it's not any kind
org new york it's not any kind of a
reflex
okay so here's a third with the podium
pretty much the same point
in classical conditioning
what's been conditioned as an
involuntary response
while reflexive response
that is an involuntary response
to some stimulus
what has been conditioned instrumental
conditioning
is our voluntary response of behavior at
the animal engages in
more or less spontaneously
because classical conditioning
brings involuntary reflex of behaviors
under environmental control
there are relatively few behaviors that
are subject to classical conditioning
why
costar relatively few reflexes
we compare dot all the things that
animals kundu reflexes constitute a
relatively small part
of their behavioral or repertoire
also you can
condition dogs to celebrate you can
condition the eye blink reflex you can
condition the patellar reflex
in condition all sorts of reflexes
on through classical conditioning are
but there's lots more that you can do
with the instrumental case
condition alleles to engage in on not
only all sorts of bought
voluntary behaviors but all sorts of
combinations or voluntary behaviors
before and i take it had the patience to
do so in this experiment
he could have trained his cats
sit-down scratch their right here's
scratch their left ear wag their tails
and then press
the paddle
in order to go out
that whole pattern of behavior
could have been shaped up
or by be compelled by of instrumental of
the conditioning
so again
classical an instrumental conditioning
reef of represent
somewhat different forms of learning and
a volvo babel animals to learn
somewhat different kinds of things
quick questions on instrumental
conditioning or the comparison with
classical conditioning
classical conditioning and instrumental
conditioning are different
but if you think about it for a second
most examples of adaptive behavior alm
reflects some kind of combination
of classical
and instrumental conditioning this has
made clear i think
by a form of fall of the learning that
is often studied in the psychological
laboratory
known as a boy who's learning
this is the apparatus weren't used in
some classic studies by of avoidance
learning
by richard solomon and all and london
win
all solomon and win lots of other of
uh... psychologist as well
use dogs in these studies
all of this is known as a uh...
avoidance apparatus it's a shuttle box
it's pretty
that's all about eight feet long
four-feet about forty five oh three feet
more things
pretty good container
on for a dog
and what are they did in this and then
these experiments
if you do you place the dorgan one-sided
all of the apparatus
and there are some whites in the side of
that can deliver conditioned on stimulus
and down here on the floor
is a warrior grated that can deliver
eight all my old not universe of
electrical shock but not only for
michael shots or anything like that
all mildly painful electrical shock two
hour to the feet of global of the dog
all and what happens in this experiment
is the body of one side of the shuttle
box
the lights will come on
or the and then a couple seconds after
the lights go on
than the shock is delivered to defeat
and what will happen is that the animal
would just kind of
naturally start moving around
and will eventually
job over
this barrier into the other side of the
shuttle box
when the animal johnson to the other
side of the shuttle box the shock goes
off the tone and and the lights go off
odd then what happens is
the lights come on in this site of the
shuttle box
secretary later
the shock comes on yahool feels the
shock of course eventually moves over to
the other side of the shuttle box
shock goes off let's go off
after a little bit of rest
lights come on shock comes on a couple
seconds later and the animals over
it's a shadow box experiment
because what the animal learns to do
is to shuttle
back in four th
the initial art of the responses on
initial on the early trials in the
experiment
art escaped royals
because they occur
after the shock has come on
white is the condition stimulus
shock is the on condition stimulus
when you make the of the response
after the onset of the shock
that's known as an escape response
but eventually what happens is
the abalone policy of the escape
response begins to decrease joint strike
with
thorndike's volvo tax in the puzzle box
so that at some point
yeah double will
vault over the barrier
and make the response before the shock
even comes on
that's the animals
avoidance response doesn't escape
shocking avoids shock altogether
and a very quickly
the animals learn
to make this avoids response just as
soon as the condition stimulus comes on
so what's going on in this kind of
experiment now
that the aval it's acquiring through
different kinds of associates
it's learning in the first place that
there's a so there's an association
between the lights and the shock
that's classical conditioning
where the alamos learning about the
association between the lights in the
shock
and then we have all learned
but there's an association between
retin a barrier
and termination
all of the shock
that's instrumental conditioning
where the animal is florian association
between some behavior
vaulting over the barrier
and the consequences of that
barrier
so all again the animals warning two
things
accommodation of classical and
instrumental conditioning
by virtue of classical conditioning the
animal comes to associate
the shock
the light
by virtue of instrumental conditioning
the animal comes to associate walking
the barrier
removal
or the termination
of the shock when you get up in the
morning
you couldn't have a somewhat similar
experience
onto these dogs in the short of ox
when you are all clock radio goes off at
your clock radio is anything like mine
when you set it to go off the first
thing that happens is that
the radio comes on
public radio or kuwait or whatever it is
that you listen to tape fog
and then maybe five ten minutes later
what happens
doesn't goes off right very diverse a
buzzer
all and then you've got to
reach over to your clock radio and turn
the bauza ralph
future earn
if your press that button
in the interval between the time the
radio comes on the time the buzzer comes
on
you can prevent buzzer from coming on
entirely
that's exactly the situation that these
towards the rent
and that you've learned the association
between the radio coming on and the
alarm coming on and you've learned that
there's something you can do either to
turn the alarm off
order preventing alarm
from coming on on entirely
on its own it's very much hard it's very
much the same kind of thing
anderson ulcers
of of avoidance learning
is what is all going on
in the hall home radio theory call the
tune factor theory will boren's learning
proposed by a psychologist name our work
in new york pardon the late nineteen
forties ok remember what happens
is that there is light
followed by shock
if the adl response during a shock
it's rewarded by escaping from the shock
if the adl responds after the light but
prior to the shock
it's rewarded by avoiding the shock
entirely
anmol recently said look the first thing
that happens here
is that you condition theater
to the white
you know the uh... the shock as painful
the animals of dixie animal afraid
and new condition anticipatory fear far
to the light
and then what you do
is you reinforce escape avoidance all by
uh... alone
by these cessation
of the shark andy associated like
so again
this simply illustrates
major form of learning combines both
all aspects of classical conditioning
and instrumental conditioning
by virtue of classical conditioning
associate
the shock
by virtue called
it's mental conditioning
all associate avoidance risque response
with or with the termination of the
shock
two factors
one factor having to do with classical
conditioning and one factor having to
learn
font having to do
instrumental condition
classical conditioning
instrumental conditioning two major
forms of learning
what is that exactly that subjects that
that these animals or learning
well for a long time in psychology
alm the alcohol learning was fought to
be as automatic as on today's reflexes
all and what happened is that by virtue
of classical an instrumental
conditioning
saw little
dogs cats rats pigeons humans
all acquired connections between stimuli
and responses to them
and this is what's known as the stimulus
response or s are learning theory which
entailed
four
different
assumptions each of which
or critical for understanding the theory
the first of these assumptions
is the assumption of association by kon
tiki woody
the f_ aren't learning theorists
argued
that associations
are formed
when there is the repeated
occurrence of two of ends
the condition stimulus
andy on condition stimulus the response
and the reinforcement
the idea here is
association performed
between stimuli and responses
that occur close together in space and
time
for pablo
the bells followed very quickly by food
within a second or two
for thorndike
patil pressing the patil
is followed very quickly
by escape
within a second or two
the general idea here is that the
repeated
joint
occurrence the repeated co occurrence of
two events
closely related in space and time close
together in space
close together in time
creates an association
between them
and that that association
that the on wall
is uh... is learning
in classical conditioning
the associations between two events in
the environment
the bell and the food
in instrumental conditioning
the associations between some behavior
and its consequences
patil pressing
an escape
bolting
the barrier
and escape
that's the first assumption
the second assumption
is what's known as the arbitrariness
assumption
and the arbitrariness assumption
basically says that by virtue all of us
those haitian by kon tiki woody
any stimulus
can be attached
to any response
you could arbitrarily select
anne stimulus in the world so long as
the organism consensus
and any response
that the organism can make
and foreman association
between them
you can select stimuli
and responses arbitrarily
and form an association between them
by virtue
poem allowed by virtue of continuity
so future but want to do it in
and arbitrariness then there are two
kind of
hidden assumptions
on in s are learning theory
which also turned out to be important
one of these is known as
the assumption of the empty organism
and wealthiest the that what mt organism
means is that you can all understand
that handles behavior
slowly in terms of all of
stimulus inputs
and response outputs
thus elevation
the light the shock
and the escape
all you have to do doll you have to know
if you want to understand what organ
donors as is a must learn
is what the stimuli are
and what the reinforcements or
that are being associate
put another way
these learning theorists
for all of the organism
as essentially a black box
that connects stimuli and responses are
those of you laws of familiar with
computers
order or other kinds of engineering
things no black box
is simply a device that connects two
things
and you don't know how it works
you don't know how it does these kinds
of connections
and he s are learning terrace
didn't know how these connections were
made and they didn't care
all they said was all they got to know
is that there are still alive and
responses
and the organism
although connects them up
we don't need to understand anything
about the organisms inter workings
in order to understand
what it's learning
all we have to do is understand
what stimuli ring pinging on the
organism
and what responses its making
and then finally
the final assumption barbie
traditionalists are theory of learning
if the assumption all of the passive
organism
the idea here is
that the organism
isn't it active during a learning
process
pavlov's dog is in trying to figure out
what's going on in the experiment
thorndike's cats
or trying to
figure out how to get out all of the law
out of the art of the puzzle box it just
happens
okay
by virtue of
the parent of the bell in the food
the animal
comes too
salivate
by virtue of the pairing of the paddle
pressing and escape the animal columns
to press
the panel
it's this assumption of the passive
organism
that actually give those
the metaphor conditioning
the idea here is that were nina
something that
happens to an organism
when you condition your hair
there put stuff on your heritage either
it gets less trivia ricketts more fruity
depending on what kind of condition your
youth
your hair isn't in or please let me
softer please please choose this one
don't use that one
in boulder the process
something is being done
similarly
and classical an instrumental
conditioning the prevailing view
is that things are happening
true
the organism
but the organism really is and actively
involved in the process
alm
or what's happening here
is that the havier is coming under the
control of the barn mental events
there's no sense he wrote
expectations were
free will or anything like that
on the park
all of the organism
these four assumptions association by
conjugate woody
arbitrariness
the empty organism and the path of
organism
we now know are entirely well
i talk about them because these
assumptions dominated the psychology of
learning
for more than half a century
and you can still see their residues in
the some psychological theories today
more important
demonstrating
however these assumptions were wrong
left us a legacy of some of the most
interesting stories in the learning
literature
studies that we're going to talk about
in the remainder of this lecture
and aware of that and the next lecture
we know it all
all of those wide variety of
experimental results
that challenge
of these kind of common sense
assumptions
about
about the learning process
and reveal that learning is quite
different
from what these early theorists thought
carnivores
all of his these experiments comment
basically two forms studies of
what we think of as
biological constraints on learning
and then later
studies of what we think of has
cognitive
constraints
on all knwo are learning
let's look at that the
biological constraints on learning first
are because
what they do is challenge a specially
this assumption of arbitrariness
here's a classic experiment by john
garcia than at the university of utah
all and his associates on what's known
as taste aversion learning
all or all of the based on that what's
known as bait showing us
in the real world
when animals
encounter a new food
what they will do is they will sample
the food don't need a small amount of it
they'll go away
and wait
if they get sick
they'll never approach that food again
they might need somethin else but they
won't go up there but they won't or that
they won't eat that particular of food
again they'll avoid it
all this is all of the phenomena that's
well known to ranchers
or who have to do with carly ortiz
it's well-known on blood into farmers of
of all kinds
and what garcia and his colleagues dead
was to bring the this phenomenon bay
china's
into the laboratory
in a particularly interesting on
particularly
experiments
the experiment is really set up
all i thought as a kind of classical
conditioning or experiment the was
you'll see in a minute
it has a kind of instrumental
conditioning quality to it as well
what happened in this experiment
is at the sotheby's subjects
which were rats befor laboratory rats
were exposed to a compound conditioned
stimulus
while they drank water
animals just drink water in their cages
and while these animals
although what to would come out the
livery water
and while the animals
were allowed to drink
they were exposed to a compound stimulus
which is at their work
whites flashing
in their cage
there was a clicking noise presented
indicate like a little ratchet that was
spinning around
and the water was flavored suite
with all the saccharine
so garcia call this compound conditioned
stimulus
noisy
the animals were allowed to drink
there's four on for a moment or two
and then they were exposed
to warn or to different kinds of one
condition stimulus
one group of rats
for chuck
after they started drinking which caused
them some
immediate
pain in the foot
another group of rats
was exposed to wait mild does of x_-rays
which after some interval
made them sick
made them nauseated
after all
the aftershock group got immediate pain
in the presence of the bright noisy
sweetwater
ghar group in the the x_-ray group
delayed nausea nausea after some period
of time also in the presence
noisy sweetwater
what garcia bended
was to put the animals in a situation
where they were allowed to select one
ought to sources of water
they were given a choice
between right noisy water on the one
hand
there was a water tap where the lights
were flashing and there was a little
ratchet noise
or there was a water source that
delivered sweetwater
flavored
saccharine
and wat holmberg go what garcetti and
his colleagues discovered
was that
bottles one avoid the water
but the water source that they are
boarded
depended upon beyond conditioned
stimulus
to which they had been exposed
here it is a schematic diagram
of the
of the experiment
all subjects were exposed to
noisy
suite
some subjects
word and exposed to
what shock
which deliver which were or produced
media pain
another group
was exposed to x_-rays which produced
delayed nausea take out the experiment
here's the compound condition stimulus
here is the on condition stimulus
here's the unconditional response
and here's the unconditional response
for group too
now we give the animals have choice
they can either
from a bright
noisy
source of water
or they can drink
from is sweet
choice on source of water
and hear are the results of the
experiment
the alleles
that were shocked
preferred to drink
the sweetwater
avoided
the bright nor easy water
by the same token the animals that were
exposed to the x-ray
avoided
those sweetwater
and pretty strongly preferred
to drink
the bright
noisy water
so what's going on here
is that the animals in the shock group
have learned an association
between pates other abs i'm sorry
we meet our boa brightness of the war
bright noisy water and shock
and the animals associated the x_-ray
have learned an association between the
taste of the water and at the uh... and
then the taste
here we have
the number of licks at their own that
they're getting
for now we have
to our animals exposed to
exactly the same conditions
saying compound stimulus
same on conditions of the two different
doggone conditions deployed delivered at
exactly the same time but they will
learn
two different things
the shark to rats
forum an association
between the site and sound of this the
condition stimulus
and at the shock
the portland rats
foreman association between the taste
of the stimulus
and
or and they're all
and their own version
what is being illustrated here
or is that
yeah walls
dot learn the same fein's okay
through this again
all elements of the compound stimulus or
associated with a shock
but these are the walls only associate
the light and the noise with the shock
they don't associate the taste with a
shock
all the elements of the compound
condition stimulus
or equally contiguous
x_-ray but the animals formal
association
between the taste of the stimulus and
the x_-ray not the site or sound of the
stimulus in the x-ray
what this shows you is that
the associations of these animals are
forming are not arbitrary
these that rats can't learn the
association between taste in shock
they'd all learn it
animals don't learn
the association
between slight and so
and nausea
it's just not something that's possible
for them to learn
here it is they sell more kind of
finding in another domain
all this is a scapegoat avoidance
learning in pigeons
this work by robert bowls at the
university of washington
and what polls discovered
was that it was the easy to teach a
pigeon
flap its wings or to stretch of snack
in order to avoid shock
very easy to teach a pigeon
thought that
but it is harder in fact it's impossible
the teacher pigeon
the pekka ke to avoid shock
even though
it's incredibly easy
to teach a pigeon
the pekka ke to get food
you can't teach a pigeon
to pack a key
to avoid shock
similarly if you look at rights
it's very easy
to teach rats
to jump up on a shelf
to avoid shock
it's very easy to teach rats to learn to
run in a shuttle box to avoid shock
but it's very difficult it's not
impossible
but it's very difficult
teacher al animals
to press the lever
to avoid shock
boulders inside
is that the of the escape an avoidance
responses
that animals find it easy to learn
are those that are part of their inmate
repertoire of escaping avoidance
responses
if you're in a park and there's a little
kid the park what a little kids do in
parks
they chased pigeons
okay never was a little kid the world
the didn't chase pigeons in a park
and what are the pigeons don't
okay that's right
they flap their wings they fly away
and
in the process of beginning to flopping
birds will stretched their necks as
preparation
solitude to taking off
these are natural escape an avoidance
responses
that pigeons have and it's easy for them
to lauren
to engage in those behaviors
are to arm
and to avoid shock
similarly
all rats will run
only in natural environment roll into a
state prov predators
and they find
running and john jumping up on shelves
to be are very natural
are very easy escape it avoids responses
to learn
bowles is in sight then
was there a boring us learning
kepala capitalizes i'm each
species specific repertoire of innate
escape and response
form behaviors
if the if the sub if they animals or
required to
learn to escape the response of those
gaping avoid they can do that much more
quickly if the escape it avoids response
that you're trying to learn
is one that is part of their
repertoire
so the general idea here
is that
be kinds of associations that are four
hundred classical and instrumental
conditioning
are not by any means arbitrary
instead
alton
baraka learning seems to be governed by
what's known only as the preparedness
principal in learning
the general idea behind preparedness the
preparedness principle
it is that
by bird true audits evolutionary history
every species
predisposed perform certain kinds of
associations
these associations that the species is
predisposed to acquire
are we call
prepared
associations
they are all other
the animals have not been
predisposed to acquire
we call those one prepared
associations
and there is still other
that are
contra prepared
meaning that by virtue of the
revolutionary history
animals just certain animals certain
species simply can't make those
associations at all
associating sight and sound of shock
that's a pre pared association
for rats
associating
pays with north york
that's a prepared association
for rats
associating sight and sound with nausea
that's controverted or
they can't do it
they're not built
to do that
associating
on don't know
taste with for choc
that's also contra prepared
rats simply aren't able to do that
the implication of this
is that you can't afterall treat the
organism as if it were empty
you can simply
arrange
stimuli and responses so that they occur
close together in space and time
and expect the animal to be good to be
able to pick up on that
the first thing you have to do
is that
you have to understand
howdy organism is built
you have to understand something about
its internal biological structure
in order to understand
water can learn
and what it can't work
rats evolved in such a way
that they associate sight and sound with
pain and taste with nausea
words by the way evolved in exactly the
opposite way
birds find it very easy to associate the
sight and sound that surrounds our food
with its gastrointestinal consequences
but they find it very very very
difficult to associate
the case
of food
with its gastrointestinal consequences
if you think about it per second
most birds or site feeders birds walk
around they steal
piece of grain on that on the ground of
the c_a_c_ door
or an insect whatever
and they pack at they're built
look at their food okay
and pack at it they have taste buds they
can taste food but they're just not
build to associate
with all
with nausea or anything like that
you have to understand the individuals
biological workings
how the organisms
rain
nervous system
has been shaped by evolution
in such a way as tall is to make it easy
for it to learn
some kinds of associations
and hard
fruitful learn
kinds of associations
first point here is that
we've got these problems
alva learning that undermine
certain
all assumptions of the stimulus response
theory of learning
undermining the assault the association
the assumption of a of all bitterness
you can't joe's pic
stimuli and responses arbitrarily
and expect animals to learn
animals are prepared to learn
those stimulus response associations
their predisposed to learn
by virtue or evolution
and you can't
construe the organism as empty
you have to understand
that evolution has shaped
it's nervous system
so as to
pre parent to learn some things
and to preventive from morning other
kinds of things
finally
it turns out that some of these
experiments also undermine the principal
of association by continuity
let's look at the garcia kaylene
experiment again
we have the bright noisy sweetwater
coming on
come it off
is shock
coming on very quickly after the bright
noisy sweetwater
but look at the
x_-rays you don't feel like x_-rays okay
there's no sensory aspect to being a
radiated with x_-rays but the animal
does feel nauseated a long-time
afterwards
what's happening here is that in the ref
case
rats are forming an association between
taste
of food and its gastrointestinal const
taste of water and it's gastrointestinal
consequences even though there is no
longer it of time
separating the stimulus
response
garcia experiment is really kind of uk
triple whammy as far ends the
traditional as far as there is a warning
is concerned it undermines the
assumption of arbitrariness
it undermines the assumption on vehicle
of the empty organism and it undermines
the assumption of association by trying
to do it
will attack these assumptions all death
or theories of learning from a cognitive
perspective
in our last lecture next monday and
uh... on on wednesday thank you very
much