okay last time we left off in our
discussion all val principles of memory
this
principal in a systematic process in
principle
which has to do with the relation
between
our memory for a particular investments
on the right hand
and i'm not going to check out the world
in general on the other hand
and the general idea here is
that memory for
things in particular
depends on its run the relationship
between those things and what we know
in general and terms of our knowledge
expectations and beliefs
so for example
turns out that they are two different
classes these
that govern divert the alcohol be a
factor
memories come out of general frameworks
arms are no on memory
first is
that schematic on driving behaviors
baha'i dividends that are consistent
with our expectations
said well in
terms of everything that's about the
world
they are very easily in colorado
for that is
douglas came out
wrapper to schema
provides a framework that what you can
understand what's going on
and fit those events rates are right in
at the same token schematic in camera
and events are difficult to encode
precisely because they don't fit with
your expectations they don't conform
with your general believes
you have to think about them for a while
so in working for him and they just
email provides
a kind of organizational framework
weird some events schema concord events
are factored in memory
in another way
this game of provides a kind of
background for elaboration
well you have to explain to yourself
wide ischemic in congruent event
occurred and they're very act-up
explaining the event
all leads to a more elaborate
trace a memory
leads to better memory for the event
later
schematic violent behaviors
don't get either benefit they're not
schema conduit so they don't get all
happy office allocated processing at the
time of encoding
and they're not schema incongruity
so that they don't get the benefit of
this extra forms of elaborate of
activity
said like and what we can do is we can
expand
does come at a crisis in principle
little bit
to be more precise
about the facts out
buddy exact relationship
between the event and pre-existing
schemata
we said already that memories of
function of the relationship between the
benton pre-existing sca model
the first thing is whether the event is
schema relevant
or a schematic irrelevant
does the event
there on the schema in any way
and if so that event is going to be
better remembered
then one that doesn't
bear on the schema
and the second part of the second
distinction that's important
there to raise them but you can be
relevant to a skimmer
if you need to be conned runs with the
schema
or you can be in congruent with the
schema and it turns out
just as an empirical fact
the schema in congruent events
tend to be remembered better
than schema cargo and events
the u_n_ expected
more processing
and all and is better off
better remember
so so far
we've discussed on member all principles
of memory that cover the encoding
the storage and the retrieval stage of
memory processing
and what i want you to see here
is up all of these principles so far
reflect what you might call that library
metaphor of memory
that is the idea that our memories are
stored houses of marriage
and you
put knowledge into memory the same what
do you put a book in the library
dot now which remains stranded in memory
the same way of book remains stored on
the library shelf
and then you want the information that's
contained in memory
you retrieved some piece of information
in the same way
that you would
or or that checker book out of the
library
this library metaphor for memory
has been around since roughly the time
of aristotle and it is not a bad way to
think about on the other of about memory
notion although memories information
that's in korea did
storied and retrieved when you want to
use it
all
it's not the whole story
and the reason it's not the whole story
is that there are other interesting
things that go along besides alm besides
storing
and retrieving information enough in
memory
but ever since i've been how's this
laundry metaphor for memory has
dominated the way we think about all of
about the phenomenon
and the general idea here
remembering
takes a former reproducing sale or rent
in the mind
and colleen
information in memory makes available
for use later
retrieval process these
dana access
to encoded knowledge
and so there are basically to mechanisms
for forgetting
that are relevant to us
you forget something if u_n_ coated at
poorly to begin with or maybe you didn't
even uncoated
are at all
codeine
makes
information unavailable in memory
by the same token
poor retrieval
makes
available information inaccessible
these are the two main mechanisms of
forgetting
when we think about the library of
metaphor of memory
in the same way you go to the library
and say i want to get this book out
and then iris is what we never bought
that book
not that encode it
or the library and says well we bought
that book a long time ago but somebody
stole it and we haven't had the money to
replace its a list of laws from storage
or as sometimes happens on a book just
gets miss florio
and you can't even though it's in the
library someplace the only way you'd
ever financed by going shelf by shelf by
shelf by room by room by room to the
library
of very arduous process
to try to find it
unenglish psychologist named frederick c
bartlett objected to the idea of how its
view of memory as a matter of
reproducing knowledge about events
and he said look im go something wrong
with the way we study memories bidders
back nineteen-thirties
are going to be even with very very
early on
so there's something to the problem with
the way we've traditionally study memory
the weight of the house studied memory
is that
wheat we try to ask subjects
remember things that don't matter to
them very much
things that are disconnected
things that aren't necessarily
particularly meaningful
and when we do that we get a distorted
the image of how hong of how long the
memory works
ambient house basically construed
memory thought is analogous to remember
in a grocery list you know when you're
company go in the grocery store without
a ruthless to try to remember all the
things you
you want to buy
whereas bartlett said
remember it is more like storytelling
when we remember events
we tell stories about these events to
ourselves
will re remember offense to somebody
else in some ways as how was your day
what'd you do today
you tell the story about your day you
don't say read the book
went office
keyboard
you know i don't do that is are well you
know i went and i
check my email another handle time on my
hand so i look at this chapter in this
book and then this person came in
there's a kind of conduct or direct
connectivity to it
that really is very important so what
while it did
was is that ok
we're going to have a new way to study
in memory
if we think that of remembering is like
telling a story then let's study apollo
remember stories
and what he did was to all
develop a set of procedures
in which
he would ask if you've got to tell a
story to a subjects
and then either ask them to tell the
story back to him
and they do that
several different on several different
occasions
what i would call the method of repeated
reproduction
or where subjects would repeat the story
back to him
once and then again a couple days later
in a couple a couple days later
or more interestingly
although erlich invented one salt what's
now known as the method of serial
reproduction
it's kinda like the telephone game that
you probably have played it
parties specially when you were in grade
school or somebody tells you something
then you tell that thing to somebody
else and they tell that thing to
somebody else and so on and so on
and what would want to
observed there
work distortions of the changes in the
forgetting is that take place
as people tell and retell stories
i won't tell you this story but this is
that one of those votes favorite story
it's a native american folk tale bump
two young men from egg you lack who went
down to the river to haunt c olson they
got picked up by a bunch of other
indians and i went to another village in
there was a fight and all sorts of
all sorts of very interesting things
happen
this is a native american folk tale
collected by the anthropologist franz
boss
from i tried in the northwestern part of
the united states
it's got all sorts of unfamiliar
material in a tunnel dot but i looked at
was the tell this to as it was a college
student all the subjects of his
laboratory
and that had them because they don't
tell the story back
and what he discovered
we're a couple of interesting things
first
subjects did engage in some forgetting
what bartlett called ever resolve all
mission
okay
so it was a progressive forgetting of
various elements of the story
all but that would notice
was that the progress of forgetting
affected mostly
narrator details
of the story the subjects and remembered
the gist of the story very well that's a
story about two of a above dot
about two indians mca picked up by some
other indians of the gulf and have a
flight to mirror hunting skills
they got that part
but they what dot the subjects would
forget
were all the minutiae
all the details in the story
moreover
it wasn't just a matter of forgetting
bartlett observed that subjects made
errors of
coalition
as well as all mission
then i remembered
elements of the story edwards actually
in the story
so for example they were to rationalize
various kinds of details so was to make
the story more sensible
to them as
young englishman who weren't familial or
that the lawyer
with native american of the culture they
will transform details
so that
all of the details of the more familiar
to them
whereas the indian but the story talks
about the indians in canoes
they might talk about indians in boats
okay although
his the general idea about object of
floats on water is there
but the exact word canoe was in their
and then i also transform the order
in which the story was told
again in apparent apparently in an
attempt to make it
order to make the story somewhat more
convenient
house
and daughters working in his tradition
basically always observed
first of all the mission that is
forgiving of nonsense syllables or words
or whatever
tablets
technique allowed him to look at
or changes in memory
all reflected in these errors of
culmination
where the subjects would
bring material into
the or memory
that wasn't in the original
on the basis of theirs
bartlett argued
far from being eight matter of
reproducing the information from memory
rather remembering involved what he
called reconstructive activity
that is when we remember something we
don't simply retrieve information
from our heads
rather we'd
build off representation of the event
that we're trying to talk about we
constructed a new we reconstructed
in that spelling
is that what what happens but we
remember something
is that although we get all of our
memories
or sometime in details
indians canoes
arrows somebody dies that's the story of
the two young men from agile ac okay
it's very very big
is fragmentary it's ambiguous
information
he's diem all believe that his subjects
also observed also retrieved account of
general attitude is toward the story
but it was a good story or a bad story
of funny story ary itgi story or
whatever it was that was what they
retrieved
and then based on those fragmentary
details
they'd inferences
about
what was going on the story well-used on
the waters of the most of them something
about both so they were maybe they were
fishing instead of hunting for seals or
whatever
they would make us the in their biggest
inferences
they will be in for making inferences
about what was in the story
based on their general
framework all of the world knowledge
based on their knowledge and
expectations hall and and attitudes
to produce a coherent narrative or as as
coherent a narrative as they could
produce
but one which is not necessarily a
particularly good presentation of the
story
all of them know that if you ever get a
chance to read bartlett's book which
many of you will if you actually stick
with the psychology major
all you'll see that some of the uh... oh
world summons dot the stories department
subjects or produce work
really very bad representations of the
story that they were read
but they were more coherent no in many
ways
network after here
is yet another principle of memory
known as the reconstruction principle
and you'll see
that this is
a principal
that sounds very much like conclusion
that we came to
all at the end of the lectures on
sensation and perception
remember that
gibson had argued
that perceiving was simply a matter of
its team information from estimates that
that's all you had to do
whereas constructive tradition in
perception says
that they perceive a has to go beyond
the information given in the stimulus
and to supplement stimulus information
with general
doll world knowledge expectations
beliefs and so on where basically argued
but the same thing happened in memory
you retrieved some trace information
okay
but you also supplemented trace
information
general world knowledge with information
derived from
your dylan general knowledge expect of
expectations and beliefs
this is a new perspective on the study
of memory
albeit one that goes beyond the or the
idea of memory is information retrieval
and basically all or the connects or
understanding of how memory works
to our understanding of whole perception
works
sickens
bartlett
his
book back in the nineteen thirties
psychologists have been are able to
study the kinds of process ease that
bartlett talked about
within the context
all the familiar brutal learning
paradigm that we use uh... in memory
psychologists been quite ingenious i
think in trying to
all
or make of rigorous
fallen north experimental studies of the
kinds of things the poor little the
bullet pointed out
one of these parallel lines
a basically an adaptation of the verbal
warning paradigm for the study of
reconstructive principles
is bailout
called all the paradigm known as the
eyewitness memory paradigm
that was fault tho pioneered by
professor elizabeth loftis then at the
university of washington loftis is no
professor of psychology
at u_c_ herb i'm
and here
filed as a list of things but the
listeners are more or less continuous
scene
on
so that
there weren't isolated words and
pictures but rather there's a storm or
less continuous seen that makes a lot of
a on narrative presented either as a
slideshow or as a video
and then after
owned it's analogous to bartlett telling
his subjects the story of the two young
men from that you like
and then later on alm
walters will have
subjects
questions about what they've seen as if
they were i witness is of an accident or
crime or whatever
here's an example
bulb for the kind of thing that loftis
david
what i've got a short of going to show
you a little slideshow
and what i want you to do is to imagine
a direct ice tender watching at the
following scenes as they transpire
that's the same that's all you get to
see
now open for the next phase of the
experiment left us what ask particular
kinds of questions like
did anyone passed a couple while they
were walking down the driveway
that another car passed the red dotson
while it was stopped at the stop sign
was there another car industry when the
man entered the crosswalk
was the man in the red shirt the driver
of the dots of
okay notice of is all factual questions
and you can answer them
are correctly or incorrectly based on
your observations
the c
after the sub after we have to some
subjects answered those questions
she vendors
damn any recognition test in which she
presented them with
slides from the slideshow
slides that weren't in the slideshow and
asked them to indicate
which was which
so for example
which arby's
although of slides did you actually see
in the presentation
barbie
which of these lights did you see
the presentation a
yes you saw that when he saw the guy
actually in the crosswalk before at the
red dots and although you hit him
but you actually saw it
this slide
almost all go a lot of loftis is
subjects falsely recognized this slide
why are you
because
besides gotta stop sign in it
and they had already hard a question
remember
that another car passed the red dots and
while it was stopped at the stop sign
the question assumes that there was a
stop sign
in fact
there was a yield sign loftis was a
little tricky here she painted the yield
sign read
okay but still it's a triangular yield
sign that you saw not an octagonal
although the stop sign
but the fact that people
mister clark questioned that resolve the
existence of a stop sign
led to many of the laughter is the
subject
to falsely remember that they have
actually seen eighty stop sign
okay
this is what is known
as
the post event of misinformation affect
okay
it has a traffic accident there is a
critical question
which for some subjects is man leading
did you see a better car pass the reds
dog dotson while was stopped orwell was
stopped at the yield sign which is what
that is
or a leading question
did you see other can car pass the red
dotson while we stopped at the stop sign
a question of storms that there was a
stop sign
when in fact
their wasn't
here is the design of the study
some subjects or a yield sign
or other subjects or stop sign
some subjects were given a question
that referred to a yield sign ok which
is normally dean if you actually saw the
yield sign
but is misleading if you saw a stop sign
other subjects got a question assume the
existence of a stop sign
which is normally dean if you actually
saw the stop sign
but misleading
if you actually saw
you don't sign
and the results of the study on is that
subcompact our recognition of the sign
dropped by about fifty percent
okay
if law for the subjects we were given
the misleading or the question
so if you've got the car would be our do
not leading version of the author of the
inquiry
you were corrected
correctly recognize the stop sign about
seventy five eighty percent of the time
if you've got the misleading version
of the inquiry
correct recognition trough to about
forty over forty percent
this is what's known again as the post
events misinformation affect
and the idea here is
they're leading questions
asked brian interrogator ten influenced
pay all of the matter resolved by
witnesses okay
practices point here
is that memory isn't
purer
your memory other event isn't uncommon
today memory once and for all at the
time the event happened
rather when you remembered something
you take information that was uncoated
and you put it together with everything
else you know
including
the fact that somebody just as to a
question that resume the existence of a
stop sign
so that your final memory your father
though you remember the event
yes i've kind of blood
or information retrieved from memory
an information gathered from other
sources
on stove post event misinformation
effect
because here
knowledge acquired or events that occur
or after an event
can affect memory
although the low four events that
occurred before him
here is another example all of this kind
of reconstructive process in memory
all this is our work by kathleen
mcdermott and all on henry robert r at
uh...
awash in university in saint louis
they are subject to study a list of
words like the following is just a
standard global learning experiment
thread to pin
always sewing sharp
symbol
haystack
borne
injection syringe
and in this team
okay i think that's that's that's a list
of subject study
and it turns out
every one of these words of the study
list
has a semantic associate all got the
word neil
needle thread ten needle needles have
always and so on and so forth
and what happened in this study
was that have been studied or list ald
associates of the word new york
subjects
remembered
that they studied a public nato as well
then in fact day did not
here it is or dildo from that study
here's memory recognition memory for the
study items is pretty good about eighty
five ninety percent of the studied items
work correctly remembered
it turned out
that paul almost the same
percentage of subjects
for also remembered
studying
the word
needle as well
whereas
all of the word that was unrelated to
the list what the word sleep wasn't
falsely recognized all here we have
another example of bartlett's
reconstructive process
if you study of bunch of words all of
which had to deal with the same concept
you begin to show your memory around
that concept
not just around the words
at you studied
leedee noodle falsely remember
information that's consistent with the
concept
even though you didn't actually
all encounter
that information
so again
this this is known as the associate of
memory allusion
because people have an illusion
that they are not an illusion of memory
are that they actually started this word
when in fact they didn't
it's an illusion bentsen induced
by
the active studying all these associate
of lee
although the related words
again
though collisions in memory
just as there are illusions in
perception
and the implications while big
implication of these allusions in memory
is the same as the implication
of what of allusions in perception
and that is
but just as in perception
weeds we do more than extract college
the information from the stimulus
in memory we do more then retrieve
information
frome all
fro moans from storage
we go beyond the information given by
the stimulus
we go beyond the information given
by the memory or trace
so that we can
falsely
remember
in the same way
weakened falsely
or perceive
so damn we have these para phenomena in
perception and memory
in perceptual illusions
we perceive the president's inaccurately
there's a kind of systematic distortion
of systematic bias in our perception
that's a product
all of this constructive activity
entailed in going beyond the information
given
by the stimulus
similarly
we have allusions in memory
where we not proceeding with the
president inaccurately but we're
remembering at the past inaccurately and
again
are there systematic biases systematic
distortions here
so that we remember
the past
in a way that makes it consistent with
what we
believed to be the case
we remember the past
consistent with how we're perceiving the
present
and again
this is an example of going beyond the
information
that's given in the memory trace
so that we want to do now
is to explore the implication big
implications all of this reconstructed
principal and memory
that memory
is a blend of information when you
remember something
what you do
if you work on a mental representation
of some past event
not necessarily in accurate record of
that event
but rather your police
memory is a with our memories are mental
representations of the past
that reflect a blend of information
contained in
memory traces things that are laid down
at the time of encoding
but also
information
that is derived from other sources
information that's
qatar provided by
or knowledge about the world or
expectations about the kinds of things
that go on and it or beliefs about world
and so on
making the point again
memories are knots best viewed as
in orange
in variable records of past experience
rather
when we remember something
what we're doing is we're reporting or
beliefs
about what happened
i believe that the dotson was stopped at
a stop sign
on the police needle was on the list
and so on and uh... and so forth
so i can of the library metaphor for
memory
can take you a long way in the study of
memory loved to try to analyze these
principles by which we encode
information memory
retainer in memory storage and retrieve
stored information
when we want to enter a question about
the past
the library of metaphor for memory is or
ism is a fairly good one as far as it
goes
but the important thing to remember is
that
remembering isn't really like reading
information from a book
remembering
is more like
writing
from fragmentary notes
fragmentary milton coated in memory and
then everything else follows
from or from our various software
various beliefs
so far we where we are now
is
we've got
unified view
are these two important cognitive
functions unified view our perception
and memory
when i started his lectures i reminded
you that
perception
dreads and memory in various ways
in order to
perceive the world we have to draw on
knowledge in police and expectations
that are represented in memory
we've also talked about how
perception
changes the contents of memory
because the act of proceeding
leaves the record
if you will trace or a nanogram
of what we've
perceived
but more important perception and memory
perceiving the world in the present
remembering the world in the past
both reflect
effort after meanie
both the perceive ur
and the remember are trying to make
sense of what they've experienced
the person who is trying to make sense
of the world that he or she perceives
right now
the remember is trying to make sense of
the world that he or she experienced in
the past
perception and memory
both perceiving and remembering
reflect
problem solving activity
the problem for the perceive ur
is to figure out what objects are out
there in the world
here they are
what they're doing
what can be done with them
and insulting that problem
the procedure takes information
from the stimulus environment
combines it with information retrieved
from memory
and produces
representation
all of the world
similarly
memory
the problem for the remember
it's difficult
what happened at such and such a time if
i say to you know what to do you have
for dinner last thursday
or that's a problem
right you got to know what what was was
thursday that they are when shopping
what would make it was too but with left
overnight what were leftovers where
there was some meat loaf maybe there was
some still toll for something like that
that i remember
trying to make sense of the question
trying to solve the problem posed by the
question
is what
uh... or
people do in the act of remembering
and this was bartlett's great insight
at me and i was thought of memory is
something we have
for eddie matos
memories and now it so i think that's
out there
on he even titled his book on their
memory in german
way the uh... went by the germans think
about it
alm over that at least aidid then
well it's
walk was titled remembering
for him
memory is not so much and now not so
much as being it's an activity
represented
by of bird
and it is reconstructive activity
by which the person challenge to
remember some of them from the past
all the information that is that his or
her disposal
and then
builds up
constructs reconstruct representation
that uh... of that passed a vent
so again
perception
and memory
all of the exemplify
this dream
of cognition as intelligent
problem solving activity
where people take
all the information that's available to
them
to try to solve the problem set for them
by their environment
will see the steam workout again
in the lectures that begin on wednesday
on thinking and reasoning and problem
solving
where again we'll see
or people attack
problems posed by their environment in
various kinds of ways
for now that we've got a little bit of
time
so let me are just stop and take
whatever questions you might have
about memory we haven't had that much
time for questions deflection sold for
any questions about memory at all
that is the kind of question what's the
difference between short term memory and
working memory
that's the kind of question about which
there are fistfights conferences of
memory researchers i don't think there's
a dime's worth of difference between
short term memory and working memory
all part of part there are people out
there who all of the pope who think that
is the difference
for our purposes there is no difference
i would never ask you a question that i
asked
that has to make the distinction between
short term from reworking memory
in fairly the differences
short term memory was conf was what was
the heart of construed in early memory
theories
as a place where information is held for
a relatively short period of time
and the point about
start switching the label from short
term memory to working memory was to
make it clear
that working memory was where work was
performed on memory okay it's not just a
passive storehouse of knowledge
but rather
it's a place where you you where
information is
brought into consciousness brought into
attention
did something with it used to solve a
problem or whatever
all it's a little more complicated than
that but that's basically all of the
basically it
but this tension between
so-called short term memory and
so-called long-term memory
thirty seconds
if that happened within the last thirty
seconds we tend to think of it is short
term memory
if it happened longer ago than that we
tend to think of it is long-term memory
that may seem like a stupid way to
define long-term memory but if you try
to remember something that happened
thirty seconds ago
that takes work
right or what was he talking about
thirty seconds ago what was that
landslide or or or whatever
charter memory has a kind of a media see
to it
wears a kind of directory dialed from
consciousness
whereas of long-term memory you're
actually trying to recover a conscious
state
that you experienced in the past
so don't get don't get
caught up on short-term versus working
memory
if you take professor glenn berg's
although professor shlomo result of
memory course like one twenty two
you'll get about a week on that
all but for our purposes you don't have
to worry about it
i had a question down here
these principles work for all types of
memory not address
but they are specially the principles
that govern episodic ur autobiographical
memory
when i started the memory lectures i
said we're going to talk about that the
sonic memory here
and that's where these principles have
basically been on covered
in the next set of lectures we're going
to talk a little bit about semantic
memory
and we're going to talk a little bit
about procedural memory
you'll see that there are some
differences
but still
on
encoding
a semantic memory depends on elaboration
organization
retrieving a semantic memory depends on
she win for mation and so on so that
does the same kinds of principle still
do a ploy
to some extent
altera voters what kind of memory
that that's very fancy called identical
memory
identical review i d_d_t_ i_c_i_ derek
and acclaimed as the focal all
photographic memory that some
individuals have where that something
passes and for them just once and they
can remember it forever
all the
i got a crime rate is something that's
nice if you've got it but hardly anybody
does
also poland
hence the violate some of these kinds of
principles
but even all the studies of people have
fun normal memories
show that
the reason they have phenomenal memories
is not that they have some kind of
photographic process in their heads
but rather
then intuitively use
the kinds of principles
that we talk about here or the into a
deadly elaborate on their memories they
organize them in various ways to use
lots retrieval cues and so on
almost sold out
even i'd so-called identical rs bill
really violate of these rules even
though they seem to have
phenomenal memory so i
i knew a guy
ones too
sat down and memorize
a list of
four hundred words in a single sitting
it just hugged for nominal ability to
memorize stuff
didn't do him any good in life i don't
think but uh...
when you look at how we did it
use these kinds of principles
sqn congruent to their insurrection
remembered it better than schema
cochran's events
and the reason i remembered better is
that when we experience
an event that violates our expectations
that's inconsistent with what we believe
we tend to do is
try to explain how that event occurred
and that extra explanatory activity
creates a more elaborate
butcher
memory trace
than would otherwise be the case
yeah what they'll do is they will change
it but they did not did that subjects
would rationalize would change something
that didn't make sense
and then they remember did very well
they remembered
they'll remember that away they changed
it so that it made sense
the ex drug
cognitive activity is what they
remembered not the event itself okay so
they won't mind i'll remember that the
place was egg you lack
right the name of the village
dino
female british college students they
might remember
fall on eldon
cassell didn't sounds like a cue lack
and that's the name that would be
familiar
uh... to uh... to them
alm
but again does the scheme of
the steam out of the schematic
processing principle
of all
reflex
the relationship between
what you're trying to remember
and what you already know
okay
and
if it's consistent with what we already
know
we remember that fairly well because for
the orignal provides extra q information
if it's inconsistent with what we
already knew
on what we're talking about people do
if you remember it better by virtue of
this elaborate of activity this this
explanatory activity
but you may remember in a distorted
fashion
alm
sold out to all
all
if i save you well what the judy do when
you say well on judy had difficulty
remembering
the uh...
but the chair difficulty understanding
the daytime television show
but you but you also remembers your
explanation for that
she had difficulty remembering the
daytime television show because she was
preparing her role acceptance speech for
the nobel prize
or something like that right and that
wasn't in the story
they'll remember for the event well but
your email remember in this distorted
fashion that was one of bartlett's
insights
well in the back yes
m evolutionary purpose to the fact that
we armed
remember our beliefs but not accurate
records
i think about answer the question two
ways the first day is it's probably a
mistake to look for an adaptive purpose
to every to every feature of the job
that that uh... that we present
or memory is a very adaptive thing to
have okay
alm
and what the reasons that the deputies
that almost as to
control their behavior
although but private behavior controlled
by things other than what's immediately
present in the environment
okay
alm
that but what do you memory works
is also adapted because dole's done a
lot of things out there that happen and
you don't necessarily want to remember
every one of those things okay
so memory has a way of all
we're putting things together
so that you
our group things together so you can
remember individuals individual items
better but not remember them as
individual items ok so all that's very
adaptive part of memory but not
everything we do is adaptive in that
sense stephen jay gould every step of
they had a great example of why do we
have two arms and two legs
we have two arms into lakes not because
that's particularly adaptive
we have two arms into legs
because for descended from fish that had
four fins
okay that's just that's thus that's the
whole story right
memory has the properties that has the
class of
certain constraints on human information
processing we can't remember everything
that's happened to us we can't process
everything that's happened to us
what we remember is going to be filtered
through attention going to be filtered
through believes it's going to be
filtered through world knowledge
we have time for one or two more
questions i think there is an exam
coming up so there's going to be some
noise
yeah is there some kind of medium term
memory
no i'm not really
as i say want to get past about thirty
seconds
well any period of distraction at all
you're really operated on long-term
memory in your following these
principles
okay i think there is an exam coming in
so we're going to let you guys go a
little bit early
horsing around the state west are
talking about think you know language