okay
justice our final reminder is if anybody
needed a reminder we've got our final
exam for this class this thursday the
thirteenth
from eight to eleven a m over a person
gymnasium
alm
the narrative review
for the opt
non-committal portion of the final has
been posted
on told available on the course website
all students with disabilities
aberrations you should have gotten
information for me over the weekend
about
what to do
if you didn't
get in touch
all reminder here's the format of the
final examination first thirty six items
are the non cumulative portion of the
final
dealing with material since the last
midterm
and that includes some questions from
the appendix on statistics
then the remainder of the exam
is a cumulative
exam that goes all the way through the
semester from beginning art to to end
there is a format
remembered or bring a scantron form in a
couple of number two pencils
all got to go to review what the study
guide as always is a good dr lots of
materials on the course website
including the past exams
and remember if you have any leftover
queries questions of any kind
post them to the forum section of the
course website
all
so that i could respond to it and
everybody in the class gets the benefit
of the exchange
please don't send me your questions on
called just by email because then
the whole class doesn't get the benefit
of the exchange
all questions posted by noon on
wednesday will get a response by the end
of business that day
along after that
no guarantees after that you should be
in bed
sleepin
prior to the exam anyway
home so that's the story
our discussion section grades are going
to know some of the jia sizeof finish
their sections under for and event of
their grades the others will do so over
the next though loved dare to so long to
be an announcement posted that your
genocide is of the post of his or raids
on the iraqi people dissipation the
deadline for our p_p_ purchase of
haitian
is today at five o'clock
it takes a couple of days for the iraqi
people to deliver
or roster showing credits
so long about thursday or friday
all-star tangerine org p p credits and
i'll put up an announcement when they're
done
but i can't correct our p p credits if
you've not gotten the credits you think
you deserve
you needed contact with the or p_p_
people
all for that
make sure however
are that you must sign your arkady
credits to psychology one if you don't
do that it's like putting in the class
idea for zaps
if you don't assign your credits toward
p_p_ if you're our cookie credits
dislike one
i hate will not
get notified about the credits
don't just disappear into thin air
also make sure on the tree you do that
clearly questions about though
format of the final exam eddie's
questions what final grading at all
if you're wondering eighteen four p p
you should be did should have been
dealing with your geo sorry
giorgio site will notify me
do you completed the alternate
assignment
walden and that all enter the grades
accordingly so as soon as i get all
those notifications
all put up my own announcement at the
american people were injured
well i'm doing it
let's put this way i am doing it as the
geo size get information to me
couple g_s_ eyes have given me the under
seventeen or kiki credits and i've enter
those already
others haven't yet
i'm on top of it
of dragon audible
anything else
okay let's see if we can figure out what
we've been doing all semester
this is a temporal power didn't bother
apollo adelphi
and inscribed on the temple of apollo at
delphi is this little phrase meant about
yourself
which is what
culture was all about
little bit later socrates off his
deathbed
reminds his disciples that
the unexamined life
is not worth living
these are aphorism was nogales up
the unexamined life is not worth living
exemplify her golden age of greek
philosophy all of the beginnings of the
western tradition and forcibly
out of which are modern understanding of
things although that develops
then the seventeenth century
read a descartes
french a mesh philosopher
hadir radical doubts about everything in
the world including whether he existed
he sat down to think about it
and then realized that because he was
thinking he must exist
couto air goes so my think therefore i
am the beginnings of western modern
philosophy the beginning of our modern
underscore arrow of increase into the
workings of the human mind
modern scientific psychology is also
participant in this history
we've now of although the arranged a
scientific apparatus a scientific
discipline
by which we can ask the same questions
about the mind that have doubled
fall-off suffers from the time of plato
onward
and especially the time from descartes
how the mind works
how mental process these are related to
bodily processes
how we use our minds to also head of the
problems of the encounter in the
environment
on negotiate our relationships with
other people or create new ideas create
new things and all of that
use the same questions fall off the
person that has been for a long time
the first answer that psychology gives
us
is around lines really do matter having
a mind to really makes the difference
because it turns out that from a
psychological point of view
our behaviors part actions
are closed by our mental states
that we behave
ordered the the way we behave in various
situations
has caused
by the way we think about those
situations how we perceive
the president environment
what we remember from the past
what we expect to occur in the future
and halloween think about all of those
things
not just cognitive processes of course
but our feelings
in various situations
our goals in various situations also
matter
to how we're going to be heyy
whatsoever minds what's going through
our minds
causes us to behave
the are
uh... the causes us to behave the way we
do
but i think we know
is that cognitive processes processes on
proceeding
remembering
thinking
are active cognitive processing
we are not behaving installing all
picture wall
all innate reflexes and instincts
condition responses of various kinds
buck we are actively trying to
understand
project
and control the world around us
when we learn
something new we are action to try to
make sense for the world we're trying to
predict in control
the events the we experience
when we attacked
objects in the environment or making
judgments about whether there they are
or not
when we tried to perform to for mental
representations
of these objects we are actively filling
in the gaps of stimulus information
making inferences about
why did object is
object is
big it is
what's it doing
what we can do with it
what it can do with us
similarly
well and we remember
the past we are filling in the gaps
trace information is incomplete
so again
in the same way that we construct a
mental representation of the present
environment
were also trying to
reconstruct
all clear all of the cargo understanding
of the past
both perception
both proceeding and remembering
our problem solving for trying to figure
out what's going on right now we're
trying to figure out what happened
in the past
and finally when it comes to thinking
reasoning and problem solving judgment
decision making
fact process these are not proven by by
recipes by algorithms
but rather they're driven by realistic
sharp cuts
in which we try to make
do the best we can with limited
information to make render judgments
wonder conditions
uncertainty
i've never seen
that we've encountered in this course
is the theme of the interaction between
the person and the situation
people are part of the situations to
which they're respond the situation to
which we respond is an environment
that's full public people
we now understand
that people are not simply affected by
their environments
but whether
that people have the ability to change
their environments in various ways
true create the environment which they
respond
by prostheses like fire evocation
selection
behavioral manipulation
and cognitive transformation
equally important
we've learned that the person
his or her behavior
and the environment in which that takes
place
these are not independent entities
they're constantly interacting with each
other in a system characterized
by body directional causality
where people shape apartments
and environments shape behavior
and behavior feeds back to change the
person who engaged in that behavior
these theme of interaction runs
throughout all of psychology
but especially
all that that is ans especially
important theme
and personality and social
psychology
but it's also a team that comes through
when we talk about
development how do we get
the bags we've got
how do we acquire
though about the capacity that we have
to think
and remember and reason
about the world
this interaction comes up first
when we talk about
how jeans
and genotypes
end up producing individual phenotypes
the interaction
of genetic potential
with environmental reality is what
the individual what he or she
or for that because
the child isn't just a creature that
develops
development isn't just something that
happens to the child
but rather all along the way
the child is in active agent of his or
her own development
the child is
actually trying to
developments trying to develop is
working on at trying to on improved his
or her understanding of the world
and that's true
even past childhood in adolescence
adulthood middle-age or old age
across the waistband
from birth to death
people are parts of their environments
and they are also agents of their own
development
and again when we come to think about
hold the person and the environment
interact
we understand in a way that we never did
before
the profound importance
of the naa naa shared environment
in developing
human uniqueness
but genetic endowment that we share with
other family members it's important
but it's not decisive
the family environment that we share
with other family members
partners is important
but it's not decisive either
the most important aspect of development
the experiences
that each individual has unique
experiences that make
the unique
person
that he or she is
this team of interaction also plays out
when we come to try to figure out
her mental illness happens and what we
can do about it
in the same aid that we see
interactions between persons and
situations
personality
social behavior
and in development
we also see
the same kind of interaction
when we come to understand mental
illness
as a product of the interaction
of going out this is
and stress factors
biological
and psychosocial
factors
doesn't even individual vulnerable
to some form of mental illness
then interrupt
with biological and social events in the
environment
bom
determine
whether somebody is going to have an
episode of mental illness
or not
in the same way
that gina types are decisive for
personality
in the same way at the genotypes are
decisive
for development
genotypes aren't decisive for mental
illness or either
what's important again
is there not shared environment the
individual experiences that will
interact
the jet vidya out this is factors
including genetic factors
to determine
whether somebody is going to have
an episode of mental illness all or not
one of the great achievements of
psychology over the last twenty thirty
years
has been the development although a
large number of
dragons other medications
that can be used too
treat mental illness
to alleviate some of the symptoms of
mental illness
but again
all these these drugs
as effective as a maybe
they do not them by themselves produce
cures form for mental illness
people can take drugs to get symptom
relief
but hong perhaps
do you know that the best tak
is to combine
a drug
with psychotherapy so that those two
agents of change can be allowed to
interact with each other
and magnifying each other's affects
finally to take us full circle
we know that the most effective forms of
psychotherapy
are both suck operate on
mental prostheses
the ones that cognitive-behavioral
psychotherapy is
the try to change
what people think
what people believe about themselves
how people
all re respond emotionally to various
events and so on
cognitive-behavioral psychotherapy is
the focus on the here in though
stead of their and then over early
childhood
cognitive-behavioral psychotherapy is
the teacher person whose skills
helpful person gain new knowledge
or the
all forms of psychotherapy
that dog that really beverly work and
again
bringing us full circle
if you want to
deal with
mental illness
you want to understand
how old the mentally ill or thinking
and perceiving the world
and try to change
those times of things
wireless emphasis on cognition
on the interaction between the person on
the environment the interactions between
genes and environment is the interaction
between dialysis and stress
mean that psychology
has to be a very broad science indeed
as a biological science
psychology has to be concerned with
such matters as how the brain works
howell
no prophecies interact with endocrine
prophecies
how on genetic
all unfold to interact with the
environment to create the individual
bought psychology has to be not just a
biological science
but also a social science
won the tries to understand
harlequin workings of the individual
mine
interact
the workings of the
also c l_ cultural environment outside
the individual
have have to understand not just the
biological substrates of mine but we
also have to understand
the socio-cultural
or context of mine
in the context of biology but one thing
we know for sure
is that whatever's going on in the
borrowing the brain is the physical
basis of it
combined is what the brain dogs
and we're now in a position with new
brain imaging devices
to gain are much more sophisticated
understanding that we barely ever had
before
about
dog biar
the normal substrates
of what goes on argument in the mind the
biological substrates of cognition
we already know
that rather than being a single massive
oregon
the of the brain is highly specialized
with lots of specialized structures each
dedicated to performing
of various of the various psychological
tasks
this brain that we've got
it is a tremendous
legacy of biological evolution we've got
brains like no other creature on those
on earth
the wait our brains were shaped by a lot
by biological evolution has given us a
particular psychological legacy
first by virtue of our
brains
especially hard big cerebral cortex and
especially that big prefrontal cortex
we have this
huge
capacity for intelligence
them nor must capacity
to learn her about the world
members capacity to understand
the things that are going on
around us
evolution also gave us
unique capacity for language a capacity
that's not shared even by our closest
evolutionary relatives like chimpanzees
first language gives us an
extraordinarily powerful way of
symbolically representing boggy of the
world
but also language gives us
an extraordinarily powerful way of
communicating
with each other
sharing with each other
or what uh... what we know
what's going on what's going on in our
minds
and then finally
all of the evolution of the brain
has given us
currently are an enormous capacity for
consciousness
the capacity to
of what's going on around us the
capacity to be aware of what's going
through our minds and the capacity to
deliberately control
our thoughts
farts emotions
goals
and and our behaviors
in the context of culture
we get something else
all in the context of culture
we understand that
although
all of the human culture is itself a
product of the human mind without minds
can't be taught
can't be any meaningful culture
but each individual now has working by
virtue of being in a culture a set of
assumptions
that paul got that that he or she has
concerning
ourselves and the universe
we get from culture
a set of categories
that we used to organize our
understanding of of the world
we get on history
of the
triumphs and errors of all previous
generations
beget institutions like schools
and universities
and churches and synagogues and temples
for preserving art though that the
heritage of the past
and transmitting it
to out to do it too
toot regeneration
we got a series of rewards and
punishments
by which
the culture and poses itself
fine the individual
and we get tradition of philosophy
and literature and art
that we can use to imagine
how things might be different
and to try to or make that imagine that
that imagine difference
or com real
when you think about now
came to be told
what the brain damaged the brain being a
product of evolution
and ninety creating the possibility of
culture
you begin to appreciate that there is
something also a paradox
on going on here
which is that mind which in turn is a
product of the brain
creates the possibility of culture
it's our conscious awareness of what
we're thinking
and their ability to use the language
to transmit our thoughts to what other
people
that's the psychological bases
of human culture
but human culture
also evolves
the individual learns
and the culture evolves
at a rate that is much faster
than biological
or evolution
we are for all intents and purposes
the same creatures our ancestors were
five ten thousand years ago
but in terms of
culture we are very very different
creatures
on entirely
what happened what this means
is that to some extent
minded which is a product of evolution
has given us the ability to transcend
biological evolution
we're no longer simply products of
natural selection
but we have the ability to make
ourselves
to change ourselves
and make ourselves
creatures club that we are
so in the final analysis
mind is the bases
for human freedom
or minds allow us to transcend whatever
happened in the past
biologically
or historically
our minds
give us the capacity
to transform the president to think
about things
new ways and therefore take
different kinds of actions
than we ordinarily would
and also to make our own futures by
transmitting what we know and what we're
thinking
to other people and two other
generations
so by using our minds we can change
ourselves and the world around us
make ourselves and the world around us
even better
but we can do this
only if we do have a great strides to do
in the first place
button that themselves to examine or old
wives and the lives of those around us
this is ultimately
the important task of psychology
to wonder stand how our minds work
and how we can use our minds in the
service of human adaptation
for the geo size
and for myself that's what psychology is
all about and it's been our pleasure to
introduce this field to you
the semester
thank you very much