okay let's continue our discussion of
the aisle biological basis of minded
behavior
first just another center
raksha lead more like a reminder
this is the first week of discussion
sections so you should be sure to attend
your discussion section
all of this week for people whose
discussion sections were on monday they
start next monday
if for any reason you can't go to your
discussion section this week contactor
geoscience they're wise you risk being
dropped from the course
if you're waitlisted for a discussion
section
we should go to the discussion section
for which your waitlisted if there's a
seat available
will do our best
to accommodate you
okay and the last lecture we began by
looking at the elementary and peripheral
parts of the nervous system
no runs
nerves
hollow
feel more
or an article of the system is organized
how the somatic nervous system is
organized into the spinal nerves in the
cranial nerves and all of that
what we want to do today begin by train
attention to
the breath in the itself
this happens to be albert einstein's
brain all which was not studied after
wrong
product a red-eye
and at least on first appearance
the brain seems to be a single massive
oregon that sits on top of all of the
uh... of the spinal cord with some other
structures
located on your needs which all talk
about and not in a little while
art
on closer examination it's possible to
differentiate among various pieces all
of these three bro cortex
by virtue of a couple
couple of landmarks
first looking up at b
cortex
from the front
or from the top
you see that the brain is divided
into two hemispheres
by this also rivero commish or just
means
okay right there
you can see from the top
you can see it here from the uh... from
the front
which to run which divides the brain
into two hemispheres
what left and one right these
hemispheres are themselves
connected
by a bundle of nerve fibers
that are collectively known as the
corpus close them
and this bundle of nerve fibers
actually ball a lot i was the two
hemispheres
to communicate with each other capacity
for mation
or between
themselves
then looking from the side
we see couple of other all landmarks
here is where they
commish arenas bug running right down
the side
is what's known as the central fisher
are very large fold instru broke or text
you can see it here
and einstein's brain
there it is the most left hemisphere
there it is in the right hemisphere
which separates
two homes
the frontal lobe of the brain of circle
cortex
from the parietal lobe
and that there's what's known as the
lateral fisher
so-called because the runs
back-and-forth here
lateral fisher
you can see it here
and orenstein spraying and again
here and einstein's brain
all which separates
the frontal and parietal lobes
from the temporal lobes
of of the year of the brain
and then finally back here
square in the back
all of the brain is a fourth loeb
known as the occipital lobe the division
between the occipital lobe of the other
blobs
isn't quite as nicely d_-mark aid
as these others are there isn't anything
like
the central fisher or the lateral fisher
partnered and in no way
when polum
when you see it
okay so looking from the top
the brains divided two hemispheres
looking from the side the brains divided
into four lobes frontal lobe parietal
lobe
are temporal lobe and uh... and
occipital
these cerebral cortex is also sometimes
known as the neocortex
merely being the latin word for it no
and the reason for that is
that these dog this river cortex was the
last is the last structure in the
nervous system
to develop
and that's true
when if you construct consider
development
fire legit attic lian terms all of the
evolution of the species
the cerebral cortex emerged
relatively recently in evolutionary time
there are lots of animals that don't
have much or cerebral cortex
and it's also true
or that the cerebral cortex is neocortex
aren't o_j_ medically
in terms of the development of the
individual species member
it turns out that these three bro cortex
develops
relatively late
in the palm in fetal com fetal
development
here it is a diagram from sun taken from
scientific american american some years
ago
comparing
the palm
the uh... was triple cortex
in various species
here's a striped bass you can hardly see
yet leopard frog
the grass snake you can see a little bit
of it there
pigeon you can see a picketing
to emerge right there
the apostle
the cats
the mechanic monkey
the chimpanzee
and the human ok all one thing you
notice here is that
all cerebral cortex gets bigger as you
proceed from one species to the next but
that's not the important thing
the body also gets bigger
what's important is
all in humans and all other hominid all
or bob primate species
the proportion of brain mass devoted to
three book or text
is vastly larger
then it is
four non primate non mammalian species
relatively little
brain messes devoted his to the cerebral
when you get to the mammals
an especially get to the primates
a lot of
ramos is devoted to cerebral cortex
so much so
that at in beyond bob primate
all let species
the brain
has to four they cannot itself
in order to get all that's ripple cortex
into a relatively small space
afforded by the along
by deal by the skull
these pictures are a little misleading
because the our brain really is and
decor as there is a really a bundle of
uh... neural tissue look kinda looks
like this
it's really more like a thin sheet of
neural tissues more like a bath towel
than anything else
paldon
done as per from brains were like that
also voters
all and
the in order to get inside the of the
osco case
it has to fold up on itself in his folds
are characteristic falls
lateral fisher
the central fisher and all these or
other
of forms and performances
okay so
viewed file a genetically
when you get to be species that have a
merge most recently in evolutionary time
on the whole lot of cerebral
uh... one zero cortex
and that's true aren't o_j_ medically to
you
in terms of the development of the
individual of fetus member
of this again from scientific american
all again this is the new world to move
all of a fetus twenty five days into
just station
and you really can't see
uh... any differentiating structures
role
thirty five days
some things beginning to happen there
forty days
into just a shit you can begin to see
the beginnings of the arm
triple cortex
fifty paise a hundred days is more than
three months
into pregnancy and that's what the
certain cortex looks like
five months
six months
seven months into just a shame notice
that the
cortex is getting so big now
at its beginning of
develop those characteristic fold so
could fit inside the skull case
eight months
and then nine months you see a pretty
pretty characteristic all human brain
with the lateral fisher very visible
and the
central fishing
or very visible again but this is
getting bigger
so it's not surprising that the brain is
getting bigger what's really interesting
here is that there is that as the fetus
develops
proportionately more of brain mass
is devoted to cerebral cortex
compared to other cartons on vocals
structures
it's a development
that's a bad storm
visible interim proportional terms
not uh... dot in
traditional brainless
alm
this is a specially
true when you consider
of a particular portion of these herbal
cortex
known as the prefrontal cortex
how something can be prefrontal isn't
completely clear that he'd frontera cuts
in front of the front right
all this is a frontal lobe here's the
cerebral
come ashore lateral fisher
frontal lobe here
portion on cerebral cortex
that's way to the front of the frontal
lobe
all you can see
that in the squirrel monkey the cat
the rhesus monkey the dog
there's relatively little prefrontal
cortex compared to the rest of the brain
but when you get to or closest primate o
relative the chimpanzee
and human
a huge amount or brain mass is devoted
to prefrontal cortex with implications
that will discuss in the couple of
minutes
so again palm
when you see this principle proportional
development
more proportionally more gray masses
devoted to cerebral cortex
in humans compared to what his species
and especially that's especially the
case
for so-called prefrontal or cortex
proportionally more of that
is devoted
to uh...
inhuman rather than other species
okay
now underneath
cerebral cortex
or some other structures that are
important
some of them are brainstem structures
others are so-called subcortical
structures
so here's the top of the spinal cord
and you can see
alm
structure known as the middle up
okay which controls vegetative functions
heartbeat on board uh... digestion
respiration things like that
we have the ponds here
which helps regulate cortical arousal
here's another structure
known as the uh... as the cerebellum
which is involved in coordinating alone
sensory uh... motor activity
and then
more beat up
further
off the brainstem
there's a strict structure known as the
fella miss which will talk about in a
minute
so you'd notice of the palaces appear
buried right underneath the cerebral
cortex
here's where the lateral fischer would
be
temporal lobe
frontal lobe frontal lobe looks at
applicable
there are these structures
like the thelma's that are nestled up
underneath
the cerebral cortex
and for that reason they're called are
subcortical structures
so here we have another division of the
brain
basically the hind brain
the midbrain and before brain
so-called
because in
most animals
quadro adalah or the quad repaired
animals
behind brain
is toward the back of the animal
and the forebrain is toward the front to
be on a more we walk operate
sofa ross behind brain is lol okay
and the forebrain
is hot but again if you read in
of literature on your oath lions you'll
see reference to
hind brain structures and four bring
structures in the brain structures
and you want to know
what that is all about okay
so downs on both a lot basics
features all of the anatomy albeit all
of the central nervous system the brain
and the brain stem
bottom-line doing more than anatomy here
this is a dog this isn't a biology
course this is a psychology course
what we what are known really
is how these various structures
how these various components all the
nervous system or related to or the mind
and behavior
water the psychological functions
or these different kinds of structures
all for example
taking a all very dramatic
all lots of mental function
known as a known as coldwell
or loss of consciousness
in which
the patient does not respond but all the
stimulation
shows no signs of a motion
bug the individuals vegetative functions
are okay
individuals in a coma
have lost consciousness
but their hearts still work they still
breathing still digest food and
eliminate food and all of that stuff
their eyes are closed
but they don't seem to go through the
normal cycles of sleep
that a person with an intact nervous
system uh... does
in
patience suffering komal comatose
patients you see the original one ought
to areas all of the brain
you're either a c our damage
the opera portion all of the brainstem
which includes a set of structures known
as the ritter killer formation
reticular formation because it kind of
falls back on itself
or that's the read part of the brain
stem
or the telomeres
here indicated in all blue
which has the function of
are dispersing sensory information
to various parts of the cortex
damage to these
areas one or the other
of these areas all of the brain
will lead to all loss of consciousness
these areas of the brain
seem to have
alarm among their functions
the hong
the presidential of normal alway keep
alertness and attentiveness
but when the damage is confined to these
areas you lose consciousness
but because there's no damage
down here in these brainstem structures
that mediate educator functions
the patient's vegetative functions will
be uh... okay
so when you look at
on
cases like call mark
persistent vegetative state and other
similar on your a logical us syndromes
you typically see
the uh... of the damage in these
locations
and the correlation
between structure and function
the fact that you lose consciousness
when you suffered damage to your review
particular formation or your phone list
it is an important clue as to the
function all of these particular
structures okay don't just sit there
directly doing something
more or less specific
and that is to say
but the function of these structures
is to regulate normal
waking
consciousness
what this illustrates is a general
principle
known as localization of function
the general idea behind
all localization of function
is that different parts all of the brain
are specialized
to serve
different
psychological functions
now this is unrolled idea goes back to
the early part of the nineteenth century
all and a group of people known as
friend biologists
also pseudo science okay
but all in europe
fallen sports time
if united states on guide of actual
whole family trawlers in the slides ours
are promoted the idea but different
parts of the brain
were associated with different mental
functions
and all of the illustrated that all of
this all structure function correlation
with these so called from a logical
heads but you can sometimes find d_n_a_
antique shops
there are always fun
on somebody actually still makes these
poem so if you want to buy one on amazon
you probably him
yeah republican
but according to the front allah jazz
the brain was not simply a single lump
of neural tissue sitting on top of the
spinal cord
instead
the brain was composed of more or less
discrete mental oregon's
you chat with or discrete organs
each of which was associated with some
psychological alva function or faculty
on
in traditional fred a logical doctrine
there were about thirty five of these
faculties
and if you think about it for a second
they represent the kind of
common-sense organization mental life if
we sat down and took a poll instead
one of the things that
people do with their minds you'd come up
with a list that's not on like that i'll
defer knowledges
so they thought that there was a part of
the brain here
located on the near the bridge of the
nose
that was involved in the perception of
foreign
here's an area of the brain they thought
was involved in the perception of songs
here is all a part of the brain they
thought was associated with worth
fullness kind of a sense of humor
on truthfulness
musicality
are they had here is a part of the brain
they thought was associated with
cautiousness
and another one with friendship
and combativeness and destructiveness
amado this an interest in conjugal all
along
home o parental love to a different kind
of love self-esteem back here
benevolence veneration you've tried
these are the kinds of functions the for
knowledge us had in mind
and where they located them
uh... in the arm
in the brain
where they'd get this idea well what
gaulan spurred time would do
is a fine some four and that there's
some guy hanging around the club
that was particularly high in worth
fullness he was always laughing and
giggling ancient telling jokes and then
look at his skull
if they saw if they don't know if they
are going to fight a gun a bulge
someplace in a skull it's a opt
that's where it gets is worthless from
that must be where the homework fullness
area is
or if they found somebody was
particularly lacking in a sense of humor
baby again examiners gold maybe they'd
find a depression someplace and if there
are lucky doesn't have any brainware is
worth fullness area is
armed on so that the uh... that look at
it structured functionality
it was an incorrectly bad way to do
science arena everything's wrong without
a six year old panda
can identify the problems with this
fucked her for knowledge a kind of took
off as a uh... as a doctrine and it
turned out
that the for knowledge us
had the basic idea right
it turns out
that the cerebral cortex isn't just a
single massive oregon
it is composed of a bunch of discrete
centers each associate id
with some psychological function
but without the list of functions wrong
and i got the correlations will
structural rolling in every detail they
didn't get one right
are as far as we can tell
could they have except by accident given
the way they did
so the general idea behind for knology
which is the idea of
all localization function
allah is right
but the details of nineteenth century
from a logical doctrine
or or are quite long
how do we do it today well
we have a number of different ways
although studying structure function all
correlations
historically one of the most important
has been the study of patients with
brain lesions
that is
uh... patients who have suffered the
damage to some particular area of the
brain
and what we can do is weakened localize
where that lesion is what part of the
brains been damaged
and then
sc determine
what psychological functions on a day of
lost
usually these ovations come about by
accident
in the nineteenth century there the
religious study people with gunshot
wounds to the head quite a bit
home
oh and
occasionally as you'll see in a minute
there are surgical lesions to brain
tissue where
all the surgeons have deliberately
excellence on portion of brain tissue
all for other reasons now and then
observed the our correspondent loss of
function
on another technique that's used aud
used historically
is electrical stimulation of the brain
where u
remember that the brains of
electrochemical system of operates on
electrical principles
so what happens in the saudi in these
cases is
you put a microelectrode down into some
portion of the brain
and you run a very weak electrical
current
or through it
stimulating that portion brain and you
see what happens
so maybe you stimulate blood-brain the
person moves his left hand
you might think you could you repeat the
area of the controls movement or in the
left hand
though most recent development in the
all methods for for studied functional
specialization
or a variety of techniques that allow us
to image
the activity all of the brain in nora
logically intact living awake
subjects
so you can put or put a subject in
they own about or c_t_ a scatter
and look at
or the structure of the brain and
correlate that with function
or right online
you can use a technique known as
positron emission tomography pet
scanning
or magnetic resonance imaging apple
m_r_i_ on scanning
to actually absorb the
brain
working what parts of the brain or
active
as subjects perform various kinds of
tasks
not going to spend a lot of time on this
on notice quite a bit of detail on this
involved white man's text specially
chapter three
and there is some detail what it in the
lecture supplements for those of you who
are interested
i don't want to get caught up in the
various techniques
what i want to do is to give you a
little some flavor
or palm or all of this law localization
and function
bob whether it's through study of
patients with brain lesions
whether it's through electrical
stimulation
or electrical recording or whether it's
through these fancy or a new brain
imaging techniques
we're always looking in psychology
to correlate structure with function
what's going on in the brain
when people are engaged installed
particular form
of mental
activity
here is a classic
case in which
our brain lesions were used to infer
the all localization of certain on
psychological functions
this is the famous case of the patient
h_m_o_
who are suffered on young men about
eighteen years of age
who suffered from
very severe
intractable epileptic seizures these
were seizures
uh... that work
they were very frequent they were very
severe
they weren't controllable by anne
of the medications that were available
at the time
truly you solve a all recording
technique called the electoral
insufferable ram or the e_g_
are h_m_o_'s
physicians all localized these up
electric seizures as a reserach thing
from all of the temporal lobe
or in his own in his brain
far ahead as an act of desperation
they decided that they would article
pick out
some of that uh... those of the temporal
lobe
in an attempt to alleviate walden or his
old in seizures itself
radical piece in the rose surgery
uh... everybody said uh... well lots of
people said don't do this
uh... nobody know what these structures
dead at the time
they found out when all by another
h_m_o_ although woke up from that from
the surgery
was what the surgeon standard
was to remove
the interior portion of the temporal or
all the time for world
member frontal
parietal occipital
temporal lobe
the interior portion of the temporal
lobe
including a subcortical structure known
as the uh... that as the hippocampus
and when a gem came out of the surgery
to some extent the operation was a
success he no longer suffered these same
kinds of epileptic seizures they
apparently had excised the area of the
hippocampus of the temporal lobe
that uh... or what where these seizures
were along with were being generated
h_m_o_ no longer had any memory
that is to say
he was not able to remember
anything that happened to him
since the time of the surgery
he was able it meant remember his pre
surgical life
fairly well there's some controversy
about that but mostly he was able ranbir
all preferred of his pre searchable life
post surgical life what the doctors
calls pols morbid all of the x
experience
was completely lost
too conscious recollection
this surgery was in nineteen fifty three
h m is still alive he's living in an
extended care facility and all
uh... in new england
and he has
no
conscious memory
or anything that has happened to him
of anything he's experienced anything
he's done on since the day
the operation
leading
people to suspect that start without no
that this structure the hippocampus
which is lodged inside the interior
portion of the temporal lobe is very
critical for laying down the memories in
such a way that you can get conscious
access to the later
the hippocampus isn't a storehouse of
memory
but the hippocampus seems the forum
a_t_r_ the to perform an important
function
in encoding and indexing memories
so that we could get at
them on the later
we know that from studies have been done
on patients and animals
since the agencies
art here as an instance where age and
lesion in in in a child's brain
led us to new insights
into the relationship between structure
and function question
yeah they took all of the quebec but
this whole shaded area here
the interior portion of the temporal
lobe
and including the hippocampus or the
middle of some other structures on here
they just went in and scope that out
you've got to remember that this was an
act of desperation on the part of
everybody's are a gem didn't want to
live with these seizures anymore
okay they were just don't parables
seizures
just really really really terrible
on there was no other way to control
them there was an act of desperation but
we don't do this surgery anymore right
are
but at the time
nobody knew
puncture the hippocampus was
nobody had any idea that it had any
particular function
if you think about it for a second he
said well it's there it's got to do
something
but nobody knew what it was
people generally thought that the member
orton mental functions were all were
performed by the cerebral cortex
also that you could take out some of
these subcortical areas and not do any
harm
we know better
naal but they didn't know that
yet he was quite a bit of his temple is
not the whole thing for reasons all talk
about the second
alm
yes you're looking for
all ok well there's a device called me a
lot of the electro in southlake around
that can you can attach electrodes to
the skull
and record
the electrical activity of the cortex
underneath
that electrode
there's just enough electrical activity
that you can kind of pickup
going to go through all we've got going
for this goal in the scalp so they put a
whole bonnet of these electrodes on a
gym
and waited for him to have a seizure
we don't know what are you going to know
that's how you do diagnosis right
they waited for about a seizure
and when
they've noticed and having a seizure
they noticed that the seizure activity
which is very clearly visible on the
g_o_p_'s
you recognize it immediately
began
in the temporal lobes
okay so that led them to think
correctly as it turned out that there
was something wrong
that portion of the temporal lobe
uh... that was causing
this seizure to be generated then spread
to other parts of the cortex
so if what part right
if the seizures starting out the
temporal lobe let's chop up some
temporal lobe
and we'll get rid of this
they were right
okay and you know
and we wouldn't do it again we wouldn't
do the surgery again
although they didn't know any better it
isn't that you have no idea how
primitive neural surgery was just fifty
or sixty years ago
uh... and uh...
on but the as i say that's one of these
great and desperate cores
uh... for a uh... condition that was
otherwise
not susceptible to any kind of treatment
all would be yelled with the amount of
damage they correlated with the amount
of uh... tissue took up
that's a general principle but it turns
out it's not the amount of tissue you
take out it's exactly what part of
tissue you take out
ald
here's the uh... here's the hippocampus
right in front of her as the amid the
low there's some other structures here
it's not yet the campus
if they had
take-out is temporal lobe
and left his hippocampus intact
he would have been free of a seizures
annie have his memory
that's very very very difficult to do
and given that surgical techniques of
the time
you can't really separate the
hippocampus from the left the propelled
the rest of the
them you do
new york portion of the temporal lobe
now without very very very very careful
surgery
all of a kind of the just born
alot to do
all thought so
all again if they are
just left at the campus alone
everything within hunky-dory
baat on they had to take the hippocampus
at the same time
they didn't know was going to cause a
problem
let's look at it
but there are cases where people of lost
remember that there are two sides the
brain you got to have a camp life
one left one right
if you take out
alm
one hippocampus and not the other
you still have some memory function
bilateral resection
of the hippocampus
obliterates o conscious recollection
increases so the syndrome
home
yes one more question about
i'll get we're going to get to that in a
minute
alm and that's why they didn't take the
whole temporal lobe out
'cause that actually does some
interesting things
anything else on h m for a second
didn't do they do this procedure were
the ones not too many more times than
once
what they did mostly was monkeys
are not i wouldn't do this again fall
it takes a while forward to get out
okay
but this was the exam was such a unique
case okay
i don't think there's another case of
this
deliberately
on knowing searchable excited of
excision of the hippocampus on the
windward got out pretty fast you
shouldn't do this
and of course half the neuro surgeons in
the country said that this order all
your crazy don't do this
fathers and look we don't know
on and dog
you've got these singers
he doesn't want these features i think
age and gave informed consent
given the fact of what we knew about the
brain at the time
you've got a it's important not the kind
of
impose our current knowledge of the
brain on these guys
they just didn't know
and nobody quoted
that the hippocampus dysfunction one
more question that i gotta go on
yeah i'm not talking car no
he did not lose other functions in the
temporal lobe
for reasons all talk about the minute
okay if i don't answer that
ethnic yet
here is i talked a little bit about the
middle of before
although here's another patient at best
animal
although men who are
suffered calcification
fault
the armadillo
sits right in front of the head here's
the temporal lobe
here's the hippocampus buried in it and
right on the right on the the front
albeit at the capitol aka fender or
something there's a structure known as
you may do well
on this woman had a very very rare
recalled syndrome
known as bilateral calcification alva
mentor
and this is what happened is that the
amid the law
well it calcified returned to
essentially
bone tissue on dried up all and other
than dan turn to something very much
like or bone
and it affected only via made a lot
this son calcification did not extend
into the hippocampus
and it didn't extend anywhere else into
temporal lobe has a somewhat more
this law very rare in rural article
syndrome but you do see cases of it from
our time to time
and what happened in this case
is that patient s_m_ basically had no
cognitive impairments
she didn't suffer amnesia or the way a
gem did cursor hippocampus is undamaged
but she had problems again
promotional all-white
she had very difficult to share a lot of
difficulty experiencing negative
emotions especially emotion of fear
and she had buried on a lot of
difficulty recognizing all other
people's emotional states from their
facial expressions we recognize this on
media lately as a person who is in a
state of fear
bypass them
neither experienced
on nor did she recognized fear
in others
and watch the same way
that weekend for
earth memory function all of the
hippocampus from what happened in cases
like h m
we end for the young motion all
structure of the a mentor
from what happened
in cases like s_m_
it turns out
that the amid a lot plays a critical
role in regulating or a motion all lives
both the experience
and the expression
of emotion
particularly the negative emotions
and particularly the a motion of fear
so here we have
very good examples of how we can use
lesion evidence
to make inferences about
the functions on various alone
of various kinds of of structures
or questions about s_m_
now she doesn't experience negative
emotions
she does it hurt while she does it hurt
as much a motion role
all but she is specially is impaired in
terms of negative emotions
and especially in terms of fear
of the mitchell is sometimes of donors
of
center
uh... in the brain yes
you know what autism have different sets
of problems are going to talk about that
a little bit later on
all but just think this is not autism
okay
and all autistic individuals don't have
particular problems with the amid dahil
on they have problems and experiencing
and expressing the motions sometimes but
that that's part of a path whole package
of other kinds of problems
that autistic people have
on to my knowledge anyway
all we've not been able yet to locate
any discrete brain damage that's
associates reliably associated with
autism
there's something wrong
in the brains of autistic people
presumably
but it's nothing like a discreet lesion
in the hippocampus or the amid dole or
anyplace else
one more question that i gotta go on
aslam dot that
since her memory was an apparent can't
you remember fearful experiences
bunny i got into that two ways
the first is that you can remember
fearful experiences that occurred to her
before her amid the leg dot calcified
all yeah i remember going up in this
tram once on a ski slope and i was
looking down i was really afraid i was
going to fall
she can remember that
she cannot reproduce that experience the
ways you can
if you were telling a story about the
time when you were afraid if should
begin to feel free to get
she doesn't have that
experience okay
second point
something will come that'll be more
understandable later on
sheet enter our choir deneuve fear
responses
okay
but you can learn to fear
something
that she didn't fear before the damage
occurred
but she does experience fear now is that
you can learn about fear
watch you can do
is to recognize objects that
but on how to put it
she can recognize objects that sheet
ought to be afraid of
okay
so you can show her a picture of a
rattlesnake if she had never seen a
rattlesnake in say look when you're hot
muck around in the desert staying away
from s
and she can learn that all ok i will
stay away from this
she doesn't have
but fear or
experience
that would go that that would be the
basis for most of our learning about
this
she can learn about
things to be avoided
things to be feared in the abstract
but these are not accompanied by any
experience
or fear
the amid door seems to be
important in generating that experience
when you made that was gone andy the
experience is gone
so there you go
two examples of how legion evidence can
be used
to infer aldy structure is a very
assault piece of the brain quick
question
what happens to the physical effects if
you're like sweating then dribble
dilation
they are generated by the amid deluxe
pyramid billet is gone
she doesn't have
those physiological
the fact that just
not part of her behavioral repertoire
any longer
precisely because
the amid all of the generates those
physiological all responses
turning attention
to the cortex itself
on get back to blog a couple of other
questions here about special about the
temporal or the the temporal lobes
we can
get other evidence all of the structure
function relations
by looking at they unfortunately large
number of patients
who was stuffed with suffered from under
a logical syndrome known and stroke
strokes are basically heart attacks that
occur in the brain not enough
art there is a l
vascular insufficiency
an insufficient blood supply to the
brain lettuce and carrying the oxygen
the brain needs to step to stay alive
and so certain our structures
or in the brain on died
this is all rough diagram of the
pasteur ization the brain and you can
see that there are these
big blood vessels that run up along the
of the central fisher
carry lots of blood to various parts of
of the brain
in people
suffer from a stroke
vascular insufficiency or an
insufficient
blood supply onto the brain there are
three
common symptoms
that we are that we observed
the first of these is paralysis
all laws all voluntary motor function
somebody down here in the last lecture
asked about hemi plea gel
handy please just something that happens
with strokes all loss of voluntary motor
function
okay
anesthesia especially tactile anesthesia
all walks of tactile sensation in
various parts of the body
nother prime alcohol prominent symptom
of strokes
and then finally
on under logical set of symptoms known
as aphasia
are basically having to do
with all laws of speech
and on dan dan and language functions
and what happens now
is that especially by virtue of
examining stroke patients and we are the
damage it
is occurring by virtue of
insufficient blood supply to the brain
weaken and for
additional aspects
structure function
uh... relations
so for example
we now know
that they're is a portion all of the
frontal lobe
just adjacent to the central fisher here
is the central fisher
your celebre fisher
frontal lobe parietal lobe
there's a portion of all of the frontal
lobe
that is known as the primary motor area
and this appears to be an area that
generates voluntary
motor behaviors of various kinds when
psalm or all all of this
portion of the brain is damaged
five because no blood is getting to it
then you lose
uh... some voluntary motor function
on me
by the same token
there is a part of b parietal lobe
just adjacent
to the central of the fisher
is called the primary the primaries some
out a sensory area
and there seems to be an area the
processes
tactile sensation
from various parts of the body the sense
of touch
damaging in this area
all will all be solved
in the loss of tactile sensation
in various
all parts of the body again we know this
primarily from stroke patients there's
other evidence as well
or that suggests that
here in the frontal lobe
a part of the cortex this devoted to
generated motor activities voluntary
motor activities
and we have a part of the pride elo
that is devoted to
recvd
tactile sensations
from various parts of the bond
or in fact there's quite a bit of
interesting organization
both the all
frontal motor area
and a parietal samanta sensory area and
this could be illustrated by what's
known as the actually two structures
percent three a motor home uncles
comatose is just a little latin word
means little man
okays little man
uh... in the head
and don't wilder penfield the great
canadian on nor a surgeon
all views dog this as a way of
illustrating
what parts are going on of the motor and
dull thoughts about a century arias
or associated with
what functions so here
a magic now
that we've
sliced the brain down aka along the
armed
along the central fisher
and we're now looking at it
from the inside
here is the cerebral commerce your
that divides the
brain into two hemispheres
though inside this rubelcaba sir done
here
and then running and write down
the central
uh... here
into
ontario
doll it popped up next to the lateral
fisher which is what this is
in the frontal lobe
okay
what we have our
various areas all of the frontal lobe
that are
dedicated to various parts of the body
so here in the frontal lobe in these of
the area
tucked in the end of the senate federal
fisher
is apart of the frontal lobe the
controls the motions of the toes
the feet
the lower leg the operating
the torso
now were
coming out
the interior portion a brain
down the side of the operable dove right
next to the central pressure
part of the more motor cortex the
controls the operon arm
lower arm
the head
the fingers
the bra leatherhead faith
the job and here's a portion tucked up
under here aware the lateral fisher is
posted that controls swallowing behavior
eat the motor activity of each different
part of the body
seems to be associated is associated
controlled by a different portion of the
frontal
of the frontal lobe
similarly
with us about a sensory areas of the
priroda low there's a different part of
the some out of sensory cortex
associated with each individual part of
the body
so here talked into the all org of the
central connoisseur is a part of the
error that
receives tactile sensation sensations
from the janet elliott
then the toes
the feet
the lower arm
the lower leg at the opera
the torso
now running down next to the central
fisher in the primal world
ya perot arm lower arm
and fingers
tactile sensations
in the face
the eyes the nose the faithful lips
here in the teeth
but all of the tongue parents and so on
talk to your under all of the lateral
fisher
notice
two principles
that we talked about when it came to the
spinal
all of the today to the spinal nerves
first is a principle of regular
association
apart of the frontal lobe
that controls the movement of the
fingers is right next to the part of the
frontal lobe the controls the movement
of the head
but part of the frontal lobe controls
the movement all the lower leg is right
next to the park while before on frontal
lobe the controls the movement all of
the
of the opera way
similarly art and for the sinatra
sensory cortex
on the primal side
there is our regular association
between the part of the body
that's been moved or being sensed and
the part of the brain that's doing the
movement or doing the sensing
donor what the jury is should notice
here
is again
a feature all of
proportional
representation
in the frontal lobe
the amount of frontal motor cortex
devoted to the various parts of the body
is proportional to the need of that body
parts
for fine motor control
very fine motor control on your fingers
look at how much
cortex is devoted
do your head in your fingers
compared to
the trunk of your body which is by any
standard much larger
similarly
in the samanta sensory all area of the
pride elope
proportionally more parietal cortex is
devoted to those body parts where you
need
fine
tactile sensitivity
again
in their heads
in the face palm
on in the yard in the feet
where you want a lot of tactile
sensitivity
you've got a lot of tissue
devoted to that body part
though ads with the spinal nerves
we see again this these two principles
of organization come into play
regular association
between
some part of the brain
and a part of the body that it serve
and a proportional
association
between
some part of the brain
and the body or that it serves
two more things
we also have
here and at the time to roll over
what's known as the primary auditory
aerial
the lateral portion temporal over to
looking outside
from from the outside you know
here's a look at a party temporal
temporal cortex that's devoted to
auditory processing to hearing and so on
and hear the very back
of the occipital cortex is apart all of
the brain
that is devoted to visual processing
when somebody experiences
cortical deafness there are lots of
different kinds of deafness
but cortical deafness
typically involves damage to this
portion of the temporal lobe
which is the primary auditory area
cortical blindness there are lots of
different ways to be blocking
but cortical blindness
in typically involves damage
this primary visual area
the occipital lobe
so again
we have
had this okay
there lots of different visual areas as
well don't worry about that
but basically
what you've got here
art illustrations all of the principle
of localization of function
motor function in the motors tripled our
frontal lobe
some add a sensory function in the some
at a sensory area of the parietal
auditory processing in a piece of the
temporal lobe visual processing and
appease of the occipital lobe
something about memory in the
hippocampus something about a motion in
the end that door that's the general
story behind localization of function
will complete it on monday thank you
very much