okay for those of you will just come to
berkeley for the first time will come to
berkeley for those of you were soft
porous or more will come back
in any event welcome to psychology one
general psychology
the introduction
to the fuel depots psychology
alm
might instructional stroma professor in
the department of psychology and all the
lord chief content provider
all for the uh... for the chorus the
semester
all right here it's the contact
information star that's important sold
for one your syllabus
are just coming in pick up a syllabus in
the back of her aware that there is
still some still left
all of the blue sheets we ran out of
will have more on wednesday and their
landline more on that in nam
kate does course or consists of
lecturers and discussion sections
the lectures will meet the for two hours
a week monday and wednesday at ten ten
will start promptly at ten ten and i go
by that clock
not by dot clock which is always a
little off that's the official clock
on there and will go through straight
through until eleven o'clock everyday
including today i have some arm bios on
mon things to talk about
all-in
for those of you who are interested in
them there are black white mean lecture
notes available for this course will
talk more about that you know in a
minute
but the lectures are monday and
wednesday and then if you have a
one-hour despite section led by a
graduate student instructor
that meets once a week
these discussion sections do
not meet this week
hard enough to get for you to get your
schedules organized and have to do with
discussion sections
but they will begin next week
bearing in mind that net on next monday
as labor day
there won't be
discussion sections on labor day
but on tuesday before it
our discussion sections will begin
forgot watchers we've got the discussion
we've got some examinations we got a
couple of other things
all up to talk about
first let's talk about the discussion
sections which as i said before
are going to be led by graduate student
instructors is a graduate students who
are
serving apus teaching assistants in the
course
these discussion sections will vary in
format but it's a pickle discussion
section
will begin with
arg some kind of presentation by the
graduate student on some thought topic
that's relevant to what we're doing all
in class
followed by a period of four
question discussions and all of that
kind of stuff
remember no discussion sections this
week
discussion sections start next week
let me introduce to you though do you
have size the graduate student
structures that are arm
all affiliated with this course first
mario chalmers
all stand-up maria
mario chava season not developmental
psychology
while melissa adams font
is in cognitive neuroscience
three alexander
in educational psychology
erin gibson
in cognitive
psychology
take kaplan
in clinical psychology
on rice martinez
in social personality psychology
alexander o'connor
in cognitive psychology
charlene can
in developmental psychology
and lindsey shaw taylor
in social psychology so that's the group
you'll get to meet them on next week on
the court's website about which i'll
have more to say in a minute will get
dongle all of the r_t_c_ assistance the
geo size associated with the various
sections
so we all know all
or who to
who to contact
okay
if you're waitlisted for this course
the chances are pretty good that you're
going to be able to get in we have some
slots left
but admission to the courses through
discussion sections
there has to be a vacancy in the
discussion section for which your
waitlisted in order for you to move into
the course okay
all got usually happens
we added three new sections of there are
those of the course just last week
those are pretty vacant
if you can move into sections one twenty
seven one twenty five one twenty six two
one twenty seven
which meet monday or tuesday
all your chances of getting into the
class are very very very qualified
all priorities demand a freshman
sophomores
the reason for that is this is all this
course is a prerequisite for the
psychology major
by the time the finished yourself or
your euphoria declared a major in
something unless you don't need this
particular version of psych one all so
much
but to all
will move people automatically off the
waitlist or into the chorus as seats
open up
art in accordance with their ranking on
the waitlist for discussion section
what matters is where your waitlisted
for the discussion section up for the
course a whole
with priority given to freshman
sophomores
so what you should do beginning next
week is attend the discussion section
for which your waitlisted
okay
if you don't attend the discussion
section for witcher waitlisted
there is some risk that we will think
you're just not interested in the course
and will drop you
to make room for somebody who is so
beginning next week
go to the discussion section that your
enrolled in
where your waitlisted for we'll see what
we can do for you
if for some reason you can't attend
discussion section next week
get in talked at in contact with your g
s_r_i_ will post those names to the
website
or probably waiter of later today
okay so that should be
fairly clear
i mentioned before there is a
note-taking service here are at the
r_u_c_ of the berkeley
all-black lightning lecture notes this
is the only authorized note-taking
service on campus
or this course dean one of the larger
courses on campus has a black lightning
note taker
all of these notes are not a substitute
for your own notes
educationally speaking in terms of how
people learn
there is absolutely no substitute for
having your own notes to put your own
spin
your own organization on things
however if you have to miss a lecture
or you want another perspective on what
went on to lecture
the black-white name lecture notes are
can be very all valuable
i think they cost thirty nine box for
the semester
which is a pretty good deal
all and you can get more information
about those
are at that
the that don't you worry at all
all of the l allen at secure so it's
uh... dot com
what a what about examinations we've got
three exams and of course two midterms
and a final
the two midterms are going to be
administered in classes one early
october there's one in mid november
and then there's a final examination
the midterm exams are non cumulative
exams
first midterm covers everything
beginning today going right up to the
first midterm second midterm covers
everything since the first midterm right
up to the second midterm and then the
final exam
well cat will have undocumented portion
that covers everything since the second
midterm
and then if you want a portion of covers
the entire class
educationally one test is not
a good idea who want to give you a
chance to go back over the entire
material
ought to take a test on from the second
time
it turns out
that you learned things better
the final exam is scheduled for on on
december thirteenth
eight oh eight to eleven o'clock a
morning we don't know where yet
but it'll probably be some jimmy and
some gymnasium
all the exams and of course are multiple
choice computer scored exams
that's to make sure that the scores but
that is the exams are scored reliably
and fairly of for everyone
despite being mortal traits computer
score they emphasize basic concepts and
principles
they don't as fuel for of god
datagrid about names and dates
while we're not told particularly
interested in that
and the exams cover
the readings and the lectures with
roughly equal emphasis i could not be in
the short time that's available to
ordered to leave basically thirty
lectures
cover all the material it's in a text
book
who do your textbook is the best
introductory psychology textbook written
over a hundred years it doesn't
wonderful job all-volunteer
of covering all of the territory
and we hope you'll do well but they will
hold you responsible for the material
it's in that class it in that book as
well
uh... important policy
there were no make-up exams and of
course
okay so we expect you to take the exams
when they're being administered
if there's some kind of family emergency
you're kind of stock in my lawyer
something that your grandmother's
funeral
will deal with that
but outside of that
you we expect you to be here
four all for the exams
their arch hello there aren't any
make-ups
yes
wells we want to
or another component to all of the
course is what's known as the research
participation program
over going to talk a little bit more
about this on wednesday
but for now
all by virtue of the parvin policy
the introductory in mid level survey
courses inordinate psychology department
all have associated with them
and research participation of all the
requirement
the reason for that is pretty simple
on psychology as a science
so laboratory science
if you were taking a course in physics
or chemistry or biology there would be a
laboratory section attached to that
course
that would give you a chance to roll
bulls down incline
blow something up by mixing chemicals
walls dissect of salamander or something
like that
we can't do that
here we can't give ear a little pigeon
or white rat to play with we can't have
your running around
administering
questionnaires to all your own hold all
your role of the door mates
so they've research participation
program
is designed to allow you to see
how psychological sciences darden
how data is collected how experiments
are conducted in all of that
at the same time
alba by participating in our ongoing
research projects
uh... in though
or the debtor while being conducted by
faculty and graduate students in the
department
in this course all the requirement is
five hours of research purchase of
haitian
or spread out over the course of the
semester it's not a very onerous our
requirement most of the experiments
all of that dot
all that door
part of the research purchase vision
program are
pretty interesting kinds of things to do
some of them are as straightforward as
completing some survey questionnaires
orders involve you talk to the ditch
were involved in doing
or actual experiments with
computers with other other and other
kinds of machines in uh... in the
laboratory
and that was
do you
do this
is by signing up
on you get your credits through the
research participation program website
the ul for that is on your syllabus is
wrote there is also a link to it from
the course website
but it looks like that you go to walden
go to this u r l right up here
psychology operably slash party p and
you'll see a number of links
all right over here
are all a number on other number of
other links
the below you too
establish
an account basically to sign in
to the for the iraqi people graham
and also to or sign up for various kinds
of experiments
we're going to talk about that more on
wednesday there'll be a representative
of the research purchase a patient
program
here to talk to you at that time but all
the information
a boat that you need about or p p
or on those blue sheets that many of you
were able to pick up
arm
of will have more blue sheets on
wednesday for those who didn't didn't
get one today
there's also a link or through the blue
sheet
off the or p_p_ website so there's
plenty of opportunity
for you to get information about these
uh... kinds of things
okay the textbook for the courses
psychology
pretty good title
by all henrik light menendez and his
associates
all henry clay benzoyl long-time
professor at university answering it was
one of my professors in graduate school
daniel race partner
all who is a uh... psychology professor
at reed college in oregon
and james grows
who is a psychology professor at uh...
at uh... at stanford
the all blvd version of the text for
using is the seventh edition it's brand
new
different
from this exhibition
different organization
different all authors for that matter
also the sixth edition
all which we've used in past additions
of the scores
won't or do
we want you to to be using the seventh
edition
there is also a study guide for the
seventh edition of all gone point in
psychology
by wrong
one quite been restored and grow strong
tonight as soon as that or university of
michigan
and pull rawson who's one of going twins
colleagues at university of pennsylvania
on this study guide is very very very
useful
it has little quizzes little exercises
fill-in the blank kinds of things
that will help you to
all improve your mastery of the material
or in the course
all of the textbook is
required
the study guide is recommended but it is
very highly recommended itself very very
very good
all resource
although you first thing we want you to
get ignored all were called snaps
the norton psychology labs
this is basically a password
to an online long ordered a set of
laboratory exercises
you will do a eight of these in the
course of the or
of the so
uh... course this semester
alone there more to they're more details
about that
in the home
in the syllabus
but basically or when you buy this thing
you get the or password
that allows you to register
for the door and psychology labs
where they called the snaps
well these labs word actually developed
by a group of dutch researchers
anzac sues the doctor abbreviation for
psychology ones
don't ask me i'm not dodge right but
that's basically what it means
well but in any event
are all three of these items the
textbook the study guide and the
password for zach's
we have arranged to be packaged in a
single unit
art that's available at a deeply
discounted price at the a_t_f_ you see
bookstore
okay are you might be able to get it
someplace else all but i know you can
get it at the issue c bookstore
all shrink wrap together and a reduced
price over a very good customers for
norton
and they give us
the best price column that uh...
that they can that they possibly can
so where you get it what you want to do
is make sure you get the textbook
ball which is required
zaps password which is required the
study guide get it or not but i really
really really
or recommend
okay so what happens when do you want to
get your zaps password
you go to the zaps you our elders ul
uh... went to what off the course
website
what you want to do
is to along
register over here
click and to register
once you register that takes you to a
page where you can enter the site
or to update your account settings
notice down here that there's a place
for you to input your class i d
you most input a class lady okay
all otherwise i have no way of giving
you credit for those that slabs that you
armed that you complete
that's the classified the
it's also on your syllabus
it's also on the course website but make
sure
when you update your account settings
that you put in your class lady and you
put in this particular class lady
before you complete
an evil any zaps lab exercises
okay on here is at that he went to the
flight
you get a screen the looks like this
with a whole bunch of
or exercises
you can do is many of these if you want
they're great fun it's probably better
than going out drinking on friday night
oh that's what i do on friday night i do
these things
but there are dates epic ones that are
required
okay
and those specific aids that's what
that's exercises
are the ones that are indicated in your
syllabus
do as many as you want but you've got to
do those eight and you only get credit
for doing all of those all of those
dates
okay discourses webcast
that is the lectures
with me
and that
of are rather the video is available
on it's also available on podcast i
think i know i tunes or something or the
like that in any event if you go to the
webcast website
scroll down and you'll see a listing for
psychology one
an indication of where both webcast and
podcast
if u after nasa lecture
or there follows something went by too
fast to what everyone another crack at
it
or you'll be able to get that
resourceful or feel off the web
another all resource we have to the
class
all it is a website that is maintained
by W W norton the publisher of your
textbook
with all sorts of interesting things on
psychology related to deployment was
articles
on exercises all the walden essays on
various topics on again
there is
aneil
this do you worry all dates in your
syllabus as well
if you buy the text on used to get a
password
to dog norton website for free
or otherwise
all of you can purchase one if you want
and then just access the site and it
takes you over to a page with all sorts
of interesting along alone things on it
for studying mastery on enhanced
learning
and all of that
week this course also has its own
website indeed space
which is an instructional website that's
maintained by prickly and a number of
all form
maintained by berkeley and a number of
volatility of universities
if you are
registered for the course
or if your body listed
you order matically have access
to this classes
of website
these days
all of that some point
when we're no longer bring taking
students off the waitlist
all waitlisted students will lose access
but if you're in rolled
your automatically given access to this
website
so what you want to do is point your
browser at this you are l
and our once you login over here
logo you'll be taken to a lot only page
looks like this
double latest all the courses for what
you're enrolled or waitlisted that had
the state's web sites
okay in this will be one of them
also you just click on that
and have been you'll be taken to a page
that looks like this
or there's another gation bar down the
left hand side there are some notes here
all here's the
clap of the course idea for the zaps lab
exercises
there's a little calendar year where you
can see what's going to be happening
there are unknown stands over here
and as they say
there is a navigation bar this is a
blow-up of the navigation bar
there's a copy of the syllabus
all record of apollo galileo record of
all the announcement of the class
here you can check your grades as you
accumulate them over the course all of
the semester
the forum is a discussion board
if you have any questions about the
lectures are readings
poster question to the
all org or that the to the forum
and they'll get a response from mir
maybe one of the geo size
are relatively quickly
here's a link that'll take you to all
the illustrations that are used in the
my lectures so you can't chest look at
those again
here's another link that takes you to
lecture supplements which are basically
things i'd want to talk about if i could
have you forever
but since i don't
i've written a mop or and all you'll see
lecture certain supplements for each of
the lectures here
with a lot of additional material
this link on exam information
takes a little page that describes the
philosophy of examinations and of course
how the examinations are scored agreed
to calculated
it also it
patients dot
all previous exams in this class
to get some sense of the kinds of
questions layouts
with answers
mostly
the right answers
while sometimes you know there's a slip
and i just didn't catch it
all but i think the mostly the you know
the correct answers
on here's a link to the court's webcast
here's a link to the or p_p_ program
website there is a link to the zaps
website
here's a link to the point and
overbooked
on here's a link for section info within
a day or so
dawn the section info will be complete
and we'll have information about or
which geo saris or working with which
uh...
uh... which sections
okay how we calculate grades
there are three hundred and forty points
available all for this course
the midterms are worth fifty points each
so there is a hundred points right there
final exam is worth a hundred points
all of section
our discussion sections worth a hundred
points discussion sections are a scarce
resource
so they're valuable
on
both hundred points are going to be
determined
but in large part by attendance and
participation on that sixty points for
section
and then completion of the zaps
exercises is going toward give you
another forty points that's aids affects
your sizes in the forty points five
points for zaps exercise and then forty
more points
for your five or research of purchase of
haitian
or credits
here are the grading standards for the
class
traditional industry standard
if you accumulate at least ninety
percent of available points
you're guaranteed sometime today
accumulate at least eighty percent
guaranteed some kind of the
fifty one percent or more guarantees you
some kind of c
if you're breathing
you can accumulate fifty one percent or
more of these points
pretty much you've got to breathe
regularly project
i do that deliberately i don't want
there to be any pressure on people are
ordained by going to get a deal we're
going to get enough
almost certainly not you really have to
screw up with me
to get but the wrath
okay
bought you know if you get in the
psychology to find out was boring
origins as too complicated or whatever
okay
the worse it's going to happen to you
with some kind of c
alm
but to all of these already as i say
industry standard grading standards
what i do want to go to set the final
distribution of grades
i'd check my distribution of grades
i guess distribution of grades in all
other introductory courses in the
biological and social sciences and i
make sure that my distribution matches
that
so we all do a look
the class will do as well in this class
as classes do
in general on average by green standards
are writer more liberal
nor more strict
then they are
at the rest of uh... address the campus
okay
anne we're going to talk a little bit
about what psychology is all about the
for now any questions about the
organization and format of the course
disaster exercises are graded on
completion
i get up i gather notified by saps when
you've completed your zaps
okay
there are deadlines
for each of these okay
that it takes
a couple of days for the feedback to get
the new take takes me a couple of days
to get buffing up on the grade book
but basically it's although it
automatically
and it's on
or not
you completed
if you completed you get flight bookings
if you don't
yeah i don't
well that is the curve ok we'd you're
just accumulating points
so there's fifty points for every
midterm for each of the midterms hundred
points for the fault them for the for
the final
we don't set the curb until the very end
okay
all but as i say
if you accumulate ninety ninety percent
point you are guaranteed some kind of a
no matter what the curve is
loosen the curve
but i will never tight-knit
ninety percent guarantees sometime today
eighty-percent guarantee some kind of
the
question back here
but if there's little reason for you not
to be a discussion section talk to your
geoscience where you can work it out
now that but there's no make up for
labor day pick
there's no discussion section on labor
day
yell and you'll notice that the very end
the last day classes on monday
okay so that's not an issue
gotten like thanksgiving
going home for thanksgiving if your
discussion sections on thursday or
friday
because that's where your geoscience yes
does that sex is sizes are for this
class okay
they are not experiments in the sense
that you're not creating data for
science these are
laboratory demonstrations
and that's what just what should have a
lot of exposure to various kinds of
things in the class
the or p_p_ is one way to do it
zaps is another way to do it
but they are
independent of each other
one more question ya
i'll be using the seventh edition of the
leibman until there's an a tradition
arm extremely loyal
to why will professor
the passwords will be good for ever as
far as i can tell
anything else yes
my office hours they were on the first
flight monday and wednesday eleven to
twelve
but not today
okay i've got a stud i thought that i
have to do at eleven o'clock alone today
also referral forbidden by appointment
furthermore i try to get here at least
ten minutes before class
i try to stay
until the last of u leaves after class
so if you have any difficulties doll
making office hours
nobody shows up for office hours because
there never convenient
for most people
just send me an email we can make an
appointment we could probably do
whatever we need to be
whatever transact whatever business we
need to transact
over email
anything else about the organization for
men of the course yes
the alternative test if you're not a
good all the pens
if you turn eighteen
by the end of september you got plenty
of time to do our p p
if you turn eighteen on october first or
after
probably not
also on there's an author of a cited
involves doing some in some additional
zaps exercises
so if you're under eighteen
don't worry about it
we've got you covered
no there's no mechanism for that
that they'll all be peace dot bill to do
that it's is itself zero-based budget
uh... if you will
or anything else about the organization
for men of the course
mole know they're just kill your back
so now you have to bring the textbook to
class i don't like to read to you from a
textbook or anything like that
professor do that once
but the
that so much for a soul
i would just leave them in your
we got stuff in your rome
in your room once in awhile
you're
all
g_s_ all you might ask you to bring the
text of discussion section but
not very often
something back here
that these guys webs whenever right
update something to be space website i'd
try to remember to send an email
announcement to everybody
but the discussion board
that's not something that you get a
naturally in email announcement of that
something you just gotta get my habit of
checking
okay
if you post a questionnaire well check
for the response
alm
but think when you start poking around
on the these days website you're going
to find it's a pretty damn good website
it's got a lot of resources on it i
spent a lot of time on it
also i think there is feedback
giving feedback
mostly positive
anything else
yes
rests right here in the
work within two if you have a discussion
and you want to switch discussion times
we could almost certainly do that
informally
okay so deal with your geoscience out
that you might be able to move into one
of his or her other discussion sections
that the that's the easiest thing to do
or swap with somebody else we can
arrange that too
whatever you do
unless you're going to that are sections
one twenty five one twenty six two one
twenty seven
do not to walk
your discussion section because what
will happen is telebrands will kick out
of the class and put in the bottom of
the wedding list
so we'll do all of that informally
beginning next week
anything else
haven't left anything out
where or
no no extra credit opportunities
alm
and the reason for that is it's just not
fair
some of you have a lot of time on your
hands
or others of you have fav
five-person families in your holding
down three jobs at extra credits just
not fair
no starbucks for me
i don't drink coffee actually
although you'll find that i dressed like
a blockbuster clerk i don't recall
anything else
all right so what are we going to be
doing this course
william james who wrote the best
psychology textbook
besides glickman
all
great american philosopher a pioneering
american our psychologist
define psychology as the science of
mental life
the whole point of psychology
is to describe the nature and function
of mental structures and processes the
mental structures and prophecies
that all underlying
human experience
thought and action psychology
it's a science of mental life who tries
to understand
hollow the mind works
what we mean barry mental life
no better description of what the mind
does
exists i think than the one who offered
by
german philosopher immanuel kant more
than
two hundred years ago
so there are three things that the mine
does
it knows things it feels things
and it does there is things
there are three absolutely irreducible
faculties of mine
knowledge
feeling and desire
great twentieth-century psychologist
ernest hogar jack hillberg
put another way you talk about when he
called the trilogy of mine
art of cognition
having to do with
knowing things and believing things
the motion
had to do with feelings affects
moods
and meditation
having to do with
needs and goals
roles and purposes
drives desires all of that kind of stuff
so what
psychology tries to understand is
how we engage in these kinds of mental
activities
highwaymen things
where feelings come from what's the
nature of notification
and on and so on
sol the scope of psychology is very
broad
and so is the scope of the scores
we will focus mostly on basic mental
processes
trying to figure out how the mind works
and in this course
because we don't have a lot
a limited amount of time
we're going to focus mostly on basic
cognitive processes
how we
gat knowledge and acquire knowledge andy
use knowledge
in addition the psychology of the
dissident things like
widow mine comes from
so we're going to be talking about the
bella dental psychology for a little
while
how mind all rose through biological
evolution howell mind changes
the development of the individual
for all one of the courts will be
talking about mind in general
how perception memory and thinking and
reasoning work
integral
but psychology is also interested in
individual differences in how each
individual
is unique with respect to or the
organization of his or her mental life
we're all a somewhat different police
somewhat different
in someone different desire somewhat
different reactions to what goes on
around is these individual differences
in mental life
are very important aspect of what
psychology is all about
towards the end of the semester
we'll talk about
pathology of mental life so-called
psychopathology
what the various disorders of mental of
mine look like schizophrenic ah...
don't depression and anxiety disorders
whatever of those various mental
illnesses are
and then finally
in addition to being a basic science
psychology is an applied science
we're not just interested in how the
mind works in the abstract
psychologists are interested in taking
what we know about how the mind works
and applying this knowledge
in various domains to education
to help the
process of teaching and learning
be as good as it can be
in psychotherapy
for the prevention and treatment
on various forms of mental illness
in the workplace
to help managers be more effective to
help workers before productive
psychology as the science of mental life
is both basic science
the tries to understand
how the mind works
and applied science that seeks to
make that knowledge useful
in kal in various in various ways
so they try to fight club what kind of
sciences psychology
psychology is first and foremost
what we call a behavioral science
there were a number of these behavioral
sciences like anthropology of economics
and political science and sociology
on each of which
has a
somewhat different approach
to understanding the behavior of the in
the park
the individual organism
whether that's a human organism or an
animal organism
acid as some of the individual interacts
with or other individuals
and with
the altman and with the surrounding
environment
all the behavioral sciences are
interested in that
they each of these behavioral sciences
takes a somewhat different approach
to understanding behavior
and in psychology what work particularly
interested in is
the mental process these that our dept
lead people to behave the way
they do
the basic
rationale for psychology is a science
is to be found in of philosophical
doctrines known as mental ism
or sometimes known as a mental causation
which stated formally
basically says that mental states are to
action as cause to affect
that is
member of the individuals mental states
cause him or her
do the things that he or she does
the cause ok d you behave the way you do
because you think
or feel or designer
the of the things uh... that though
that you do
so for example
consider all
fairly dramatic example behavior
a person commits suicide
questions why did somebody do that
why did he or she behave in that
particular way
psychological explanation
always explains behavior in terms all of
the individuals mental states
so for example
we could get over any kind of
explanation for this behavior
in terms of what the individual norms
new or what the individual believes so
perhaps this person committed suicide
because he believed
he was all of no value
or we could give unemotional explanation
or that individuals' behavior
in terms of his or her
emotions
affects moods or feelings so perhaps a
person committed suicide
because he or she
depressed
feelings not knowing not believing of
feeling explaining behavior
or might give in motivational
explanation
for that individuals' behavior
in terms of his or her
drives
needs
goals for so long so that
the person committed sold suicide
because they no longer had the desire to
live
psychological explanations of behavior
are always in terms of knowledge
feeling or desire
always in terms
the individuals cognitive
emotional
motivational
states
so when with try to think about
kind of science psychology is
you find out pretty quickly
that psychology is a social science
and the reason for that is
all behavioral sort of sciences try to
understand the behavior of the
individual
but the individual
lives in a social environment we are
social beings we live in a world of
other people or with whom we interact we
cooperate we compete with these
individuals
so psychology as a social science
tries to understand
the relation between the individual
and these social world in which
he or she lives so you'll find
psychologist
looking at
various aspects of social interaction
how we interact with each other for
cooperation and competition
how we understandable other people or
how
groups and organizations influence the
behavior of the individual
personality and individual differences
also usually thought of as part of
psychology as his social science
for psychology of the social science
and it's also
okay biological science
just as psychology of the social science
because the individual
because humans or social
creatures
psychology is a biological science
because we understand that the brain
that is the physical bases of mine
and so
who want to stand out of mind works
probably auto understand a little bit
about how the brain works so are in this
course will do a little bit of neuro
anatomy little neurophysiology we'll
talk a little bit about how the nervous
system relates to all other bodily
systems like the endocrine system and
the uh... and the immune system
or
molecular and cellular biology as you'll
see is also relevant of all it's a
psychology
too bad acts
armed evolutionary biology also relevant
to psychology
but finally
or ecology which looks at the relation
between organisms in the environment
is also something that psychologist have
interest in
especially
the relationship between the individual
and social
environment
so psychology of the social science
social biological science
in some sense it's also a physical
science
because the brain
is a physical chemical system it
operates on a core team to are basically
electrochemical
principles and one of the most important
new tools
for psychology
or a set of devices
devices that allow us to
wall
and various ways
damage the brain take pictures of the
brain
while people or engaged in
mental activities
so because though a brain is the
physical basis of mine
and the brains of electrochemical system
psychology also cones
to some extent has a
physical science
the fact that psychology can be thought
of as a biological maybe a physical
science in some respects
raises the question of reduction is a
or it's one of my favorite quotes by
from
ernest rutherford
of typical attitude on the part of
people like him
there's only one finance
that physics
all the rest is stamp collecting
oh
never mind that brought the prince of
won the nobel prize in chemistry
he seems to have had some
self-paced
of there
there is a tendency among some
scientists to think that
what if that if you really got a science
you want to be able to reduce the
principles of psychology two principles
of biology
and principles of biology intern two
principles of of physics
and one of the
underlying questions in psychology one
that you might grapple with in your
discussion sections
is wider or that can actually happen
loan or not
to what extent
can we reduce the principles of
psychology to the principles of
uh...
particles operating in fields all twelve
forests
my own view is that that's
not the right way to do psychology
rather i'd prefer that you think of
their bane
different levels at which we can explain
various aspects of behavior
there is the psychological level of
explanation in terms of the individual
underlying mental states cognitive
emotional and motivational states
however
you can also give a sociocultural
explanation of the havier
of the kind of favored by economists and
sociologists anthropologists
that explains behavior of the individual
in terms of socio cultural structures
and practices what's going on in the
society
that the persons a member of what's
going on in the culture that the person
to member of
or
you can give an explanation
on biophysical terms in terms of things
like neuro transmitters
jeans and hormones these are all related
to each other in some ways
but what i want you to think of the view
i want you to think about in this class
is that you should these levels is a
legitimate explanation of behavior in
its own right
physical explanation or a biological
explanation behavior
is no better
that a psychological explanation of
behavior
it's just a different kind of
explanation psychologists explain
behavior
in terms of
the individuals
states
all of that as i say you know others
sort of other sciences
might do it differently
so for example we could explain behavior
psychologically
in terms of the individuals not
feelings and desires
we could give of that explanation that
same behavior
in terms of something socio-cultural
that he was in a group and as leader
told them to do it
whether you're a japanese kinda qazi
pilot in world war two
or a member of the jonestown colt in
guyana
altered just though about just about
twenty years ago the explanation of both
suicides
is to be found in the cultural surround
of the individual
or you could give a biophysical
explanation
bike so i think he well maybe there's
some genetic predisposition to suicide
and that accounts for why somebody dot
these different levels of exploitation
all
of equal status
in psychology we favor the psychological
level of explanation
in terms of knowledge
desire
so think about psychology standing in
the center of things
okay
connecting down to the biophysical level
explanation because the brain as the
physical basis of mind
and connecting off
to the socio cultural level of
explanation
because the individual
is imbedded
in any wider
our context
in the end psychology connects up
with lots of different fields of inquiry
psychology on share is with palm
dot the philosophy empty of theology and
literature and art fundamental questions
about the nature of human existence
and hull the individual's experience
is shared with others
psychology share it with economics
and sociology
and history
and after apology
a concern with the relations of
individuals
society
it shares with biology and physiology
and physical anthropology
the relation between the individual
and other creatures
and it shares with
of physics and chemistry and cosmology
uninterested in
the place of the individual in the
universe as a whole
these are their fields of inquiry
physics chemistry biology sociology
anthropology
study the world outside the individual
whether it's the physical world
or the social world psychology studies
what working hard once called
universe within
the individual
the universe
that exists
within
the individual mind
will be good talking about all of these
things and more on wednesday
when we begin to look at the brain as
the physical bases on line
thank you very much