okay let's finish up our study of
personality and social development
today we're trying to make it worth your
while give you something to talk about
morrow
when you're with your
the question we ended up with last time
wise
why
is that their children from the same
family are so different from each other
these behavior genetic code uh...
studies for example
show that even identical twins who share
the same genetic heritage
had the same family environment
still turnout very very different from
each other but a lot more different than
you'd expect park to uh...
blood to be the case
part of the answer of course is
even though
children may all be the products of the
same parents everybody's got a slightly
different genetic heritage ok not not
the identical twins but everybody else
or the other kids in the family
have a slightly different genetic
heritage
but it turns out
that the family environment or at least
that part of the family environment that
is shared by all the children in the
family
is just not decisive for personality
and we know that
because when you look at various
dimensions of personality and attitudes
and other aspects of social behavior
variability within a family
is almost as great
as the variability
families and we want to know why that
should be
a the case
probably the best analysis all of
the hall
all above the forces of within the
family differences in personality
comes from a psychologist named judith
rich harrison's are written a couple of
very provocative of books on this
and that she has argued that
somewhat paradoxically
one of the many of the sources of
residents are pro-family differences
also lie within the family itself that
is there are things that go along with
in the family environment
the tend to make the children in their
family
different from each other
as opposed to the same
well read expect
our family environment to be the same
for all the comforter all the kids
that just turns out not to be hard not
to be the case
but harris is also made the point
that they're not sure if i remember also
extends importantly beyond the whole so
so that as soon as kids begin to
interact with other kids in their
neighborhood they go to school they go
to sunday school to go wherever it is
that they go outside the home
they begin to all interact with
different characters
and those peer groups
are also
going to
act to make kids are different from each
other
here are a couple of all of examples of
this what
harris herself calls for
group socialization
theory on phone of the vote of
personality development
and basically chuti argues
that there are two different aspects the
socialization
or rather there were two different
contexts in which socialization takes
place there's a socialization context
inside the house
where the parents are trying to get the
kids to grow up in a particular way
and that there is a socialization
context outside the home
we're teachers
or clergy
peer groups are and and so on are trying
to get the kids to grow up and i'm not
in another way
and she draws a very interesting analogy
all between what goes on as kids move
outside the house and back inside the
house
with the situation for a bilingual and
by cultural individuals
so for example
a kid who has raised to the united
states of the spanish-speaking
households or a chinese speaking
household it doesn't really matter
on it turns out that one of the things
that kids do it
are deductible speak spanish or chinese
inside the house
but what if it goes outside which is
going to speak
english or whatever language it it is
that that that they're here
of the peer group speaks
when the kid comes back inside the house
the trial is going to revert to the
language of the parents
this code switching
occurs not just linguistically
but also occurs culturally as well
so that wilder inside the house
children may conform through the demands
of their parents
once they get outside the house
they tended to conform to the demands
all of their peers
again there's a kind of code switching
here
and i think that there is no more
powerful example
all of all dot no better example of the
power of the child's peer groups
and pure cultures to influence a child's
behavior
than the case of food preferences
all of your two you were too young to
remember this now but when you become
parents
you'll discover that one of the things
that will drive you completely crazy
is to be is the problem of getting your
kids tui what you want them to eat
kids are notorious
for resisting other foods that their
kids that that their parents want to be
they're all sorts of interesting all of
the things that go on there
but the best way to get a kid to eat
something
is to show him or her
that his or her friends
the same thing
kids want to eat what their friends one
e
they don't want to be what their parents
want them about the
all it's a very good example
apollo
things that go on outside the home exert
a very powerful influence
on on milk uh... charles behavior
here is another example somewhat more
earth scientific example i suppose less
anecdotal
this is research by david well with the
university of arizona and his colleagues
go over the years have done a number of
behavior genetic analyses of adolescent
behavior
all like smoking or drinking or
delinquency or
on having sex or becoming pregnant those
kinds of
all those kinds of things
and out there what is a merge from rose
studies
is an extremely interesting pattern of
results
that i think our best illustrated by by
smoking
it turns out that parents who smoke
tend to have kids to smoke
that's just a correlation
that's all
that's out there
and when you do the behavior genetic
analysis
you alcee
that the correlation between perished
smoking and child smoking is mediated by
the jeans
rather then by the shared environment
analysis not on like the ones i showed
you
on uh... on monday
but it's also the case
that adolescents and smoke tend to have
peter's fall who smoke
and that of course
is unaffected of the not shared
environment
so the general idea is
that paul while there's a tendency for
parents the past smoking behavior on to
their kids
through some kind of genetic mediation
whatever that might be some kinda
thing about the physiology of nicotine
or or whatever
alm
i think that this that child's peer
group does not experiment was cigarettes
that child is
not likely
to experiment with cigarettes
but if the child karoo is likely to
experiment with cigarettes that active
is likely to experiment with cigarettes
depicted parents also smoke
their kids going to stay a smoker
so this is a really interesting
contribution
genetic contribution from the parents
apparently to weather the kids going to
smoke or not
but also a huge
contribution from the child's peer group
address and his colleagues
have done several of similar analyses of
alcohol although consumption
of delinquent behavior
of sexual behavior
and all teenage pregnancy and they found
the same pattern of results
all the way along
that there's a genetic contribution to
each of these behaviors
don't know exactly what it is
are but there does seem to be a genetic
contribution to each of these behaviors
there's shared environment
is a very weak determined of these
behavior
button i'm sure in barman
and especially the example albeit of of
the adolescence pure group
is a very very very powerful determinant
determine
of what's going to are happen next
there's another all example from
tenderloin
who looked at all for the academic
motivation and all
well fourth and fifth grade children
all
in the schools that she studied kids dot
tended to form cliques you probably
remember this from your own elementary
and junior high school
all-time on in both in the school she
started clicks usually came into forms
all the brady kids kind of coming
together
and all of us slackers kind of hung
that's not a surprise
but it turns out that is a surprise is
that they boundaries between the brains
on the slackers are tend to be a tend to
be pretty fluid
so that over a period of time
kids will tend to move
back-and-forth
between one cleek and another
and what she showed us the instability
include membership
our kids are always part of one click or
the other but they tend to move back and
forth between them
and it turns out that kids attitudes
toward achievement motivation changed
when they move from one week leaked to
the next
sofa brainy kid moved into begin to
develop all friendships with slackers
that kid would tend to become a slacker
and not be interested in academics
if a slacker kid happen to move of the
conference with a bunch of brainy kids
that he became more interested
uh... in uh...
lesbian academic achievement
and the point here is that
kids intelligence i_q_ scores remain
constant okay
and prevent parental influences probably
remain constant as well
what changed
was the kids pure group
and the kid dot developed at it
on of the concept of in accordance
with whatever the kids pilgrim wars
when i want to do now however is
returned to the family
does the environment
and address the question of while you
are children from the same family so
different from each other
bite bite looking by looking in more
detail at exactly what the family
environment looks like
i pointed out call a little earlier
that there are these are facts the
forces of within family environmental
differences
and i want to give you art and example
of the above each of them
there is some sources are depart bom bom
bom within family differences
that are
stimulated by the child him or herself
these are called trial driven effects
there are some builders better off than
evoked by the relationship between the
child in his or her parents
they're known as
relationship driven effects
there are some that come right from the
parents independent of what the dc kid
does
these are known as parent driven effects
and then there are very interesting
affects
albany
microenvironment of the family itself
what are known as family context effects
let's look first
adtchile driven effects
these are very much like are the kinds
of facts that i talked about are in the
lectures on personality and social
interaction
when i talked about
avocation
as a mechanism for persons in situations
onto to uh...
in iraq
and the general idea here is where
something above the child
changes the environment for that child
versus other children in the family
and the example of already getting it
was a very good example of this gender
roles socialization
the family environment for the girls are
a family
is different from the family environment
for the boys myfamily there's nothing
about what the kids are doing here
it's just being a little girl
gets you raised in a different family
environment
then being a little or boy does we saw
this very clearly
in the baby x_ studies
where children who are identified as
girls or boys
were treated differently
of the independently of their actual on
gender
of literature has some other examples of
this
it turns out that
cute babies tend to be treated
differently than only babies by their
parents even by their parents may well
be about
it's just different
arm
uh... and again that's not good nothing
to do with a kid except the kids
physical appearance of the fifth day
arent so it's a thought and for the fact
that driven by the child in some sense
or because the trial
like you personally children just evoked
different behaviors
or for a lot from people
and that's also true
for healthy children versus children who
were killed
law ability who is we've got some kind
of like
chronic illness
is going to be treated very differently
on not just with respect to medication
and doctors visits
but the is going to be treated very
differently on all sorts of dimensions
compared to healthy fit
so here are some examples within the
family environment
different depend on whether a girl or a
boy
whether you're cute
or not cute
whether your healthy
or not healthy all good examples of
so-called trial driven
effects
are also some other caught by the trial
driven effects
that don't have anything to do with the
appearance of the trial
but have to do with the child's actual
behavior these are all of them sometimes
known as reactive affects
we hurt the trouble actually engage in
some behavior
that make the family environment for
that child
then family environment for of vodafone
for some other child
and most of these react to affect
have to do with temperament it's just a
fact of being a little kid that altus a
little kids pretty much straight out of
the wall
five different terms of temperament
some kids are very fussy other kids are
very quiet
all some kids are very quick to get
aroused other kids are very slow to get
aroused that's what we mean by
temperament
all and it turns out
that these individual differences in
temperament
illicit different kinds of behaviors
from
although from their parents
and depending on how their parents
react
to these behaviors on the part of their
children all of them that the
environment will be different
for one kid as opposed to another
for example many parents engage in a
kind of cool
visited feedback with all of their own
with their children depended on
temperament
uh... in such a way
that auto within such a way of member
the what positive feedback is
is off the back and positive echoes the
deck that strengthens the response to
produce that
sold although it might happen
that a parent's who
produce a child is very quiet
but i believe the trouble
required trial
just left below stays quite
all by the same token a very fussy child
especially in the novice parents mayo
mustard all sorts of behavior that the
parents may think may combine ovens and
are intended to calm the trial down
but really have the effect of simply
making the child foster your
orlando and forcier
on remember some years ago i live next
door to paramount's current setup
very very
part of the collegue trial
and you could just hear the parents
screaming at the tip constantly kid's
fault
these weren't bad parents either they
just didn't know how to cope and so the
kid would start screaming they started
screaming extended screener day would
scream louder and i would just go on
like this for hours and hours and hours
i got a lot of work done in my office
here
similarly all some parents all believe
gage in negative feedback kinds of
behaviors
are better intended to somehow
dampen
or reduce
all of the behavior that god that that
uh... little of produced it
on some of these go by the name of lower
limit control behaviors because what the
parents do with the stated to approach
it is very quiet ok will look to be
quiet
but we're not going to be talk about it
so when the kids
kind of been
by itself for a while
no availability try to engage the kids
try to get the kids area roused
that's a different
very different kind of behavior that
what you see the positive feedback case
where required trial will just be left
alone to be quiet
similarly
some parents will engage in what are
known as upper limit control behaviors
this is usually with fosse kids
was that all will lead to foshan cry a
little bit but we're not going to do it
too much
ok will let you go
at after a while will try to get you
calm down
these are different ways of treating the
same kids
aquatic kid cadet positive feedback
remain pretty quiet
well positive kid to get treated with
lower limit control behaviors and become
a little bit more active
a frosty child
ten be given positive feedback that just
makes the teamwork posse
or the forty child can be treated with
look upper limit control behaviors
that'll tender quite required at the
trial down
either way what's happening
is that the child is engaging in insight
and behaviors that elicit a response
from the up from the environment
and you can imagine parents who were
born
we're going to get a quiet it is their
first child whitey gage in positive
feedback
they require child for their first born
but the second it if that is also quite
a sight
you know i for instance a little bit too
quiet too shy to advertise let's jack
this one up a little bit okay
so you get two-thirds reply temperament
buck one of which is a lot more active
of the book is born with quite a permit
but one of his own party turns out to be
of an adult with a was a lot more active
on than the others ok so here at twelve
it affects
with the process starts with the kids
either the kids appearance or physical
condition or some behavior
then the environment
response to that by treaty the children
differently creating a source of within
family difference
turning quickly to relationship driven
affects here we have sundial process
that's analogous to the former should
bode arvo bulb person by situation
interaction
as i discussed immediate lectures unnav
of the personality and social
and here
there's a large literature on what's
known as the temperamental fit
between child and parent
art you've got it introverted trial
introverted parents
introverted parents know what to do with
introverted jordan
they don't necessarily know what to do
with with extroverted part of the
children
so in extroverted trial is going to be
treated differently
depending on whether that child was
raised by of extroverted adult or an
introverted adult
and the same thing is going to happen
with an introverted child who is raised
by introverted adult versus a vet of
extroverted adult
forget the belt business whoever he or
she is
that child is whoever he or she is it's
the interaction of its tough tucked
between parent and child that makes
things are that makes things very
different
on you can imagine for example
and extroverted child
or into and extroverted into all of the
parents
little bit happy review eat better fit
into that environment
the next kid who comes along little
brother or sister is a little
introverted
is going to turn out
very differently because the
relationship with the parents
is are different
for each of these uh...
each of these two children
movin again
ga fairly quickly to the third category
the third source of all of the within
family differences
later known as parent ribbon effects
all of these are again often have to do
it or often independent of the child's
behavior
and i look at them sometimes to cargo
transformations
because they generally have to do with
how the parents
perceive
the trial
how the parents
tall
categorize the child thought if you will
for example there is a literature
that shows that
of the children who are unplanned before
that is products of an unplanned
pregnancy
tend to be treated differently
then children of of a plan pregnancy
calm that's got nothing to do the kid
okay
but it does have everything to do with
the way the parents view the trials and
the effects of the uh...
of the child on the uh...
on the environment
part of the family
all again there's a big literature on
identical twins
when bio parents
palm all uh... produce a part of the set
of identical twins
the major decision they have to confront
all follow they're going to treat
these kids
are they going to treat them
very similarly
or are they going to go don't take extra
efforts to treat them very differently
and again this is just a decision that
the parents make
about uh... about how they think this
post to treat the kids
some twins are
all given are similar names
they are addressed alike
the parents make sure that they go to
the same schools and have the same
teachers and purchase a paid and some of
the same activities
all their parents will treat they're
twins exactly
the opposite
they'll go to great lengths to make sure
in their own writings
that each gut the child will go on grow
up with a different identity
on the give them different names dress
them differently make sure they get
different teachers and hang out with
different friends and all of that
this is something that's not something
that the twins themselves choose
but it's something
that is imposed on the twins
and again art twins
whose parents make a decision to treat
them quite differently
by definition
have eight much
love much more variety and they're not
sure environment
then twins whose parents make a decision
to treat them of pretty much the same
another variant though that you don't
just have to be twins to get this
you can in the child although childhood
development literature
there are lots of examples
all of our so-called contrast effects
usually a contrast affecting the first
child
versus of versus later children born in
the family
all of its kind of almost by definition
that parents
don't know what they're doing
with their first child you can read any
books you want all but that first child
is our real surprise and lots of uh...
lots of ways
are there lots of uh... mistakes you can
make their lots of things you just don't
pay attention to
so if the first child is easy
offer example
paul the second child often
is perceived as more difficult to raise
similarly at the first trial is
difficult for them to raise later
children what may be seen as more as as
easier to raise
and that's going to the vet difference
in relationship between parent and child
is going to affect
how the child comes up bomb
avail
that friends well who's who had two
children both are both boys
or cool world of though the first one
has had tremendously large number of
behavioral problems uh... kids okay you
know graduating from college and stuff
like that but four able to touch and go
there
for the first off for the first five
eight
uh... years but at this kid was around
but there aren't they think they were
really didn't have any idea that the kid
was having any probs
on and so that they didn't realize how
things work for at their first game
until they have a second hit
was an entirely different you know it
can be like this
uh... and it was at that point that they
began to consult with foam
with those psychologists and others and
kind of get the first kid onto on the
track
but again
kids
or under the same parents
valvoline but the second child is born
to parents who were much more
experienced than they were the first
time
and for that matter the first kid is
profiting from the aloft
from the experience is that the parents
said
the second trial
so dead
then start these sources of differences
even within the same family even within
the same household
some of these come from the kids
themselves boys girls healthy six
whatever
some have to do
with the
between the personality of a child in
the personality of the parent some of
them have to do just what the parents
own
ideas about parenting and they're all
and their and their level of expertise
and then finally they're all of this is
very interesting set of family context
effects
we're all
there there seemed to be systematic
differences between author
between siblings within the call
within a family
calm
now we've got to think about those off
for a second
because it's very clear that months when
civilians ok there are no systematic
genetic differences
along dont win siblings in a family
all none twins have fifty percent of
their genes uncommon so random on
average and it's a random
fifty percent of the jeans
however there is an emerging literature
stillcontroversial but very interesting
and all of literature
that suggests
that there are systematic differences
already in in birth or or position
within a family
are sold out
or older children
tend to offered by a different position
within the family
than younger ones are due
and this fifties differs differences and
family position
orbs their differences and birth order
have systematic differences other have
systematic co-author of impacts
on personality attitudes and uh... and
so on
all of the traditional view reason why
this is controversial all guarded is
the traditional views that there aren't
any birth order affects if you think
about it for a second there are all
sorts of confluence of
uh... that attended the study of birth
order affects home are for example first
boren's almost by definition of older
than
latter boards africa's it's has to be
that way so differences between first
words a lot of words might be an
artifact of bomb talked a lot of age
oda people lore in social economic
status tend to have bigger families that
people who are higher and socioeconomic
status
so the difference between a first born
in a family in a fifth or in the family
they have more to do with the
socio-economic status of affair with
scott five kids that it has with the
went within the first american firms is
between of
between uh...
about sibling position
and the end up in the past the general
view
has been that these methodological
contrasts account for whatever calm
though the periphery perfect have been
found
and there really aren't any systematic
differences
well i tended to birth order
that situation is beginning to change no
and one of the people all who's
responsible for this change is though
is a ghost a scholar who is that there
are two historian
who's turned into a psychologist
frank's all the way who is here at use
the berkeley
who ought some years ago produced a very
interesting analysis
of birth order affects
on personality
using the big five home
structure that we've talked about before
to measure individual differences in
personality
solloway is a big fan of charles darwin
alive and in the in much the same way
that darwin argued that different
species compete
four unleashed within their environments
solloway argues that siblings also
compete for
well i mean shore up the their proper
place
within their family
although and looking back at the history
the family especially
uh... in the seventeenth eighteenth
nineteenth early twentieth centuries is
that what they are there is really a
very big differences between first
boards a milder brands especially
with respect to boys
and that is
that and in uh... the traditional
european society
first boren's got a lot more choice
of their of of their neesh
them and the letter boards do
on it you know i've been in europe until
very recently
there was a legal principle bonus
progenitor
which meant that all the family
resources got went to the firstborn
first-born son
and second with second what water-borne
funds
had to
had to fend for themselves on me to go
to the military maybe go into the church
or or or sort something like that
you could still see the are
do you know
hong
shadow of progenitor
in things like british royal family
okay who gets to be the next gohil
moderate in england
it's charles
why does charles get to be the next king
of england pressies offer son
okay no other reason he could be smart
you could be stupid he could be good he
could be bad he's still going to be king
of england
argues that it became immigrant just
because
he was elizabeth of force on
and stole all solidly argues that first
boren's
by virtue of didn't get getting this
financial and the start of the social
inheritance
released all of the spent a lot of time
pleasing trying to please their parents
by fulfilling their parents'
expectations engage in all sorts of
traditional behavior
and that although solloway argued
is going to make first-born children
tend to be more conscientious
and more conservative then water-borne
by the same token solloway argued
letter boards
are not going to get
the crown
they're not going to get the family
homestead
all and all that
so one matter boards are going to
threaten the authority of the firstborn
all and in in fact
fifth there's no there's nothing to
speak
letter boards are going to be more
likely to rebel
than husband first boards or uh...
because some of the first forms are not
going to inherit
dubbed the though from the parents'
expectations
letter words are going to seek all
different ways of getting are getting
distinction
and he argued the letter boring so
they're going to become more and patsick
more egalitarian
more energy authoritarian and they're
going to strive to be different they're
just trying to be unique
knots dr to be conventional
well that's the general theory question
is does it work out that way and
practice
and it turns out that they have
although
when you are a look at all birth order
differences in personality in terms of
the first bought the in terms of the big
fight
it turns out that first boren's tend to
be a little bit higher on your bought a
schism
that motherboards through those of you
were letter boards can hold us over your
big brothers and sisters heads tomorrow
at the dinner table
all but it turns out the first boren's
tend to be more jealous
more anxious
more fearful
are more likely to affiliate with others
under stress
that doug wilder pornstar
similarly
with extra version
all i'll go first of the first the first
boards tend to be more extroverted
then of the latter barons
extra version has to do with
assertiveness
orlando again we'd expect
offers pour in to be more assertive
we're likely to hold them take a young
take a leadership role
and so they do on average
firstborn score higher
on measures of extra version
than of the matter bornstein
all similarly in agreeable to us
firstborn again a love letter boards to
underscore called all the higher
turned out that done first boren's
first boards one up
t_-thirty should the family against all
costs
letter boards tend to be a little bit
more easy going about these kinds of
things okay you can have
this thing in our own co-authored in
something else
of i think about charles is soft
uh...
younger siblings you know they're not
spending a lot of time trying to be king
or they're off the photographers and
flying helicopters and stuff like that
letter boards are more used to going
cooperative and popular
again you know differences you know
but they are systematic differences
there statistically significant when you
do the studies alright
conscientious
the bench refers read the rebirth for
the first born
first boards tend to be a little bit
more conscientious
than uh... all of them that the latter
boren's
they tend to be more responsible more
itchy but organized korea entered
more organized and plan for
there is an advantage provider boards
when it comes to openness to experience
again it's always does
letter boards to be born to rebel their
less traditional their viewpoints
and it turns out
the firstborn czar more conforming
more traditional
and more closely identified with their
parents
than are a lot of arms
also again
we see these systematic differences in
personality
that have to do with all of them
what what position you walk it by uh...
the family
foley extracted these kinds of results
all by reading the literature and it's
very complicated literature it's very
very very controversial
also
just kind of forget go this forget this
ald
would really like to see although
somewhat more systematic confirmation of
it
on bill plus who is a psychologist at
the university of british columbia was
here at berkeley on sabbatical some
years ago and in the context of the
all research purchase a patient program
argued in interesting study of
firstborn versus letter born
of personality he simply asked people
ought to
on consider
themselves and their families and to
identify vault butch
kid in the family was most likely to be
the achiever in the family
and which kid in the family
was most likely to be the rebel the
family members of the two was central
predictions of solely
the first boards will be more
achievement oriented
and latter brings will be
more of more rebellious
and what paul is dead
was to break up his cell of subjects
into kids from auto child families kids
from three child families
kids from four child families justify
chance
just by chance
artwork kids all from future openly
you'd expect
are the first born to be nominated as
the cheever half of the time
have the latter born to be nominated as
the rebel half the time has just by
chance
but it turned out
of followed this video subjects
dominated the firstborn is the achiever
about two thirds of the time much more
often than you can expect by chance
and nominated the latter born
uh... as the rebel almost two-thirds of
the time to get much more than you'd
expect by chance
same logic four altus of ships
three kids in a family
you'd expect
one-third
all of those children to be nominated is
chambers just by chance
two-thirds of the latter boren's to be
nominated as rebels just by chance what
wiped off paul was discovered was that
in fact the figures favor
are there more
first warns nominated to cheaper said
you'd expect by chance not a big
difference but it's there
and more letter boren's nominated rebels
and the same thing grows on for a
situation of four
more firstborn senator specter chance
identified as the cheapest
more letter boren's than you'd expect by
chance identified as as rebels
are just the when paulus
went back to the university of british
columbia
he did the study again
so these are canadian
are college students
and again you feel all the way along the
line
more first boren's that you'd expect by
chance
are nominated as achievers as the
achiever in the family
more letter boards
that you'd expect by chance are
nominated has the rebels and the family
so there does seem to be something to do
this
all of that for these systematic
differences in personality all of that
seem to have to do with the position all
of the child in the phallic there on the
same family brought out the same parents
the role of it in the same house but the
first boards in the letter boards
tend to be different on average
this is an every for sport is the
achiever right
and every letter board as the what is
the rebel
it's just an average that question here
stopped
only children aren't in this particular
study
but i'm going to show you that's
thinking i'm going to show you something
about all the children that i think is
absolutely fascinating
absolute essen
without your question
often accurate with respect to this
although i suppose you'd expect anything
that you would ordinarily expect
only children to be to be like for
sports
because well there are the firstborn
it turns out though all the children are
not necessarily the same as being the
firstborn artisanal respects and i'll
show you that day and second dataquest
i know exactly how it was conducted
now what
but they did with of what they did was
they would ask you
with his toothless just imagine your
copy go to
too
two siblings okay
they say consider u
consider here two siblings
which one is the achiever in the family
animates they consider yourself
consider your tues siblings
which ones the rubble of the family
and it turns out that you would nominate
on average
the oldest sibling as the achiever
one of the younger siblings as rebel
that's on the study was done
there lots of different ways to do this
but that's how they did so this is
really kind of
reputation within the family
did this happens unfairly sometimes all
you know
she's lost smart one
right kids know kind of who's who in a
family and that's what he was
uh... capturing
awk
in this i'm sure there were such kids in
this study
but they didn't break it down by spacing
im go get 'em that they have a chance of
the list but no show your study where
space is actually might make a very
interesting difference
but again you've got a look at that
although
in the literature
the general tendency is to think that if
there's more than six or seven years
between siblings
ican kind of the clock starts all over
again
that your functionally and all the child
fro that functionally penalty trial ma
got two older
siblings my sister's ten years older
than i am my brother seven years older
than than i am
are by the time i was growing up i was
five years old man
brother was twelve-mile
sister was
almost graduated from high school
they were part of my life so much
rebooter disturbance
no i don't have a nice people we had a
really nice family was right in that
respect that
it's not as if they were around the
house a lot
you know they were off doing their thing
arm also
did the use of these are family
constellation affects
really are only supposed to be
or holding
when there's less of a space
between kids
okay let me show you one more
these this is a absolutely fascinating
follicles study
all corporate order and measured
intelligence so-called i_q_
this is work by robert science you've
heard seen this name before
all up and he's the guy who did mere
exposure affects studies he's now at
stanford
and a graduate student of his army
marcus
songs all of the publish some time ago
this is a man analysis all involved
all of them
who'd of data that was collected
in the context all been invented world
war two known as the dutch famine in
nineteen forty four
arb dutch word occupied by the germans
there was a
massive crop failure that was already
going on
are and that there was a tremendous
amount of hunger and starvation in the
netherlands of doreen o during that year
it turns out that in the netherlands
every
mail
when he turns nineteen has to go there
does not drafted if universal
are drafted in in uh... in the
netherlands
also all of the conceived of these are
kids so there's a study
of kids or aged eighteen
all who were born around the time of
this famine and and the the years old
right afterwards
and in the proc and then in the course
of their our military aptitude testing
they were given a non-verbal test of
intelligence is known as reagan's
progressive matrices which is very
interesting intelligence test
and what's the investigators did all
was to allot
score no average scores on this
intelligence test as a function of
family size and birth order
and when you do that you get photograph
that looks like this
here it is
transformed i_q_ score
now i want you to understand one thing
the difference between the lowest point
in this bill
and the highest point in the scale is
three points
on one hundred-point skill
these are not huge differences
but they are theoretically very
interesting differences because of the
pattern that you see here
first is you see
well but have a rich like his court
tends to
did decrease as a function of family
size
here are
to child families
the first part of the second borne
pretrial families
first second and third
for child families first second third
fourth
by child families
six trial families seven
and dying child families as the size of
the family increases
the average
i_q_ score
pens to go down so that's the first
effect
the second effect is that within the
each family size
as birth order increases again
the i_q_ score tends to go down a little
bit so here for families the birth of
shirt size of two the second born score
slightly less than the firstborn
fidget fought size of free
firstborn second board
third board for four firstborn second
board their board fourth born can see
this
pretty much all the way down there are
some glitches here double talk about
uh... later
so we also have
on stall
don't small but significant and
theoretically interesting
declined and average i_q_ score
according to before
asked about uh...
than about all the children
there are the scores
for all the children
this is very interesting
because only children tender score a
little bit more significantly lower on
average
then
the first boren's
over to a child
or of free child family even before
trial family
are dependent on uh...
what you make it
sold their art these
systematic affects
an i_q_
based on
scripture size family size
and also based on performer within the
within the population
here are the basic affects and advance
and marcus
attributed this pattern of results which
is now i've been replicated in about a
half a dozen large-scale studies all
vault evolve of i_q_ scores all
wanted to a number of all of the debt
different processes that they'd grouped
together in terms of what's called the
confluence model of development
are and what they're talking about here
mutual influence poem and
children
on children's i_q_ scores
okay mutual influence
there's eight dilution effect and what
science argues
every neuborne
comes into a family
of functionally diminishes the
intellectual resources in that family
that the reason for that is that
newborns a very nice but there
you can't talk about
particle physics
arm so there's a sense in which they did
each newborn diminishes the intellectual
resources for the families as a whole
fuck does also growth effect
which is that ask each child grows up
that child becomes in some sense smarter
and begins to contribute more to the
intellectual resources of the family so
the newborn
diminishes intellectual resources but as
per child grows up contributes more and
more
each matter boring
increases the dilution of the families
intellectual resources
but each early board
counteract that dilution
when the third boren comes into the
family the first in the second boring
have already started growing up and they
start songs or the compensating for this
on a dilution
and it turns out
when the details of the mathematics
the spacing matters allot so what's
actually going on here
the first is
that there is a teaching abstract on
high q_
and that is
that early boren's
profit
from being able to in a position to
teach something four-letter words
one of the reasons
that older siblings the main reason that
older siblings
score higher
then their younger siblings
is that alder siblings have had the
opportunity to teach their younger
siblings teaching makes you smarter
so that's the first thing
so this is teaching affect
there is a last child a handicap
notice
that the drop-off from the next to the
last child to vote last child
is very striking
it is typically much bigger than any of
the other intermedia dropbox okay
what is the last child handicap
the last child handicap is fell last
child born in the family don't have
anybody to teach
doesn't get the advantage of teaching
affect
similarly
there is and all the child handicap
there are the average scores of the only
children
and again the only child handicapped
comes from the fact that a only children
don't have all older children to teach
them
but they also don't have younger
children
ought to teach
are visible vs also have the same kind
of a fact
twins or triplets born into a family
all they don't get to teach each other
much there's no older versus younger
arms of the affect their
all but there are also other really
interesting aspects of this
for example all the model predicts
that single-parent households will be
the children of evade single-family
others single-parent households if it's
a real single-parent household
will be at a disadvantage
because
in a traditional nuclear family
two-and-a-half
okay
so each newborn will have
correspondingly less
affect on the intellectual resources
volvo of the family
this is compensated for somewhat
by at least in theory by the fact that
in lots of nominally single-parent
households there are actually lots of
adults around
there may be are across from her
boyfriend who's the who's involved in
child care
there are parents and grandparents are
involved in childcare the prediction of
this model
is that domain dulce there are around at
the child the better it is for the child
so of extended families with lots of
aunts and uncles and grandparents around
are going to be better for the child's
intellectual development
then vendor if they're not
but the point of all of this is
that this is a confluence model
where everybody in the family is
contributing true
this dream but they did the body of
intellectual resources in the family
and everybody in the family is drawing
from that same body of intellectual
resources
as you moved into the family
growing up in the family move out of the
family your having an effect on the
environment within the family in such a
way
that the environment is different for
each
of the kids
quick question
it's nineteen
that's exactly right
phone
so uh...
yes uh... the dave dave dealt with that
problem and on the other studies have
also dealt with a prom so there isn't
any age con filed uh... here
also again the idea here is
that every child is part by professor
her open environment
okay because that point
the rb four
this environment is constantly flatly in
the influx
as people move into the environment as
people grow up in it as people move out
the environment is constantly auto
changing
each individual is influenced by this
constantly changing environment
and each individual is contributing
through the change that occurs autism
home
in that environment
in this way
development isn't something that
happens to the individual
the important thing about that they did
important message about the republic's
model
is a development
doesn't just happened to the child
neighboring child isn't agent of his or
her own development
contributing
to what goes on and how he or she
is going to come out
so i would just as each person
is part of his or her own environment
each child
home
it is an influence on his or her own
that's it
have a good holiday come back monday
we'll talk about psychopathology in
psychotherapy
thank you very much