okay let me remind you about uh... oh
the a final exam scheduled for next week
thursday
the thirteenth
in the morning from eight to eleven
we've now got the room for that exam
it's going to be a two-thirds
through thirty-first gymnasium
for those who don't know it's over
on bancroft way on the side of bancroft
way
auto i'm preparing right now a narrative
review all for your call for your use of
the post into the course website
by friday
by the end of business on friday
usually we do some kind of group review
during the uh... there during the day
days
all pissed
semester been experimenting with these
written narrative reviews
and they seem to have worked out
remarkably well test scores in this
class are higher than annular class i've
ever taught
all
so we're going to just continue to do
that
this way you can stand bad
during the day and their days and uh...
oh
you're studying
austin's with disability accommodations
are going to get a memo for me
probably today about the final details
but there are no surprises there the
same as usual
while reminder the uh... final exam has
two components to what the result
non-committal portion that covers the
materials since the last midterm
our material development and the
material on psychopathology
they will also cover the rudiments of
that dot appendix on statistics
arnett invoke remainder of the exam
sixty four items will be ok would have
exam
the covers the whole thing
from beginning motu to end
all hundred questions
here remember get the reds controller
for books like this
and there are lots of resources
available for the exam but there are a
few the bell curve review that i just
discussed of the up by friday
while the study guide as usual is a very
good resource for test preparation
lots of materials on the course website
electroless trations while the lecture
supplements
how old all my past exams at least since
i've been at berkeley
our role with are up there
and in addition as usual
if you have any other standing
questions
you can post them food be forum
on the chorus website
fatherhood instructions for doing that
although
and if you get those questions up
by noon on wednesday noon on wednesday
all guaranteed to have them answered by
the close of business
on wednesday
sooner
but if iraq by wednesday
hauled out of the uh... just fine
anne young questions about the
format of the exam
same as always accept
it's twice as long
you got three hours to do it that's
plenty of time
edits in the first gymnasium
uh...
okay
all of them are saying that our
discussion sections three g a size will
be putting in your discussion section
grades all of this week and over the
weekend
also if there are any corrections that
have to be made you need to get in touch
with your g aside very very fast okay
because we've only got
ninety six hours after the exam to get
final grades all in order
although the deadline for completing
your rocky p purchase a patient is
monday again at the close of business
all make sure when you've accumulated
your five credits that you assign those
credits to psych one otherwise they
don't come to me
i don't have them yet all i don't get
them until sometime in after monday at
five o'clock
blog but what i do get them all input
them to the uh... great book on the
website and that'll send out an
announcement
that the young
that the orchid he credits have been
entered
the only issue there is that
i can't correct your p_p_ kravitz
all the only people who can do that or
the are p_p_ committee i only know what
they told me
so if there are any issues about our p p
credits
you need to be dealing with the or p_p_
committee yes question
that the just relieve your geo site
goes though he or she is keeping a
record of that
that's for a cabal of people who are
under eighteen when the class started
and you're doing the alternative
onto the r p p
i'll just turn your information into
your geo side
and he or she will get the information
to me
anything else
okay last time we were talking about
interventions in sac apa fucking how we
treat mental illness once it's been
diagnosed
and up at the close of business last
time i was talking mostly about
various biological treatments
for mental illness
especially the pharmaceutical revolution
in of ordered treatment
that has occurred since the since the
nineteen fifties
with a proliferation
of a wide variety of drugs that seem to
be quite effective
in at least reducing the symptoms
associated with such major forms of
mental illness
as through the frontier
affect of disorder
and anxiety disorder
what i want to turn through today is the
author major
treatment
form of treatment for mental illness
which is psychotherapy
which doesn't involve direct biological
treatments like driver's door ec t_e_ or
or cycles surgery or anything like that
do you think about it for a second
all forms of psychotherapy are
essentially educational in nature
you've got mental illness people who
have strange thoughts are strange
feelings run wanted desires or whatever
and was like a therapy dog is
essentially
is to provided
and experience through which those
mental status could change
through which a person can acquire
new believes no more a bit more our dept
of believes
or feelings for all of our desires
either through some sort of a learning
process
or barrio fourteen the person an
opportunity
to reflect apart those prophecies
and part two
especially important ways of doing this
or others cognizant focal cognitive
therapy
which tries to deputation to change his
or her
knowledge in police
about him or herself in the world
cognitive therapy will also operate on
feelings and desires but it's really
directed against knowledge and believes
or behavior art therapy
which tries to change arbitrary try to
change behavior correctly
almost talk about
these mostly
also
the first point dramatic
is that both pharmacotherapy
and the psychotherapy
are intended to change the mental
prophecies in the mental states
of mental patients
pharmacotherapy tries to do that
indirectly
the whole purpose of taking psychoactive
medications whether it's
oddity psychotic medication prescriptive
friend here
or a uh... assess all arrived for
depression or sutton bed that i had to
team for our own before anxiety disorder
is somehow to change the person's mental
state
to get rid of hallucinations to lift the
patient's moving too
complications anxiety or whatever
but it doesn't type changing the
chemical state all of the brain
in psychotherapy all
all the various forms of psychotherapy
tried to change the person's state of
mind directly okay
by through various kinds of experiences
there's no chemical mediation that is
there no pills involved
noteworthy end of the lecture today
all talk about
are the prospects
for forms of treatment that combine both
pharmacotherapy and all and
psychotherapy
there are three major forms of
psychotherapy that are use these kind of
these days
sold more than others
classically separate therapy was known
as secretary manic
and insight warranted it was based
largely on these theories of sigmund
freud and his followers who argued that
various forms of mental illness
reflected or unconscious
conflicts conflicts between various
kinds of forces plano
in the palm of
the plano unconsciously in the person's
mind
and basically the idea was the idea
behind psychoanalysis and other forms of
psychodynamic therapy
is to help the patient as to achieve
some
inside
into the nature of these conflicts
so that he or she can more effectively
evolved over the resolvable
all recently
we've had that we that we've seen the
evolution of a number of so-called
cognitive-behavioral although that's
like a therapies
that are intended to change
now look at them for off
and now we're grappling behaviors but
they do so through educational
experiences essentially
that do not focused too much on things
like
unconscious conflict
the childhood are rich in sms of mental
illness and so on
while one big difference
is a photodynamic therapies
tend to focus on that there are and then
of the patient
what happened in his or her childhood or
or or whatever
with that
the cognitive and behavioral therapies
tend to focus on they hear and now
when you're feeling now how can we
change that
what kinds of behaviors are you engaged
in now how could we change that
without necessarily engaging
in some kind of inquiry into the deep
history
although or these problems
and then finally there
there are better than it is a dollop of
the class of so-called humanistic
all-star apis
which i don't know i don't know whether
there really isn't best classified as
they refuse that all
because the people who go to
psychotherapists for humanistic therapy
art mentally ill they don't have
schizophrenia they don't have an
affective disorder they don't have a
full reward obsessive-compulsive
disorder
but what they want to do is the somehow
improve
thereabouts
to lead to better lives but they're not
mentally ill in the usual kind of sense
these humanistic therapy is of the sort
practiced by
abraham buffalo and carl rogers and
others
tend to be very bad directive
whereas most active psychotherapy is
intended to
argentina symptoms if not sure
although it does have some kind of
underlying disease
or basically all of these humanistic
therapies
don't have any particular goal in mind
all except perhaps
all go over to nicole of helping the
person
offline meany nor actual lies to himself
or whatever
but the really interesting difference
between traditional psychotherapy
whether it's abbe sako
dynamic
sort
cognitive-behavioral sort is the change
in the loop in the relationship
between the suckers
and that the patient
all
instead of out of their api or a
cognitive all of their api
the person with mental illness
really is in the word patient in the
same way you would be if you want your
doctor with the flu war you went to your
doctor with a fever something
if they dr
find out what's wrong with me and tell
me what to do to get rid of it and your
doctor says you've got the flu here's a
pill or you've got an infection here's
an antibiotic or whatever
but in the humanistic auto
all of the other therapies
the uh... though there's really more of
our client
all service provider
relationship
we're the or the person will come to a
humanistic therapists and say i want to
find more meaning in my life i want to
actual ice myself i want to find a peak
experience and it's really a good job of
the psychotherapist
toolbar fortifications
okay
to help the patient get what it is that
he or she wants
or put another way in traditional
psychotherapy as in traditional medical
practice the role of the patient is to
do with the doctor travels
him or her to do
in the humanistic therapies
the role of the provider used to do with
the client wants also that both the
purposes acted more like a loner
or an accountant or
all advertising expected over somebody
on who basically works
uh... at the behest of the uh...
of the client
focused mostly on cognitive behavioral
all forms of psychotherapy
you know of
uh... in in this lecture
because for reasons that you'll see in a
minute
they're the ones that
really work
all right here is one area where
cognitive behavioral therapy
homeworks especially well
this is out document of behavior
terribly for anxiety disorders like
phobias or obsessive-compulsive disorder
although the very traditional behavioral
therapy for for business
is what's known as systematic
desensitization
a patient comes in
with an unwarranted excessive fear of
some object
maybe it's all of the presence of other
people were of snakes or whatever it is
that the person
has
on extreme fear old and wants to at once
to fix
and what the behavior therapist will do
will arrange
for the patient to have
progressively
more
intense exposures
with the feared objects soul patients
got up to make phobia
of first session all the way it might
just be asked to talk about snakes and
be told that there's a snake in the next
roman
the next session
of what that goes ok than the sneakers
broad and and put it up for a reimburse
something in the presence of the patient
and then
moved closer and eventually
now this makers on the lap of the
patient and uh... of all this kind of
stuff that everybody's fine
what's happening in systematic
desensitization
is the patient is learning not to be
afraid of snakes
because there's nothing to be afraid of
from little snake through though
alone
fault but that's the loneliness periods
okay
that gets rid of the anxiety
while there's another version of this
cold implosion therapy or flooding there
is a technical difference between the
two but it doesn't really matter for us
there instead of
all arranging graded exposures
the patient is all put
are in direct contact with the fear dot
object of right away
this kind of captain there until the
fears subsides
again a very good example of this might
be off veera fights we are in systematic
desensitization
you have a person
walk up the outside stairway from
ground floor of the first floor then for
the first for the second floor of
brisburg the second for the third floor
implosion thirty eight am and they are
and they say they're until thereof fear
of heights or whatever it is subsides
now this is not something for amateurs
to do
okay
so if you got up to eighty brothers
something is afraid of heights
you do not take em up to the top of the
transamerica tower okay
all of this is something that you've got
a lot need a lot of training to do right
if you do it wrong you'll make the
patient was
that he or she was vindicated buck if
you do it right
it works like a charm these are the
treatment of choice
for these kinds of anxiety disorders
there just terrific
and they all
homework they both work both systematic
desensitization
and implosion therapy or flooding
choir principle that's well known to you
from your from lectures and redeem
alerting
they're essentially extension regimes
all of the idea is that
fear is a
conditioned response
to all ought to go over some situation
or another
and what you want to do is to arrange
new learning experiences
so as to extinguish that responds
and in addition
of what the behavior of therapists may
do is to promote the active acquisition
all call more adaptive coping behaviors
so
theater pure extension
on fear response or extinction of the
for your response
or combined with
the learning of some
more adaptive
coping response
his brother example cognitive therapy
for depression
i talked last time about two cognitive
theories about the origins of depression
backs our notion of depressive gen x_
camara
that people like water decadent believes
that expectations
about themselves
about the world
and the future
and that these depressive genic
cognitive schemata
people depressed
the automation of the of the of sadness
follows from
these various kinds of police
and that has argued
all of the intended inode in addition to
that
are becca's argued that though
uh... depressed patients
our engagement have suffer from certain
kinds of cognitive biases like don't
over generalize things or something
if something goes really badly
bill generalize their negative
expectations to everything uh... ordered
around them
but backed off phone quite so what was
that you could be quite successful
in the treatment of many depressed
patients
by simply
persuading them to think otherwise its
location comes as i am are rotten person
dot world is terrible and dot whenever
everyone is going to helena handbasket
and although the purposeful sec
or you're really a rotten person
from anybody like you didn't have
succeeded or repair or whatever
persuading the person that things aren't
as bad as he or she believes them to be
in some cases
that was actually on range for the
person to have therapeutic success
experiences
so that the person who actually have an
experience of success
and not simply all their have to
reinterpret
all past experiences
it's kind of like systematic
desensitization except in reverse
whereas systematic desensitization
about his own educational wishing
that tries to get rid of
some kind of police for emotional
reaction
or cognitive therapy
actively tries to get the person to
acquire
a new set of beliefs about him or
herself
similarly we talked about a person and a
low res idea
that depressive people have a particular
attribution old-style they tend to make
stable
internal
global attributions for the things that
happen to them
and that went bad things happen to them
are making stable internal global
attribution of this week
this bad things happen because i'm an
awful person i've always been awful i
was going to be awful
and therefore not everything
that's going to make a depressed so or
what they propose is that what approach
cognitive approach to depression
is to of org
basically teach the person
to make more realistic more adaptive
followed causal attributions about the
world
the patients' symptoms
are symptoms auto emotion
sadness
followed by the unwarranted excessive
but the idea is that these
the sadness
flows form of beliefs about him or
herself
or about the world and what you want to
do is you want to get rid of the sadness
you've got to change the police
that's the whole idea behind behind
cognitive uh... behind cognitive therapy
here's another example of carpet
behavioral all
other therapy at work
it looks like a physiological disorders
like the stress related also recycle
octave vote part of the last time
obviously if you've got somebody has got
a medical problem
that's resulting from exposure to stress
but first line of treatment is to get
into the stress or you know
if you've got a guerilla living in the
room next door dealing that perot was
making a nervous
vertebral
right feel better instantly
dot sometimes you can't get rid of the
stress or
live in a world of stress
someone once called of modern life the
age of anxiety are and so it is you
don't know whether somebody's got out
bomb you or whether somebody is going to
declare war where they're going to get
hit by a beauty buster or whatever it is
but it's going to happen to you
all of so of productive
it in a world where you can't get red
of all the stressors that impinge on you
all but you need is a cognitive
behavioral therapy
that will teach you to respond to the
stressors more adapter memoria de
actively
and so called the one very
useful approach to stress reduction
israel taxation training
ally and biofeedback that'll actually
retrain the u_n_ atomic nervous system
so as to maa flight
the persons on orthodontic responses
to stress ors
to change the activity of a sympathetic
branch
of the autonomic nervous system
so that it doesn't
farzana said the person into all
paroxysmal missile all uh... panic and
uh... and anxiety
he originally samples
are not so much for major mental
illnesses of any kind
but for the kinds of problems of living
that people will often consult
psychotherapists about
all of those were all there is a dog
very to popular very effective form
all of our social skills training known
as the sort of assertiveness training
which is very useful for two different
kinds the kinds of billy widespread
properties
all the problems
so people just how problems of
assertiveness there are people out there
who dull
who can say no
okay megapixels and while a lot of
trouble
by being unable to the bug bite but not
say no
and the reason
don't say no
quite literally they can't say now that
a lot to do it right
so what happens in the furnace training
to give people practice would say no
so you know nicely
okay
you can maintain relationships with the
people that you sometimes will of will
have to say no to
but that's the real skill
as anybody knows
who's ever had a friend asked him to do
something
that they are really didn't want to do
very hard to say to somebody now i don't
want to do this yeah
all but
with the sort of mystery you can learn
how to do that and a very effective way
public speaking of anxiety is another
place where assertiveness training is
very
very useful
there are a lot of people out there who
are scared to death by the prospect of
speaking in public
alm
and all of the poster mistreating
can actually help them by training them
how to do that by giving them practice
and also speaking in public they can
become much much more affective at it
and that's what you're doing if you're
changing the person's skill
you're changing a skill that the person
didn't have interpersonal skills that
they didn't have before
another place where this happens
isn't sex therapy all of whether you're
married or not some people are having
sex
all and all
if you haven't found that out already
you will someday find out that it
doesn't always go as well as you'd like
it to go
arm
are many individuals have difficulty
maintaining sexual arousal when they
read gauge the sexual behavior
many people have difficulties in
achieving orgasm
and again
not to treat to smart about it this is
the schedule
okay
six is skilled activity there's nothing
natural about human sexual behavior
right it's not like dogs and guerrillas
think about when you were told the facts
of life that
you will put you know what where
as just crazy
and it doesn't always go
and people who need to learn
how to make law
how to have sex
so that they can
get the kinds of pleasure and share the
kind of pleasure that they want to our
with their partner
and sex therapy
does that in the same way well not
exactly the same way that you get my
point
in the same way that assertiveness
training
helps people doubt
the more assertive
sex therapy actually teaches people how
to have sex
so that they can
have more pleasure
and give their partners
more of the pleasure that they want to
give them
all of these forms of therapy
whether a systematic desensitization for
forty years
cognitive fault but there are before
depression
social skills training and various of
various sorts
all of which are trying to change the
person's police
change the person skills
change the person's cognitive and
emotional
are competencies
they're not looking to analyze your deep
seated relationships with your mother
they're not trying to figure out whether
you you're using
reaction formation were displacement to
defend against the out of the other pple
complex
they're taking people as they are
giving them educational experiences
that'll help to make
the question though question that's hard
over the practice of psychotherapy
almost from the beginning
is a question of whether actually works
we are persuaded by the medical
establishment that drug treatments work
okay because they've done clinical
trials
but part of the czars psychotherapists
for a long time we're reluctant to
engage and that kind of research
to actually demonstrate
that psychotherapy works and there is of
course a problem dependable
social stereotype of light psychotherapy
which suggests that it doesn't work
think about the average woody allen
character is the average woody allen
movie
art that characters billion
psychoanalysis for five days a week for
twenty or thirty years in
never seems to change
never seen this
to get better
and a lot of people of harvard the
suspicion that maybe
that's really
what happens in psychotherapy
people go to a show of money to a
psychotherapist
but they never change
and they never get better
how do you think of a british
psychologist
in nineteen fifty two
revealed the extent literature on the
outcome of psychotherapy and came to
precisely that conclusion
he concluded that psychotherapy simply
didn't work
okay one-third of patients and
psychotherapy got better but one-third
of patients who didn't get psychotherapy
also got better that there was just no
evidence port the effectiveness of all
of bothered of psychotherapy
there is the date here
this nineteen fifty to review
card is published
just about the time that the
pharmaceutical revolution
and all of the day in in in mental
health is beginning
all and of course the pharmaceutical
revolution
was a pharmaceutical revolution
precisely because we had
scientific evidence that these drugs
overworked
the evidence that drugs work
combined with the available evidence of
psychotherapy doesn't really work
also gone mad many people in the medical
in the mental health or establishment
to begin to abandon
psychotherapy
in favor
volvo in favor of uh... drug treatments
hurt the situation is now changed
all
psychotherapists have become much more
imbued
much more responsive
to modern social and economic demands
for what's known as evidence-based
practice
a movement within the healthcare
generally
to make sure
that the procedures that physicians and
all other health of service providers
use
actually work
actually accomplish or therapeutic or
goals
and these are filled with psychotherapy
community
has responded to the demand for
evidence-based practice
by collecting
new evidence engaging in more research
to show the psychotherapy does work a
lot after all
the general idea
behind evidence-based practice like in a
drug condition is compared to pick a new
drug zoloft
pack still howled or whatever these
drugs are
and belgium to half the patients
and the other half full either not get
any treatment or they'll get a placebo
drivers something like that
and then you can determine whether your
new drug actually works by comparing it
to ought to a placebo
you can in principle at least
you can do the same thing with
psychotherapy
you can
take a group of haitians
give half of them some kind of stuff
erica treatment
are for the other half
on you don't read them you compare them
to
two other no treatment control
sometimes there's actually placebos
psychotherapy
that you can or that you can do
all or at least
compare anew
all of the form of psychotherapy
with traditional practices
okay
and quantitatively
check
to determine whether psychotherapy works
after all
here is a classic
analysis of the effectiveness of
psychotherapy
by glass and his colleagues published in
nineteen eighty at the very beginning
some of the evidence praised of
evidence-based practice movement
in psychotherapy
what i've done a good smith of smith
lessons our colleagues and their
colleagues
of
analyze of number of studies
involving a many different kinds of
treatment
psychedelic treatment like
psychoanalysis
distraught therapy which is kind of a
new age therapy that's not used too much
or anymore
all client centered therapy of the sort
proposed by carl rogers
here are some cognitive behavior
therapies systematic desensitization
behavior modification
of that type
cognitive-behavioral therapies for
depression
and that we have here this figure
all of the better presents the
effectiveness of psychotherapy are
basically says that
how many more patients
who got some formal off psychotherapy
got better compared to no treatment
controls
and what you can see here
is that on average about eighty percent
of
patients we'll get some form of
psychotherapy
do better than naude unplugged on
treated controls
this was the first
systematic quantitative evidence
the psychotherapy all worked on worked
after all
that the other things that smith glass
and miller pointed out
was that these figures are all pretty
much the same the role in the seventies
and dogs and uh...
and the eighties
and i'll get that kind of interesting
what it's like what i also seek a
cognitive behavioral therapy reduced
systematic desensitization therapy
bardera analysis
first view of their analysis
seem to suggest that
psychotherapy worked
but that particular form of
psychotherapy you've got didn't really
matter
very much
this is what led to what glickman and
other individuals and others as some
people in psychotherapy
refer to as the you know as the day
woodrow bird verdict
are gifted everybody here are bred alice
in wonderland
if you didn't there's something you
should do what we are so went over the
break
all at one point dialysis in wonderland
and she all the witnesses
on a bunch of animals go over all
who do work and what they call a caucus
race
and basically a caucus race in the
elevator around
and then they'll stop
okay that's what the caucus race is done
and alice asks the dodo bird who was one
uh... because she was so who's going to
get the prize
and the dodo bird response replaced or
everyone
as one
and so everyone must have
of the prize
there is a tendency and the
psychotherapy community
to opt to wonder if you get burt verdict
about the effects of psychotherapy
secretary of the works
okay but it doesn't matter what kind is
still available but kinda psychotherapy
debt
all forms of psychotherapy wherein
they all get the prize
of being paid for
by insurance or or whatever
it turns out to be not really truth
and you can see
but that's not really true
when you look at these percent two other
allot or the probe percentile scores
for work the active cognitive-behavioral
treatments
as opposed to the more so i could never
have agreed humanistic or the treatments
these numbers are bigger
so at least by this standard all
people who get cognitive behavioral
therapy
tend to do better
then people
who are get although that's like a
dominican or humanistic forms of uh...
of psychotherapy
but there's another way to measure the
effectiveness of psychotherapy
it's not just cut
where people stand on some percentile on
the score
but rather all of us the physical
comparison of what's known as a fact
someplace where you take
the media telkom
of one treatment
the average outcome
and you compare it for the average
outcome of some other treatment
are basically the idea here is remember
means and standard deviations from the
appendix on statistics
what effect size of one point though
means that the average subject in one
group
scored one standard deviation higher
than the average subject in another
group
now you don't usually get effect sizes
that largely do sometimes
although colin
gould to develop a statistical measure
basically classified effect sizes all in
this way that that sizeof
point to all one-fifth of a standard
deviation
called a small affect
effect size of half a standard deviation
called a medium affect
effect size of
say home
forces for the standard deviation
colourful larger effect
when you take the smith glass and miller
results
and recast the man forms of
affect fleiss's and not just percentile
scores
if what you see something
really quite remarkable
all forms of psychotherapy
work
him that they are all associated with a
positive effect size
and is a fact sizes are
quite a large by cohen standards
the cognitive
the cognitive-behavioral and the
behavioral
although treatments or associate with
larger effect sizes
work better
by an average
for various kinds of bar
on bob things
then do this uh... the humanistic
or the second amendment
wildflowers
so it's not true
that we'll have one
and almost tab prices
what is true with at all
finish the race
and everybody's going to get you know a
purchase of haitian metal
cognitive-behavioral therapies are
better
on average cognitive-behavioral
therapies
all deserves all status as the ya as the
standard of care
here's another
uh... recent comparison by whites and
whites
on we are looking at uh... effectiveness
not an adult and children adolescents
buff treatments received by these
thought individuals are classified as
non behavioral either or psychodynamic
or humanistic
or behavioral including cognitive
treatments
and you can see that the behavioral
treatments for children and adolescents
roughly twice
the effects on its as are for the
as for the non behavioral on treatments
so all psychotherapy is really are
created equal
sam forms of psychotherapy are better
than others
on average
cognitive-behavioral forms
the focus on the hill now
and our actively
devoted to
change
an agenda of change
tend to work better
than psychedelic therapies that focus on
the
there and then
or humanistic
therapies that say
gee i don't know what you want to do
today
of
in the first place
also sounds like a therapies are good
for specific problems
systematic desensitization implosion
therapy
flooding
they are the treatment of choice
four various anxiety disorders
for phobias
an obsessive compulsive disorders
the cognitive-behavioral therapies
are ort eve ficient
on average
the us like a dynamic or humanistic
therapies
which is to say that they get their
results more quickly
and therefore more cheaply
on sixty or treatment sessions usually
to get a successful outcome with
cognitive behavioral therapy compared to
other forms of therapy so i know
advocacy grounds does it work
how well does that work
on specificity grounds you are there
specific treatments for specific
disorders
on efficiency grounds
how much bang for the box do you get
what's the clotbuster cost-benefit ratio
bacardi behavioral therapies
tend to be uh... the yard
though you know that they're a piece of
choice
and they tend to be
they tended to serve
oh uh... status as the standard of care
for for psychotherapy
then the recent trend one new trend in
all of the treatment of mental illness
has been to combine
psychotherapy
with pharmacotherapy to see all uploaded
to see what happens there
here's a relatively recent study by
teller
and associates patients with major
depressive disorder
all
oh who got cognitive behavioral therapy
basically
back type cognitive behavioral therapy
all or
or a new
you s_s_ alright drug like axial
and these patients
we're randomly assigned to either to get
psychotherapy alone no drugs
drabs alone
no psychotherapy
now or a combination
of drugs and psychotherapy
here or the results of treatment after
all a after twelve months
what you can say
drugs here are
patients or actually in remission no
symptoms
in the green patients huang have fault
all responded positively but they still
got some symptoms
you can see that the other columns of
drug alone
and drug plus psychotherapy
they're pretty much equivalent
psychotherapy as as good as the trial
the combination of drug and the
psychotherapy basically almost doubles
all of the success rate
all you get much more our success
and especially
much more on many more patients going
into
are going to complete remission
combination
of drugs and therapy seems to work
better
then either drugs or therapy alone
here is another
retesting all but the data from the
keller study we've got here is this is
where they started out at the beginning
of therapy you can see that all three
groups pretty much equal
well over at the end of twelve weeks you
can see that
all three groups responded but the drug
plus psychotherapy group responded
better
and then back here is a yell a one-year
follow-up
and you can see that all these
patients
at all three groups up pretty much
maintained
they're all of their treatment success
but here this
very good
treatment success for the drug plus
psychotherapy
on combination
has been a specially all of the
especially well maintained
sold this combination
you don't have to choose between drugs
and psychotherapy for many conditions
the combination seems to be better
there and all all of them now
anyone below one should that be the case
well
scenes
civil that drugs and psychotherapy
operate i'm different aspects of mental
illness
but then the drugs give u says no far
less quick
symptom relief
if you've got ends i disorder
beautify things a tranquilizers
reordered and he owned by the agents
will reduce your levels of anxiety
if you've got depression the s_s_
alright will tend to
all your mode so you're feeling better
pretty quickly
just by virtue of not one of the drug
but that's like a thirty dollars
a specially cut active forms of
cognitive behavioral therapy
will teach you ways of coping with your
enormous better tissue better ways of
thinking about the bad things that
happened to you
teach you better ways of coping with the
falls on situations that though
that cause the wings lady
are better ways of basically adjusting
to your depression
the fact is
there when you terminate drug treatment
the drugs will wash out of your system
and physiologically you're back where
you work
but learning the endeavor
over loons
once you've learned something you've
learned it forever
and the other the idea here is
that even if you go off your medication
but still holds
the new bullies the new coping
strategies that you've learned in active
cognitive-behavioral psychotherapy
will last you for a long time
ones reminded all of the old adage
if you give a man a fish
he'll lead for a day but if you teach
'em and how to fish
for life
it's the same kind of thing
yet give somebody a drug
they'll get pretty immediate symptom
relief as long as they're taking the
drug
but if you teach people active coping
strategies
active things that they can do about the
rumors
that is
something that they can use
even when they're not home
even when they're not taking the drug
so far we've talked about psychotherapy
as a treatment for individual patient
with mental illness
give a patient drugs
give a patient's psychotherapy
or drugs in psychotherapy in of aligned
in combination
but it's very clear
that for many forms of mental illness
active treatment has to reach beyond
under the individual patient
and
or extend at least to his or her
immediate family
also for example with social skills
training
teacher person in the therapy rule
mohabbat saying that would have people
nicely
the patient is gonna have to practice
that
okay
who do you have to say no to all the
time
n_c_r_ family right let me ask you to do
something
so established has to be treated
so that the family well except no for
and answer
similarly
in family therapy whether it's
marriage therapy
or afdelhi therapy father there for a
for a child with some kind of conduct
disorder or whatever
you've got to treat their family
because too often what happens is
that the family accommodates itself to
the individual family members' illness
and when the family members stars to
change the whole repeal of the family
gets disrupted
so what the problem that's not just at
the individual has to learn to deal with
his or her mental illness
but the entire family
and all other people neighbors friends
although
or whatever have to deal with this is
well and that's what things like
structural family therapy will do
it's not just that somebody
comes in for treatment at the bar family
comes in
for treatments or whole family is
participating
uh... in their treatment
he resolved
an example of this out at work
there is a real
offer for more than thirty people or
adding difficulties are in their
marriages there are basically three
different kinds of therapies part that
we are using first is what's known as
behavioral couples therapy
are which basically focuses on
changing
all
behaviors on one on one purple them
persons behaviors
that bothered the other persons
behaviors so if the husband will pick up
his socks in the white hates that
you know behavioral couple therapy
teachers and the pickup in stocks
alm
if the are if the art of what woman is
did that with the wife is got some issue
with with the children or whatever and
often doesn't like that
though that the white to support you
know how to complain about the kids or
whatever
but the focus is on the individuals
problems
in cognitive-behavioral couple therapy
the focus is not so much and changing
problematic behaviors but i'm changing
ichi individuals interpretations of the
others problematic behaviors
so far has been a while pickup in stocks
all bugaboo be out of the white homes
for their own just that kind of guy he
does so many other good things will pick
up his stupid socks okay
and everybody kind of gets better and
the people kind of adjust to own jostle
each other
but the third floor of a couple therapy
or emotionally focused couple therapy
doesn't focus on the individuals
behaviors
it doesn't focus on the individuals
interpretations of the other individuals
behaviors rather focuses koppel
and seeks to strengthen the bomb
that joins these two individuals
and it turns out
that's but one that works best
everything works right
the traditional behavioral couples
therapy
boser very nice effects license to kill
for those effects license they're very
very nice
cognitive
a couples therapy that focuses on
interpretations or problematic behaviors
that works really nicely by new focus on
the bag
when the whole gore treatment is to
strengthen the relationship between the
two individuals
when the koppel is treated
as a clickable
not just as a pair of individuals
that's what tends
too
to work best
so i can or whether you're talking about
along with what they're talking about
major forms of mental illness
we're talking about the risk of into
problems of living or
uh... dot that's dad
you had to have to move the all of the
individual
and focus
the uh...
on the person
in his or her
social context
when you think you are mental illness
try to do it
when you can't cure a mental illness do
what you can to uh...
relieves symptoms or two
help the person to jost
but there are some other forms of mental
illness
that are joyce
not curable
brain damage
is forever
so the organic brain syndrome they tend
to be uh... incurable
mental retardation
uh... that's something that's a chronic
illness
many forms of affect all of all of major
mental illness like schizophrenia and
affect of disorder are also
or things that
planet
very it's a bit always go away even with
very very good treatment combination of
drugs and psychotherapy or whatever
what do you do one of those cases
well in the past we use the warehouses
such individuals in mental hospitals
which of the wards of which were full
of chronic mental patients
but not all of the glove
full of treatment
active rehabilitation
in the same way that somebody with a
broken leg
worth spinal cord injury
or us dot those stroke barbara producing
aphasia
would get active rehabilitation
to require skills
to learn how to cope with a chronic
disease
in the same way that diabetics are not
just given insulin
were also given
our own dot thong informational
lifestyle changes and eating habits of
exercise at all that
the modern treatment of chronic mental
illness
also has to focus on
teaching person
to occult
with his chronic illness
try to get better
make an optimal social adjustment
or rehabilitation scheme
that again
and just focus on the individual
but has to focus on the entire
social matrix in which that individual
lives
individuals have mental illness
but the successful treatment of mental
illness
must go beyond the individual
the social cultural walt
wold in which that individual has to
live
thank you very much will finish up on
monday