okay last time and lecturer we are
intact
lou wins
pseudo formula behavior as a function of
the person and the environment
and looked at their work various kinds
of relationships that can obtain among
these three elements
the person's behavior
the person's internal
psychological dispositions
and the features on the external
environment
and at the end all of the lecture i
described for you
on
anyway
major achievement of traditional
personality psychology
which is to provide a way
concise framework for summarizing the
individual differences in now in
personality
all known as despite factor model of
her that trace
extra version agreeable as consciousness
of notional stability and intellect ins
now where the years there has come to be
about the consensus among personalities
psychologist
that this five factor model many
representative universally applicable
structural personality
he has tipped the data is derived mostly
from the north american college students
but it looks as if
this is a um... hum
structure per se that's uncredited
ordinary language
we use terms like
extroverted agreeable hands on the moshe
least able to describe each other
and also it's a structure
that appears to be valid across a wide
variety of cultures
american culture european culture
asian culture whatever
also appears to be valid across or
different generations my generation your
generation my grandparent's generation
and also appears to be valid across
various developmental ethics
you can use this language
to cap to capture
individual differences in personality
among
very young children you can also uses
language to capture individual
differences in personality armand
on middle-aged people reward people or
whatever
now one thing i have a point out
is that the five factor model itself
can be made even more concise if you
think about it
because those kind of a two-dimensional
superstructure here
two different kinds of evaluation
first evaluating the person that has
more or less desirable undesirable on
the social groans
and evaluating the person who has more
or less
good or bad
on intellectual grounds
so inmates cultures
we tend to favor extroverted people over
introverted people we obviously favor
agreeable people over disagreeable
people
conscientious people over non conscious
of cartridges people emotionally stable
people over in the stable people and we
also tend to value smart people over
stupid people
also again
all of this the payoff eleven analysis
that you're going to look at
you could say that this this five factor
model itself
all
can the altered compress
into a two factor model or even a one
factor model
good or bad
personal qualities
okays ope these five
factors
because i'm five basic personality
traits okay
extra version agreeable knows
conscientious nis emotional stability
and all
openness to experience
and the question is what do you do with
these
without the cartoon
versions of what i've called the
doctrine of trade so hard person a soft
for some week for sonora strong version
bud mcpherson simply says
that traits summarize
the services
congress that labels to summarize
various aspects of people's behavior
how coherent
how stable
how consistent and predictable it is in
various dimensions
so if i see somebody who smells a lot
and somebody who are has a lot of
friends
and somebody who blows to a lot of clubs
are going to summarize that person's
behavior in terms of
something like friendliness
but the strong version of the doctrine
of traces what interests us here
and that is but rates
has people to behave in a particular way
if i see somebody who smiles a lot
has a lot of friends
alm
double lost a lot of clubs
that the uh... the idea behind the
strong doctrine of traits is that the
person who does these things be clause
he or she is extroverted
okay
on
that somehow
having this disposition
really does dispose u
to behave in particular ways
introduce these terms for our last time
coherent stability consistency and
predictability
and i want to are gonna try to explain
those a little bit
all more
all it now
first
with respect to coherence
what we mean that is that
personnel about putting individuals
personality
hangs together
makes sense as a coherent paul
as a coherent whole
and they can distinguish a couple of
different types of coherence
so for example
there might be coherence along
papa graphically different behaviors by
topographic papa graphically beat
different behaviors
just mean different behaviors that
involve different parts of the body
so it might be
that a person who tends to smile a lot
also tends to believe
those are different kinds of behaviors
and as if there's a correlation between
them
it might be because extroverted people
both penned a smile
and tended tubely
similarly
there's a coherent someone what you
might call semantically different traits
that is traits that are all that have
somewhat different meanings
but still i hope there's a correlation
among them
people who are friendly
tend also to be a sort of
okay tuza carly
being friendly doesn't mean the same
thing as beans assertive
they are totten semantically different
rate labels
but the fact of the matter is that
friend friendliness and assertiveness
tend to go together
and they tend to go together because
they're all paths of facets
all this broader trade
all extra virgin so much of that
with with the doctor traits sorry is
every harker cole structure
begins with
the big five traits like extra version
and a greater boldness
and mastered underneath these are very
broad traits
or more narrowly defined at cyber net
rates like warns and assertiveness
extroverted tend to be warming to
personally warm
physically warm but interpersonal e warm
extra parts also tend to be a sort of
here's a grill mullis
there are two facets of their respective
agreeable people tend to be trusting
and they also tend to be altruistic
and dusted off under each of these
subordinate rates
or behavioral tendencies so warm people
tend to like most of the people that
they know
and a tender form strong attachments to
friends
a sort of people tend to be dominant and
forceful and they tend to lead groups
trusting people tend to believe that
most people are almost
and they tend to assume the best
about people altruistic people
tend to be criticism re body
and they tend to be charitable now wire
and i don't really have a slide
but these are just behavioral tendencies
and so you can imagine that or mastered
underneath here are specific behaviors
observed in specific situations
if i'm extroverted i tend to be warm if
i warm i tend to like most people
and now the next question is
i'm going to meet somebody in a couple
of hours at my office and i got i like
him or not
him personally
when i got home tonight i'm going to
meet my new neighbor just moved in
across the street and the question is
well i'm going to like
him in her or whatever those specific
behaviors
are nestled onto these behavioral
tendencies
so that coherence of personality
that's given by these personality traits
simply means that there is a really
there as a hierarchy of personality
tendencies
where we have very brad dispositions
like extra version agreeable dance
somewhat more narrowly defined
are dispositions like warmth and trust
and assertiveness and altruism
and so on all the way down
just like
our discussion of super ordinate and
subordinate categories
here we have
subordinate and super wordnet levels of
analysis of behavior
and the idea behind the storm version of
the doctrine of traits
traits
personality this coherence if you say
that somebody is warm
you can
expect them to like most people in the
form strong attachments to their friends
because those are part and parcel of the
warm their specific worries of being
interpersonal e war
okay
now with respect to the other three
aspects of what rates do
all traits not only did coherence
behavior
but they also gives stability to
behavior over time
somebody is extroverted at time warner
we also expect to find them extroverted
at some later time because they have
been straight
that disposes them to behave in a
particular way
if we find somebody who likes most
people
at age five
we expect that people also that person
also toll-like most people and age
twelve
stability turns out as an empirical
matter
greatest over short intervals of time
but still the ideas that having a trait
gives stability to new york behavior
severly
we can think about
the consistency odd behavior across
situations
if i smell it somebody in the
supermarket and i got a smile it's but
that that somebody other somebody else
on the street
if ari make friends with my new
next-door neighbor
am i going to make friends with the new
colleague who moved into the office next
door mine in them
in pullman hole
and again
the ideas that traits make behavior
consistent across situations
it's by virtue of having a trait
your or consistency your behaviors
consistent across situations and again
as an empirical matter
are consistency is greatest
when you are looking at behavior across
the jewish instead are
fairly similar to each other so if
ronald you're looking to buy the right
make friends with a
new personally meet in in my
neighborhood
that might
correlate with the with my tendency to
make friends with a somebody
just join my church or whatever very
similar situations are kinda neighbors
in in some sense
and then finally
it's traits that make these
your predictable
if you know somebody's extroverted if
you know somebody's warm
because
extra version is a disposition to behave
in particular ways
knowing that somebody's extroverted or
to enable you to predict
how old they are going to be haven
in some specific
of the in some specific situation
it is to that problem or predictability
that we're going to turn
right now
to what extent ted we predict opin
individuals' behavior
in some specific situation
nileen
something about his or her
road personality
dispositions
sometimes were able to use
bomb all of them
but personality measurements
to predict behavior with quite a bit of
confidence
bomb
here for example
so sweep
have somebody we know was extroverted
we can predict that they're going to be
relatively warm
we could predict
that they're going to
or like most people on average
but the real question is
well this extroverted people like judy
when he meets ur
well this extroverted person
still call judy after she moves away
okay
are these are the kinds of things that
extroverted people do
or if you're a sort of
or if you're extroverted you're going to
be they're going to tend to be assertive
you can be darlington forceful
but then in some specific situation
will this person interrupted speaker
or will this person takeover
the task
again what we're trying to do here
is to use information about people's
personality traits
dispositions to behave in a particular
way
and use that information
how they actually will behave
here a couple more examples of it
from agreeable this no way that
somebody's agreeable
how confident we can we predict
they don't let his co-worker borrow some
money
how confident we can we print archery
predict that he'll still like this
co-worker when the co-worker doesn't pay
the money back
okay
idle preventing that a person is
altruistic although
will the person ald of the plate to the
you know store clerk
are or little person
or contribute
the psalm or charity
and again as i said before sometimes
did these kinds of behavioral
dispositions could be very very powerful
predictors of behavior
the best example okay
of predicting specific behavior
phloem
qualities of a person from a person's
traits of the additives
probably the best example
comes on the domain of political
behavior
where we classify somebody as republican
or a democrat
liberal or conservative
and then predict
how that person is going to vote for a
particular candidate in a particular
election
here is that
recollected by john joseph reported just
a dearest so i'll go
analyzing
the relationship between political
attitudes and voting behavior
across all large number of presidential
elections
are from nineteen seventy two
to nineteen seventy-four
and just to
all of make things all a little bit dull
uh... geezer
we've got subjects buckle classified as
basically based on our population sample
united states
we've got subjects classified as
democrats and republicans
and then are they've also rated
themselves as how liberal they are
on a seven-point or the seven point
scale
and then the all what joe stated simply
assess
hello you voted to call people voted
based on are hall log on how liberal or
conservative
all of the political rant asian
all the candidate was
and what you can see here
is that there is a very strong
relationship
between political attitudes in general
and voting behavior
democrats
or overwhelmingly vote flammable
political candidates
republicans overwhelmingly vote
for conservative political candidates
correlation point ninety two you can't
get while higher correlation
not in the social sciences
you hardly see correlations that high
art but again
this is something that occurs election
after election
here is our most recent presidential
election carry versus bush
okay
and you can see
demagogued the liberals
voting for carry
conservatives
voting for bush
over well mainly
go back one ground versus bush
same pattern
liberals voting for gore
bush i've got conservatives
nineteen ninety-six clinton versus dole
same pattern
something funny happens there it's
i think it's ralph nader actually
lomb part sterile the overall pattern is
quite clear
that part
hello liberals are going to vote for
clinton
and conservatives are going to vote for
dole let's just keep going back clinton
versus
of the first george bush bush forty one
again a very strong relationship
mike dukakis versus the first george
bush
again a very strong relationship between
people's political orientations whether
they're liberal or conservative
and who they're going to vote for
mondale versus reagan
quarter versus reagan
carter versus ford
mcgovern versus nixon
okay and again you see this this same
kind of pattern
these are very
early very powerful predictions
nelene where a person is a republican or
a democrat
youtwo a tremendous amount of leverage
in terms of predicting hollow that
individual is going to vote
here's an example of a general
disposition
a dinner tonight that would have just a
legend
favor republicans are favored democrats
predicting behavior
in a specific situation and as i say
very very very strong correlations
remember
correlation can't get any bigger than
one point no
these are correlations
in the high eighties
and all and all the low to mid nineties
they're very very very
very very strong
but now let's don't usually see i have
to tell you
we do not usually see this strong a
level of predictability
i have specific behavior
generalized behavioral tendencies
here is of more represented experiment
all conducted here at berkeley
by david finder is now a professor at
u_c_ riverside
jacket gene block
all who are retired professors here
taught at berkeley
all in this study
aren't the out of the stuff this is a
study of children
and all the data domain owners delayed
gratification
this is not topic i'm going to come back
to over and over again in these lectures
to have gratification
has to do with the child's ability to
control his or her impulses
all kids one stuff
kids are one stuffed sometimes they
can't wait for other times they can
so very very very important to although
the personality trait
it has to do with what the blocks called
hugo control
the ability to delay gratification talk
date for the things you want
to inhibit aggression not to strike out
when you don't like somebody
and the ability to plan ahead in your
behavior to get your assignment start on
time
arms and uh...
world and so on
so what all funds were conducted in this
study
is to take four-year-olds these our
children and they are research nursery
school
here on the berkeley campus
and the teachers rated these children
in terms of there you go control
whether they're able to delay
gratification or not
unless there are many dimension known as
evil resiliency
which basically has to do with the kids
ability to adapt to new environments
how secure is the kid
howell competent as a kid and so on
and then work visa investigators did
was to try to use these broad
evaluations of personality
product
how'd children were behaving in a
particular
situation
and there are two situations are that
they are that they studied
wind is known as the gift or a situation
and the other is known as the resistance
of temptation situation
in the gift or a situation
the experimenter would come into a room
with a kid was sitting with only gilly
wrapped gift you know i'm eggs right
wrapping paper ribbons and stuff like
that
and are going to get to the child is her
four-year-old children
antec i've got a gift for you
but you gotta wait to open it
but you gotta wait
arm so don't open it don't open it
i got to go away and do something now
just sit here for a while other than
ever that gift
and then the experimenter walks away and
of course some kids sit there and they
look at the box and they need fiddle
with the reforms or whatever they do
and other kids are tearing into the box
immediately as soon as the arm
as the investigators left
that's how we mean by doing
gratification
send kids kentucky gratification whether
kids temple gratification
can be of yellow in the resistance to
temptation situation the uh... child was
taken with was brought into a room where
there were two sets of toys on one side
of the room
well puncher
kind of or ratty
reopen
dougherty toys not on healthy dirty just
they just didn't look very nice right
and then on the other side of the room
with these
really great new terry's bright clean
fresh new
the kinds of things that are being
advertised on t_v_ right that very
second
and all of the experimenter says on to
the kid
okay i've got a leave the room now
and all while i'm gone
you can play with these toys over here
meeting the ready duri old undesirable
toys
but touch these stories over here
because they belong to missus
morgenstern and also for her class they
are not for you
the experimenter leaves the room and of
course some kids star claim of the toys
and immediately some kids run right over
the missus morgenstern stories and start
playing with them despite the fact that
that's been expressly forbidden by the
alone
by the uh... by the experimenter
so the question here is
how well can we predict
harwell children are going to
the lei how long children are going to
delay in the gift of my situation
and how welcome to predict
how ought to resistant a temptation
children are going to be in this other
situation
and the answer is
that yes i am ability to predict
these all of these behaviors
also under his colleagues looked at
four different
all predictor variables here is just a
thought brutal measure of i_q_
and that site
that sold much smaller correlation than
point nine five
but it's still significantly better than
zero so there is some predictive power
here
here is the critical
are persona dimension
eagle control estimates that's related
to the big five trade of conscientious
nis
and again there's some ability to
predict behavior correlations un
significantly different from zero
correlational point to five
interestingly eagle resiliency also
predicts behavior a little bit this is a
trait that's related to mirada schism
alms and out that some of the again
civ not point nine five but not zero are
either
and then one of the items
that that showed that the teachers rated
the children on was the specific trade
aud
is up and they had to delay
gratification
and again you get all they have
significant correlation if your unable
to the lake ratification highly on able
to look to the lake ratification
don't resist very well so that's why the
correlation is negative
but again the point here is
that you do have slam ability
toooo
predict behavior
juvenile ij all of the individuals
of the individuals personality traits
but the other point is
these this correlation which is quite
representative of the studies that have
been done
on in this domain
there are limits to did to the degree
that you can't predict
behavior in some specific situation for
example walter michelle
uh... has suggested all of that the
upper limit
of the correlation between personality
in general
behavior in some specific situation
isabel point three oh
all of member correlations
vary from zero
to one
this is a correlation that is better
than nothing
okay but for from perfect
the general idea here
is that there is a ceiling
on the extent to which
we can predict behavior
in a specific situation from knowing
the persons
personality traits in general there is
some predictive leverage
but there's not by a lot of predictive
and this is just one study autumn dozens
and hundreds of dollars buddies such
studies
that have been done in the literature
that suggests that there are limits
on the extent to which
we could predict behavior
audience on specific situation
from knowledge of
the individual's personal retrace
armed
that's one part of the dialectic between
epperson and his or her behavior
the died that part of the dialectic that
says
there's a classical relationship
between
the internal
qualities of the person
what his or her traits and attitudes are
and how that person is going to be haven
in some particular situation
let's stop for a second and see if there
are any questions about this
there is some relationship some
predictability but it's far from perfect
that's three bottom line here
any questions what yes
all guys across america
it's just because of the way
correlations work
all be able to deliver gratification
you're highly unable to blade
ratification
that you can't wait very long
okay remember the positive correlations
high values odd one variable predict
high values on another variable
when a coalition is negative
high values on one variable predict low
values on the other so
if we had said
able to the lake ratification
if the specific item had said eventful
belay gratification
but carly she would have been
positive
twenty-seven but the specific item the
teachers rated was unable to belabor
application
well because that's the kind of more or
less the closest
big five straight
blocker jack block who own kuo but will
become fund or work
not contradict believer in the big for
you
he's a believer in what he calls the big
to on hugo controlling legal resiliency
but when you look at what he means by
evil control
it's very close to conscientious
if you look at what he means by evil
resiliency is very close to murata
schism
if you like the word
pay no attention to that part
pay no attention by men behind a curtain
alm
what else is there
yeah what we mean by topographic we
different behaviors means
behaviors and involve different
parts of the body
to be done to make a long story short
so smiling involves my face
and waiting and both my hands
but if i'm a friendly guy i tend to
smile of people attend a way that people
but their topic graphically different
behaviors
but they're correlated with each other
people who tend to smile tender wave
because the other kinds of things that
extroverted people do
by semantically different rates
we mean traits that really have
different meanings
arm
friendliness
doesn't mean the same thing as
assertiveness
okay
to be friendly means uh...
have lots of friends and be nice to
people
too assertive means to put yourself
forward and a kind of take control of
things
but as a matter of fact
these two semantically different rates
are karmaloop park are correlated with
each other
because they're both related to this
higher order trait of extra version
okay as women
anything else about this yet one more
yes that's right the difference between
the week version and the are in the
strong version
is that
in the week version treats just kind of
summarize a person's tendencies
so if i said
judy is
intelligent
so much or how do you know judy's
i said well if you know she wins the
chess tournament and she understands the
symphony and all this kind of stuff
but if i say
judy's intelligence
causes her
to win the chess tournament
that's the strong doctrine okay
where we can say that
having a trait
causes you to behave in a particular way
it's at strong version of the doctrine
of trades that's really at issue here
because the idea here is that
being able to
on where are we
dealing with a new
have been high on the eagle control
classes you
the daily ratification
or are being high on non-verbal i_q_ for
that matter causes you to be able to
lake
gratification
now what we want to do that with his
look at the other direction
of causality
okay
and he looked at
relationship between
qualities of the person
his or her political attitudes his or
her
doll ability to the lake ratification
and behavior in some specific situation
that we want to do now
is to look at our recent recall of fact
all the individuals' behavior on the
person him or herself
how the individuals' behavior
deduct back
if you will
to alter
traipse the attitudes the dispositions
all of the individual him or herself
and that's a good example of this
is what's known in the trade as
discussed in your textbook lightens
textbook as the self perception theory
of attitudes formulated by daryl bam
back when he was a staffer professor
bemis now at cornell university
and the sale perception theory about it
dudes
reverses our usual view orbit called
relationship between attitudes and
behavior
we usually think of
of attitudes as causing people to behave
the way they do
and the liberals
liberal nis classes him
vote for terry as opposed to bush
causes him
to vote for
mcgovern as opposed to mix and or
whatever
and but then the argued but that wasn't
necessarily the case
rather from guns point of view our
behavior
in some very important sense
causes us to have the attitudes that we
have
put more concrete lee
it's not a perception or awareness of
our own behavior
at least perform
attitudes that are consistent with the
behavior
in the usual scheme of things the
attitude comes first
and the behavior flows from it
in behrens
self perception theory of attitudes
that behavior comes first
and the attitudes
let me give you an example of this
all this is a classic experiment in
social psychology known as the for the
door effect
this was an experiment conducted in the
context of his safe driving campaign
in the state of california
and what these investigators did was in
the guy is all of public opinion
all surveyors
then door-to-door in a number of
neighborhoods air nam
uh... in in the heart of various cities
in california mostly
palo alto
armed and tabatha neighborhoods
and whoever not old woman and knocked on
the door whoever opened the door they
said
i were from the california safe driving
campaign
and we have this petition
that supports safe driving
would you like to sign this petition
anybody here in
opposed to safe driving
pretty much everybody has expressed
signs this petition gus right you're not
going to say well now allow opposed to
safe driving i'm not going to sign your
stupid petition whatever so they've got
around to have to households of these
various neighborhoods
and that's the best line of this
petition
and virtually everybody who was asked to
sign the petition
agreed to do so
later
barely returned to these neighborhoods
and now instead of knocking on the
although two-and-a-half the doors in the
neighborhood
they not done all the doors in the
neighborhood and said
harley
were from the california safe driving
campaign
we have this
drive carefully sign
that we would like to post in your front
yard
and is that the biggest
or girliest saline you can imagine
that's just
as old as a as a piece of silage
putting that site in your front yard
would drive property values down by
thirty or forty percent it's just that
there was just a terrible
on either side
all dot
it turned out
large numbers of people agreed to post a
sign in the neighborhood
and what's interesting in about it
is that people who are earlier signed
the petition
we're much more likely to agree to post
a sign it and their front yards
than people
who hadn't
that asked
to sign the petition
now i don't mind that virtually
everybody who was asked to sign the
petition
did so
so these people verbal reasonable gas
is that these people who weren't asked
to sign the petition
what they've done it
but it turns out it is the act
on signing dot petition
that leads people two-degree supposed to
be a big audibly
all its safe driving a drive carefully
sign
in their own
twelve in their front yard
wetsuits not happen in this experiment
was at the subjects who signed the
petition
something went through their minds like
this all i remember i signed this
petition
almost really be in favor of safe
driving
therefore because signed so much in
favor of safe driving all but the post a
sign
bad behavior
led to the creation of an attitude
consistent with the behavior
and then they had no release form to
entertain led to or further behavior
this is known as the footnote door
technique
something that's known by
palm uh...
salesman sales people and political
candidates the world over
and for that matter anybody
if you want to get somebody to do you
want big favor
ask them to do a little favor first
they do it a little favorably on like
this guy
no i don't do the big favour so you've
got them not one of a quarter and pretty
soon you're signing over your monthly
paycheck
but again it all starts with the
behavior
the behavior comes first
here is another example
this is the experiment by bob shall be
at a higher is at the state university
on subject recruitment
offered online this experiment subjects
recruited for experiment by telephone
all and all
the subjects were informed
before they agreed to participate
that the experiment would begin at seven
o'clock in the morning
hi i'm bob shall be reelected to come
into this experiment it it's going to it
won't take place at seven o'clock in the
morning william will you come in
and uh...
for the other half of the subjects they
were informed a different began at seven
a_m_ after they agreed to participate
high on bob shall be the i'm doing this
experiment would you like to produce a
cultural right like to participate
thank you very much
it starts at seven o'clock all see you
then
and now the question is
how many people will actually arrive on
time for the experiment
here is the data here
subjects who'll well-informed
about the starting time of the
experiment
before they agreed to participate
well actually less likely to show
for the experiment
subjects or informed of the although the
father of the overall
with experimental start time
after they agreed to participate
all were much more likely to show
why because child he had his foot in the
door
they had already agreed to participate
that behavior appellee band led the
subjects
to four minute attitude that was
consistent with actually are showing up
later
thus in their favor
agreeing to participate
leads to the big favor later on
actually showing up
at the on godly all work
seven o'clock
how in the morning
again
what what what this experiment
illustrates
is the reversal or the usual god
direction of causality
bad behavior comes first
and the attitude
columns
this is the reciprocal affect
or behavior on the person here's one
more example another classic experiment
by shelley check in now at n_y_u_
on conservation attitudes and behavior
in the yard guise of a young
prescreened like one you did on at the
very beginning of this sort of the
semester all touch a chemical and and
and baldwin administered a test of
environmental attitudes obviously things
like do you believe in environmental
conservation do you think it's important
to pick up trash do you think uh... it's
okay to throw your
coke bottles by the side of the road
stuff like that river when the systems
twenty years ago report that we're on
the time of the first birthday where
people did actually very fairly widely
on their attitudes about environmental
conservation
but instead on what you did in in any
event what dot jacob involving dead
was the classified as subjects as
prayer book work on environmental
conservation
all and also
classify them as in terms of whether
they had week
or stray dog
all orcon attitudes
after this pretest
trumpeter baldwin administered another
questionnaire
in which subjects were asked to reflect
on their specific behaviors
with respect to environmental
conservation
so for example all
old thought that there were
items like
i pick up other people's garbage okay
even
very
pro environmental people don't
necessarily pick up other people's
garbage one april when they find that
lying around
so one group got these very difficult
items were
most people are going to say no
and i've got a group of of the people
got these other items
where all
you know i leave the lights on and clean
rooms are not using way everybody does
that from time to time it's the kind of
thing it's easy to answer yes on too
what they did with the ethical to
wind one group
to reflect on their work
prayer environmental behaviors
and another group
i have some questions that led them to
reflect on their
aunty
environmental behaviors
and then
we administered the test
of environmental attitudes
what happened there're
is that
for subjects who had
relatively weak
pro or empty and barter mental attitudes
okay
when they were all
when they are what we're retested
the distinction between them became even
greater
when subjects
with we've got it too
will lead to believe that actually
behaved in a way that was pro
environmental conservation
baby came
more strongly in favor of environmental
conservation
when subjects were lad
retrieve
bof a memory
behaviors that were opposed to
environmental conservation they became
all dog a book more negatively
although if alton
disposed
towards that behavior the experiment
didn't work that way for people with
strong environmental conservation
attitudes okay which is interesting but
here's another case
proceeding in your own behavior
leader of four men attitude
that's consistent with their behavior
that you proceed okay
all of these experiments
are consistent with this
idea of daryl barons about the self
perception our theory of attitudes
the people in for their attitudes
from knowledge of their own behaviors
which is if you think about it the same
way we infer
home
or other people's attitudes if i want to
know whether you're
pro rent the environmental conservation
are falling around and see if you pick
up other people's garbage in we've
lights on the rooms are not using and
stuff like that
themselves
we do with ourselves as well we don't
have attitudes
what we do is we form they don't know
that it is our cause our behavior
rather reform attitudes
all in line with the behaviors that all
that we engage in
one more example of this paw paws idea
is what's known as the james lang a
theory all of you mention which
claiborne also talks about
again our traditional view
the traditional view that believe james
sort or the crystallized
is that even mentions
lead us to behave in particular ways
all if i walk in belum guarded from
walking across campus and i've got a
jump start of the bushes near california
hole
that rebuffed is going to elicit fierer
in me
and the fear is going to make me right
away
the emotion closes me to behave
in pay particular
jane said gee maybe it's the other way
around
maybe on survey shows of our own
behavior cause or a professional states
as james put it from an doesn't run from
the bear because he's afraid
the man is afraid
because he runs from the bearer
but behavior comes first the internal
emotional state
all columns of comes later
now this is a very controversial
although point-of-view and all
and out of a psychology
but there is some on some evidence on in
favor of it
all here's kind of the traditional view
here all the from from from paul ekman
facial expressions of emotion
being in that particular emotional state
causes us
behave in a particular way
indirect wins case
are causes us to expressed sorrow motion
allstate's
on our faces so
here we have ek wins
basic emotions happiness sadness
fear
anger surprise and discussed
and the traditional view
although she will states
a characteristic of us as people
classes oz
make these facial expressions
but james and his of width
thus deduction data psychologist name
logger said no
expressions are caused bio motions
expressions harvey motion the behavior
comes first the emotion
here is an example that parking that
kind of illustrates palm uh... james's
point
was work by james letter
all in which all
all in the guys all calibrating some
equipment some psycho physiological
recording equipment also
layered after subjects to hold certain
expressions on their faces
and while they were doing that
he collected all he collected various
kinds of mood ratings you get some sense
of what wrongful
of what he did
if you take your pen or pencil and just
do two things
all first
arctic about a pencil not dot point okay
alm and just hold it between your lips
okay
and then do the same thing and hold it
between your teeth
notice
that when you hold
all
thought that that would when when you
hold the uh... the pencil in your lips
all between your legs
your facial expression begins to looks
at you all look pretty fair
when you're doing that
whereas when you hold the barbara berra
pencil between your teeth
a little bit estas kinda naturally all
look very happy all there
and that's actually what larry david he
manipulated people's faces
so that they were expressing
fear or anger or discussed or sadness
and then ask the subjects or write
themselves on with their most states
and they discovered
was a subjects
mabe who was manipulated facial
expression that was a facial expression
of fear
actually
felt
fearful
subjects whose faces look angry
actually
felt angry
subject since faces
well looked like they were in disgust
felt so im discussed at that one didn't
work out so well but it worked out very
nicely for said this
he'd be all subjects whose fill a facial
manipulation of the facial expressions
were manipulated
to reflect sadness
actually began to feel sad
that behavior came first
and the mood came later
here's yet another example of how
your behavior
feedback
to shape
traits your attitudes your moods and
depart and so on
all of which has to do
with this
general idea that there is a very
separate colt
calls our relation
between the characteristics of the
person
and the person's overt behavior
sometimes the persons traits in states
moods and attitudes
lead the person to behave
in the way that he or she does that's
one side of the causal link
all other times
behavior comes first
and the internal disposition or st
cotton second
behaving in a particular way
leads you to all have
a particular kind of emotional state
this is the kind of situation that
summed up in and anybody here ever see
you know the movie or the play the king
and i agree and in the high schools
something like that gay around that's
long before i happy to know i'm not
going to sing it to you here
whenever i feel afraid i'd hold my head
a wrecked and whistle a happy two nd so
no one will suspect i'm afraid
and then it goes on and on and on welch
everyday my shoes i strike a careless
posed
and whistle are happy to him so no one
ever knows i'm afraid
and then the chances are not talking to
her son is they're pulling up by the doc
in not in bangkok the result of this
deception is very strange to tell
for when i for the people i fear rifle
myself as well
bad behavior comes first
wesley that have been thrown
makes you feel less afraid
behaving as if you're not afraid
behaviors are caused by
internal states and traits
but they also
callers
you listed vent also can deal with it
internal states and traits
that's the reset record relationship
between the person in his or her
behavior
next time on monday
look at the same reciprocal relationship
that obtains between
the environment
and behavior
thank you very much