one more reminder
that there is an exam in this class next
week first midterm next wednesday
there'll be a review and class on monday
by the geo size
palm
i think i've got all the disability
deduct the s_p_ starcom additions
you know
if i haven't
act fast because we have to make
arrangements for you
home
okay are just a reminder of the coverage
everything from the beginning of the
course until
the end of business
today
lots of resources for our ball for the
exam on the course website
go to the court's website click on exam
information in the uh... in the
navigation bar
and you'll get everything you need if
you have any questions
poston through the of forum
of the course bulletin board
paul
and will get an answer to you just as
soon as we can
fifty mobile choice questions computers
scored
on roughly half of the lectures roughly
half of the text
sold bringing you've gotta bring your
own scantron form we don't supply goes
and you've got to bring your own pencils
as well
and that's what the scantron form looks
like some of you already got it
ones i've seen of the right ones
and there's that
last time i'd focused on what's known as
the ecological view of perception
all of you know that says that
perception is
simply a matter of
extracting information about the distal
stimulus from the proximal stimulus
by which is meant
the entire pattern all proximal
stimulation
that falls on these sensory surfaces of
the art of the pursuit
and i thought was traded oven
the ecological view with a young or
run-through
various principles by which
we recover information about depth or
distance the all of the distance between
all of the distal
stimulus and the perceive ur
and noted that
all
there are some cues the distance
that require
to rise
some the require only one i did
some of these cues are ocular in nature
and that they're provided by feedback
from the musculature r_b_i_'s itself
and all others are optical in nature
uh... in that they have to do with the
pattern of light
that falls on the retina
these cute
alm
relatives sawyer superposition and shot
to win and so on
are sometimes known as pictorial cues
because they have been used by artists
these western artists
since the time of the renaissance
conveying depth or distance three
dimensions
in order to dimensional surfaces like
canvases and
frescoes
just to review again
what's going on here is that from the
ecological point of view
all the information that the perceive ur
needs
to see objects in depth to perceive
distance is provided by the entire
pattern
are proximal stimulation
that falls on the perceive urs sensory
or systems
and it gives an argued
that over evolutionary time
are perceptual systems evolved
to extract just that stimulation that's
relevant
for proceeding
motion and so on
so this is a somebody pointed out on the
forum all of this this morning
are kind of nativist
viewer perception
that the perceive ur comes into the
world with all of the equipment that'd
needs to extract this so i kind of
information
it's part of
the procedures innate biological
endowment
doesn't require regular neend requiring
the experience
on doesn't require any so-called higher
mental process these involved and
reasoning judgment an inference
like these stimulus response view of
learning
he hit the ecological view a perception
is an extremely powerful an extremely
attractive view
this particular cognitive process
but like the stimulus response theory of
learning
it is a ltd
view all perception
and there are so many important problems
with it
which is what i'm going to devote
today's lecture are true
wherever headed
is an alternative you of perception
which is known as the constructivist
view
are summarized most aptly by the part of
their psychologist jerome bruner
that this really says
that in perception the perceive ur must
go well beyond the information given by
the stimulus
gibson said all that's needed for
perceptions to extract information from
the stimulus
brunner argued that that wasn't enough
dot all but you had to do i do
more instantly extract stimulus
information
one reason for that is sometimes
stimulus information is just
insufficient for perception
the stimulus does not provide you with
what you need
difficult what it is where it is what
it's doing and saw one
and also sometimes as will see a little
while
stimulus information is misleading
on the august the stimulus information
conveys a
misleading all perception 'em mislead
impression of what the stimulus is like
fred gibson
perception is a mechanical process
for rotor perception is an intelligent
process
that requires that the
perceive ur
bring to bear on the act of perception
his or her knowledge all of the world
and requires the perceive her to make
various kinds of judgments
various kinds of inferences to engage in
the reasoning and problem solving
in an effort to figure out
to figure out what it is that is out
there
where it is and what it is
here is an example
what some people take to be a limitation
of the ecological view it's a phenomenon
known as sides constancy
remember
from our discussion on monday
besides distance rule
that the distance
of an object
to put all of the to the perceive ur
is eight
function actually and inverse function
of the size of the recall of the retinal
image
cast by that object on the perceive
resolve or on the project receivers
ratna and here's an example of how this
might not work
here as a lawyer in
and it's far away from the alright
and when this lawyer and as far away
from the eye it casts a relatively small
image on direct mail
here is a wine and that is come closer
to the alright if you will
and this lion cast
a march larger image on the retina
buck you don't print one of the lion
comes closer to you
you do not perceive it getting this
okay you know it's a wonderful life a
little light and over there
and what do i was a really big lie and
over here you don't do that
you perceive the lion getting closer but
you don't perceive the lion getting
bigger
size remains constant perceive size
remains constant despite
changes in the size of the retinal image
that occur as a function all of the
object
on the getting closer
so here you have an example
where proximo stimulus is changing
the size of the retinal image is
changing
but the perception is remaining constant
okay
there's a discrepancy between what the
information is
and what the perception
here is of abroad or more abstract
definition
of what these perceptual constancy czar
all about
and every case of perceptual constancy
dot pattern of proximal stimulation
changes
on in the case of sites constancy the
retinal image gets larger but the
perception of the distal stimulus
the mental representations of the distal
stimulus
remains constant the in not the case of
size constancy
the object is perceived as getting all
closer
but it's not perceived
i was getting
a larger
the nineteenth century german
psychologist
of one helmholtz
all
worried about this problem he said its
exemption
the perceptual system
is making the inferences
okay
on about the size of the distance of the
object
performing certain kinds of calculations
but you're not aware of these
calculations as you're performing them
they're being performed unconsciously
all we can really specify what these
calculations are
we know the lord me by inference
but the general idea that helmholtz had
deeply or the person who is going beyond
the information given
by making the inference
that the object is getting closer rather
than growing in size
okay bula compensating for called the
for these up for these distance cues
so here in fact is what really happens
you'll never see just a
pw or lion in the distance right
there's always some kind of background
so what happens here is that when they
are when the lion is far away might see
him walking out of a forester something
that's supposed to be a tree
on and the lion in the tree
cast
out an image of one size on the on the
road
here is the lion emerges from the forest
and comes closer to the perceive ur
v_r_ the art of retinal image of the
lion
becomes larger
the compound rison between the lion and
the tree route changes
and what's happening is the perceptual
system
is taking account of the changed
relationship
between the rebel sizable lion
and the retinal slice of the tree up
here
and the rebel sizable lion
and the rebels size of the tree here
there's a kind of calculation
that the perceptual system or performs
so now we'd see that there are
true kinds of
cubes order if you will to kinds of
information
that contribute
to the perception of constancy
the first
is
not just the rebels sizable lion you're
looking at but the rebel the size of the
rebel image of everything your looking
that the comparison of the object with
its background
will give you a true picture
of whether that's a lot and it's growing
in size
world by an that's coming mirror
and if you think about it for a second
the comparison
obvi
object with its background
those kinds of unconscious inferences
are actually consistent with the gives
sony in view
because what gives them says his that
all the information you need for
perception is provided by
the entire pattern
of stimulation
not just the stimulation the comes from
the object you look at that lion
but also the image that that those
stimulation of columns from the
background of the object
the trees and the far east
but there's also the case
and this is what's consistent with the
broder
view of things
that we know something about the size of
trees and we know something about the
size of lions
it's this world knowledge
that we have
that we apply
when we see when when the when the uh...
when the
rebelled image of the lion gets larger
we know the lions don't suddenly expand
in size
okay we know that about creatures
and so we
take that knowledge about the world
and use that to construct of perception
of the of the line as coming closer
rather than
so again
we have the rebels size story is
actually consistent with kids and
ecological view
but there's this other story
but knowledge that we have the printer
we bring to bear on the active
perception and that's consistent
with the greenery in dubai yes
well the retinal image
of the things that
org of athar are getting bigger that's
right but they but they are not getting
bigger themselves
well for one thing
you know you're moving
okay
'cause you're driving a car or you're
walking or whatever
but again
the the story is the same if you the
perceive er or in motion
okay
the without morpeth the size of the
rebel image cast by the objects that you
are approaching is going to get bigger
but did some would say work
you've got think about the rebel sides
of the object you're approaching
compared to the rebels size of all the
other raj x in the background if you
make that comparison
you don't see the object getting bigger
you see the objects getting closer
bruder would say yeah that's true
but it's also true
that we know about the size of the
trucks we meet on the highway
or when you go to pass up an
eighteen-wheeler
the eighteen-wheeler doesn't get bigger
and then get smaller and your rear-view
mirror
your own personal that's a little truck
you say
it's was close to me now it's far away
and because you know the trucks don't
change inside theater
okay so point here for the constant sees
is that there are two different kinds of
principles involved
one is
gives sony in comparison of the object
with its background
okay
the other is
bringing to bear
what you know about the world
as you construct
you are perception of the world
let me go on and give you another
example of this
here is shaped constancy
here's a door
which if it's characteristic rectangular
shape
but as the door opens
noticed that the
shape of the door
he calms
more trapezoidal
okay
parallel lines become not parallel
anymore
this line becomes longer than this line
that's even more so as the door opens of
even more
but you don't perceive the door is
changing in shape
this is shaped constancy despite changes
in the pattern on stimulation
these square sides
to these
angled sides
you don't see
the object as audited as changing in
shape
so here
we have
the first challenge
to the gives sony in view
all the information you need for
perception is provided by the stimulus
because here stimulus information is
changing at least to some extent
but the perception
is remaining
constant
here is another example
this is a white bonds
against a black background here's the
base
here's the stem here is the lip of the
blogs
but then when you look at at what else
do you see
you see some faces here is or farhad
unknowns
lips
chan neck
farhad knows
lips chin and neck
if you look at the white part you see a
vaults
if you look at a black part you see
faces
okay
this is the rueben bwz all ribbon of
baseball as figure
or invented by a guy named
but the point here is
that the pattern of stimulation
has remained constant haven't changed
anything up here okay
buck despite the fact
but the pattern of stimulation remains
calm
your perception of
the object
ten change
depending on with you look at the white
part
or you look at the black part
you see abbasi against or wapas against
a black background
or you see
blacks silhouettes against a white
background
here we begin to see
our second
major challenge
the give sony in view of perception
this is a figure known as a reversible
figure
reversible figure because the perception
will change
reverse figuring ground
you see
to quite
on kinds of
here's another example
that so-called becker cube
but i want to do is just look at it
a couple of seconds
people who were way off of the site may
not get the suspect
what's happening
yet to different parts pop out ok
sometimes
this corner any seems to be mirror
to u and escort p on on the other
occasions this quarter the seems closer
to you
then the corner eight
okay so which is nearer to you
the stimulus isn't and off
okay to provide you with this
information
it all depends on how you look at it but
again the point here is
that the pattern of stimulation is
staying constant
but the perception obvi object is
changing
this is another reversible figure
sometimes known as an ambiguous figure
because it's not at all clear
along which of these of features is home
or is in the foreground and which of
them is in the background but it's
nothing about the pattern of stimulation
that's causing perception a change okay
perception is changing despite the fact
that the stimulation is remaining
constant
this is a of the figure that you'll find
in uh... in orchard specially medieval
and byzantine art
or it's known as the ought the idea q
this is a war from the admissions son
heavier della bach
fall church in tucson arizona
that's all painted like this
it my way since both the eighteenth
century
and again what you can see here
aversion of the neck curriculum
so reply flash went off
didn't realize his coat look like that
these before
digital pictures
here's another version
this very much like the nectar cuba's
notices schroeder staircase
set of stairs
and as you look at it
you'll see that your perception of the
set of stairs
reverses
sometimes you see this wall
as closer to you
than this wall
with the spear is going up
ops okay you got sick
now you see
this wall is nearer to you but the
stairs kind of
it's kinda like the poseidon adventure
or something right
the world turned upside down
again
same thing
you can see this as a buzz that artistic
variant on the schroeder staircase
though this was painted long before
schroeder ever
came onto
here is a picture of a dim your young
woman with her head turned away from the
perceive our
here is her scarf
her hair she's got a feather your hat
here is her
over file id
her nose
hurtin
some kind of
a necklace around her
uh... around her neck
very nice picture
or if you can see i kind of a craggy
older woman
what are you here
one right here
long kind of a crooked nose
persist lips
sharp
chin
her hair
this is our cartoon that first appeared
in the british humor magazine punch
was discovered by you g boring has a
famous all psychologist now deceased
it sometimes known as my wife and my
mother in law
but again
the picture hasn't changed
that stimulation remains constant
but the perception can change depending
on how you look at it
you're either seeing are young
fairly pretty young woman turned away
from the proceed or
or you see
already somewhat
not so pretty
not so young woman
staring down
the perceive ur
stimulus remains constant
the perception
changes
here's another example of this is a
picture of a doc here is the doc speak
the dockside
the doc snack
the back of the docs head
or it's a rabbit with the rabbit ears
the rabbits on
idea lecture you get so much good
feedback right
the little rabbit smiles and so on
this picture had originally appeared in
a german humor magazine called there for
the end of the latter
which i think means low-flying blatter
but i'm not sure
in any event the american psychologist
joseph just roll picked this up
and it's now a known as the just roll
rabbit doc figure
stimulus remains constant
but the perception changes
depending on
how you look
these are again
nor does m big u_s_ figures sometimes
reversible figures sometimes are known
as by stable figures
and the important thing about them
is that the pattern of proximo
stimulation remains constant
the image cast by the object on your
radnor doesn't change at all
but the perception
changes
depending on what you focus on and how
you are identified various features on
the object where you bring we could go
beyond the information
of the provided by the stimulus
you go beyond that information
drawing on your own world knowledge of
expectations your beliefs and so on
you will see
or objects differently
only even though
the wrong
the signals remains the same
this is all going back to rubin's laws
for a second
this was a all vase produced in england
for the silver jubilee the twenty-fifth
wedding anniversary of queen elizabeth
the second earner concert prince philip
as a very nice laws
okay
all but when you you the vase who gets
the black background
what you see is
phillips
profile
and elizabeth ps
so lovely commercial adaptation of the
idea of of the reversible
when i was in college
college students everywhere had these
things on their walls
all of
posters by the swiss artist mc asher
and again what at what s your dollars of
his arch makes a lot of use of
reversible figures
you can't perceive this is painting a
day and night
you can proceed with that
words
flying to the right
or you can perceive it as
words
to the left
not enough information in the object to
tell you what's what
okay
it's how you look at it
here we have all another escher
paintings circle limit four palm
you can c
white angel's against a black background
or you can see
that's
against
a white background
again
all the information
is insufficient to tell you what it is
is that a picture of angels or is it a
picture
that's
here is a painting by salvador dali of a
market one north african market
here's a person sitting at a table with
saturn
there is some rulings hearing you're
looking out on a deal on radio log
this talk of desert
everybody see that
how about the
figure all of them
french philosopher roussel right here
with his brawl
is to always his nose his mouth
his chair and and so on
this painting is called slave i'm sarah
gardner subtle voltaire
slave market with disappearing boss told
boulter is the title of this painting
and again before their vote although
dolly use
school rebirth of all figure
all locked in his paintings that
delivers
darcy an exhibit of salvador dali
paintings
you'll see him use these by stable
figures are quite dog
okay
some again point here is dot the
stimulus is remaining constant buck
perception changes
depending on how you think about it
so stimulus remains constant the
perception changes
depending upon
what parts of the object you pay
attention to
perceive or is actively constructing the
perception
not mechanically extracting information
the all from the stimulus
in that constant sees
we have perception remaining constant
despite change in the stimulus
in the reversible figures we have
perception changing despite stability
in the stimulus
in either way we had decided ciated if
you will
perception from stimulation
we've shown
that perception
is not all or is not just a matter
of recovering
the information provided by the stimulus
here's another our class of examples
this is what's known as the miller liar
illusion
where again if your way over on the side
you may not see this quite so well
almost people c
horizontal line the top-line as longer
though it's not
okay can see that it's not
everybody can see that those two lines
are exactly the same in length
but knowing it doesn't make any
difference right there look at the
miller lawyer louis got snow looks
longer right you know it's not but it
still looks
this is known as the miller lawyer
illusion
on all of the to another example of it
here is all
uh... real a real-life example
taken from inside and outside a
commercial office building where you
have
vertical
bar here
the so-called eros
uh... and hear we have
we're looking from the inside
this vertical bar
with the
brothers and at this bar
looks longer than this one even though
you can match them up or if you worked
with a look at it on the uh...
on the course website
you can see right here
is a parallel lines
this line
and this line exactly the same exactly
the same length
but still of the look that way
okay doesn't look that way audible
here is another
version of this
this is known as the ponds old allusion
this line
the topmost line top top line
typically appears to be
longer
then at the bottom line
even though
it's not you can see that they're
exactly
the same
but again takeaway
those cues
and
length of this line jumps right back
uh... into
into the picture
what's going on here these are these
allusions
or or there are no other example of one
helmholtz called unconscious law
unconscious entrances
the upper line remember what's going on
here specially consumes pressure the
puzzle delusion you can think of these
wines
as
perspective lines
converging aligns converging
towards a uh...
towards a better she'd point in the
distance as in the
linear perspective rule
that i talked about all last time
but now if you think about these things
as receiving in on in distance
and you apply the sides distance rule
this subject
cast
and image
on the road no that's exactly the same
as this line
if you perceive
this line as farther away
because so the distance
cues provided by these
converging lines
your perceptual system will conclude
that
this line
must actually be longer
this line should be longer than this one
if this line been farther away is going
to test an image of the same size as
this line
what's happening here is
the present as if the perceptual system
go through a kind of silly prism okay
yelper wind up here as farther away
but the size of the rebel image of the
upper line is the same as the size of
the image of the lower line
therefore
a conclusion an inference therefore it
must be at the upper line is longer
than lower line and again these or
unconscious inferences
that create delusion
that one-liners longer than another when
in fact it is not
or part of the perceptual act of going
beyond the information given by the
stimulus
apply in what we know about size and
distance relations
to construct a mental representation are
percept
that is not necessarily the same as
the object we're proceeding
something very similar happens with the
miller wire allusion
you can't think of these
brothers here
as as if they are converging lines
so they provide information about
distance
okay
so
if this line
is perceived as farther away from this
line but the retinal sizes are the same
then you will conclude
that this line
must actually be bigger
than the other one mechanism behind the
miller lighter allusion
and the pollen solution
basically the same okay
the bom
perceptual system
is taking account of distance cues
to make it inferences about sides
it's not recovering information about
size from the stimulus it's making a
inference about what this law is or
flights might be
here's another example he got a really
good view of it last night
on if you were looking the right way to
the beautiful full moon
all outside and all of this is a full
moon rising over the east bay hills
there's alcatraz or island
and what you notice when you look at the
mourners arises over the hills is that
it looks huge
but then you go out later at night
and you look at the moon up
are in the senate in the middle of the
sky look at the moon and see if it
doesn't look so big
that's what this is what's known as the
moon illusion
okay
the more illusion is
but the more it on the horizon appears
to be a larger
than the moon when viewed
at zenith
it's not
okay
it's just
the moon doesn't change in size
all of those that crosses does it
crosses the skyline
but what happens is
the visual system
takes into our college
distance
information
provided by
objects on the horizon
to given impression that the mood is
very large when you look at the moon
overhead you don't have those distance
accuse any longer so you see the moon
pretty much the size
that it is so again the moon illusion
is another example
aldape fursat being created
bite unconscious inferences
by going to be on the information given
by the stimulus okay
to make things appear different from the
way they actually are
size constant things
reversible figures
now the perceptual delusions
or third-class a perceptual phenomena
that suggests
that the ecological view is not quite
right
that we do more than extract information
from the stimulus instead
we go beyond that the information given
by the stimulus
to construct
our process
here is another example has called the
ames room
there used to be one of these at the
exploratorium over in san francisco i
think they've temporarily dismantled and
now anybody been the exploratorium
lately
is the answer is still there
near until either been over there awhile
either it's a bit of next time you go
look for this thoroughly about three
ames rooms in existence now
or the end of the one of the
exploratorium is one of the better ones
here we have
true
young girls
or one who looks very tahole
and that the other one all look so looks
very short or in fact there identical
twins and their as close to the same
insides as to little kids alot and i can
get
but when you look at the moment when you
look at people in the ames room
what you will see
is something like this or one person is
seems extraordinarily
and the other of seems extraordinarily
of the small
the way this works like this
here is a about the kind of schematic
diagram beings room
when you look into the room
you have got some kind of set of
expectations about what rooms are going
to look like rooms are rectangular
okay
they have ninety degree
uh... angles of the recorders the floors
of the ceilings people balls that ninety
degree angle
the windows in the doors are rectangular
they have ninety degree angle sanam
that's what we expect rooms to look like
and when we look at the end room that's
what we expect to see
but in fact indians room your viewing he
has room through a little hole in the
wall here
and it turns out
sailing all beings room is angle dot up
in a kind of trapezoidal matter
so that this corner is way higher that
though uh...
what what what higher with respect to
the floor
than this corner is moreover
this wall is angled weight out
with respect to the absorber
so that
point here is much more distant trauma
the viewer
then this point is
the our windows are arranged in a
trapezoidal shape so that
things kind of
in a particular way and what happens is
you've got
a four-foot tall kid standing here
again stop three forty three and a half
what'll
ceiling
and you've got of four-foot tall twin
of that child
standing here
against an eight or nine foot
or highlight ceiling
giving the impression
that the one
child is very very very tall
and the other top child
it's very very small
this illusion would not work
if all we did to get our impressions of
size was too one pack the size of the
retinal image
what happens here
is that
we have expectations about what rooms
are going to look like
we have expectations about hold hold
children are and these expectations
lead our perceptions astray
leaders to perceive things differently
the way they actually are
so again indians rule
we have all lack of
the usual distance cues
there's budget very misleading stimulus
information even a floor here notices
checkerboard floor
creates kind of perspective lines in the
way that raphael lsd painting the school
of athens did
but these aren't in fact square
dave there trapezoidal as well in shape
alot to to uh... to create the solution
so there's all unconventional geometry
we don't expect it so we have we bring
to the perception on inappropriate
expectations about what things are going
to look like
so we don't compensate because of the
lack of distance cues because of the
unconventional geometry we don't engage
in our usual compensation
for differences and rebel size
and instead
the the world
in this very very strange
there's very strange way
so again
knowledge expectations and beliefs
are brought to bear are in the act of
perception
this is a contribution
from the inside their head inside the
memory of the perceive ur you will
it's not just a matter of extracting
information
from the stimulus
this aqua holds true four
certain cultural differences
in perception
here is a picture of a all-girl of a
digi a logical of formation in new
mexico it's actually on the navajo
on reservation
and it is known mostly as ship a rock
all because the early called european
settlers
looked at this
and it kind of reminded them all-day
clipper ship
with mass and sales and so on
but not a hole in the apache who lived
in this area didn't call it ship a rock
they don't know anything about clipper
ships
they call this waited rock wind rock
because it look to them
as it was kind of like a legals and
hawks wing
european settlers
with their knowledge of clipper ships
thinks is looks like a club wrote that
this looks like a clipper ship
native americans lacking that knowledge
but had a lots of knowledge of birds and
feathers think that this object looks
like o
looks like a wing
cultural differences and knowledge
expectations and beliefs
can create
cultural differences in perception
here's another example
ask you if we ask you what this is
most of you will say it's a whale
yours that's smelled
here's its fin
here's its body
here's it's tale
or you could think of it is a kangaroo
here's its
snout
and it's a year
and it's four leg
body and its little study kangaroo tail
this is known as the royal kangaroo
reversible figure
now what's the law a lot of you saw the
catcher looks like pointed out
but it turns out that if you present
this figure to australian college
students
basically kangaroo immediately
here and that an experiment we did
all be presented
the way ok grew and act what's known as
the cut on a core inflation that is the
way you'd expect to see attend guru
and demand on conical orientation hardly
ever see we hardly ever see kangaroos
like this
no matter how do you worry into the
figure everybody
north americans and australian soil the
whale and saw the whale immediately
australians
were more than twice as likely
to see the arm
to see the kangaroo
then north american students work
and that was especially the case
and when the of when the figure was
presented in the non canonical
of version and the reason for that is
that actually australian c_k_ gruza look
like this
they see dead kangaroos
they seek a dead kangaroo strong up on
fences they seek a bruise and all sorts
of weird positions goes
that's something they do with kangaroos
there
country that kills its national animal
alm
okay there are pressed for ranchers are
kinda like coyotes in this country
but the point is
australians naught off a lot more about
kangaroos the north americans do
so they're more prepared to see
kangaroos and ambiguous figures like the
way ok grew
and they're more likely to see this
figure
inaugural calling another orientations
here's another example
the constellations in these sky
the patterns of stars that we've got
that that we look at
are often
or referred to
as if they were objects of various kinds
here's our ryan the hunter with his
legs
his belt
his head
is she old
and his club
here's torres the bull
with his
head
and
the tips of his horns
if you think about it for a second
this might look a lot like a hunter but
doesn't look anything like a ball
okay
why people did what i want to look
locate stars in the sky was that i'll
write will make this one cuts kinda
sorta like a bull will call the taurus
the bull right
and people but what makes a likable and
was well what here's the warrens
and here's the space and and and so and
so forth
that kind of built up
or perception
makes
a stimulus that doesn't look very much
like a ball
into
percept that actually dogs in some sense
resemble a bull and again different
cultures
deal with the constellations in
different ways
here is the
all these on star pattern the
constellation
that most of us know s or some major the
great bearer okay
the body of the bearer
and the bears
tale
some head their does look a whole lot
like a bear but that's what we call it
we call it
the great there
in
nora and in france
that same pattern of scrawled stars
is called let castro rule
okay
or the big dipper
here is the pot and here's its handle
in medieval europe a specially in
stars in the a medieval spain
the same pattern of stars
was looked at what was the with
identified as charles why did
here is the wagon
with the axles of the wheels
and here is the yoke attached
to horace
in england the same a pattern of stars
is called aplomb
you go to that bar in berkeley the story
plot we'll see this pattern of stars
right
and it's not cold
or some major
it's called the plot no
all
some greeks and saw or heard as well as
native americans refer to this is the
great bear
but look at how different
the greek constellation is from the one
that's familiar to us now
here the beer ranges much
more
widely
than the pattern of stores itself
in china
the same pattern of stars
was perceived as celestial bureaucrats
you've got of bureaucrat
on a podium
and soem supplicants coming here to want
to talk and doesn't look anything like
that
but that's how the object was perceived
by the ancient chinese
that was the perception that they used
to guide their orientation in the sky
and then finally
into ancient egypt
precisely the same pattern stores was
recognized
and all it was perceived as
home
a_d_r_
part of a bull
and a
aboard mir
and amanda
and uh... we're in kind of hippopotamus
doesn't look anything like that
but that's how the ancient egyptians
constructed eight percent
from ambiguous stimulation in
the environment
night sky
one more demonstrations as what's this
it's a dalmatian dog ok here is the
dalmatian here's is four legs here's his
hind legs
drinking out of a puddle or something
what's this
train locomotive
steve all right
steam engine wheels here
what's best
what could this possibly
what came over for donot see these
parallel lines here and there is a
surface is going out to the back
see what you're doing is
you're trying to figure out walk could
this possibly be what do i know when the
world that looks like this
the stimulation itself is very ambiguous
but when you start thinking about it for
a while
you begin to perceive what the object is
perception that is intelligent activity
it's not just a matter of mechanically
extracting information from the stimulus
out in the environment
rather the perceive our has to actively
engage in problem solving activity
bringing his or her knowledge
expectations and beliefs to bear on the
problem of
figuring out
what the objects on the world are
where they are what they're doing
what we can do with them
that's the intelligence of perception
and that is the general thrust
on the constructivist view
thank you very much
you will be meeting with a genocides on
monday