okay we're going to be general lectures
today on the biological basis of mental
life
psychology was to find out the very
beginning of the existence of the
science by william james
as the science of employees as i
described last time james argue dot the
whole purpose of psychology
is to try to understand the cognitive
emotional and motivational process these
that underlie human experience
thought and action
but because the brain is the physical
basis of the morning
the bribe the mind is what the brain
does
james began his
offense treatise on psychology with a
discussion of brain function
setting a precedent and followed almost
universally in introductory courses for
the next more than a century of begin in
the course
with some discussion wild the biological
basis
all of the of the month
the story of the mind
includes the study of mind and body
and that means to study
now the nervous system is a biological
structure and as you remember a from
your high school biology
biological structures are hierarchically
organized
we began had to sell level which your
remember is the
through all smallest most elementary
piece of living matter
that can live independently
cells
groups are related sales combined to
form tissues
groups of related tissues combine to
form oregon's
groups of related oregon's combined to
form systems
and there are a whole bunch of different
systems
that make up the individual
human organism
for humans and most other animals as
well there are a bunch of different
systems in the body the nervous system
is only one of them
there's the endocrine system in the
musculoskeletal system and the
respiratory system and all of that
were going to be conference learn
archimedes lectures
the nervous system pretty exclusively
but as the over text book makes clear
there are ordered that the nervous
system is connected to all other systems
fortier
and are particularly interested in are
the connections between the nervous
system on the one hand
and the immune and the endocrine systems
on the of on the other hand
okay sold under our system is one such
system
and as a biological system it truly is
higher record hierarchically organized
at these fellows level
we have these structures known as no
runs
nor under the elementary structures in
at the nervous system
then we have groups of neurones combined
in the tissue level
tecum to formal somewhat larger
structures
known as nerves
and again leo and nuclei all describe
those a little bit more in a moment
then bunches of nerves and ganglia and
nuclei
format the oregon level
the major structures of the nervous
system
the brain the spinal cord
and at the brainstem
and that the system level it turns out
that there are
not does not just one nervous system
but there are several different nervous
systems the nervous system itself
is hierarchically organized
we can distinguish at the outset
between the central nervous system which
consists of the brain and the spinal
cord
and indeed peripheral nervous system
which consists of all to other nervous
systems
known as the semantic nervous system
and the autonomic nervous system
basically the peripheral nervous system
although that part of a system that
connects too
central
owner of a system
and then all of this staff
these that these different aspects of
the nervous system combined with the
other
all bottling systems
to create
the organism
as the individual
so here's one of your on looks like this
is a schematic diagram of under on perot
wants a different kinds of iran's
becoming somewhat different shapes and
sizes
but they all have the same kinds of
uh... of structures associated with them
there is a cell body
these structures known as dendrites
branching out from the cell body
then there is a warning of
filament like
on tax ein
and then the acts on and said what are
known as terminal endings
which preval look like that and rights
i'll let you know in reverse
neurons com in three basic types
there are first
afa renewal ron's
which although process sensory
information
basically carrying neural impulses
from the sensory receptors in the
twilight ear without
bono's are the are your whatever
in toward the central nervous system
then there are different
no-refunds
which carry
motor impulses out from the central
nervous system
to the effector organs of the body like
the muscles in the tendons and the
internal organs and so on
and then that there are interneurons
which comprise
the central nervous system
a large parts of the spinal cord
or and the brain and the brain stem
well here in africa ron
handling sensory functions
and eastern or on penalty motor
functions
or an internal ron running between the
africa the free world
art this is the basic structure all
neurons look-alike
from this point of view
a cell body with dendrites branching off
and acts on connecting to
terminal
uh... terminal fibers
as far as behaviorist concern
the smallest unit in the nervous system
is what's known as the reflex arc the
reflex arc is kind of an abstract term
there isn't actually such a thing in the
nervous system
but you get the idea of when you
understand you consider that the reflex
arc
concerns arvo
one aspirin or on
processing
sensory activities processing sensation
one different
nor on processing
bodily responses
and one intern or on
connecting
the effort nor on with the e for immoral
reflex arc you'll see an application of
this
or in a in a larger of the scale in a
couple of minutes
all but basically
what the reflex arc dawes is to mediate
the organisms motor response
to an environmental stimulus
to pick up
through the censoring or on the after a
new rod
information about what's going on in the
environment
process in through the internal run
connected to the different know ron
are generates some kind of response
to that
environmental event
and it turns out that the larger
structures in the nervous system
are composed of all
variously
afferent
different and injure neurons
so all the nerves
the nerves in your arms and your all
legs and and elsewhere
or composed although bathrooms andy for
nora stats with nerves are made out of
and then we have these are structures
known as dangling ella and nuclei
which are composed of
interneurons
okay more central ought to shoe the
distinction which
i don't think i've ever held anybody
responsible for but you will see these
terms in the literature
dangling out the term ganglia generally
refers to
all clusters of internal runs
that reside outside of the brain
and the spinal cord
whereas nuclei refer to of clusters of
interneurons the reside inside the brain
and spinal cord
the basic level of the nervous system
three kinds of no runs afferent neurons
processing sensory information
if ur in or on the processing motor
information
interneurons connecting the two
the three
types of neurons together comprising
the reflex arc which processed these ons
response to an environmental stimulus
and then put the tissue levels
you have nervous composed of africa
reefer and a runs nuclei and ganglia
composed of avenger morons
so now let's move up one level
from the tissue level closer to the
order level
and what got the major divisions of the
nervous system
i've already introduced this to you
alcohol uh... in an earlier slide but
just to repeat myself the major division
the nervous system is between the
central nervous system on the one hand
and the peripheral nervous system on the
other hand
the central nervous system consisting of
the brain
the spinal cord and the brain stem which
connects them
the peripheral nervous system consisting
of
subordinate nervous systems
the simatic nervous system
which runs
between the central nervous system
and the sensory receptors
in the year the nose and throat the eye
and also inferno runs
that broad
the muscles and pendants in the in the
body
and then finally
there is an automatically nervous system
which connects the central nervous
system
to the internal organs compo controls
the functioning of
the heart belongs and all other kinds of
organs
you couldn't turn down like down a
little bit if you want
or not
so now let's work on the autonomic
nervous system and see how cats
organized
you're going to get a picture here of
what we think this is hierarchical
organizations that are ninth agree
because it turns out
that there are two components to the
autonomic nervous system
the sympathetic nervous system
is that part of the autonomic nervous
system
organizes the body to me to email
urgency when a stressful event occurs
when a surprising event occurs when
anything unexpected occurs
what happens is that the sympathetic
nervous system
kicks in
octopodes enable the organism
to deal with whatever
is going on
first the sympathetic nervous system
on mediates what's known as the flight
or fight
response
usually especially if you're a little
animal wondered arrival mht
all what you're trying to do is either
defend your territory against all other
alleles of your species or you're trying
to prevent yourself from being eaten by
big around al's of another species and
to be all the sympathetic nervous system
on mediates that flight or flight
response
all that's a classic are terms but in
the literature since nineteen teens
more recently rediscovered
another emergency response that's
mediated by the sympathetic nervous
system
which is what's known as tandem and be
friend
or some all-female in some organisms
it's the email displease she's
that prepares for flight or fight
female the species
tends to engage in what's called tended
to be friend in behavior
looking to the young
all or providing all support
all four of the other ralph we're going
around and again that's a disarm worlds
the sex difference
or that you find in psalm
arkansas mammalian species
all but whether you're male or female
all gault rap or most or a cat or dog
species
the sympathetic nervous system
all also has the function
of generating of national ozell
and it does that by stimulating
the flow of aid hormone adrenaline
through the blood stream
through the various auto internal organs
although sympathetic arousal
all helps the organism either margin
sees but it also produces all of the or
arousal of the various emotions and the
through the release of another hormone
nor adrenaline releases shorter stored
all barley sugars
into the bloodstream
and of course those bottles of blood
sugars go right to the muscles
and enable the organism
to engage in
flavor flight
tend to be friend
affectively
also
some of the last thing the sympathetic
nervous system does work activated
is to reach shuttle the flow of the
blood
away from the surface of the body
towards the internal organs
and that has the effect or palm uh...
reducing
blood loss
incase your wounded
case you don't make it in the
flight or floyd uh... response
all-black
there is sudden visits as sympathetic
branch of the all oregon it never system
that does all these things
basically all engaging an emotional
roles all
and all of their risk behaviors
that allow the organism to meet
emergencies
parasympathetic nervous system
by contrast
basically is engaged in
palm org
mediating vegetative functions of
various kinds
if the parasympathetic nervous system
that handles things like
digestion of food
the elimination
of waste
reproductive behaviors
and so on
sympathetic
nervous system
emotional arousal
flight or fight
tend to be friend
parasympathetic nervous system hall of
basically mediates
vegetative functions of the body
that's not quite cold there is to it
however
because it turns out
that the parasympathetic nervous system
is also involved in the organisms
response to
stress ors response to emergencies
but the all parasympathetic nervous
system
only comes into play in emergencies
in response
to are arousal off the sympathetic
nervous system
it turns out
that when the organism reacts to stress
the parasympathetic and the sympathetic
nervous systems
activex kind of antagonistic matter
they basically poll the organism
enough opposite on directions
so for example
let's look at called sympathetic
activity
when your
oh when your own exposed to some kind of
stress or
the sympathetic nervous system
dilated pupils of the i_r_a_ inhibits
tearing
inhibits elevation when you're nervous
your rice chem wipe your mouth gets dry
arlene inhibit stomach and contractions
or relaxes the bladder
really get nervous you might wet
yourself
although inhibits off at the general
russians and so on
but look what parasympathetic style
system does when the sympathetic nervous
system is diluting the peoples of the
ali
the parasympathetic nervous system is
constricting
the pupils of the airline
when the sympathetic nervous system is
inhibiting the salvation
the parasympathetic of the system
is is on stimulating or the celebration
so what happens here
when you are stressed when you're all
when you would counter some stressful
event in the environment
the first thing that happens
is at the sympathetic nervous system
kicks in and it does all these things at
once at acs ads a unit
without every rapid onset comes on very
quickly
and
also has a very rapid offset
if you're almost
running across the field
and you see the shuttle hawk you're
sympathetic nervous system kicks in to
enable you know it will run from the
hawker whatever
as soon as the hawk is out of sight or
whatever what happens is that the
sympathetic nervous system turns itself
off the very fast okay
but what happens is all the sympathetic
nervous system or activity
tend be friend really seen store blood
sugars all that stuff
deeply bodily resources
and so you've got to have some system
that will act to restore those resources
for the next emerg emergency the comes
around
and that's what the parasympathetic
nervous system
does
in response to or
in environmental stress or
parasympathetic nervous system
on discrete pieces of the body at once
it acts discriminative lee
all the where it's really needed
moreover
parasympathetic nervous system
has a relatively slow onset
the sympathetic nervous system has to
kick in immediately or you're gonna get
eaten
okay
but it's going to take you would want to
come to consume those partly resources
so the sympathetic nervous system
doesn't have to act so fast
moreover once the emergency is passed
you have to do anything okay
but sympathetic paris embedded nervous
system
has to continue to work for a while
to restore the bodily resources that
were depleted when you were a meeting of
what when you were a lot of the meeting
the of the emergency
so what happens is when is the stressful
event
and walking across campus on guerrilla
jumps out of the bushes or something
your sympathetic nervous system kicks
off
of the media rate
okay and as your running away from the
guerilla in a paris a bit nervous system
will start working little bit
then when your off ordered safe from the
animal
on your sympathetic nervous system trent
itself all pretty quickly
but the parasympathetic nervous system
keeps going for a while to get those
partly resources resources of blood
sugars and all that other stuff
all going on going together
and that's why for example
when the your
exposed to some kind of acute stress or
when the stress or goes away sometimes
you feel like you crashed a little bit
right well that's because
as the sympathetic nervous system is
trying to wind you up
okay the parasympathetic nervous system
is trying to want to go
the antagonistic
all or interplay of the sympathetic and
parasympathetic
dawn nervous systems for example
all the accounts for
funny are dynamics of addiction
okay where
all if you would call it
ingested it uh... you know
an addictive drug
may feel good for a while but then when
the drug wears off you don't just go
back to normal you crash
okay the crash
crashes mediated
by the continue with activity of the
parasympathetic nervous system
so that's what i have to say it right
now about the autonomic nervous system
basis two functions
ald prepare alag mediating the organisms
response the stress
and also mediating various kinds of
educator functions
any questions about your nervous system
okay remember if you have questions
about lectures are reading at any time
you can always post them
the court's website
and all will and don't get to the
okay so that's the on the other part of
a system
let's look at these american nervous
system
which consists of
the nerves
that run to nerves are run children from
the brain and the spinal cord
in fact there are
of thirty one spinal nerves
so-called because they emanate from a
the spinal cord these are all spinal
nerves
on here
and then there are twelve cranial nerves
so-called
because today of emanate from the brain
or do you know
or the brainstem
or
here is the biggest verbal talk about
that made it
on which actually comes out of the brain
stem the goes into the trunk
of the body
but that's basically what the somatic
nervous system all looks like
those two major divisions
the cranial nerves
and the spinal nerves
the cranial nerves are highly
specialized structures
they're highly specialized in terms of
the functions
they perform
there are some all cranial nerves
that are exclusively aspirin
in nature
that is they are devoted
to processing sensory impulses arising
from various sensory receptors and
taking them
toward the central nervous system
so for example you've got
alm cranial nerve one the so-called
olfactory nerve
that runs
from but knowles
essentially from the nose into the brain
and mediates the sense of smell
cranial nerve to the optic nerve
runs from the retinas of the eyes to the
brain
and mediates the sense of vision
so some of the cranial nerves these are
just two examples
are exclusively aspirins in nature
in that day
mediate
only sensory
or impulses
by the same token there are some nerves
that are exclusively different in nature
which is to say
that there on the other point started
they control motorists motor behaviors
of various role in various ways
here's one cranial nerve three the
ocular motor on her all moves the
audience
when you move your eyes back-and-forth
up-and-down
so on all that's or being done by the
ocular motor ger
here's another one
or cranial nerve twelve the
hypoglycaemia her
which has the of function of moving the
tongue
so when you talk when you eat
when you do some other stuff
you do it by virtue of the of the hype a
colossal mirror
and then finally just to make things a
little confusing
there are some cranial nerves
are mixed in nature because they combine
afarensis andy friend functions
so brady on the reply
the tribe general mirror mediates the
sense of touch
around
the face and the aural cavity
also that that it's afrin function
but it's different for sure
is to mediate
chilling activity when you chew on your
food
all you're doing it by virtue of home
at the french impulse is being carried
by the tried jumble more
here's another one
hooked on cranial nerves seven the
facial nerve it's afrin function
is to mediate the sense of taste
for connects the
taste buds and other receptors in the
tongue
home
to the brain
so that you could taste your food
and then
facial bone facial nerve
all seven as a different nerve
all mediates the movement of the phrase
when you smile
when you for our when you start or what
you do what you do with your face
all you do it by virtue of
the you foreign
aspect of the ill of the cranial nerve
so again these cranial nerves are highly
specialized
some are exclusively afferent in nature
summer exclusively you for into major
and all others are mixed
body contrast
the spinal nerves all combine
afferent
and evil and
sensory
and motor
are here is a all schematic diagram of
on nerve of spinal nerve connecting to
beall the spinal cord
and most of you can probably see this
there are in fact
roots
of this spinal nerve
one route carrying sensory information
from the receptors from the center
receptors in towards his spinal cord and
there is another route
that is carrying
different motor information
onto dude to generate a motor response
all contacted that's the eastwind
all of the year old of the spine
although the splendor
all basically that's the idea date each
of these idle nerves combine offering
two different functions
running along
branches and different
pathways
here are the thirty one spinal nerves
you don't have to memorize this this is
in the human anatomy course but i do
want you to have some sense of what the
nervous system all of the looks like
and one of the things you should note is
is that
their is a regular association
between a part of the body
that is served by a spinal nerve
and whereabouts biomarker next to the
spinal cord
so what here
you have the cervical division
the spinal cord which basically all
hands on
fallout
own nerves there right now to the arms
and hands and the
and the fingers ok up here
then there's the forensic division
all which told the spinal nerves busy
running to the internal organs of the
body
and then down here at the lombard sacral
division
and all of the uh...
on that the others
carry the nerves that operate the legs
and beyond and defeat
okay so first
there's a regular association
between
the part of the body third by a spinal
nerve
and where it connects to a to the spinal
cord
the author interesting feature of the
spinal nerves
is that there is a kind of
proportional representation
there are more spinal mirrors devoted
to those parts of the body
they either need to acute censoring
function
over
fine motor control
so you've got lots of mirrors
that run to the arms in the hands and
the fingers
and you've got
lots of mirrors that run to the legs and
defeat as opposed
all of but not so many that run too
beyond
to the trunk of the chest cavity of the
body
more nerves
where you need either fine sensitivity
flying tactile sensitivity
flying of fine motor
and so that's basically
how that is organized will come back to
this and uh... you know
in a second
uh... fit this except to say
all
there are
within the spinal cord itself
several different tracks
these are they've been read here and
what are known as the a's sending
tracked of the nervous system above the
spinal cord as carrying
after rent impulses
upto spinal cord to the brain
denim blue here we have the descending
tracts of the power in the spinal cord
caring even friend impulses
down okay that's what's called
descending and out to the motor all
parts and then the rest of this
basically is
all of the association tissue
on this is a these are essentially
composed of africa ron's distract
these distract composed mostly of you
for an iran's
these tracks
composed essentially volvo
of the internet
so what happens here is at the spinal
cord ok is where the brain connects with
the rest of the body where mess where
the the brain
prostheses
tactile sensations what you're feeling
what you're talking and also generates
the motions
of the legs of the arms in the hands and
the and the nerves
let's look for a second the implications
of some of this
for what happens when somebody's suffers
a break in the spinal cord
that the spinal cord
is carrying african polls is off to the
brain and it's carrying you've rented
impulses down from the brain
weapon there's a break in the spinal
cord
those impulses stop
there's no way for them to get across
break in the spinal cord
so that when people suffer a break in
the spinal cord
date paul manifesting neurological
syndrome
that is known as parallel major
paraplegia
which involves
both all also sensory function and all
lost of voluntary
of movement
so if there is a
breaking the spinal cord
here somewhere in the parece activision
the person will be able to
feel things with his or her hands
and move his or her hands because my
hands are mu are or or controlled
body on
spinal nerves are above the break
the person will be paralyzed
fog with respect to
the legs and defeat and the toes
and we'll also have
no tactile
sensation
from that part of the body
all what happens ok when you're when
you're flannel cord is broken why don't
you just
died
the reason for that is
see this vegas nerve that i pointed out
before
that's cranial nerve
art and that is very very very high up
and it's the biggest nerve that
different keeps
of the heart our and other
essential baat
vital functions on going
when somebody aqua suffers from
paraplegia they lose sensation from the
affected part of the body that is the
part of the body that is below the break
in the spinal cord
they also lose
voluntary motion ma movement
are from of the in areas below the break
in the spinal cord
but they do not lose
all
bathrooms any further processing
even in cases of paraplegia up
you can see maintained
some stimulus response connections
and he's the most response connections
or known as the spiral reflexes
and they're known as a spinal reflexes
because they are processed solely act
all level of the spinal cord itself
you'll you'll lead
we think about
all the pactel
stalled but
of the touch sensation
coming up the legs going up the spinal
cord to the brain the brain generate a
motor responsibilites down the spinal
cord and out the thrown out the spinal
nerves
that's true for voluntary motor
activities
but there are certain involuntary motor
responses all reflex responses that are
process
solely at the level of the spinal cord
one of these is the so-called patellar
reflex
probably all of you of experienced in
the doctor's office
you tap the patellar tendon
your get a little
jerk reflex colognes on here
that is alle
common all part of our
neurological uh... diagnostic test
and that's
dot maintain remains intact
in paraplegic of patience
but these vinyl ulm reflexes
have certified interesting properties
the first is
that's why uh... reflexes in
cases of spinal cord injury
tend to be exaggerated
they tend to be stronger then the spinal
reflexes in individuals with an intact
spinal cord
it's as if
da brain is sending signals down the
spinal cord that modulate or dampen the
activity of the spinal reflexes
when the brain can no longer communicate
with that part of a spinal cord
spinal cord
zala the spinal cords left with soem
devices
it it gives i more exaggerated
uh... response
another characteristic of the spinal
reflexes is that they are unconscious
because they are processed slowly at the
level of the spinal cord
nothing about this activity reaches
the brain which is the seat of
consciousness
a person will not
no that he or she is engaging
in the
paraplegic individual won't be directly
aware that he he or she is giving one of
the spinal reflexes so if you had a home
offers for the spinal cord injury
and you blindfolded and so they couldn't
see what you're doing
tap their patellar tendon they give the
patellar reflex
but they would neither feel the tap
nor would they be aware
all their all of their legs moving
so all of these final reflexes are
exaggerated
they're unconscious
and they are also
involuntary
with my impact spinal cord level are not
going to give the patellar reflex i'm
not going to do and i'm not going to do
it so you couldn't do it
got some voluntary control over this
thing
but when there's a break in the spinal
cord that voluntary controls lost cassie
inhibitory messages
can't get down spinal cord
moreover
here are not happy my patellar tendon
moving my leg just fine
can't do that
in case of paraplegia because that
requires
a signal that submission dated in the
brain
to go down the spinal cord
and it just can't
too
to the centers
so basically that's the story with
respect to
the also matic nervous system
and its branches cranial nerves
and at the spinal nerves
anne questions what that gap
hemi pleaser is not usually caused by a
break in the spinal cord
henny please show up to him at least of
my knowledge all stand corrected over
here in a second
heritage is usually something you see in
cases of stroke
where a person has had a vascular
insufficiency the blood supply to the
brains been cut off
and some part of the brain has basically
destroyed
and what happens is in many cases of
stroke
all of that vascular insufficiency
affects only one
part of the brain or another
and we're going to discuss this today
we're going to discuss that next
wednesday
but although there is a principle of
well nervous system organization
con trolled lateral projection
contra
lateral okay
other side projection
and to make a long story short
you're left cerebral hemisphere
controls the right side of your body
you're right cerebral hemisphere
controls the left side of your body
so
if u had a stroke
that is damaged certain centers in your
left hemisphere
you'll lose
some functions
did the right side of the body but not
on the left side of the body so you'll
have weakness
all everybody by watchdog what the
senator tim johnson last night on the
news
dave i watch the news
they gotta watch the news ok all gotta
watch law-and-order reruns but you've
also got to watch the news
of
some of you may remembered that dog
senator tim johnson oliver north dakota
upto
eight months ago
suffered a brain hemorrhage not a stroke
exactly but something like a stroke
all and what happened was that on that
dawn
stroke affected hit the lovely brain
hemorrhage with localized in his left
cerebral hemisphere
alm and what it did was to basically
wipeout
on his orbs on
person three
pactel and motor functions on the right
side
uh... but also going to talk about this
later on to language functions tend to
be localized in the left's ribble
hemisphere so we lost the ability to
speak
after eight months of intensive
rehabilitation those of you saw the news
last night
sort of senator johnson
speaks okay
he's not going to give all bigsby
trouble for the senate anytime soon but
he could communicate
alm
but called that as the you know if the
problem
tim johnson the or a_b_c_ medical
consultant in such a group of uh...
c_n_n_ medical consultant pointed out he
has a lot of weakness on his right side
argued
use the wheelchair he could get up
but he's very weakened his right side
com that's kind of a heavy preacher
it's because the damage was in the left
part of the spring
dancer
sometimes i give you more about answer
than you watch okay
and if it's ok it's okay if it's
fraud or race or at mir something of
anything else about purple yes something
back here
august painter phantom limb pain
that's really complicated
located
it's true actually i know the answer
this
all but it's too complicated for me to
do in the late in the eleven minutes
that are left in fact them only got
about three minutes left we're going to
do it in on smith
would you post that just as a reminder
to me pose that question on the forum in
the course website
and i'll give you know
of very
clear answer
all i had something else down here
ya the eastern or on czar for all
intents and purposes connected the
muscles
in the same way that the aspirin or ons
are connected to
center receptors like
the retina b_r_t_ and the year and all
of that
palm so yes he's right
breweries in the form of his work the
way they do is to say
connected well falls
the reason the africa runs work the way
they do
is that they pick up
the probate uk ferry
sensory impulses that arise in the
center receptors in the bottom
medical on up
i'll take another question to win will
you have
it all depends on the extent of the
damage
you could have
they injury to the spinal cord
okay
that doesn't actually destroyed tissue
there there's some capacity for nervous
sought that nervous tissue to recover
function
or you can have a bruise or something
and apple
double temporarily all all result of
that kind of loss of function we're
talking here
about
they kat in the spinal cord not an
injury
although there are exceptions i talk
about this a little bit the lecture
supplement that glavin talks about a
little bit in his chapter three
for all intents and purposes central
nervous system damage is permanent
gone forever
okay
where your helmets
where here
shoulder pads
and on don't jump into anything you
don't know what's underneath you