okay let's move into our last set of
actual lectures
the past weeks
we've been speaking mostly about mental
structures and processes that underlying
normal experience thought an action the
kinds of things that
ordinary people experience
in the ordinary course of everyday
living
we've had occasional
all
reference to mental illness various
forms of brain damage and so on
but what we want to do with this set of
lectures is to examine mental illness it
its own right
to try to figure out
but the nature of his own abnormal mala
dept of behavior
the abnormal mental structures and
processes that
that underlie it
and the kinds of interventions that we
have
that we can
art that we can use to treat and to
prevent on mental illness
it turns out however that
it's not seek to define mental illness
or psychopathology in the abstract
all but the best we can do is to begin
albright analogy to the notion of
pathology in
term psychopathology is actually derived
from the great
first of course
the term psychic psyche psycho
along periphery dust storm behind a new
ends in modern scientific psychology
referring to mental processes and
activities ok and then there's pathology
all again from the greek
had to do with deviations from mahal
from normality
if you think about medical
illnesses for a moment
cancer
heart disease or whatever
but you ought to have in every case
it is either
deviation from merrimack anatomical
structure
or band is broken off partisan built
right along the stone work right
there are deviations from normal
physiology there's some substance
running through the blind risks on the
cell process that's
all that's good that that's going all
right
so that's what
medical pathology looks like
and then we think about psychopathology
armed again we're going to look at
deviations fred look normal
mental structure and function
but again trying to figure out exactly
what means what's meant by
normality
turns out to be not as easy in the case
of psychopathology
as it is in the case of medical
pathology
in general
when you ask people to define power to
describe what they mean by
normal mental life for normal behavior
you'll get almost of definitions of
looks pretty much like this
which you can think of as a kind of
conceptual prototype of psychological
abhorred psychological normality
in the first place we generally think up
psychologically mammal people
as having
what you think of it accurate any
ficient mental function
to put up a loudly
armed
mag lev people pretty much see the
rabbit
and don't have to wind dot don't have to
go to too much trouble
to do that it's all
accurate
and it's efficient
similarly in the air national realm
normal individuals have minimal
all
or national reactions
diverse kinds of events
in the motivational realm
their desires their goals are more or
less or or reasonable are given their
circumstances
so that's what we mean by accurate and
efficient mental function
basically reminders working the way for
us to work and doesn't have to work too
hard at it
by self awareness
well usually mean that an individual is
over
ordered his or her beliefs
and desires and feelings or has some
awareness
of what his or her
also or sudden awareness of wat
his or her impact is our mother our
people
on process control
you generally think of also controls had
to do with
of the individual's ability to in do
things like
gratification
tolerate frustration make plans and
follow-through on them
by self esteem we generally refer to
apartheid person feels about him or
herself
psychologically normal people
usually feel
had about themselves whatever time
sometimes you look at america's a follow
your heart level person
that now's the time
it's a show right you know it's like
that going on saturday night live
fallen
and uh... sexual relations based on
affection
that is on some kind of positive feeling
for the people
with whom you're in iraq and we're not
just talk about the friends and
girlfriends here
we're talking about
passes and subordinates neighbors and
all of that kind of thing
onslaught relations based on a faction
as opposed to social relations based on
manipulation or art competition or
whatever
and then finally we generally think are
psychologically normal people
as latino less productive lives
being able to lobby metalworking able
make a living in being able to do areas
kinds of things
and
are having some degree of creativity and
their lives as well
now by creativity we don't mean you have
to be our stravinsky or a beethoven or
out
or a picasso or something like that
devising a new way to know
organizer shopping list
are coming up with a new plays are not
in their in soccer or something like
that
is of the day is an example of kind of
everyday on everyday creativity
as divides and i think i've just
indicated
it's not so easy to the following these
subordinate features of normality either
but when you start talking about
normality you begin to get people
talking all on all of these lines
and if you're going to define
psychopathology as deviance threaten
mental abnormality
once you've got some sense of what you
mean bag normality
the next thing you have to do
is to figure out what it is that you
mean by
deviants
and now it turns out
not to be so easy
so for example
we can think about deviance
in statistical terms ok applying the
what is sometimes flat out as the
frequency criterion offer deviants
and basically what we say here is
everybody is too far from the average
we're going to look at it as
statistically deviant
if your state to smell into standard
deviations of barbara below the average
for some kind of all of the ban on some
kind of quality
we're going to think about all of you as
home as being
psychologically abnormal in that respect
and of course
abnormality or have to be statistically
infrequent ok abnormalities
statistically frequent
that it's not clear what abnormality
means of anymore but they do have this
problem with an application of
statistical norms all word which is let
me go to a positive about positive
deviations
think about
are measured intelligence so-called i_q_
for a second
all we define individuals who are
mentally retarded
as those
who were all that have
i_q_ scores more than two standard
deviations below the mean
mean as one hundred on the work for
adult intelligence kale
got a standard deviation of fifteen
so people don't like use less than
seventy
we begin to think about as falling into
a category of mental illness known as
mental retardation
but the asians co-op
as well as die alone
if you have an i_q_ to standard
deviations above the mean that is a blow
up about one thirty
we have a special label for that cold
genius organiser technical definition
of a genius somebody who's like he was
above hundred and thirty
home
all part
it's not clear but you want to classify
geniuses as mentally ill
just because strike you scores are
statistically infrequent just because
they
deviate from normality
or the and and and and some statistical
way
alm yes you can define solved although
psychological deviant statistically in
terms of
infrequent
uh... would have been infrequent
characteristics
but you have to deal with the problem
of positive deviations
similarly
you can define psychological deviance in
terms of departures
from social norms
all in the trade this is called applying
a compliance criterium
the the definition of psychological
deviance
and the idea here is
that normal people ought to be able to
comply with prevailing social
norms on him but
people who are psychologically abnormal
either can't do that or have a lot of
difficulty doing that or don't want to
do it all oral or whatever
and again we would expect the people who
are psychologically normal
have the ability to confirming their
behavior
to altered to prevailing on norms
off but there are good their apartment
at some additional problems that come up
when we try to reply you
all of this compliance criterion
to the diagnosis of mental illness but
first of these is that there's a
tremendous amount of variance across
cultures
in terms of what is considered
appropriate behavior
if u greed somebody in the fall european
culture
the manuel negative gradient somebody is
different but if you greet some body in
certain middle eastern cultures of for
example do things in the middle east but
you wouldn't do in the netherlands
and you do things and netherlands but
you wouldn't think about doing
all it in the uh... in the middle east
all work for that matter charter japan
or or or anyplace else about picking on
any particular
they're real the world here
that's just a lot of areas across
cultures
so or dot loggers that that creates a
problem with some with all
of the
compliance criterion
whose culture are you going to reference
the compliance to almost over
but there's also a variance involved in
northbrook
social norms
across time within cultures i think the
probably the clearest example
all of this with respect to our mental
illness
is homosexuality
when i was undergraduate for that matter
when i was a graduate student which is
not all that many years ago
on nineteen seventy to nineteen seventy
five
for the first couple of years in net dot
in that period
homosexuality was defined as a mental
illness
you could go to
the diagnostic and statistical manual of
the american psychiatric association
and find homosexuality all in their on
has a uh... at as a form of
psychopathology
but in nineteen seventy three the
american psychiatric association changed
its mind
literally took a vote
all of the association
and decided that homosexuality wasn't
going to be quite policy trolley per se
wasn't going to be classified as a
mental illness any longer
and they did that because the culture
had changed and it was very clear
that there were lots of bhargava lesbian
people out there who were perfectly
normal in all respects except for their
sexual orientation
and just because
boys like boys and girls like girls was
no reason to classify that as a mental
illness on any longer
but that's not true and other cultures
okay
all again homosexuality may be something
that is abnormal in some cultures
not in or others
it's with within a particular culture
abnormal at one time not and all other
or not it another time
warner perhaps the most difficult lol
dramatic example of how you can simply
blindly apply a compliance criterium
onto our deviation from social norms to
determine who is mentally ill and who
all isn't
our third criterion that people try to
use to the following the park without
the psychopathology or mental illness
there's a criterion all personal
distress
it's a subjective criteria it's the kind
of criteria that you would counter
when somebody goes to a psychotherapist
and says
on dr
i'm realtime really depressed
and i don't want to be depressed
well i'm really anxious and i don't want
to be anxious
on help me
arguably a pillar give me some
psychotherapy or figure out what all the
help me figure out what's wrong
alter onto one
to will
or did you get this thing
and it's true
that most people are this mentally ill
people are distressed by their mental
illness
in the same way that most
physically ill people are distressed or
by their illness
but it's not necessarily are the case
again in psychopathology
we'd rather station between
true different kinds of
pathologies or two different kinds of
symptoms
ego symphonic symptoms
and you go to stunning symptoms eagle
simply refers to the self here
indigo symphonic symptoms
thematic the malad active behavior or
the malad active thought pattern or
whatever
is perceived by the person
as a normal part of his or her
personality
here she isn't
at owners everybody else
but it doesn't bother the person who
has the other those who has the problem
all whereas ego to stomach symptoms
are the kind of i was talking about
before
or a person says
are more depressed than i ought to be
on more anxious than i ought to be are
not thinking clearly any longer or or or
whatever
egos despotic symptoms
bother the individual who has these
particular symptoms
armed
personal distress park right although
the criterion for a psychological
deviance
so long as you're dealing with a goat
historic symptoms like a anxiety and
depression but they may not work they
will not work
or when the person displays ego
symphonic all symptoms
or
alone
deep
the symptom itself
person perceives as part of his or her
own
or personality
they could be a roommate for a second
your roommates got something that just
others that have a lot to you
and he thinks it's flying
he said don't do that anymore so what do
you think would be this is fine that's
the kind of
deaf distinction we have between the ego
symphonic and ego despotic symptoms
and then finally but we try to along
try to define psychological deviance
we often apply a criterion of now
adopted in this or harmful knows
the persons
mental illness
very often will lead him her to be haven
such a way
that is harmful
to him or herself
or to what other people or at least
increases the risk
of harm
part of the person himself or of or to
others
and again
often
ul
then behavioral problems that stem
from of the from mental illness
that are harmful to sell for others were
these potentially also
for example some people who are very
depressed maybe at increased risk for
suicide that summer is obviously harmful
alot to to self but you wouldn't want to
have harmful must be
amin necessary criterion for mental
illness
because they're all sorts of behavior
the harmful to other people
that we don't necessarily want equality
classify
as forms of mental illness
all sorts of criminal behavior
is harmful to other people
but it's not necessarily the case
all all criminal behavior
is a product of mental illness
in fact we have a special category four
all
met criminal behavior that is the
product of mental illness called the
insanity defense
which are succeeds only about one out of
every thousand attends right
solo in society
we're not prepared to ascribe all
criminal behavior to mental illness
but we do sometimes excuse
some criminal behavior
on grounds that the person although it
is mentally ill
so it turns out
that in the same way that defining
psychological normality is in fact evi
defining deviance from psychological
normality
isn't so evi either
in the same way
features are normality that i talked
about before
self esteem and self control and
self-awareness and accurate and
efficient ulm
or processing the oval although of
reality
they form a kind of conceptual prototype
that psychologically normal people u
kind of like that
similarly
psychologically deviant people what
kinda like this
okay
they tend to deviate from saw
statistical lauren so they don't
necessarily
argue that
they tend to deviate from social norms
though not necessarily
they tend to experience
personal distress about the rumors
but not necessarilly
and their enormous tends to lead in the
direction of mel adaptive behavior
not necessarily so again that we have
here
is just at the level of trying to figure
out what psychopathology means in
general there's a kind of family
resemblance
that unites
people have mobile mental functioning
certain set of they tend to have a
certain set of features in common
and there is a family resemblance
that all unites or people
who have some form of mental illness is
well
the tender to have problems will likely
as world income
eternal
that we've got to do in these lectures
is to pursue the analogy
between
mental illness on the one hand
psychopathology
and physical illness on the other hand
in the same way that medical illness
involved
deviations frelimo
physical
metaphysical structure and function we
can say that
mental illness or psychopathology
involves abnormalities in mental
structural or function
abnormalities in cognition
where people have defined abnormal
approval
of problems percy dean or remembering or
thinking or communicating
difficulties in demotion
where plot people's emotional responses
to events
are somehow problematic or difficulties
in the hall in motivation where their
goals
disorders
motivated behavior
somehow or abnormal
and in fact when you look at their
various kinds of mental illness
that are described for you and that
chapter envelope and i'm not going to
repeat all those diagnostic categories
of in these lectures
you'll see
that each form of mental illness
there are less satisfactorily
in one or the their all of these broad
categories
so we have certain forms of mental
illness
all where their primary
problem the primary symptom
it has to do
with cognition
in our timers disease
and other forms of dementia for example
there is a problem
basically a problem of memory okay
that's why i alzheimer's our patients
are treated
often treated in so so-called memory on
disorders clinics
but as you'll see in a couple of minutes
there's another form with major mental
illness
schizophrenia where there are two
different problems in cognitive function
all schizophrenics that would have
altered to a particular difficulties
with memory
but they do have a lot of difficulties
with attention
and they have a lot of difficulty
maintaining
or normal trains of thought to have
difficulty or thinking are clearly
there is
there is a class all involve dot mental
illness is known as the anxiety
disorders
well the problem with the primary
problem
is not one of cognition
but rather is one of emotion
in the anxiety disorders
people feel abnormally high levels ald
negative emotional states like fear
alarmed
and then in various affective disorders
like mania and depression
again
the abnormality is a motion elin nature
not primarily cognitive nature
depressed people
feel sadder there mate
or two
all
people with mania
feel happier
well i suppose or that they want to
and and and and the motivational our
domain we have a uh... you know
a form of mental illness known as
psychotic with me
otherwise known as antisocial
personality disorder
the end of the these individuals
seem
all in the able to
conform their behavior
to the demand solved the although of the
wider social the barman
basically
they just don't care or appear it
appears
but they don't care
to conform their behavior
to of the prevailing social demands but
in the each instance of psychopathology
we have someone abnormality in mental
structure or function
on thirteen
the person's ability to engage in
normal cognition
emotion or motivation
which results
in some kind of abnormal
or mel adoptive of behavior
so again
very definition of psychopathology
is based on an analogy
between mental illness
and physical illness
in the same way that medical pathologies
refer to abnormalities in
physical structure or function
psychopathology refers to
abnormalities
mental or psychological structure
or function
we can continue to pursue
this analogy between mental illness on
the one hand and physical illness on the
other hand are by looking at that is
known in although psychology
as the medical model all psychopathology
and the idea behind the medical model
its employees
is the preferred is simply to pursue
this analogy between medical illness and
mental illness
all the way on down
so for example
but the real language that we used to
talk about mental illness
is language that is derived from
medicine
we have mental patients
who are treated
in mental hospitals
we have programs
of mental hygiene
better intended to prevent of mental
illness of from occurring
we diagnose on mental illness
we treat of when we tend to try to
achieve a cure
or if we can't all or they'd if we can't
killed a mental illness
then we tried to put the person in some
kind of rehabilitation program
it's exactly analogous to the way we
treat
medical illnesses of various are the
kinds
if you saw for any yaar
a lot of that there's some kind of uh...
a spinal cord injury
first thing we do is diagnose it
then we try to treated if we can try to
fix it
if we can't
would give you a rehabilitation regime
to allow you to learn how to live with
that it's exactly the same way
we treat
of mental illness
then that the medical matter of illness
we think about
all symptoms
as being closed by some kind of
underline or the pathology
but symptoms refer to
public manifestations
of some kind of of illness
when you have a fever
you take your temperature if it's above
ninety eight point six
that's the symptom
ald
some kind of underline of pathology
if you've got obtain in your
or you've got swelling in your legs
it's the symptom of some kind
of underlying pathology
and in the same way
the symptoms of mental illness whatever
they are the abnormal fears or the
difficulties in communicating or the
delusions of a host of asians or
whatever
but to be
on uh... caused by some kind of a
hundred flying pathology
and the idea of diagnosis is the figure
out what that underlying pathology or is
so their heart
individual symptoms of mental illness
tend to cluster together
to format syndromes
syndromes like
schizophrenic though
anxiety disorder
childhood autism
mental retardation
manic-depressive illness bipolar
disorder or whatever
brought this up with the irs
mental illnesses
although identified in terms of salams
set of symptoms
which tend to go together
and then finally and the language of
medical pathology
we have diseases
which are syndromes that have some kind
of known cause
okay
on
for example
or if you have leukemia we know what the
causes of leukemia or the symptom of
leukemia is an abnormal
white cell count
or bought
you underline collins
or is for the it is
something
gone wrong in the blood stream
are and that is the difference between
ascend rome which is just a cluster of
symptoms worried about the cause is
and the disease
which is a syndrome
with anyhow
with unknown cause
okay so we can
this is what the medical model
psychopathology really looks like a nine
stressing this because you will often
read
and one of the places that you will
sometimes read this is in your textbook
are somewhat yet accurate portrayal of
what the medical model all is all about
also before
but the medical model of psychopathology
is that the assumes that there's an
organic or physical cause
of mental illness
turns out that is not what the medical
model or is our is all about
commitment
argued gotten better
fall but he's still
doesn't quite have the medical model
right after work it out and for twenty
five years
uh... and uh... still
resisting my influence here
or partner
andries old friends one of my teachers
are part of the apartment refers to was
the pathology model as what i mean by
the medical model the only difference is
i'm right when i refer to it as the
medical model
or and uh... and he's not
our medical model for psychopathology
says
is that psychopathology has a natural
cause
our cars that can be understood
by the application all of the scientific
on the method
that's ever medical bottle assumes
medical model was first and foremost an
analogy
between mental illness and physical
illness
but as far as close as coal
all the medical model
says
is that mental illness
has a natural cause
that can be discovered by science
natural cause as opposed to watch
two hundred three hundred years ago
we padegi super natural mobile of mental
illness
that basically said that
mental illnesses foreclosed by
demon possession
that the day i had gotten a lot of the
person
art and art i i was making the person do
it and engage in these kinds of things
and the proper treatment for what we now
recognized as mental illness
all is essentially xlr schism
of the of the devil
dartmouth the bottle of mental illness
that prevailed
as recently as the evolved
as the fifteen th and sixteen th on
fifteen to sixteen centuries
well recently however
burger is another alternative to the
medical model
known as buffalo model of mental illness
which basically says
the kinds of symptoms that are part and
parcel of mental illness
dana bradley
displayed
by the person
there is arms all their it's both full
behavior
so when somebody's walking down the
street and quacking like doc or dot
speaking and some kind of uh... oh
or this weekend some kind of weird
language
the ideas they could be
normal if they just ride
to be normal or if they wanted
to be normal
all in the same way
that if you think the class of mental
illness is demon possession
but proper treatment of mental illness
is acts or schism
if you think
that mental illness
is deliberately willful behavior
that proper treatment of mental illness
or the mental illness
punishment
it in the eighteen th and eighteenth
centuries
that's exactly how the mentally ill were
treated
they were punished they work within two
silence which were essentially prisons
for the mentally ill
of there are triggered it would look in
the nineteenth century literature
and find prescriptions for our caller
equality
dumping people in whoever many people
dot waterboarding exactly but pretty
close
arctic at the death of the dead out of
it
all
all of the brutal treatments of the
mentally ill and templeton all intending
onto
basically punishment for be mentally ill
but we don't do that under the medical
model
will be saying in the of medical model
is that people cared help
the mentally ill
anymore than they could help
had been cancer or heart disease
and people
don't was
killed themselves
to be audible of the mental illnesses in
the product out
spirit possession or demon possession
anymore
than cancer
or heart disease is a product of spirit
possession
all
weird even session
so here is conduct henry think about
mental illness
in very or in very broad our terms
when it comes to not the
natural classes of mental illness or
again we can think about two different
kinds of causes
there are some at a genetic theories of
mental illness
and there are cycle genic theories of
in this summer genic theories of mental
illness sino comes from the greek word
for a body
mental illnesses related to solve the
problem in barely functioning
okay
is coming up problem of anatomical
structure
we now know
that the calm symptoms of al timers
disease
all related to
data anatomical into irregularities
plaques and tangles in neural tissue in
the brains of people
with al timers or disease
but sometimes the anatomy is intact
it's operations are
not quite correct
you had a good have all the
on the same way that you could have
detected anatomical sd
leading the mental illness you can also
have defects
in physiological function
leading to mental illness
for example asg latenan talks about in
his are
it is chapter
there are all grown
there is any other prominent curious cuz
a friend here
that related to the death of the
deficits in a particular
neurotransmitter known as dopamine
and there is a prominent theory of
depression that relates to
to abnormal all levels of a particular
moreau transfer
known as serotonin
here we have
defects in physiological function
operating in a about amie it's
essentially normal
is and i'll timers disease
you have what appears to be
abnormalities in anatomical structure
sometimes the origins of mental illness
are indeed some atlantic
the are mental illness has its origins
in
some kind of abnormal
bottling function
but it's not always the case
we also have certain forms of or mental
illness
they are in underwriting closed inside
patriotic
there's nothing particularly wrong with
the bodies of the individuals there's
nothing particularly wrong
with all of the with their own anatomy
or physiology
but that there has been some kind of
experience
or some kind of
all learning that has produced the o
deal uh...
the problem
i think probably the clearest example
although i a l a a psychedelic
of or cause of mental illness
isn't post-traumatic stress disorder
ability
of widely
all recognized form of mental illness to
carried your about it on the news all
the time
on with veterans coming back from all
from old iraq suffering from pete e_s_t_
or
vietnam veterans saw that although those
suffering from p_p_o_'s d
because that is psychological
these individuals have been exposed to
traumatic experiences of various kinds
that lead to the development
although form of mental illness
known as post-traumatic stress disorder
that along with their anatomy
nothing wrong with their physiology but
was part of but there's been some
psychological experience that has led to
the alone
or the to the old formation of these
terrorist kinds of symptoms
and but sometimes
it's not so much
the direct experience of travel have
been traumatized by some art of those
fumbled
massive uh... psychologically damaging
of that
but dont think there is some forms of
mental illness
that seemed to will be acquired by the
individual
ald
through a history of social learning
three clear example i think is and
what's known as the
learned helplessness model of depression
where
marty seligman
lynn abramson lora lohr eight and i and
others
have argued
that some people become depressed
because they have learned to think about
themselves and their world in a
particular way to have
on abnormal the death
who negative expectations for themselves
all for the future
on and so on
all of his again nothing wrong with the
brains of these individuals
their dopamine system there serotonin
system is working pretty much a fine
but the problem leading to the
depression
is that they have learned to think
about themselves and the world in a
particular way
so dead
these some energetic causes of mental
illness
can be discovered by science
okay but can the secretary dick
causes of mental illness
again
it's the idea that there are natural
causes
that can be discovered by science
is at the root
of the medical model
volvo of mental illness
so now let's get a little less abstract
for a second
and let's think about exactly what kinds
of mental illnesses although there are
again not going to go uh... this song
because glavin does such a good job
of of it
just to say that there are cool lots of
different forms of mental illness can
take
sometimes some forms of mental illness
or donors organic brain syndrome
because they seem to be closed by
damage to one or another
of the brain structure
there are certain developmental
disorders like a mental retardation
or childhood autism
that he emerged
all over the orlando or you're really of
bases of of of psychological development
or a parent in infancy your tolerable id
or childhood
then there are other
forms of mental illness that become
apparent in adulthood
there are so called psychosis like
schizophrenia were the affect of
disorders
so called the roses like the anxiety
disorders and up and phobias
there is some psycho physiological
disorders
like some forms of all sorts
where the physical
disease
has a psychological clause like lots of
stress
and anxiety
their dissociate disorders what used to
be called hysteria
like multiple personality disorder to
some sort of identity are disorder
on
their classes of various personality are
disorders
home
there's not just one
oracle
discrete symptoms
even although seems to pervade the
persons entire personality
antisocial personality disorder all is a
very good example
of all of this class of mental illness
bender various behavioral disorders that
we classify as mental illness
some people a difficulty sleeping
sleep disorders
those are
of the forms of although psychopathology
and then sometimes people just have
problems including that they approach
uh... psychotherapists or psychiatrists
clinical psychologist psychiatric social
workers
to try to solve
i want to break up with my boyfriend i
don't know how to do it
skater
worried i won't find another boyfriend
or whatever
contracted through it
and help you get rid of him
all
so we've got these various forms of
mental illness and again
go right but it's very good describing
what these forms of mental illness or or
or like i don't want to repeat that
material here
what i do want to do army and the time
this remaining twisted up however is to
talk about
highly classified the various forms of
mental illness
when you plan to
clinical psychologist or a psychiatrist
or a psychiatric social worker and say
i'm feeling more of a lot done really
feeling depressed or i'm really feeling
anxious
i can you help me
there first thing
following the medical model the first
thing you want to do
is to diagnose the owners to try to
figure out what it is all of that that
that's wrong with the person
and again
are watching to see the connection
between
medical and psychiatric diagnosis on the
one hand
classification on the other hand because
what happens is
when you make on medical diagnosis
you classify a patient
into a category
of people who have on kind or arab
disease or illness in common
the symptoms
one of the person has hallucinations or
on depression or anxiety or whatever
a convict those as features
and at the same homes
which are
std defined by clusters off-color
currying
although the symptoms
can be thought all of those categories
so schizophrenic
is a category of mental illness
all individuals with schizophrenia have
certain kinds of features all you know
in common
and then you want to diagnose mental
illness in a patient
you to the same thing that you do if you
are a medical doctor
diagnosing a physical illness
what you try to do
is to match
the patients' symptoms to the symptoms
better characteristic of various kinds
of illnesses
and then say
first thing we know is
you have bipolar disorder
or you have the symptoms of
post-traumatic stress disorder or you
have
the symptoms of schizophrenia or
whatever it is that you've got
diagnosis is essentially an active
categorization the american psychiatric
association
has published in its diagnostic and
statistical manual
and official west
all the various forms of mental illness
there are and what bearer
characteristic
all symptoms are
so that when you're confronted with a
new patient
determined what his or her symptoms are
and then basically
figure out well
where the our where the individual
should be ought to be appropriately all
the classified
that's an interesting
is follow this idea
that psychiatric psychiatric diagnosis
is essentially an active classification
and then try to figure out
exactly what kind of all categories the
psychiatric diagnoses
even
history
off the coyote re but they are in a
psychiatric diagnoses various forms of
mental illness
were considered to be proper steps just
like the proper sets that we talked
about in our lecture on categorization
so for example
alm
nineteenth of early twentieth century
psychiatrist
distinguish between psychotic season
overseas
in psychosis
all that there is a alm
departure from reality testing the
person just doesn't see reality are
correctly
in the new roasters
there's usually some kind of underlying
anxiety
if you have difficulty in reality
testing
you be labeled
with psychosis if you add problems of
anxiety you be able able too
out with directions
reality testing
and anxiety we're defining features
or the categories
morose is
and also i got the psychosis and
neurosis uh... respectively
and then
once you determine that the person had a
psychotic disorder
then you could make a more fine-grained
classification
in terms of whether the person had say's
is a friend here
or manic depressive illness if the
person's all god departure from reality
testing was in the cognitive domain
the psychiatrist would lean toward a
diagnosis of schizophrenia
if the person's
depart all problems with reality testing
were in the emotional domain
you wouldn't know make a diagnosis of
manic-depressive illness
similarly
if a person
had some specific advice like
being afraid of heights
or being afraid of spiders are being
afraid of even the presence of other
people
you would diagnose the person is having
a phobia
but if the person was just worried
about everything
all the time
you'd make a diagnosis
solve all of anxiety disorder
all
to be more concrete
oregon bloodwork be swiss psychiatrist
who are first identified
the mental illness that we know no ads
on schizophrenia
argued
every individual with schizophrenia
displayed at four
different kinds of of symptoms
association disturbance
affleck disorder in which the person
though the failed associations from one
idea to another
was impaired
and had o'neill
or an inability to experience emotion
especially positive emotion
ambivalence
all or any difficulty and i'll make it
up
on his or her of mind
and what we were called autism
of which doesn't mean what
autism means today
but basically means all of that means
social withdrawal
these are known as the former enemies or
schizophrenia ok notice
all of their uh... their initial letter
and blow argued
very patient with schizophrenia
ideas for symptoms
and any patient who had to use force
symptoms
what happens
schizophrenic
these symptoms work
single a necessary an jointly sufficient
to define the category of schizophrenia
and all
further barriers forms of mental illness
we're diagnosed in precisely all of this
white so you had a super category of
psychosis
a basic level category alts cuz a friend
hill or manic depressive illness and
then underneath alm
alot of schizophrenia
deborah subtypes
and these subtypes were created
in exactly the same way as you create
subtypes of a proper set view of things
simply by adding new defining features
so importers view simple scads of
schizophrenia consisted just of the
phrase
associated association disturbance
at had only a
ambivalence and autism
hippocratic schizophrenic added a
symptom of childlike behavior
catatonic
all bout of schizophrenia
added a symptom multiple movement
disorder essentially
and paranoid schizophrenic added a
defining symptom ought to lucien
his whiskers are for any other
sale with all the other forms of mental
illness in the early days of psychiatry
each of these mental illnesses
was construed as a proper set
her the defining symptoms we're single a
necessary and gently sufficient to
define the individual is having one
disease or another
there were sharp and rates
hopewell belgrade's
between adjacent categories if you had
reality testing problems in the
cognitive sphere you were schizophrenic
if u_n_ reality testing problems in the
emotional sphere you had
manic-depressive illness
if you had reality testing problems you
were psychotic
if you had exactly disorder
you were dorado
they were sharp boundaries
between budgets and categories
it was a hierarchical vertical structure
all
created
by eddie and subtracting part of the
defining or the defining symptoms
okay so you have
a hierarchy don't look like this
mental illness divided into psychosis
and the row sees
psychosis divided into the matter to
press of illness
and schizophrenia
and schizophrenia deflated into
it's four sub categories yet sad they
really need system
just like
proper sets are a very neat system for
classifying
or other kinds of objects automobiles
birds
and vegetables
but it's a system that alternately
failed
for the same reason the proper set
categorization fails in the domains
of fruits and vegetables
an order will be ols and all of
birds and fish
because it turns out
well that mental illness
is unstructured quite this way
or understanding that took a long time
and lead to a revolution
in how we think about psychiatric
diagnosis
a revolution which i'll talk about on
wednesday
thank you very much
will see you on wednesday