okay
last time we discussed
principles
that seemed to govern the encoding stage
of memory processing
actually free but only to pertain to
long-term memory
there are three things you can do with
an item of the poor i thought that the
operative encoding
the first is to engage in in
what we think of as well
maintenance reversal
simply repeated an item over and over
and over again
the way you might repeat a telephone
number that you've just looked up in a
telephone book
before you get a chance to dialect
that repetition
fine for maintaining and item in
inactive state and what we call short
term or primary memory
but it's not particularly good
adnan coating the eddie lasting trace of
a memory
in what we call a long-term or secondary
memory
for a time for that you have to do some
other things
what i think you have to do is to engage
in all of that sort of processing
alm
think about individual items that you're
trying to remember
in such a ways to connect off these
individual items with information that
you already possess in memory
and we saw in the death of processing
experiment
that the deeper the processing the more
elaborate the processing
but better the memory is going to to be
the third motive processing at the time
of encoding is a little bit different
from that
and that's known as a organizational
processing
and in organizational processing
we're not so concerned with relating
individual items on information to
something you already know
rather a registered in relating to
individual items of information
to each other
and the general idea of a car
the mayor of this organizational
activity
that you engage in
all of the better
obscure subsequent memory is going to be
you'll aberration an organization
are the true
primary principles
that control what goes on
at the time of encoding
no we want to do
is to assume that a memory trays has
been adequately uncoated
well-organized
and once it's in coated
that memory trace
becomes unbearable
for used
by the individual
and what we want to know now
is what happens to was subsequently
well the first answer is that had memory
that memory remains at a highly active
state so long as the individual
pays attention to it
refreshes it
all rehearses itt
in that room fashion that we know that
we talked about later
but you can't do that all the time you
look up a phone number
on babies have repeated yourself forever
right you gotta think about other things
you gotta look up on their phone number
is you've got a attend classes you've
gotta watch t_v_
or whatever it is you do
it's about a point when you stop
actively rehearsing the item
but the retention of herbal really
begins and what we want to know is
what now happens over the retention
interval
when a memory has been and coated
and placed in storage
and what happens
to make a long story short
is that you start forgetting the
information
immediately
how many times have you
look up a phone number
dialed it
talk to the person and then
alm
serology what was that phone number or
you need somebody at a party
and you turn your attention away for a
second
and then you have difficulty remembering
his were her name that's what happens to
be in forgetting
and it's something that happens over the
all over the retention interval
and we want to know wide that occurs
okay
well the first thing
is to show that it occurs and this is
the second major finding all of this
classic
pioneering study of memory by every
house back in the eighteen hundreds
very impt
on the experiment that i showed you last
time
last time we saw a cs an experiment by
having house in which he buried the
number of repetitions that he gave too
these nonsense syllables
and then looked at memory is a function
of repetition
what we're doing here what they've been
hosted in this experiment
is to
learn
memorize a list of nonsense syllables
all according to some criterion of all
of mastery
and then
very the retention interval
fraum twenty minutes
to an hour
about nine hours a day two days seven
days that's six weeks or something like
that
all
and off
quite a bit to see
why what happened to this sort of memory
trace as a function of time
and he measured memory again in terms of
savings in relearning
so is looking at the strength of the
memory
all
as a department in terms of hollow
much effort it's going to take him to
move to relearn the thing later on
more settled more savings meaning a
stronger memory trace
and what you can see here is
that there is pretty substantial savings
after just a twenty minute retention
interval
but the savings drop off quite rapidly
after an hour we're down below fifty
percent savings
after
eight or nine hours from down below
forty percent savings
after saw a couple of weeks
were way down to or just twenty percent
savings in their own relearning
so this is a typical result of these
kinds of experiments
and uh... that is a progressive
forgetting with time
forgetting increases with the retention
interval
and this is just a very simple
early example
on next principle of memory function
which we call the time dependency
principle
which simply says that memory diminishes
as a function of the length of the
retention interval
the longer the retention interval
fold less memory
going to have
now that's fine
but psychologist what we really want to
know is why does this occur
wide his memory fade with time
all-white whitewater do we had this kind
of progressive forgetting
and over the years
psychologists have entertained
at least four different hypotheses
about what clauses
time dependency in memory
the first of these
always known as the decay hypothesis
and the idea here is simply
tien phillies memories in the same way
that prolonged exposure to the sun will
fade a photograph
or prolonged exposure to the wind
will adult will or you raise footprints
in the sand at uh... at the beach
it's a passive
process of decay
that things simply go away
flow with time
every second hypothesis concerning time
dependency
is what's known as the consolidation
hypothesis
and the idea here is
empty and voting process
does not happen
instantaneously
rather it actually takes time for a
memory to become
firmly implanted in storage and if you
do something
during this consolidation interval
you could prevent the memory from being
adequately are
adequately stored
also that the consolidation of prophet
opposites
and get what's happening here
z ideas that
happens through the memory
during this interval
when it's in a somewhat are somewhat
vulnerable state
authored a hypothesis
is all
what's known as the displacement
hypothesis
and the idea behind the displacement
hypothesis is that the
storage space if you will in memory
is ltd
and there comes a point where if you're
going to put new information you've got
to take some information out
if you've got a visit to take about a
computer metaphor of unit moved for a
minute
on wed when you're
hardest gets full
in order to make room for something new
that your office you're working on
you've got to a raise something else or
a more mechanical
or analogy would be a file drawer
there's only so much room in a file
drawer right
and if you're going to put keep putting
forth wild folders in the file drawer
you're gonna have to get uh... throw
some doubt
that's the general idea behind the
displacement hypothesis
and basically what it says it is
that called information tends to be
displaced
from eleven displaced by new information
and that displacement constitutes all
laws
memory storage a permanent loss
from memory storage
before the pipe offices
is different from that and that is
what's known as the interference
hypothesis and the idea behind
interference
met information isn't lost from memory
permanently
but rather the accumulation in of
knowledge in memory
makes it harder for you to get at any
particular item of information
again if you think about a flat out or
metaphor for memory
if he just keeps stopping stuff again
although i thought that the war stuff
that's on the file drawer
the harder it's going to be to find any
particular piece
of all of information let's use a nice
filing system
like alphabetical order
over or something like that
but the important thing here
is that are
in in the process of displacement you're
actually losing memories from storage
and documentaries art of storage
whereas in in interference bumped the
out the nudging question
remains unavailable in storage
but they're simply eight failure
retrieve it
it turns out
that each of these four
hypotheses about time dependency
applies to a different kind of memories
but talking here about long-term memory
episodic memory
and it turns out
that all of as far as long-term memory
is concerned
the primary determinant of
time-dependent forgetting
is interference
not passive decay
not consolidation filter
not displacement but rather
time-dependent forgetting
seems to occur by virtue of the fact
that
individual items stored in memory
interfere with each other
each of the items stored in the country
makes it harder to yet at another item
in memory
although so we get
what we know as the interference
principal long-term memory which
basically says
won some memory is uncoated
strategy is
for all intents and purposes permanent
there is no permanent forgetting of
anything and aren't you know that in
storage
but rather all time-dependent forgetting
occurs by virtue
or interference
and this principle of interference
or is always illustrated by what's known
as the paradox but the paradox of
interference which basically says that
the more you know especially the more
you know about any particular thing
the harder it is to get any particular
item of information
it's a little counter-intuitive you
think well if you're an expert on
something about all the stuff of the tip
of your
our fingers
but it's not true
the more you know the harder it is to
get at any particular item of
information
here is a classic demonstration of this
by john anderson a psychologist at
carnegie mellon all university
what anderson did is very simple metrics
permit
in which he asked subjects to
memorized sentences
that represent
represented fax
about people in locations of these work
is just cut mindlessly
material those are very profound
experiment
so subjects rest alert about that those
sentenced the doctor is in the bank
and the fireman is in the park
and the lawyer is in the church
and the lawyer is in the park
notice what happens here
dr
and bank that's a unique person
and that's a unique location
here we have a fireman who is a unique
person
but he's in the park which is also where
the lawyer is so we have
into individuals
associated with the same location
and then we have
the water is in the church
and the lawyers in the park
one individual associated
part of the part of the locations
so anyway
what anderson dead was to read asking
subjects to memorize services like this
are to a ought to uh... to a criterion
of memory
and then he simply ask them
to perform a recognition test
in which they were simply asked
did you study this ends
so if i ask you did you study the doctor
is in the bank you'd say yes
if i ask you if you studied the doctor
is in the park
you would sim simply say no to that
these
subjects
memorize these fences to a criterion of
perfect learning
so they performed almost perfectly
obvious recognition test
but whatever sanded
was to measure that's fine
that it took subjects
to successfully all recognize these
items
and he god
onset of response elite and sees hall
like this
so here
we have
all vd
subject to memorize one fact about a
target
to fax a lot of target were three facts
about a target
here one fact about a location
two facts about a target
or three facts about a target and
they're making judgments about ivins
they actually studied
or fake items that they didn't study
and that you can see in this light is
these are small businesses like small
reaction time differences
in terms of experimental psychology
these are big affects these are very big
differences
and you can say
that it took subjects
last time
to verify fact where they are going to
learn one fact about a person
then if they have learned to were three
facts about a port
less time to verify
if they weren't one fact about a
location that if they have learned
to or three fax about a location
this is known as the fat effect
response latency increases with a number
of facts you know about doctors and
lawyers and fireman and parks and banks
in churches
the more you know about these
individuals
the more you know about these locations
the harder it is
to retrieve any particular
island of information
and this illustrates the of yell fan
effect in memory
again
leads us to restate the time dependency
principle
that so far at the long term endeavor
memory is concerned in any event
memory diminishes with time but it does
suck mostly by virtue of interference
competing memories interfere with each
other
get in the way
of the retrieval
called and get in the play of the
retrieval process
this interference principle
all the intern
leads us to
state an important distinction that all
that that applies to allowed to memory
and that is the distinction between
the availability of a memory in storage
and the accessibility
all of that memory
when you want to retrieve it
and make are gonna make use of it
knowledge may be available in memory
but by virtue of interference among
competing memories
it may be hard to gain access to
available knowledge
when you will
when you want it
so that's the distinction between
availability and accessibility
and we're going to see that uh... come
into play in just a couple minutes that
general point however
is that
although
memory encoding
memory storage is essentially permanent
not all memories available in storage
or equally accessible
not all memories of billable in storage
or equally are raw are wrong
equally accessible
at any particular time
so how do you gain access to a memory
how is it
that we gain access reach back and
firing
on knowledge that we've
although that we've stored in memory
but general idea here is
that accesses stimulated by a clearing
if i save you what did you have for
dinner last night that's a question
and that's supposed to alter the guide
your research through memory you don't
look for your pet's names
in response to a question like that
you don't look for your record of
lunches
in response to a question like that
you know look column onto your memories
from early childhood
or rather you focus your retrieval
yesterday
if i ask you while when did columbus on
uh... across the ocean
then you look for knowledge that you
have a blog columbus
not for knowledge you have about
neil armstrong or whatever
so whenever we try to gain access to
memory
we do it in the form of some kind of
question about what happened in the past
and then the subject
has to add information
from memory
information
that constitutes
the home
you know the answer the question
bi chai by retrieving
gaining access
to available information stored
in memory
so that's this distinction incumbent
memories
available in storage may not be
accessible
when retrievals attempted
may not be accessible for example
by virtue
interference so now what we want to do
is to explore some of the factors
governing retrieval
we're going to assumed elementary sprays
has been adequately uncoated by virtue
of elaborate is an organizational
activity
and we're also going to assume that that
memory trace
as nao reb now remains available in
storage
overseas
on the all over some retention interval
it hasn't been in a syndicated hasn't
been
displays that hasn't off
or there is a bit of failure of
consolidation hits in there
it's available
and the question now is
how do we gain access
to available memories
and the short answer is
gaining access to available memories
is on that or
of having
of particular
retrieval
cues
consider for example
three different kinds of memory test
that are commonly used
in experiments all of this sort
free recall cued recall
and recognition
and uh... free recall
the query to memory
basically is a very very query
and simply sites
sometime and someplace where something
happened
if i say to you
why did you do last night
focused your intention on some
particular
piece of the past or
what did you do the last time you
weren't pullman a whole
okay
all what i want you to do
is simply to tell me what happened in
that particular event
in the bronco learning paradigm
for your call queries
usually take the formal
what were the words on the list
gain you don't ask anybody that you
don't provide any more information than
that
is simply say what were the words on the
list
by contrast include recall
the query to memory
provides more identifying information
about the target avent so for example i
could say all what were the color words
on the list that i showed you
last time and then you can
focus attention on color words
and not think about the other words that
were on the list like the body parts of
the four four deductibles or all or
whatever
or we can give you a wicked mission test
all wear in fact
the query
contains
a copy of the target
again if i said was orange one of the
words on the list
that you read last time we were in class
so have already presented the word for
you
and all you have to do is find it in
memory
and say
on say yes or no
you're familiar with this distinction
from your history of academic testing
free recall
short answer
okay
there is a long-term potentiation
and ended on the right down a
description of what long-term
potentiation is
cued recall okay
arm
that were all but what's the l
mean of trace logbook conditioning or
something like that what's a distinction
between trees conditioning belay
conditioning
here the query
adds information i don't say tell me
everything you know about classical
conditioning
rather write focus the question so that
you have a better idea of what you're
looking for in memory
and then
finally and recognition test
that's your typical multiple-choice exam
okay
essay
fill in the blanks
multiple-choice
very good analogies
all for friedrich all tests
cued recall tests
and recognition
tests in memory
here's an experiment
by handled holden and michael watkins is
the same michael watkins whose work i
showed you last time
comparing the results of free
cued recall and recognition
tests of memory here are subjects were
simply as to
study a list of words
and then for the free recall test
the rest report what the words were that
they've studied
on the cute recall test
they were asked to farm
flaw order the rest report
the color words or the names of four
four footed animals or whatever anna
recognition test they were asked
questions like
was one of the words on the list orange
or was one of the words on the list
purple
art here were plotting the number of
items remembered in response to each of
these tests
and what you can see is that free recall
doesn't produce much memory
cued recall produces quite a bit more
memory about twice as much or memory
and recognition are testing produces
quite a bit of memory
reckon chin test
as a rule
art easier
recall tests
of memory is easier to remember
something on a recognition test
that it is part of free recall test
and among recall tests
killed recall tends to be easier
as a test land on their memory this is a
typical result in these kinds of of
experiments and as a result
illustrates yet another principle of
memory bitches
what's known as the q dependency
principle
and memory in here would basically say
that memory depends on the
on mount of information provided
by the retrieval cue memory depends on
the informational value barbecues
provided
at the time of retrieval
free recall test
doesn't provide much information what
words on the west
that's all you get
cued recall tests
provide more
information over the color words on the
list
what where the body parts on the list
recognition tests
provide
lots and lots of information about the
target memory
was it all range or purple
was that finger
or fort wasn't lyanne
or tiger
or whatever
so the q dependency principal basically
says
you can gain access to memory by virtue
of
retrieval cues
and the richer
the more informative these retrieval
cues are
but more likely you are
to gain access
to information
stored
so let's stop for a second see if there
are any questions
about
dependency principal and about the q
dependency principle
the distinction between availability and
accessibility
and
the problem of interference anything at
all about this
now let's go one step
we usually but what i have portrayed and
coding and retrieval process is so far
i portray them as one related to each
other
on memory gets uncoated
and then it gets retrieved okay
but it turns out to think about it for a
second there it is an interesting
interaction between encoding and
retrieval process these
which is that retrieval cues
ten compensate
four
port increase all of the poor processing
at the time of encoding
if u
don't engage
in elaborate is an organizational
processing at the time of encoding
you're probably not going to produce
very much on eighty-three recall test
of memory
but you'll probably remember more on a
recognition test
the cues provided at the time of in
coding
if they're rich enough
they can compensate for
impoverished activity
onsite accuse provided the time of
retrieval if they're rich enough can
compensate for impoverished activity
at the time of encoding
similarly
if you wouldn't get a journal lots of
processing at the time of retrieval
in gauge of lots of elaborate in
organizational activity
when the time to but wild at when the
time comes for retrieval you don't have
to do too much
more effort you put into encoding
fell less effort you need a retrieval
the less effort you put into encoding
for more information
you quality uwm uh... need for retrieval
and this general idea
that there is all and interaction or a
kind of compensatory relationship
between and coding
and retrieval
is very important property of the memory
system
not studied something very well
you might do ok on a recognition testing
of multiple choice test but you're not
going to do very well
on a_d_r_ on an essay exam
on youtube engaged in what the box
well elaborate encoding activity
or you don't need that he helped over
recognition test the ancient
greeks and romans
people who didn't have a lot out paper
available to go to them
maybe use of these kinds of principles
wednesday or when they were preparing
they're all of their speeches for
example in the are greek agro
or the or the roman forum
is very common if you look at worli
or rather ancient of texts are rhetoric
to find
on speakers
being taught aid mnemonic device
known as the method of low side all by
which they are stalled supposed to in
code
the points that they want to make and
their speeches in such a way as to make
it easy for them to remember them later
on
so for example if i were using the
method of low side
to altered to memorize this lecture on
might say ok we're going to begin with
the principle of time dependency and an
associate that with pullman holt
and then we're going to so i think about
the principle of interference and an
associate that with the valley life
sciences building
and we're going to think about the fan
effect on going to put that in the
chancellor's office in california hole
and now i'm going to take the occu
dependency principle
and i'm going to associate that with
we'll arrive at four a_m_ and now if i
want to
remember
what my lectures going to be about
all i have to do is mentally retrace my
path
getting from my office in pullman hall
over to your real wrote a trim
and pick up those points along the way
if it was in fact
house cicero and all other roman orders
memorized the speeches they didn't have
a lot of paper
they didn't have them cargo on marble
slabs of the hold them up in front of
them
all-weather read their work
they used man demonic tricks like the
method of low side
part make it easy for them to remember
the points that wanted to make
in the order in which they wanted to
make them
these demonic devices
all
involved setting up
various kinds of strategies at the time
of encoding
to make remembering
easier
the time haldol
at the time of retrieval
so no let's do another memory test in
that blast list but i presented to you
what were the liberals are women's first
names don't look on your slides
number that list
and talking about it
thirty minutes or so
amber
anybody named amber
usually get at least one amber
these days nobody mister anyway
all
members are perfectly good
goals or woman's first name any of you
probably know somebody named amber
all
when you started this list
you studied it in the congress party the
word amber in the context of all other
color names
orange and purple
u_n_ coated with the word amber
as a color name which in fact it is
but then when i ask you to retrieve that
word
uh... yesterday uh... center to did to
retrieve it
as a grills or woman's first name
and it was for
now that word is their you remember all
everybody remembers that word now is a
lawyer at the time
one how come you weren't able to arm
how come you were able to get at it
this dog difficulty remembering amber
okay
depending on how it's uncoated
illustrates what's known as the encoding
specificity principle
and this is another example of the
relation
between encoding processes on the one
hand and retrieval process he's on the
other
what the encoding specificity principal
basically says
is that memory is best
when q information presented at the time
of encoding adept at the time of
retrieval
matches
q information processed at the time of
encoding
memory is best
when the cues
presented
at the time of retrieval match
accused
that were processed at the time of
encoding
and codeine advertiser color name
makes it easy to remember amber as a
caller word
but makes it hard to remember amber
as egg rolls
all of them go all the girls were
balloons or first name
this principle of encoding specificity
is what accounts for
some of the most fascinating phenomenon
of memory white state dependent memory
we now know that if you were very
the person's physiological state by
giving them drug
on one occasion and maybe not at another
that memory will depend
on the match
between the individuals physiological
state at the time of retrieval
and that individuals
physiological state
at the time of encoding
also for example
if the person is
drugged
or did and it's given no drug at the
time of retrieval
and no drug at that paula and also no
drug at the time and coating memories
pretty good
but if the individual was audited coated
the information under the influence of
case psychoactive drug
and then tries to retrieve the
information
after the drug is washed out of the
system
memory is going to be worst if the
person and coated in the non drugs state
trying to do is drug during retrieval
again memories going to be pretty bad
all but
if the individual encodes during
paula paula dot thought the drug state
and then tries to retrieved during a
broad st
memory is going to be pretty good
pretty good by say
because it turns out that almost all
psychoactive drugs impeller
encoding and retrieval process needs
okay whether it's alcohol
or
substances that you're not supposed to
be taking like marijuana
although or all of those psychoactive
substances
impair
memory processes both at the time of
encoding and at the time of retrieval
but if you look at samal doses of these
drugs
you will find all of that there is a
pattern of state dependency
so if you win coated
the in information
under the influence of a drug
you'll remember it better
if you are also
under the influence world
that drug
again just so i'm not misunderstood
this doesn't mean that you should study
with a bunch of beers
and then come in
for a mid-term exam
okay
because alcohol impaired as many
functioning right
alcohol impairs both encoding and
retrieval
but in the laboratory were beacons to
where we have a good study these things
safely under tight control we go we've
we've been able to show
that subjects who studied with a little
buzz on
remember better if they also remembers
but they also retrieved
with a little are both on here is an
example of this is an experiment by
jim swanson
and marcel cans barn
classic study all of drugs state
dependent memory
in children with all attention deficit
hyperactivity disorder
august those on early study of the drug
ritalin
i'd add fadiman type drug which has
paradoxical effects than
or kids with the d_h_ the all uh...
of the to what come down and focus
and what happened in this experiment
was that swanson kids born ask these
children
learn a list of facts they were actually
the locations of zoo of animals and
their resumes
but tiger arisen that are rondo losing
that campbell is in the citizen the all
regina zoom these kaiser canadians
okay
saw the kids
studied one list all the words
under the influence of berlin
and
date
although they're not a group of kids
study out without the influence of
ritalin
and then
they were given a relearning test
okay
always ritalin or without ritalin
and this is the percentage of errors
salawah errors means better memory
you can see
there when the children lower nd list
under the influence of drugs
of ritalin
the showed fewer errors and rewarding
and when they wrong
all learned of the list under the
influence of no drugs
they showed fewer errors
when they relearn under the influence of
no drugs this is a classic pattern
or drug dependent memory
are just happens to be children with a
p_h_d_ but it was traits the point
if you've got its eighty h d
and you learn something
when you've
kutcher does of ritalin
you'll remember it better
if you're also
all working on your does volvo
overload
so they are not a number of these
drug-induced state dependent memory
effects that have been observed in
humans
we get the strong affects with very
strong drugs
barbiturates
easter nitrous oxide
you can get some affects with nicotine
just another reason not to smoke
right don't smoke or your study cuz it
can't smoke in here when you're taking
an exam
all
marijuana hallucinogenic give moderate
state dependent effects
all
there some other drugs to give
relatively weak affects but these
all major sedative drugs
can produce very strong state dependent
affects on memory
all it's not just a matter of
drabbed affects on memory emotional
state can also produce
all effects on nov or the state
dependent effects on memory
here's an experiment by eric i can janet
metcalf
in which
all subjects were made happy or sad
while they studied a list of words
this was all by virtual musical mood
induction although i can metcalf played
very happy techni music
for half their subjects you know
r_v_ overture to the ballet giselle was
one of their uh... tunes very very nice
happy music
can't be said was that his l
palm
the uh... the other group of subjects
were played music that paul that was
intended to make them said
all
moves toward skis russia under the
mongolian boots
okay
plated half speed
this is really directly saying this is
all four piece of music not occur great
piece of music played at full speed
all but in any event
the subjects were given this musical
note induction barbie stories list of
words
and i've never given a musical mood
induction when they attempted to
remember at the list of words they had
studied some subjects were happy in both
conditions somerset in both conditions
somewhere happy while they studied sad
will be retrieved somewhere said while
they were still while they studied
on and unhappy with the retrieved
and what you can see here is
that the match between encoding mood
and test mood produces
the best memories
if you're happy
when you encoded
you remember more if you're happy at the
time of retrieval
if your sad when u in code
you remember more if you are said
at the time
all retrieval
so here's a guy another example
of this encoding specificity principal
as it applies to emotional state not
just drug state
here's another illustration of the
encodings festival specificity principal
applying to environment the environment
in which encoding and retrieval occurred
this is an experiment by garden and
battery
that was done with palm
deep-sea divers these in fact were navy
seals being trained as part of the naval
base in the in san diego
quite an extraordinary experiment
died in battle we talk about our bunch
of these guys
and our
all had some of them study a list of
words while they're on the dock
and then drive to adapt the twenty five
feet
and remember the list of words
on deliverable subjects
dole to adapt the twenty five feet
struggle is the words like
held out this list of words in front of
their masks
all that and then came up to the surface
and were tested
and you can see
that if u studied on land
you remembered better if you are tested
on land
if you studied underwater
you remembered better if you were tested
underwater
bum match between the incumbent
environment
and at the retrieval environment
makes a difference
if the retrieval environment matches the
encoding environment you get better
memory
if their is a
mismatch
so what we've seen here all four bunch
of examples of what's known in the field
as context dependent memory
okay
why do you define
context in terms of time
workplace
features of the external environment
like whether you're on the broader
lander twenty five feet under water
features of the internal environment
like your physiological state controlled
by drivers
or your emotional state or whatever
dark to my knowledge there are no
studies of motivational state dependent
memory
but you can imagine experiment in which
people study a list of words while
they're hungry and then test or tested
while they're hungry i bet dollars to
doughnuts you get the same kinds of
facts
though i suspect that hunger or also
interferes
and coding
on and uh... and retrieval
still
what we've got here
is in the encoding specificity principle
what kind of limitation
on the q dependency principle
q dependency principles said basically
what matters
to accessibility what matters at the
point of retrieval is the informational
value of the retrieval cue
more information supplied by the
retrieval cue the more likely you are to
gain access to a memory
now it's true so far as it goes
but these
the these studies illustrating the
encoding specificity principle
make it clear
that it's not just a matter
mt of information it has to be right
claim
of information
all
the information supplied at the time of
the retrieval
has to match
the information that was processed at
the time of the coding
if you're going to have
very successful or retrieval conditions
so and coating
how you would call it a memory
sets the stage brook hart you're going
to retrieve it
if you encode amber as a color word
they're going to find it difficult to
retrieve amber as a girl's first thing
similarly
retrieval
in some sense
recapitulate
the encoding process ok so you've got to
do with the title retrieval
engage in the at the time retrieval on
the same kinds of process easy win
gauged in
at the time oven coding
when encoding and retrieval conditions
are kanga runs
backed increases the likelihood that
you're gonna gain access to trace
information
when encoding and retrieval conditions
arkin timberland
that's going to make it
a lot kal a lot harder
so
that's the story bobo
encoding specificity
and at the eliminates all
extension
adi q dependency principle
anne questions on encoding specificity
mu dependent memory
last time we talked about this principle
of encoding
that says that
the elaboration principle
the basically says
that more you connect new information up
with pre-existing knowledge
the better the memory is going to be
again that's true so far as it goes
but there are interesting called by
their qualifications
on on this
let's look at that point the
relationship is between knowledge
gerald allege and memory
here we're talking about the influence
of
will be called semantic memory
in the last lecture
your generic abstract knowledge and
beliefs about the world
and you're at the thought of memory
your memory for a particular
or experiences
they want to know what the relation is
uh... between these
here is all that experiment all using a
variant on the verbal learning paradigm
known as person memory paradigm in which
we ask people to
study and remember
facts
about or love facts about people
in this experiment
we first
present person with setup general fax
about an individual like a judy
we simply say to his intelligent
she's surfaced
she's artistic she's refined she's a
magid itive she's witty note the kind of
person
this is
okay so that's your general impression
of judy
and now i'm going to tell you some facts
about her life
okay
sheet
one the chess tournament
second she attended a symphony concert
judy made the same mistake three times
she was confused by the daytime
television show
judy ordered a sandwich for lunch
and judy took the elevator
to the third floor these are the kinds
of facts about judy
we want you to remember in this
particular experiment
but point of having you learn something
about judy in general
was to establish i kind of ski you know
oriflame work
but you can use to encode information
about judy
and if you noticed for a second
some of these behaviors are kanga relent
with the schema
she won the chess tournament and she
attended the symphony concert so kind of
thing you'd expect all smart
artistically sensitive sophisticated
people
some of these behaviors more in
congruent with the impression you have
about dog judy
she made the same mistakes vetoing this
let's kind of a dumb thing
she was confused by the daytime
television show
another
dumb thing to do
these are inconsistent
with your impression of this person as
intelligent witty sophisticated on
sensitive and all that
and then there are these behaviors like
she ordered a sandwich for lunch
and she took the elevator to the third
floor
breach of shrug your shoulders in
doesn't have anything to do with it if
we don't know about judy
we have
behaviors that are
congruent
with your schema for judy
congruent with your overall impression
of judy
some that are in cumberland with your
overall impression of judy and some that
are simply irrelevant
to your overall impression
of judy
and now what we do is we tester memory
for these three different kinds of facts
and will be kept is a pattern of results
that looks like this
memory is best
for schema conger on fax
doesn't talk there is going to christina
conklin fax okay
as opposed to schema irrelevant facts
soul remembering that judy went at went
to the symphony concert that's
remembered pretty well
remember that remembering that judy
ordered a sandwich for lunch
remembered not so well
but what's interesting about this
experiment
all is that memory is best
for schema
income grew and fax
memory is best for the fact that judy
was confused by the daytime television
show
and the jury made the same mistake
three times
what's going on here
walker illustrated in this experiment
is the relationship between
memory for a particular offense
and knowledge of all the world in
general
and it's a band of memory for particular
bad
depends on its relationship
to your knowledge of the world in
general
here we have what's known as
the schematic processing principle
which basically says
that memories of function
of the relationship between an event
and pre-existing knowledge expectations
and believes
memory is very poor
for information that's irrelevant
to pre-existing knowledge expectations
and beliefs
better
for indictment for information that is
kanda relent
with existing knowledge expectations and
believes
but it's best
for information
in congruent with existing pre-existing
knowledge expectations and beliefs and
here's what's going on here
give you give me one minute
dusky no
medellin judy is intelligent and
sophisticated insensitive
that provides you with additional treat
all information q information but you
can use the search memory for
intelligent sophisticated artistic kinds
of facts about judy
schema conroy knowledge is favored in
memory because the schema provides
additional q information at the time of
retrieval
schema in congruent behaviors get a
different advantage in memory scheming
in congruent behaviors get advantage in
memory precisely because they are
surprising and unexpected
and when you encounter something that's
surprising an unexpected you think about
you try to explain it
why would somebody as smart as judy be
confused by the daytime television show
well maybe she was thinking about to all
of the nobel prize she was going to get
tore law manish focusing on proving
formats last their arm or something like
that
the explanation provides more
opportunity to wall operate the event in
memory provides you an opportunity
moored to process at a bit more deeply
steamer content promotion gets the
advantage of retrieval cues schema in
congruent information gets an advantage
from elaboration schema irrelevant
information gets another advantage
schema irrelevant thought information is
poorly remembered
thank you very much
at a good weekend will finish this up on
monday