okay on
in the last several lecturers
we've been looking at fundamental
psychological processes involved in
learning
perceiving and remembering
and one of the things that we have
uncovered in these
discussions
is that
learning proceeding and remembering
require more
than merely forming associations between
stimuli and responses
more than the extracting information
from armed
of the stimulus objects
more than retrieving memory traces
encoded
are in the past
rather
and each of these prophecies
the person is actively trying to figure
out what's going on
in learning
the organism is trying to predict in
control environmental events to learn
what follows what
and what's gonna happen next
in perception
the perceive urs apt
trying to figure out what objects are in
the environment
where they are and what they're doing
in memory the remember is actively
trying to figure out what
and in the past so he or she can use
that information
on you know in in the future
the point of this
is that yet is fundamental
cognitive processes these basic
functions of learning and perceiving and
remembering
dependent to medley
on the so called a higher mental
processes
involving the reasoning
judgment
inference and a problem solving
and what we want to do not go in that
this next series of lectures
is to focus on these aspects of thinking
to try to think about
hobby rezant about objects and events
in order to make a judgment
and decisions
concerning them
gary hankins then philosophy end in
psychology
of very popular model for this judgment
and reasoning process
that's known as the normative model all
of a judgment and reasoning
and what does normative model basically
says is that when people engage in
problem solving when people reason about
events
they follow the principles of logical
inference
principles of logical inference that
have been with us since roughly the time
of aristotle
furthermore
this enormous model argues
rather of sorts
that judgments and decisions and choices
are based on a principle of rational
self interest which is to say
that we make the choices we make because
we think that they're going to benefit
as in some way
this principle
of rational self-interest is intern
based on a principal of
optimality
which means that in making choices
making judgments
we want to maximize our gains
and minimize our losses that's the
principle of optimality
maximize games andrew and minimize
losses
but our judgments are also based on a
principle of utility
which is to say that we want to achieve
our goals
in the most you fish and matter possible
but i want to take forever to figure out
the all-new
the uh... oh god answered assault
we want to get to the correct to the
correct judgment
are just as easily as we can
this enormous model of judgment and
reasoning
isn shrine to in economics for those of
you of how to economics course
a set of principles known as rational
choice
and all uh... according to traditional
economic theory
alm assumes the existence of a kind of
creature
or they call it homo economic times
or economic man
all who basically
behaves
chooses reasons
makes judgments
based on
this idealize description
of how judgments and reza means are made
one
cleaner expression of this normative
model of judgment and reasoning is an
emphasis on the use of algorithms
in reasoning band
our judgment
and problem solving
we define algorithms as logical
systematic rules
for making trip
this and inferences
and the idea behind it
algorithms
is that
if you're confronted with a problem
that's soluble
problem that can be solved
application all of the appropriate
algorithm will inevitably lead too
the correct
okay if a problem a salary will
application of the appropriate algorithm
will inevitably lead to the correct
answer
therefore it follows that if people were
rational in their judgment all of the
judgments and decision making if they
were rational and their choices and the
way they went about solving problems
then they would always employ algorithms
whenever they were confronted
with any kind of problem
the emphasis on algorithms is part of
the parcel off
all rational on choice view
all-volunteer in judgment and decision
making
let's take a detailed below those
all about estimation
suppose you want to are
estimate how many people there are
living in united states
farm
bellcore's who could compromise suppose
and we do every ten years in this
instance
but that's a lot of work
okay
so what you really want to do with the
problem is
to come up with a reasonable estimate
of the number of people who are living
in united states
arm this is a problem dot or his
currently confronted by the federal
government for that matter state
governments
in the problem of the argument in the
problem of the census
united states constitution
mandates that ever intended
there be a cult
all of the number of people living in
the united states so as to correctly
apportion fitness like congressional or
rub representatives
but for a brother things as well
it's turning out to be too difficult to
do any headcount
of people
there's simply too many people united
states
living under too many different kinds of
conditions in too many places
alerted to even uh... that expect that
there be a reasonably accurate head
count
saw there from time to time
there are proposals
too
all-out use statistical criteria or
statistical process ease
to get our best estimate of what
this head counters
and in fact we know how to do that
there is an algorithm
statistical algorithms around for
estimation
and basically they say
first what you want to do is to draw a
representative sample of the population
or perhaps a random sample
or perhaps what's known as a stratified
sample so you didn't make sure you have
equal numbers of men and women in your
sample or
something like that
and then what you do is you count that
representative sample of the population
and then you extrapolate from the sample
too with a population at large in again
there are rules in statistics
for figuring out
her buchanan forever
population values from the values of
samples
following these kinds of rules
it's known
that we're very unlikely to make a
mistake estimating the population of the
united states statistically
armed doesn't under count the poor
it doesn't under count
minorities as far as
whereas because
people
and members of ethnic minority groups
often live
outside the mainstream all fall
dot of society
it's very difficult to get of proper
account of these individuals with an
actual headcount course a legal problem
is that the constitution mandates a head
count
as you've got account these people you
can't estimate them so there's a
difficult legal question here but the
point is we know how to do this
statisticians of known for a hundred
years
how did produce
very very good estimates of large
numbers
like the population all the united
states
and they don't by applying various kinds
of algorithms
approach to
the use of algorithms in
problem solving in making judgments
is itself
an example of a lot
attitude for problem solving
known as means and analysis
in the means and analysis all problem
solving
we take we've we began first
the elements
the features that are common to all
problems
all problems have a set of germans
assumptions
that you can make
about the state of the world
second
all problems have
specified in them some goal that want to
achieve
third
there are transformations that have to
take place
to get from
the original state of the problem to the
bell st of the problem and then finally
there are some obstacles
on the way to the colstate
these obstacles are kind of defining
features of problems you don't have a
problem and then some there's some
saluted some obstacle or two with so to
a solution
but the general idea
is that when you've got any problem to
solve
what you do is the first thing to do is
you forearm on mental representation of
your current state
then you form a mental representation of
your goal state
you calculate the difference between
your current state and your goal state
and then you take some steps that will
reduce that difference by some amount
and then what you do
is you recalculate
we represent
the goal state and your current state
recalculate the difference and then take
another step
that will reduce that still further
i walked over here from my office and
pullman hall this morning
and when i thought about it i thought
about that but it was raining action
without
how my going to get to pullman hall
on with the uh... with them with the
yield minimum likelihood that i'm gonna
get wet
so i try to calculate a shortcut
and so what i did was alright instead of
going down the steps nearest may all go
down some steps or the over here that'll
let me
walker undercover for a little bit
longer
i represented my current state
i represented the goals date
calculated the difference between them
and then took some steps
reduce that difference
all
applications of means and the problem
solving
involved this kind of process
it's something it's a process that
it's been studied into a problem very
fickle your problem in the psychological
literature
known as a tower of hanoi problem
which basically says unhone away there's
a temple
in with there's a tolerance thx t four
sacred goldman discs each trimmed with
diamonds
and these discs are stacked on top of
each other in such a way that the
largest
and the smallest is on the top
and a problem for the monks in the
temple
is to move the disks from one location
to another in such a way
that a larger discussed replaced on
top of a smaller desk
and that's fine you can figure out how
to do that radius
onto disks and
put them over there
but no there's an obstacle the first
obstacle is that you have to move the
discs one-at-a-time
the second obstacle is you'd have to dot
do it in such a way
that their arden never larger disk on
top of a smaller desk
and the third obstacle is
either as sacred desks
and there's only one other place in the
temple where they can be hollows okay so
how are you going to do the problem
here orthodox how we're going to do it
how long's are going to take
the legend is that before the monks
complete the task the world will end
i think that's the legend of the tower
of happily
here's a simple representation of it
we've got
a tolerant discs
small on top of larger on top of the
largest
we want to get them from this location
the dislocation and there's only one
other location where the discs
can be stored so how do we do this who
wants to do the powerful wipro
i see something you do it
flustered wonder
you know i don't
okay let's do it
how to solve this problem
for one of the melbourne
their eg that's exactly right that's
exactly how you get it
and notice how to get our life for you
and your couple of other people didn't
and doing this right yeah i calculate my
cardiac calculate what you want to go
against step-by-step reduce the
difference between where you are and
where you want to go
that's the means and algorithm for
problem solving and that there's a
problem that soluble the means and
analysis and guaranteed to produce dot
correct answer now of course i can take
a long time
it turns out r_k_ that by doing this at
all of this way if you were actually
sitting in the tower of hanoi
are moving sixty four just in this way
all at the rate of one per second would
take five billion years
that's it
pretty much the age of the earth
all right so
well it's a pretty good guess that the
monks are not going to finish this task
before your calms ought to an end
for your is absent exercise this week
you're going to do a version of this
problem on known as the harvard supports
problem actually zaps calls at the
missionaries in cannibals problem
but it has the same kind of all
although property to it
on one side of the river there's free
hobbits and three works
orcs eve hobbits when they are a number
of them
the creatures have a boat that's cable
taking too
individuals at a time across the river
and the goal is to transport all six
creatures from one side of the river
ought to the other with the proviso that
at no time
in either location
can works out number hoffitz
now that's formally
pretty much the same as the power of
hanoi problem
and you solve it
using the of means and problem solving
analysis though some of those of you
who've already done that's number for
you know that there is
a kind of subtle obstacle
or here
and all the that to you
to figure out
exactly songs exactly what that is
again
means the end
approaches to problem solving
exemplified this algorithmic reasoning
the algorithm constitutes essentially a
recipe for solving a problem that
specifies all all the necessary
ingredients
and their amounts
and of the order in which they're going
to combine are and if you follow a
recipe if you've got all the ingredients
new fall the recipe carefully you're
gonna get i'd take
fried tofu or whatever it is that you're
eating right cooked properly
and something that's in of that so addl
all you have to do
is follow
the steps
this same kind of approach
tendon principal be used
to solve a fundamental cognitive problem
which is approx on the of categorization
categorization is an extremely important
aspect of all of cognition
where we sort the objects of the world
into categories
are based on
some kind of similarity
so all cars
you know buicks and
dodges end
homers and twenty orders
they all belong in the category of
automobiles because they have certain
features in common
although do you think about perception
cognitively
the endpoint of perception is not simply
to identify the distal stimulus the
treaty or the gorilla or the dinosaur or
whatever
but you also wants the categorized an
object
so that you know what to do with it
because they are yes i know what this is
it's like these other things or you
already know what to do along with
the great cognitive psychologist jerome
bruder
went so far as to argue that every act
perception
is an active categorization
because when you perceived an object
you perceive that as similar to
somethings you already know about
and different from
other things that you already know about
and the question is
how do we go about categorizing the
objects in our world
again there's a classical view of this
process accomplice
from aristotle
and basically says
don't too bold
logical way to think about categories
is in terms of property sets you
probably remember the term proper sets
from
eighth grade
mathematics maybe ninth-grade
mathematics
all in dog did in that the in separate
or proper set
is a set of objects
that have a set of defining features in
common
and a defining feature these defining
features are signalling necessary
to identify an object is a member of a
set
and
the package of features is jointly
sufficient to identify an object as
remember of the part of the set
give you some examples
so in cat in geometry
for example
we have a set of
are geometrical figure is known as
triangles
which are defined as two-dimensional
figures
with three sides and three angles
all triangles
or two-dimensional figures with three
sides and three angles
that div those features
define the category of triangles in
geometry
all up and that's different
from the definition in geometry o
quadrilateral sp
which are features into dimensions
that have four sides
and four angles
all quadrilateral our share
these three defining features on in
common two dimensions
four sides and for angles
similarly
in the domain of animals
we distinguish between categories of
birds
robbins sparrows eagles hawks
trout
bass
salmon grouper
earth will it ever
all all birds arbroath births with were
warm-blooded
and have further someone's
all birds or warm-blooded vertebrates
with feathers and wings
bos four features
or a single enough history
and jointly sufficient to define the
category of bird
whereas all fish
or cold-blooded vertebrates
with scales and fins
those four features
or a single investors there re
and jointly sufficient to define the
category of fish
every creature that's abort abort
cold-blooded
with scales and fins is a fish
just the way fisher defined
all by home
by zoologists
and sold that's generally that that's
the idea about defining features
now
another aspect all categorization bright
by proper sets
is that
you can
arrange categories vertically
into hierarchies
of super it sets
and subsets
and the general idea
is that in the proper said
categorization
subsets are perfectly nested
under super sets let me give you an
example of that
again we'll go back to geometric figures
there are
here's the whole
class of geometric figures out of up
here
and it turns out that there are
floor
types bob geometric figures
points
lines planes and solids what's the
definition of a point
religion electorate
okay
is a geological figuring no dimensions
k points don't have any dimensions right
what's the line
one dimension if you don't want to
mention your align
planes to dimensions solids three
dimensions
here we have geometric figures
arranged a december sets
according to the number of dimensions
and then we have
types of planes like triangles and
quadrilateral
all triangles
are two-dimensional figures all
quadrilateral czar two-dimensional
figures but what we've done is we've
added by defining feature
triangles our planes
with three fives
quadrilateral zz our planes
with forrest sawyer
and then we have subsets of triangles
okay
what some people lateral triangle
what's the definition
all sides article altered equal at all
triangles equal five equal angles i saw
sleaze triangles
two sides are equal
scaling triangles
no sides
are equal same thing with quadrilateral
created subsets based on
dark features had to do with your
quality of sides and angles
but notice that there is a perfect
nesting here
all equal lateral triangles are
triangles
all triangles our planes at all planes
are geometric figures
it's not the case of equal lateral
triangles are kinda quadrilateral
or that trapezoidal or a kind of solid
while there are tropical alaska let's
not get into
uh... was like a tinder that the point
here is
in
classification according to proper sets
sets can be
arrange the hierarchy of subsets and
super sets
by simply adding or subtracting defining
features we ad
defining features
triangles and quadrilateral
we add defining features
to get people lateral
and i sasa lease triangles
and so on
another feature of categories as proper
sets
has to do with the horizontal relations
between categories and it follows
from the motion of the proper sad
he said membership hasn't all along or
non quality to it
you're either indosat
or you're not in the set
if you're a geometric will figure you're
either a triangle
or a quadrilateral or something else
there are no geometrical figures that
are kind of
kind of triangles and kinda
quadrilateral as you've either scot-free
slides and three angles
or you don't have three sides in three
angles
you're either in the set or not
put another way
there are very sharp
boundaries
between adjacent categories
there's a sharp boundary between being a
triangle indiana quadrilateral yes
all okay
let's go back to our perfectly dusted
nesting here okay
squares are kinds of rectangles
so there's actually a subset here
depending on how all rectangles
have four equal angles
okay
the difference between a square in the
not us wareham in that category is what
you've got people sides
so all squares are rectangles
technically all rectangles are parallel
grams but here
i'm talking about there being just two
parallels uh... unparalleled sides aka
rectangles
here we have all the subsides parallel
here we've added another feature
albrecht of the simplified diagram do
you get the idea
the bite amin features
you create subsets
good question
let's go back here for a second again
if you're a geometrical figure your
peter all liner a plane or us or a solid
or something else
because you get a gun general dimensions
one dimension to or three p
if you're a plane
you're either a triangle or
quadrilateral there's no in between
if you're a triangle
you're either an equal lateral triangle
or and i saw sleaze triangle or scaling
tribal
again there's no in between
and terms of
horizontal relations among adjacent
categories
there's a sharp
division
between adjacent categories your reader
and one category
or your
another feature of categories as proper
sets
is that they have what we call
homogeneous internal structure
by which we mean
all instances alta category
or equally good instances of a category
unequal lateral triangle
is a perfectly good triangle
because it's got three sides in three
angles through dimensions
and then i saw sleaze triangle
is a perfectly good triangle because
it's got
three sides and three angles in two
dimensions
it's not that unequal lateral triangle
is in some sense of better triangle
okay
they're different but they are all have
the same defining features
because all members all of a proper set
share the same defining features in
common
week improper set theory
we consider all instances of a category
to be equally representative of that
category six all sugar
the same set
defining
features
so again
from the proper said view of
categorization
all logical view account of a recession
that goes back at least for the time of
aristotle
we can generate and algorithm
for determining category membership of
an object
if you want to define a category
all you have to do
is to determine
what the defining features are of deck
all you have to do is to determine
what features
all category members share in common
what features are singly necessary
and jointly sufficient
to define that category
more important
if you want to characterize an object
the proper said view of categorization
gives you an algorithm for doing that as
well
if i hold something awful and say
is this an envelope
then what you do is
first you analyze the features of the
object to use your perceptual apparatus
to figure out what the features or the
object
then
you retrieved from memory
your knowledge of the defining features
of that category and then you simply
match the features of the object the
perceived features of the object
defining features of the category
represented in memory and if there's a
match usse yes this is a member
okay
so if i show you an object i say is this
an automobile
you look for things like four wheels and
internal combustion engine and this and
that you say audience it has all the
features or mobile so i'm going to call
it an automobile
this isn't algorithm
the pro if the problem of categorization
of soluble if there's an answer to the
question
is x a member of category wayy applying
this kind of algorithm where you simply
match the features up
all in terms of diff
in features
tell you
an object is a member of
the category or
are again
if you're
want to know whether or not ject is a
triangle
see if it's a plane
see that's got three sides see the sky
three angles of a dozen triangle that's
the end of it
and you will
so again
from this point of view
categorization is fundamental cognitive
problem
is something
that can be solved by the application
of a
single
are simple algorithm
and of course if that were true i
wouldn't have spent so much time
described in this
turns out
but there are some
serious problems
the classical view
of categories as proper sets
in the first place
there are some
categories
that have what part did better known as
disjunctive categories
peter because
objects in the categories
do not necessarily share features in
common
there's one very familiar example
and that's the strike
in baseball who's a baseball fan here
how do you define a strike in baseball
no but we're talking about the within
the game
pitch has to cross the plate
and it also has to be at a particular
hike that has to be roughly from the
needs of the batter to roughly though
armpits
all that ur okay
that's one definition of a strike what's
another definition the strike
in baseball
dot the only definition yes
a fireball okay
fobel's also a strike
what's another
definition of a strike
are swimming in a message does it matter
whether a crosses the plate if you swing
and miss
that's also a strike
i don't know what that is
what else are what else gets called a
strike
in baseball
it's a strike if the umpires says it's a
strike
project
so now we got for different things
they are all strikes in baseball than or
equal under the category of strike they
have no features in common
okay no features in common
so this is an example of a disjunctive
category
another example somewhat less familiar
to many people
is the category of jazz often call form
of music
what's the definition of jazz
yeah but what is jet what what what kind
of music and jazz music
lots of that's a theory about what jazz
means in creole that's right on to have
sex on we're not going to her okay
bargain jazz turns out to be very
difficult to define
we think about jazz is a form of music
that's based on improvisation
but church organist improvise when they
play bach so that's not
singly necessary
also we think about jazz has been based
in a musical form known as blues twelve
bar blues were calling response although
format
but there it for some forms of jazz like
swing
that are bluesy role
also there and get them we have a
disjunctive category here
there are
piece of the music that are classified
as jazz
that don't have any features in common
the fact
have a category like the strike in
baseball
but it's not
characterized in terms of singly
necessary in jointly support and
defining features
is a problem
with the classical view of categories as
proper sense
here's another problem
there are many
objects
where whose category membership is on
clear
for example if i ask you is or rocket an
article of furniture
who says rug is an article of furniture
who says it isn't
see there you go
you know what what is
everybody or not everybody can override
his
everybody here know what article for
nurturers
how com you can tell me
how come there's disagreement about
whether a broad is an article of
furniture
similarly is a pickle a vegetable
well yeah i think pickles a vegetable
but you don't really like serena pickles
the finished rolled right it's not like
broccoli or green beans at something
like that
in fact the reagan administration got
into a great deal of trouble
whenever brady should rules for school
lunches in which they classified pickle
relish as a vegetable
augsburg for purposes of counting
whether kids were getting bashed ables
or not
so i can
one of the problems here is that there
are many familiar categories
and many familiar objects
whose category membership is on clear
this is actually
the source of an important of a very
interesting legal problem
bad weather a tomato is a fruit a
revenge triple
who says it's meals a fruit
who says a tomatoes a vegetable
asi there is another one
indeed terrorist activity american
tariff act of eighteen thirty three
all of the imposed a double duty import
duty on vegetables imported to this
country in their natural state
but there was no duty on fruits
the customs collector for the port of
new york
declared tomatoes to be vegetables for
the purposes of collecting
all of this import duty
i swear this is true there was an
organizational as the international
tomato cartel
which so would it be customs collector
for the port of new york
claiming the tomatoes were fruits and
therefore not subject
to this import duty
a case of went all the way to the
supreme court
fair in a decision written by mister
just as great
he concluded that but honestly speaking
tomatoes are the fruit of the ball
bovine
but in the common language of the people
these are all vegetable like potatoes
carrots and lettuce usually served at
dinner in the width or after
the small fisherman's
which constitute the principal part of
the repairs
and not as fruits
generally hasn't developed
when you look at it
what you see that
justice gray is not alkaline thought
proper set notion of categorization here
okay
he's the clarion
tomatoes to be vegetables
even though you know once
that vegetables or fruits
and why is he declaring tomatoes to be
vegetables
because we're treat them as vegetables
they seem to go with vegetables you put
tomatoes on your cell that you do output
tomatoes on your cornflakes
we concert tomatoes to be vegetables on
but that although on and and that's and
that's basically the way it is
what u
one other point one of the problems with
this
proper set view of categorization
is that it's sometimes very difficult to
specify
the defining features all of
categories that are familiar to us
we use certain categories all the time
but if you put a gun you're head and
said tell me what the segue necessary in
jointly sufficient defining features are
you would have a lot of difficulty
the classic example is the concept of
game
of want something that the philosopher
victim stein worried about a lot if u
workup
detainment in the are dictionary
you find it defined as
competitive physical or mental activity
engaged in for amusement
okay
which is fine
except that there are lots of things
that we classify his games that don't
fit this at this uh... definition
likes solitaire
solitaire there's no competition
you're not even competing with yourself
rated sensitivities
their children's game of women around
the rosy
has no winner
you can't win ring around the rosy right
now just it's not possible to bring it
uh... yet
children play this game hours and hours
and hours on end
and then you can take something like
professional football
which is not
a source of amusement
its work it's hard work people get hurt
and so on
are there's nothing funny about
professional of nothing funny about
professional football
so i can the prod the point here
sometimes very difficult to specify
just what it is that makes a game a gain
nevertheless this is a concept
that we use quite frequently
it's a concept with which were all
are familiar
here's a more recent example
the concept of planet
you looked that up in the dictionary
and you see planets defined as
a celestial body that revolves around a
star but does not revolve around another
celestial
that's a perfectly fine definition
planet except when you start considering
that there are lots of things that seem
to meet this definition
that we don't want to call planets
like need yours
okay which revolve around celestial body
okay
fine
but we're not going to admit media risk
into the category of planets
comets too
okay
and then they are objects in our solar
system like series which is as big a
hunger rock out there between jupiter
and saturn
all and this anew a planet dot sometimes
known as veto
all that all of the orbit so i won't be
on the orbit all vocal pluto
discovery of series ends in a row
created a definitional crisis for
restaurant owners
because they will realize that the
concept of planet that they've been
working with since the time for the
astrologers just didn't work any longer
okay
although
and especially have this problem of or
pluto pluto just doesn't look like any
of the other planets okay
it's real small
it's very far-out in the solar system
it has is very wierd orbit but doesn't
look like any of the other orbits uh...
in nam
uh... of the home of the planets
so we have these objects
that fit the definition of a plan of a
planet but we don't want to call them
plucked
and then we have this object that we
call a planet
that doesn't really fit the definition
of
the category
so what happened couple years ago
actually last year
all the concept of planet god redefine
they were actually fist fights at the
international astronomical union
about how to define planet
also we now have
plan is defined as
an object that orbits the sun
with enough gravity to compress its
fears with that gets rid of series which
is not spherical
and enough gravity to clear it's orval
neighborhood that gets reduced our
series but it also go through pluto
okay
also the pluto is no longer a planet
because it doesn't have enough gravity
to clear it so
it's horrible on the neighborhood
this is a problem that is still being
confronted by astronomers okay
the next meeting of the international
astronomical union two thousand nine
is going to take up the definition of a
planet again
now astronomers have been doing their
business for or really long time
and they still can't figure out what a
planet is
this is not a criticism of astronomers
this is just a really good example of
how sometimes it's very difficult to
specify
the defining features
categories
yet another problem
with these traditional definition of
categories categorization
is a phenomenon known as in perfect
nesting
think about are nicely nested
categorization of animals and a fish and
birds and birds into
examples of birds
subtypes likes peril and chicken
according too
proper said fuel categorization
it should be
it's easiest to identify an object as an
instance of a
closely adjacent category
so it turns out to be easier to identify
this peril as a bird
that it is to identify a sparrow as an
animal
subjects will take less time to identify
a sparrow as a bird than they will
identify espero
as an animal
because these categories or further away
but quite the opposite happens when u_s_
people dot chickens
people have a lot of difficulty they
take a long time
to identify a chicken
as a bird
but they take a look at least short time
to identify of chicken as an animal
part of the other way
chechans
are represented mentally as animals but
not as birds even doctrines are birds
the concept of chicken
is in perfectly nested
the category
and then finally related to this
we have variations in what's known as
typical ality
uh... in the home elegant inn
categorization
i've already alluded to one of these
variations
pluto just doesn't seem to be like the
other planets ok it's not a typical
planet
mars and venus and jupiter their typical
planets
similarly
if u_s_ people what up to two name
typical birds
build name
words like sparrows and robbins and
evils
but they will not name
words like
chickens
and aust riches
and penguins
even though they're all warm blue
blooded vertebrates
with feathers and wings
valuation untypical ality
among the members all the category
creates problems for them
proper said view of categorization
because
from not point of view of the proper
said fuel categorization
categories are homogeneous
all instances of a category are equally
glued
members of what category
but that's evidently not true everybody
agrees
that a sparrow is a better example of
the category bird
than it should do this
okay everybody agrees about that
a sparrow is simply a more a birdie bird
then triggered this
here is some data collected by the
barclays own eleanor rauscher was a
pioneer
involved would lead us to change our
understanding of categories
here are some typical
categories furniture vegetable bird and
fruit she presented her subjects with
instances of these categories
and simply as subjects to rape
howard an example
each of these instances
so that people think chair
is a really good example of our of
of furniture
but ashtray he is not
abroad gets a very
pete and corn there are very good
examples a vegetable
tomato is a pretty good example
all vegetable remember tomatoes not
vegetable
okay
but we think tomato was a much better
example vegetables in a pickle is
for example all and fruit
okay we actually think a pickle has a
better example of fruit
then a tomato is
on here bird sparrow was a much better
example rate a much better example of
then chicken is
now you can say okay what he's a weird
categories
here it is work cargo right your own
textbooks author andrea lilac live and
work in the decline of our graduate
student
where we take examples
of categories that are clearly proper
sets
and again present subjects with examples
of them
and ask them to raise how puttin example
they are
subjects think
that the number four is a better example
of the category even number
then the number-two
annul sixes
they think that the number three is a
better example
of the category pod number
than the number four hundred and forty
seven is
they think the squares and rectangles
are better examples of plane geometry
figures
denny ellipses are
and i think that mothers and housewives
are better examples of the category
female then princesses
or police women are
all of these instances
jerry incumbent
the singling necessary and jointly
sufficient defining features of category
membership
and everybody recognizes that
everybody recognizes that these are that
these are
classic instances a proper sense
nevertheless
people
perceive
differences into the calorie
within these categories that she would
not occur
if we think about categories and proper
sense
why does this happen
the factors of here's another good
example this or ed smith and his
colleagues
as subjects to classify
highly typical medium for the kelly a
low typical objects
arctic sibal lot less time
took tickled to categorize a highly
typical
instance of a allah category
as opposed to an atypical instance of
the category
typically affects in calories they
should
are any real problem
it turns out
none of these problems what occurred
if we actually used
algorithms in the process of
categorization
none of those problems would occur we
wouldn't have any it difficult to know
whether or raw does nordica love
furniture
or whether it tomato was approved or a
vegetable
the fact that these problems do occur
suggests
that way
actually
categorize objects
in a way that's quite different
from the logical
rational
algorithm implied by the proper set
view of categories
apparently
or mental concepts are not structured
like proper sets after all
and on wednesday
i'll tell you how they are structured
thank you very much
i'll see you on wednesday