okay when we begin
and before i get to leave first lecture on
psychological development
well just review the bidding on the exam that
you took last week
uh... thanks to the quick work of the g_s_a_
lies we got that scored very fast
there was just one bad item number ten
the uh... item analysis psalm uh... revealed
and so we we scored that one correct
for all responses
and when we did that
because distribution of scores of books like
this
means gore about thirty-nine
median score reporting very very good performance
on the exam
and again you can see
characteristic
on curve not exactly a verbal distribution
but not bad
that's the yellow buoy the exam came out
as i say it was very very pleased
often a couple of you have frog
query me about
data input there isn't a great book
i made a couple
i didn't make couple of others all but the
deadline for requested their hand we scored
your spent runs is wednesday
afternoon so we want to get all the stuff
taken care of
before the final exam
is is upon us
i posted
complete feedback on the exam to the court's
website united analysis little commentary
on the to the items
on i haven't heard anything all
were close to the forum
about that
okay we're gonna talk about thingy development
of mind and especially a personality getting
today
and all in order to do that but i want to
do first is simply too
all point out
that in the previous lectures
we've taken pretty much taken mind and personality
as a given
we've looked at how
normal intact sometimes brain-damaged adults
engage in perception and memory and thinking
we've looked at
personality and how we have interacts with
the social environment to produce various
aspects of social behavior
and what we want to do now is the figure is
to try to understand how we get that way
how do we come to proceeded remembering thank
the way we do
how do we get the personalities that we have
that internet shape the environments in which
we our work
in asking this question of where my obtained
and a personality come from
we can identify reader for weight
of answering that question
an aunt or genetic view of development
a file a genetic view of development
and any cultural view of development
v
why would you know that
view which will take first
all really is concerned with
the evolution
mental and behavioral characteristics
evolution doesn't just shape
morphology of the body
it turns out evolution also shade certain
aspects of how the mind works
and certain aspects of behavior
and then older time again
on psychology
this file a genetic view of development that
is a development
of mind you don't cross species
all was all expressed by uh... the sump you'll
notice comparative psychology
which would try to compare
different species of animals
humans chimpanzees rats dogs cats
octopus
hauled all fins
whatever
on various mental tasks
all specially learning tasks
to see a follow up their various species stacked
up against each other
more recently however this file or genetic
new development
has been expressed in a relatively new subfield
on psychology known as evolutionary psychology
related for those who've taken as solar sociology
course related ballfield and sociology known
as socio biology
and basically what evolutionary psychology
tries to do
is to understand how our mental characteristics
evolved over the course of hominid evolution
on the jet the general idea is that
the way we think about
is something that evolved in this environment
of early adaptation basically the east african
savannah
somewhere at some time in a place to see there
are a couple
hundred thousand years ago
and that that's where our mental characteristics
came from
and one of the ideas that the evolutionary
psychologists have
is that the players kinds of the errors that
we've sometimes make unreasoning
or due to the fact that are resilient apparatus
our brains evolved in that this environment
are trying to use
although i don't know about the
referendums
involved in an earlier environment
to halt
think about baker and environment and that's
what leads us to make certain kinds of mistakes
i did not sure
haul for you what i think that but that is
a very new trend and uh... the psychology
today
the cultural view of development
has its origins in nineteenth century psychological
anthropology
as european countries spain
portugal
england
friends
germany awg branched out and began to develop
colonies in africa age uh... and south america
early anthropologist began to be interested
in doing mental comparisons all between
believe that if you will the conquerors
and the concord there is an emphasis on earlier
for political psychology on mental characteristics
between so-called advanced societies
uh... and so-called primitive societies
we don't think about
alguna development
onto cultural development quite this way anymore
uh... but still there are certain characteristics
ald
cultures
which may shape
how the people who belong who live in those
cultures
of
you know that fake
especially of interest this w of development
is the advent of literacy
does being able to read and write
make a difference the how people think
we know that being able to read and write
eases the demands on human memory between
have lecture notes
for example is that it had to do it
figure out
retain at all using the method of low side
or something like that
and that may very well change
how we remember
all similarly
forms of economic development
reforms a political development
it's been argued
all of the shape
how the individuals who live under those various
kinds of regimes of work
again this idea that
cultural development
affects how people in that culture think
on is a pop
identified with a field psychology known as
cultural psychology
which basically
begins with the assumption that there is a
diverse city of mind
as well as diverse city all of gender all
raise sold off socioeconomic status whatever
that not all people think the same way
that people of different cultures
may think differently in certain respects
and those differences in
modes of thought
differences and habits of thought
will although that will all affect
the relations between all of those cultures
the file a genetic to development cultural
view of the relevant both very important but
they're not going to be the focus all of these
lectures
and are not really the focus of your textbook
material either
off the lectures and the tax focus on the
third view of development
which is known as the aren't road genetic
view of development
which has to do
with the development of of mind and behavior
overload mobile life course onto individual
species members
from birth
through infancy the childhood adolescence
adulthood middle-age old age seven cents
hollow do with the various modes of thought
change
how does personality how do well
forms of social interaction change
as the all person the individual person moves
through this particular life-cycle
this is a traditional focus of what's known
as
developmental psychology
very big subfield uh... in psychology
and again we can break down
the uh... be you know interest of development
psychology
into true broad categories
cognitive development
how thinking develops as the individual develops
and the social and personality development
how person how we get our personalities and
how those personalities change over time
your textbook depaz adolph lot of attention
the to both these aspects of development
especially good i think is glickman's chapter
on cognitive development
i'm not going to have too much to say about
cognitive development in these lectures
what i want to do instead
is to focus on social personality development
and ask the question
of basically
how do we get the way we are
each of us has some level of
extra version and eroticism in agreeable this
and conscientious those
that of facts are
although our intercourse with other people
and a question as how we get that way
the way we usually think about this
is that we get the way we are
through what combination of forces
that are generally doggone thing
subsumed under the rubric of
nature
and nurture this is a dichotomy
that was off
originally proposed
uh... by two hundred fifty years ago by surprises
colton darwin's on cousin
and in spot erred by uh... passage from shakespeare
on in the tempest where of prospero says no
taliban
the taliban with the devil
well boring devil on whose nature nurture
can never stick that is taliban's boorda double
and nothing but you do to him is going to
change him and anyway
simply argued that
shakespearian dichotomy of nature and nurture
was a convenient way to separating
two different kinds of developmental inference
that all of them influences
the two different fault uh... elements
of which personality is composed
and golden
went on to define
palm
his terms
naturist although the man although the person
brings in tune with the world with him
nowadays we think about in terms of the individuals
genetic and almonds
what genes he or she is carrying with jeans
here she's been given but i
the repair roads
or moral endowment
although
various aspects of constitution whether the
person on has any physical infirmities ans
bored with any physical and for all of the
uh... differences or whatever
or for that matter individual differences
in uh... in temperament
all by the convoy contrast
nurturer
on gold find as
every influence that affects the person
from birth
onward
and that includes both the physical environment
physical circumstances under which in individuals
raise
but especially the social environment
the are going to be matrix of other people
into which the person is boring
and nurture generally covers things like
the individuals history of social learning
or socialization regimes are imposed on the
individual
but basically
everything that happens to the individual
over it his or her life courts
now it just to all make a point in passing
you've seen this dichotomy of nature and nurture
before you thought of the perception chapter
where we talked about are philosophical nativism
versus philosophical empiricism
the database
believe that
all
individuals were born with certain kinds of
innate knowledge
whereas the empiricism
believe that
the individual was born the aid blank slate
with pablo rostock in latin
on which
all of the individual was written buying experience
the nature and nurture dichotomy
as some of the same characteristics
when we discover that somebody is high on
extra version or high under rod a schism or
something like that
we could do you think
that he or she dot that way
it is just naturally that weight because they
were genes for these things for example
or we can think
that the person somehow learned see that way
through a history uh...
social
expertise
and in fact if you look in the literature
at the traditional literature on nature and
nurture
you'll see
uh... in in some ways
the hall
deal
conflict between nature and nurture in development
recapitulate in some ways
dot khan that conflict between the person
and the environment
that we talked about in the last of for lectures
for example it very common
to c
nature and nurture
genes and environment
opposed to each other
one
was important
and the odd on wasn't important at all
a kind of oppositional
stands between
nature and nurture
or are somewhat more altman co comfortable
stands for people that they are all well it's
both
on somebody's high-end extra virgin
they've got jeans for your extra virgin and
they've also been brought up to be actor burt
that nature and nurture
are both important personality development
but that they are somehow
independent
of each other
ceo word like independence
special intercourse run by me
he wonders and that's not the final answer
that in fact
what bergen or whatever
his house nature and nurture interact
to produce our mental characteristics
to give us
the personalities
that we have
if in fact there is a kind of
what i like to think of as a developmental
corollary
to the doctrine of interaction ism that we
talked about last time
remember that the doctrine of interaction
is absurd
that person's on
fireman's are not separate from each other
they interact in a very real sense a person
bizarre part of his or her own environment
in the same way when it comes to development
we're going to see that development
isn't just something that happens to the individual
okay
not something that you're coming to dubai
virtual forces
completely outside your control
but just as the person as a part of his or
her open environment
so it's going to turn out
that the child ism agent
of his
worker
development
we see this
all very clearly
all when we try that we're going to look at
something like the development of gender identity
and gender roles
what happens
when a little boy or a little girl
grows up to be a more or less masculine man
on more or less
feminine all-female
well it turns out the blood turns out that
that developmental process can be viewed
through the lens all be person-to-person situation
fraction and we can see n p psychological
development of all
or the of gender
evocation selection
behavioral manipulation and cognitive transformation
all drew this very briefly
we've already talked about how
that child's gender structures the fireman's
in which that child is going to be raise
that physical appearance all of the newborn
infant
whether it looks like a boy
or whether it looks like a girl
is going to determine
whether it's bedroom is painted blue or pink
whether against twenty trucks or dull carriages
to play with
weather gets footballs or dolls what it meant
that when it when an adult straight
all of that
the is taught environmental change that is
evoked by the physical appearance of the trial
little bit later on
children begin to notice their own gender
may begin to
think of themselves as boys or girls
and data begin that they've been recognize
themselves as boys and girls
and they begin to actively model their behavior
on or other people who look like now
so little be little girls
start emulating
the older girls and the women and their environment
little boys star daniel eighteen the older
boys and the older girls and their environment
they are selecting an environment for themselves
and what they say
i want to be with those people that look like
me
on a whatever those people who have a look
like me
that is the trial selecting
his or her or environment
similarly
there are examples engender development
all behavioral manipulation
it's just a matter of fact
nevermind what
reasons are
but it's just a matter of fact that the average
little boy
has somewhat higher activity levels than the
average little girl does it's got something
to do with testosterone uh... we don't have
to go into the details there
but it dog a bottle of little boy in an environment
is going to make that it
different
if there was a little girl in that environment
all color in his or her place
so gender activities and
on the gender differences in activity level
our behaviors lead to give rise to be haters
that change the environment
for the child
and then finally
uh... as the arms of the child gets to be
age four five six begins to have a
begins to getty
all more or less fixed identity for itself
as a little boy you're a little girl
then what happens
is that the child on begins to
or actively
embrace
various gender appropriate behaviors
as they are defined by the situation
all allied
all that that is that their department of
child's all the culture
so it's not just that the tribe the kid says
i want to be with those people will look like
me
the child says
i'm a little boy
i wanted to avoid things
i'm a little girl
i want to do
girl things whatever they are
all in new york ny barb
okay so again
just a small example
of how various modes of persons situation
interaction
play themselves out in activity in the development
of the individual
sold at in each of these ways
the child
exit active role in its development
of becomes an agent
of his or
old development
traditionally however
the nature under juror
dichotomy
has been viewed in terms of one that counter
poses
jeans and environment
and that's going to be the theme for the rest
of the lecture on today
here is where we begin
this is a deal
by you know that's near albany when genome
all twenty three
pairs of chromosomes
there's an extra was so
there was a white chromosome into of so-called
sex chromosomes
this is what they look like
that's what they're what what looked like
about nineteen seventy two when this particular
illustration or was off was published
this is what the human genome
looks like
just a couple weeks ago on craig banter who
is one of the awful pioneers all board of
of genetic analysis has produced published
the first genetic autobiography
is publishing autobiography
that is on where the individual chapters are
dictated by if you if you will by his jeans
here's his
this is that there is a poem gene shamir are
taken from all of the new york times
twenty-two
uh... peers chromosomes and an external body
and what bob enters don
is going to identify on chromosome one
i've done gene that's linked to heart attacks
on
chromosomes seven
another gene that's mine
for heart attacks
here on chromosome all grow chromosome twelve
budget investment will be city an insulin
resistance
here on chromosome twenty one
it gene that is linked
to of ordered them to alcoholism
the advance since nineteen seventy two war
in nineteen fifty four
on thundered through wanted to die
is that we'd be going to identify individual
genes that dispose people to have certain
kinds of pomp
physical
and behavioral
and mental characteristics
there are
in the kind of short had
jeans four
things i've got a gene for alcoholism i got
a gene for breast cancer i've got a gene for
possible conviction or whatever
behind this idea that there are genes
four things
is a particular version on genetic determination
the idea that somehow genes are decisive
in this process
center doesn't believe this is a more sophisticated
all view of all of genetic
uh...
heritage
that most people but the when you read about
this stuff in the newspapers
you begin to see this cut this idea that there
are genes four things
presumably
on creating these things out of whole cloth
all quite a bit
but in fact
as we now know
genes expressed themselves through the environment
there's no genetic influences in the absence
of environmental influence
g king's and environments interact in various
kinds of ways
so when we think about
how nature and nurture genes and environment
a direct
we want to distinguish first
between and individuals genotype and his or
her
phenotype
the genotype you can think of because of biological
potential
what you bring into the world with you
as part of your genetic endowment
craig venter brings with him into the world
although certain genes
that palm bay
to some extent
predispose them to be haven particular all
kinds of ways
but the individuals phenotype
the way adventure or anybody else actually
turns out
is what happens when the genotype
inderpal
pollen counters a particular environment
so that you could actually have
people with different genotypes
but have the same phenotype different genotypes
but the same law
risk of heart failure or restore or behold
level of extra virgin you could have
or people with the same genotype but different
phenotypes for reasons that will talk about
here and admit
this happens
because
jeans interact with environments and we can
identify
three different kinds of environments that
all of that interact with the end of the fiji
the individuals dena type
to produce the individuals eventid
the prenatal environment
the environment all of the uterus
the womb in which the fetus
develops more the first
for the first nine months to nine months before
birth
depending on what goes on in
the uterus
the abid individuals with the same genotype
baby born
quite different from each other
one reason why women who are pregnant
are encouraged not to smoke
encouraged not to drink alcohol
because that stuff goes right to the fetus
on thoughts carry wrote that carried to the
bloodstream
and can affect
the of peter's
through the prenatal environment
that we have the perinatal environment
perry the greek word for around arrive on
the time of birth
various kinds of things can happen
his aides are very difficult labor for example
beckon have consequences for the kid
if the obstetrician drops the kid on the floor
that could have consequences all four o_ printed
alternate phone somebody go against too much
or too little oxygen to the infant
that could have consequences as well
and then finally
the postnatal environment everyday basically
from the time of birth on
can have an effect
on the individual
on of the individual as well
halloween began to understand
how we begin to ask the mate
but various contributions fog jeans and environment
separately and in interaction to paul
to various aspects of personality
the technical way to do this the easiest way
to do this the most popular way to do this
is by virtue of
twin studies
where all of the method in behavior genetics
where we basically right too
identified the genetic and environmental
contributions
too hard
to individuality
by looking by comparing
identical and fraternal twins
models i got a twins
so-called identical twins
are the product of a single fertilized egg
that divides
early in
gestation
so models i got it wins
have one hundred percent of their genes in
common they are genetically identical
for all intents and purposes
genetically identical
by contrast
dies i gotta twins so-called fraternal twins
which of the product out to different
fertilized eggs
they have only a fifty percent of their genes
in common
on average
of models i got a twins are identical dies
and other twins
are no more like genetically that any two
siblings
or
also you can imagine now
if a particular
trait
like extra version norton around a schism
is inherited
true the extent
that a particular personality trait is inherited
we will expect a fine
that models i got it twins are more alike
on that tree
dies i gotta twins that is the essential logic
of behavior genetics
if it ever trade is inherited
to the extent to trade is inherited identical
twins should be more alike on that trait
offer turtle wins
on should be
on gets more interesting uh... you know the
in a moment
lol but here's the method again
what we would do
we're interested in
genetic and environmental contributions to
a trait like extra version bergeron a schism
we did minister a personality questionnaire
assess individual differences and traits
and then we would look at the similarity between
as measured by that statistic known as the
correlation coefficient
remember that the correlation coefficient
as a statistic
that expresses
the strength
and direction of the relationship between
two variables
if a correlation is positive
high scores on one
are accompanied by high scores on the other
effect on correlation is negative high scores
on one or accompanied by low scores on another
the higher the correlation
bus stronger the relationship somewhat but
the greater dissimilarity
so we'll be doing is we look at the correlations
between twins
on various trade measures
as a measure albee
on degree awm
similarity the degree of resemblance between
them
infiltrate is completely at inherited
if it comes with a particular trade is completely
determined by the jeans
we would expect models i got it wins to be
precisely identical
with respect
or
offered sprit something dichotomous we'd expect
a hundred percent uh... allied concordance
if want we had a tree
would expect the other point
to have the tree think about
for a second identical twins
or of the same gender
one hundred percent of the time
ones mail
is going to email
but fraternal twins that's not the case if
one kittens mail
the other twins could email only fifty percent
of the time
so if they don't trade is wholly inherited
we'd expect the correlation among ball between
fraternal twins
to be about
point five all ocracoke words written of about
fifty percent
if a trade is wholly inherited
we'd expect the correlation between to individuals
to work
on related genetically
no blood of the relationship
there would be essentially in random
association
here is an example
imagine the we've got
a scale of extra version that goes from zero
to sixty begin this questionnaire to a set
of twins
here are ten pairs of twins
here are
their scores
on the scale of extra version
on for twenty rate one twins course pointing
the other twins scores eighteen
for twin pair ten
one twins scores fifty-eight
one twin scores fifty-seven just by i've always
yet
you can see that
these twins are very similar to each other
in terms of extra version
if you actually calculate
the correlation
you'd thought of you get a correlation of
point nine nine
are almost uh... of almost perfect
or the correlation
all children that these twins
are highly
all of highly similar to each other
in personnel
now this is made up data
here's what the real data looks like
this is research by job lol unpublished dose
of years ago numbers haven't changed at all
on since then
lol live administered questionnaire measures
of the big five personality traits
neuroticism extra version agreeable this conscientious
nissen openness
two sets of models i got a good dot i dot
gotta twins
calculator the correlations between them
and this is what he got a pattern of correlations
that looks like this
the average correlation for each of these
personality traits
four bottles i got it identical twins
about point five oh little bit less
the average correlation
four died psychotic
fraternal twins
was about half that
roughly about point to five point two six
on on average
the fact that model as i got it twins
or more alike
on these trades that are diver gotta twins
prima fascia evidence that is on first glance
on the face of it
of evidence for a genetic contribution of
personnel
a if there's a genetic contribution of
personality
we would expect
identical twins who were genetically identical
to be more like on that trait then fraternal
twins who are not genetically identical
and that's exactly the pattern bc
these are far from perfect correlations
okay that's more that's more the story to
calm
but the fact that these correlations
routinely
higher than these correlations
and z correlations routinely higher than the
z correlation
tells us genes have something to do with it
that's not all their is because obviously
models i gotta twins
do more then we share
jeans
they also share
environments
unless they're separated at birth which happens
but doesn't happen very often there raised
by the same parents the race in the same hosts
of the house to go to the same schools they
have some of the same teachers
and uh... and so on
models i got it twins
have environments
that are more alike then dies i gotta twins
born on when siblings
after all they're the same sex
they look like each other
people got a mistake them for each other are
the good beechwood to be treated more alike
that dies i gotta twins are
so the question is
just because
models i gotta twins resemble each other
doesn't necessarily mean that that's because
a trait is result caused by jeans
how can we tease apart
these genetic and environmental contributions
to personality
here's how we do it
first we want to distinguish between through
different aspects of the environment
what's known as the share environment
and band on sheraton bar
the share of environment
refers to all the aspects of the environment
that children would be in the same family
have in common
on
two identical twins will have
the same parents
at the same brothers and sisters their raised
in the same arms legalistic church there in
the same neighborhood
or all that stuff
on but that's referred to as the sheraton
barman
witcher shared in common
by siblings
in the family
but then that there is also
then on we share in bar
sometimes referred to as within the family
barriers
because this refers to
although things
children in the same family
that are not uncommon
all the things that all of the refer to their
order you need to experiences
so for example yen
uh... in families
some siblings are older
others are younger the older siblings take
care of the younger ones
the younger ones are taken care of by the
older ones
that is eight
difference
in thong
that's it but that's about it than aspect
of the non shared environment
even twins
uh... bulls say oh i'm older
hear all about thirty seconds of your older
by two minutes or whatever
but still twins will distinguish between themselves
in terms of
and who was on younger
gender
boys in a family art than a different environment
somewhat than the girls on in a family
on and so on all one kid joins the boy scouts
one boyd joins the boy scouts
one boyd joins all the local all uh... football
team
there have different
environments outside the family
one kid reads tolstoy
the other kid reads nije
they have
very different environments is well uh...
outside our outside the family
so we want to distinguish not just between
genes and environment
we want to distinguish between two different
aspects of the environment the environment
that children of family have in common and
the environments
then our unique for each child
in the family
and it turns out
that this twins study method
which can which allows us to as to make the
contributions of genetic factors to all
floated to personality
also will allow us to estimate
the contribution of the shared
and and i'm sure on environment and here's
how it goes
total variance
represented by the bell curve here's the distribution
of extra virgin some people low
some people high lots of people fall in the
middle where does that variance come from
sum it up douglas on the net variances genetic
variants
is due to individual differences in gena types
all other variances due to environmental barron's
individual differences in environment
both shared and i'm not sure environment
we begin by saying that poll burials armstrong
treat
is the psalm
of the genetic variants
and the environmental variance
we breakdown the environmental variance into
that aspect of the environment that shared
among family members
and that aspect of the environment
that is not share
along family members
and we can use the twin study method to estimate
the contributions
of each of these
doctors
and here's what we do it
total variance
is a sum of genetic parents and environmental
very
we can estimate the genetic
contribution
to a variance by simple formula
of doubling the difference between the model
saigonnet twins and the ties i gotta twins
arm
the mathematics for that little
if you think about it for a second
i'm g if a trade is wholly inherited
models i got a twins will be hundred-percent
alike they'll handle correlate one point out
if that same traders holy inherited
so i thought about it wins
will correlate with each other
point five oh
double the difference
perfect get one hundred-percent of the variances
genetic there
the environment is made up of the shared environment
and the not shared environment
we estimate the non shared environment
by whatever leftover when you know what the
models like da dik resemblances
remember
if a trait is wholly determined by genes
we expect
identical twins
to be completely alike
any differences between
identical twins
can't be due to genetic differences
because
there weren't any genetic differences
any differences between identical twins
can't be due to the shared environment
because they share the environment their race
in the same house by the same parents
all any differences between on pedicle twins
must be attributable two nine nine sheridan
bar
to the twins unique experiences
once we've estimated
the genetic variants
the variance due to the non charred environment
we can get the of variance due to the shared
environment basically
subtraction
here's how it works
on magic we've got
models i gotta clean correlation perfect one
point o_ dies i got a twin correlation appoint
final
plug these values into the formulas
double the difference between models i got
a good guys i got a twins
two times point five oh
all the variance is genetic
for the not answered environment
one minus ends the envy is one so there is
no
variance due to the nine short environment
variance through the shared environment is
what's left over and there's nothing left
over
if you see a pattern like this
you've got a trait
that is entirely determined by the jeans
in which the environment plays no role whatsoever
but now let's take another example tomatoes
i got a correlation is
point five oh
advise i got a correlation
is point for road
double the difference between mc twins and
easy twins to get an estimate of genetic variance
twenty percent of the variances do the jeans
for the nine charter environment
you take the m z correlation subtracted from
one
half of the variance is due to the non shared
environment
further shared environment subtract what you've
already got
there's thirty percent leftover
thirty percent of the variance is due
here
environment
here's another example
higher and z correlation
pointed out
but also a hired easy correlation point seven
oh
double the difference
two times point one oh
twenty percent of the various attributable
to jeans
one minus eighty one by this point eighty
twenty percent of the parents do not share
the barman
subtract those from one
sixty percent of the variance in this case
is built for the sheraton barb
even though d_m_z_ correlation is as high
as it is
it's still the case in this example
sixty percent of the variance most of the
various is due
to this year
one more
because this is the where we're going this
is the visa correlations that you thought
in the table before
emes e_ correlation of point five oh
easy correlation of point to fly double the
difference between them
fifty percent of the variance attributable
to jeans
one minus fifty
fifty percent of the variance attributable
to the non shared environment
what's left over in this case is nothing
attributable
the share environment
these are abstract examples
now let's go back to lowlands data
where we found the actual correlations for
the big five trades
frenzy twins
roughly point four eight
pretty easy twins roughly
point to six
on average
plug these values into the figures
here's the one for actor version
correlation applied for a frenzy twins correlation
a point to a four-fold
easy twins
double the difference
forty percent of the variance attributable
to
genetic factors
one minus the mc correlation
fifty two percent of the various attributable
to the bond shared environment
what's left over is nothing
attributable
the shared
environment
when you run these calculations for all five
of the big five traits
you see three things
really really clearly
for each army has been five personality traits
there is a substantial amount of variance
that is determined
somewhere between thirty five
and forty five percent of the variance on
each of these trades
attributable to genetic factors
very little
variance
is attributable to the sheraton environment
that is to the environment
that children that these children have by
virtue of being in this members of the same
family raised in the same household
by the same parents
however
a great deal of the variance
is attributable about fifty percent on average
isn't ridable to their non shared environment
despite
by genetic contribution to each of these fob
igf-i personality traits
there is still
very large
environmental contribution
most of that contribution
comes from that
not on sheraton virb
not the sheraton bar
it's not what
children the same family
by virtue of even the same that way that makes
extroverted erotic or whatever it is these
unique experiences
and then finally
if anything
benign shared environment
is more powerful
than the jeans
nine showed environment is certainly more
powerful than the shared environment
and i'm sure the barman is well probably more
powerful than the genes as well
this up pattern with the over and over again
here is a pattern tears out to be delivered
genetic study published just a couple of months
ago
on what they call age of sexual debut
age at your for sexual intercourse
they did it work and study
farthest and they found that there was a significant
genetic factor
very little contribution
from the from the shared environment
they are able to interview should
factors operating
within the family
a huge contribution
benign shared environment
so again
something like something as simple as ager
first intercourse
there is a genetic component
there's a big environmental component
uh... are not shared environment
greater than the share
environment in terms of determining when that's
gonna happen
here is another off guard this study
of the study off from the university of virginia
twin study of political attitudes
where on twins were asked to fill out a questionnaire
which they were asked about
various liberal and conservative along
attitudes
here we have the correlations for
measure of liberalism political liberalism
versus conservativism
models i gotta twins
correlated point six five
size i gotta twins correlated point
all four three
political party affiliation
take those figures
plug them in
to home
applaud him into before it was
some genetic contribution
to variance there's something genetic about
whether you're liberal or conservative
but again but not a shared environment is
more powerful then they shared environment
and at work that way
all the way down with the exception of education
shared environments really important
thought god determinant of of education
parents usually say
you're going to college and you are going
to college too
uh... that's the sheraton bar
parents hardly ever say
ball you go to college and go to hell or whatever
it is
not what usually are happens
but again
the idea here is
when we look at
what determines behavior
jeans environment
what aspect of the environment
what aspect of the holiday in iraq it turns
out
but there is a significant
genetic component
to individual differences in personality
and in attitudes
but there is a also is significant environmental
problems
and that is so important typically as to dominate
the shared environment component it's not
the environment within the family that makes
people what they are it's the environment
outside the family that makes people all of
what they are
in most cases
the power of the nine shared environment
matches
or exceeds the power
the genetic code contributor
and personnel
for now the question is
how to make sense of this
how to make sense the fact that
their genetic contributions to individual
differences in personality and attitudes
non shared barman is much more important then
the shared in part
the encik which will elect and on on wednesday
is basically
on simple what we want to know
why it is
that children from the same family are so
different from each other
why is that they'd even identical twins or
is different from each other home as they
are
each child has a different genetic heritage
okay
but it turns out that the family environment
is not decisive for personality and attitudes
being raised
by the parents that you were raised by
in the house that you were raised in
is not what makes you or what uh...
of the white you were art there's as much
variability within families
on one brothers and sisters almost as much
variability between families as there is variability
between families
the reason for this is
the idea that children are written are raised
in
the same for and children a family are raised
in the same family is true for the point of
view of the kids eat codes
and telephone numbers
but turns out not to be psychologically troop
it turns out that there are all sorts of
dipole sorts of
variances within a family going to talk about
these all last night next time
and lots of variance all part of the variance
outside the family leading to the conclusion
every
or where are we here
leading to the conclusion that
saddlery child is raised by different parents
raised in a different household
worships at a different charge
attends a different school
that every child is raised andy unique psychological
environment
and that unique psychological environment
contributes to the uniqueness of his or her
personality
how i can be
that two kids
even identical twins
can be raised by the same parents in the same
house go to the same schools go to the same
churches and end up so different from each
other
is an interesting puzzle for psychology and
all talk more about it
next time thank you very much