okay here we are now we're going to
tranfer attention away from
basic cognitive processes like
perception and memory and thinking
and begin to put all this material
together
in anyhow
somewhat higher level discussion
all of the individual behavior in
his or her social world
and let's begin just be just by
reminding ourselves also
through fundamental facts about human
nature
the first that we've emphasized in the
first part of the scores
is that
human beings in their behavior are
intelligent creatures
we're not just operating by virtue of
love
innate
stimulus response connections like
reflexes and tax season instincts
our behavior isn't just a product of
classical instrumental conditioning
that stance in various responses to
environmental stimuli
rather
throughout our behavior reflects our
attempts to make sense of the world
around us
what frederick bartlett cold effort
after meaning
the learning we're trying to figure out
what's happening what's votes
predicting what what's going to happen
next one of the consequences of our
behaviors
in perception we're trying to figure out
what it is that's out there and where
it's going
in memory we're trying to figure out
what it was that happened at some point
in the past
all of that reflects effort after
meeting
it's also the case
we're not just intelligent creatures
were intelligent social creatures
all of our individual experience thought
and action
take place in an environment that's
followed by other people
and our
everyday interactions with other people
arbor ogle guided by various processes
have to do with cooperation and
competition
and all the other things that we can do
with each other
that raises the fundamental question for
psychology as a social science
which is
what's the relationship
between what's going on inside the head
of the individual
what he or she is thinking and feeling
and one thing
and what's going on in the social world
outside the individual what's going on
in the
all in the lives of other people that
have some kind of a fact
on what's going on uh... on the
individual
the classic framework for thinking about
these things was given to us by late
german emigres psychologist about doll
seventy years ago now kurt lewin that's
his picture
armed ended comes in the form a kind of
singer mathematics all formula
where learning to do that
the individuals' behavior
as a function of to kinds of
determinants
personal determines
fire which lumen meant
states and dispositions there were some
hollywood internal to the person
what the person fat or believed or felt
or wanted
these things that are going on inside
the individuals had
and on the other hand
determines that lady in the environment
of private side of the individual
whether it's the physical environment
how amazing it is how hard it is what
the air pressure is whether it's raining
or these social environment
whether there are other people around
what they're doing what they're feeling
but they're wanting and so on
but the general framework remember
psychology always interested in
explaining that the behavior all of the
individual organism and we want argued
that that individuals' behavior was a
function of
these two types of determines personal
determines
and environmental determines
the branch of psychology known as a
personality psychology
have traditionally focused its attention
on the personal determinants of behavior
that is to think about behavior
as a function of things that are going
on inside the individual
and personality psychology generally
construe is
these internal determinants or personal
determines the behavior
in various ways
as people's beliefs
okay
i believe that it's monday therefore
writing
come to class this liked each other new
mondays
all up attitudes
volume
fault the likes to teach more or less
on mondays
also like on the class and teach all
trades i have all certain
level of some kind of trait that makes
me do what i do
emotions motives or whatever it is these
are all construed as somehow internal to
me
that will lead me to behave the way i do
know and on the other hand
but deal with in traditional personal
reflexology
is that situational factors or largely
irrelevant
okay the probe the primary determinants
of the individuals behavior
have to do with these individual traits
side of the traditional method
charging for personalities like orgies
is to
assessed people's level
also i'm trait like friendliness
and then you use those assessments
to protect their behavior
on simon trait relevant dimension
so we'd expect that
friendly people would smile more than a
man friendly people friend friendly
people or it kind of people kinds of
people who smile
so what we do here is reclassify group
of subjects into those who were high and
friendliness
and those were lowered friendliness
and we observed
the probability that there'll be smiling
at any particular moment some of your
smiling now so i'll be or not
in this song
this method
we would want to relate that of behavior
to your level of friendliness that's the
general logic behind
traditional personality psychology
here is the real world example this is
data collected by berkeley's professor
all over john's some years ago
this is study of m_b_a_ students up
publicly on a business school bihar
school of business
and left our john and his colleagues did
was to administered a personality
questionnaire
that with all that you heard our trade
known as conscientious
in these individuals
also some people were harlem
conscientious this there are very
conscientious very responsible very
dedicated
and others were kind of low
unconsciousness they were going for
slackers of various kinds
and then what all of god dot john did
all blows to accor range for the start
of the individuals these m_b_a_ students
fish are now at proper to cover time
for end of the for an appointment and he
simply measured
there are a little time for the
appointment that they arrive on time
that they are rivals or did they are
ripe early and what you can see here
is that individuals who were
measured as haryana strata conscientious
this
tended to arrive a little bit early for
their appointments about thirty seconds
early but still early on the further
appointments
whereas individuals who are low in
consciousness
tended to arrive late further
appointments
all more than five minutes late
on average so here we have sam trade
some disposition that is somehow
internal to the person
his or her level of conscientious miss
at then predicts
all-white solved what what he or she is
going to do
in some specific situation
generalizing from this
are we have alva with a big difference
of all in the psychology of personality
comes to us from gordon all port
a psychologist who worked for many years
at harvard
aldrich of
so that's called the doctrine of trades
and the document rates basically says
that the individuals behavior individual
behavior
varies as a function
also internal dispositions that's what
rates are there internal behavioral
dispositions
that renderer behavior
coherent
stable
consistent
and predictable at all
the flight and give examples of each of
these four charms
are as we go on so behavior varies as a
function
of internal dispositions
that render behavior
coherent stable consistent and
predictable and again these internal
dispositions
common wide variety of forms
but most research on the document traits
as either
ought to do with
personality traits like conscientious
nose sore extra version or friendliness
or something like that
attitudes
for example all liberal versus
conservative political attitudes or pro
feminist or empty feminist gender
attitudes or whatever
so that we could
uh... flowing from the doctrine of
trades
is what we might call the cutout i call
it a typical method
for personality research which is to
measure some personality variable
whichever one you are interested in
conscientious ness might be one
and we consider that the predictor
variables these measurements can come
from self-report questionnaires
or rating scales of the sort that many
of you filled out
altering the calm
pre screening
far beyond increase screening packet for
the are ppr experience
or they could come from general
behavioral observations instead of
having you filled out a questionnaire
we could go to your parents
or your siblings
or your roommates or your sorority
sisters or it's some body
who knows you well
and have become already one of these
various dimensions like conscientious
nis and that's what we do is we take
these individual differences across a
big group of people
and then correlate these individual
differences in some trade
with individual differences in behavior
in some specific situations
the assessment of personality
constitutes a predictor variable
we're trying to predict
how people will be haven
on some kind of criterium
variable
that method is to be contrasted
with the method in traditional social
psychology
which focuses not on personal
determinants of behavior
but rather odd environmental
here we have been women's terms
behavior as a function all of the
environment
and traditional personality psychology
will try to on assessed sam aspect of
the environment
whether it's the physical environment
house stuff it is in a room
or whether it's the social environment
how many people are in the room
and then alm volatile
try to predict behavior from that
consists construing personal factors
like the kinds of factors that the
doctrine of traits is concerned with as
largely irrelevant
so to return to war smiling example
we might observe whether somebody's
smiling
when they're in a situation with a close
acquaintance
or whether they're in a situation with a
stranger and we might observe that
people are more likely to smile when
they were in the presence of somebody
they know
then they will that then they are when
they were in the presence of somebody
they don't know
here is the situational factor got
nothing to do with a person
got nothin with their level of
friendliness or anything else
we've got some situational variable
that predicts
the likelihood that somebody
will smile unit
professor janet colleagues
looked at situational influences on
punctuality as well
all again for these cities are quickly
m_b_a_ students
and what are john all of the dead
was too
art has some stones some students
arriving
for an appointment to the scheduled in
the morning
or other students arriving for
appointment that was scheduled in the
afternoon and any of you who have had a
morning appointment know what happens
rapids
all here
we have students
all who have an appointment time in the
morning
and they tend to arrive late
for those appointments by about five and
a half minutes on average
students who have an appointment in the
afternoon they tend to arrive a little
early amend it more to early
here again we're treating personality
variables is completely irrelevant
and were simply looking at the effect on
behavior
whether somebody is punctual are not as
a function of the situation whether
they're appointment is for the morning
or
afternoon
so again
contrast into the doctrine of trades we
have what might be called the doctrine
of situation is on all up which is often
generally vulva associated with another
harvard psychologist b_f_ skinner
all portend skinner were at harvard at
the same time
the animosity between all port with his
doctrine of trade since kidder with his
doctrine of situations
was sold
fears
but they are said to break up the
harvard psychology department and put
the all poor people on one floor of the
skin or people on another floor
all about
whereas argued that the havier though it
is a function of trades scare argued
that behavior goes is a function of the
external environment okay
although
all of those so much so that start the
skaters quite famous for the salt for
the school at the ground
or person does not act upon the world
rather the world accident on him
and reactions in the situation skinner
was all learning theorists he was on
steve's old stimulus response
behaviorist of the first order and he
viewed although all behavior as
essentially all of them out matter of
conditioned responses
to dog to environmental variables
so we had the doctrine of trades
we have the doctrine of situations that
basically comes from skinner
and the doctor the situation is a man
gives us the kind that i call or
traditional method
four research and social psychology
which is that we manipulates on the
feature of the external environment
whether the appointment is for the
morning or the afternoon
whether there are other people in the
room or not whether there were a claim
missus or strangers or not
okay
we've got the port subjects in these
various embarked on environmental
conditions
and then we determine the effect of this
environmental manipulation
on their behavior
in some specific
on situation
in the language of psychological methods
the manipulated a feature of the
external environment is known as the
independent variable it's something that
is manipulated by the experimenter
and the
all behavior is known as the deep end in
variable that is
we want to see whether the behavior
varies
depending on the level all the alle
on on the level of the independent
variable
here
flowinfreely mullins equation behavior
as a function of the personnel and the
environment
we see the all the evolution the
emergence of true great traditions
within personality and social psychology
traditional personality psychology
focusing on personal determines the
behavior and calm or
social psychology
focusing on the environmental
determinants of behavior
now of course
he could have it both ways if you want
the usual assumption in psychology
has been
that these personal and environmental
factors or independent of each other
okay you can have kind of off eclectic
position
okay there are a person personal
variables like trades
that influence howell person will behave
so
your level of friendliness
will determine whether you smile or not
and they're all features on the
environment
white whether your looking at a
acquaintance or a stranger
devil determine whether you smile or not
but if you'll notice
these two
cole pathways if you will
are entirely independent of each other
there's appraisal determined at the
behavior and it's got nothing to do with
the environmental determines the
behavior there's no connection between
them
there's an environmental determinants of
behavior but it's got nothing to do with
the personal all of the determinant or
for
of behavior
while you can see this
graphically
this is a graphic display of the kind of
outcome you'd expect
if the personal and the environmental
determinants of behavior
work independent of each other
here we have
on two levels of friendliness
hi friendliness and well friendliness
and we have to
all very all levels of the situation
with an acquaintance
and with a stranger
and you can see in this graph i know
this is soooo delegated i don't know
what's conducted this experiment or
chili or experiment like this in a
second
the behavior as predicted by
of the level personality trait
people who are high and friendliness
tend to smile more than people who were
low and friendliness
no over behaviors affected by the
situation
people gore facing an acquaintance
are more likely to smile than people who
are facing all stranger
but notice that these affects our
independent of each other
these lines are parallel
it doesn't matter whether you're facing
the mcfarlane acquaintance
or you're facing a stranger
if you're high-end friendliness you're
more likely to smile than if you're not
and it doesn't matter
whether you're a friendly person or an
auden friendly person
if you're in the presence of an
acquaintance
you're more likely to smile that you're
not these lines or completely parallel
now this is just an example
if you look at the dot where in john's
study of punctuality you see an example
of the independents
also the person and at the art of the
situation
here we have
all subjects
classified as high and low in
conscientious as that's the personality
variable
and we have subjects arriving for
morning
and for afternoon appointments that's
the environmental variable
and you can see
that these lines are almost perfectly
parallel
you could be
highly conscientious or not very
conscientious
if your appointment is for the morning
you're going to turn to a crime of late
if your appointment is for the evening
unprofor the afternoon
europe are going to tend not to arrive
late
and vice versa
dot the fact of the personality variable
is completely independent
all of the effects
all the
although the environmental variables so
here we go
there at the future of person
environment independence is first
the effect of the personality is the
same regardless of the situation the
person is in
and second
the effect of the situational variables
it's the same
regardless of the kind of person
okay
conscientious people can attend to
arrive early for their appointments not
late
people have appointments in the morning
tend to arrive late
as opposed to people who have
appointments in the fall in the yard in
the afternoon
now the idea that person variable
doubling the postal determines the
behavior in the environmental determines
the behavior
were independent of each other lag in
the history a personality and social
psychology
to what kind of competition
kind of competition you see between a
red fox and a yankees okay
all of basically to say which affect is
more powerful
but first of all although the affect of
or personality traits
or to be a fact of situational although
variance
off however people came to understand
quite quickly
that this is really not the right way to
frame the question about the relations
between
the personal determinants of behavior
and the environmental determines the
behavior
because in fact
the personal and the environmental
determines the behavior arch
not independent of each other
rather they seem to affect each other
puttin the technical language
the person and the environment tends to
contract
and the first person to really talk
about this a lot
was the late kenneth powers of god
canadian and american psychologist work
for
almost his entire career at the
university of waterloo
so in nineteen seventy three
announced what has come to be called
the doctrine of interaction ism
he says block
neither traits number two situations are
the primary determines the behavior
for the simple reason
that situations are as much of function
of the person's behavior
as the person's behavior is of function
of the situation
what powers meant by that was
people a fact the environments
which in turn off that their behavior
it if people are affecting their
environments
the person purcell determines the
behavior and the environmental divall
determines behavior
are no longer independent
so what we really have in borrowers view
is a situation like this
where we have
personality traits like friendliness
that might affect behavior
and we have environmental conditions
like whether you're with all stranger or
acquaintance that might affect your
behavior
dog and you've got or the personality
factors that will affect the environment
itself
this is
the all of the ki
to with darker and by the addressee
resum
and later on in these lectures
we're going to talk about the various
ways
in which people of fact
the these situations or the environments
which intern influence
their behavior
but to continue our examples here
here is about
specimen
example all of what we mean by
interaction is on
here again we've got or subjects
classified in terms of friendliness high
and low
and we've got
our situations classified whether there
is a static wings of the situation or
whether there's a stranger in a
situation
note that this graph looks a little bit
different from the other one i showed
you
here we have still behavior as predicted
by the personality trait
so friendly people are more likely to
smile than on the friendly people
and
behavior is still affected by the
situation people are more likely to
smile in the presence of an acquaintance
than they are in the stranger but in the
presence of a stranger
but noticed but these are facts are
no longer independent of each other
it makes a difference
how you behaved in the situation
depending on what kind of person you
wore
so if you work pay friendly person
flyover more
in the presence of an acquaintance
fall under the bed a stranger but
there's not that much of a difference
friendly people just smile all the time
right that's one of the ways we know
that they're friendly
here we have these aren't friendly
people not so friendly people
who make a big discrimination
between the one situation
and the other
so here we have an example of how the
effect of the person and the effect of
the environment our message of on
behavior
are not independent of each other
at matters
what kind of person isn what kind of of
situation
so again just to spell this out
all if we look at the features of the
person all environment interaction
we can say that
persons and environments in iraq when
the effect of the person
depends on the kind of situation
that person
we can say
the effect of a situation depends on the
kind of person
who is in it
and again here are some other examples
as a somewhat more dramatic examples of
the person by situation erection
this is what's known as the crossover
interaction
where
you have people who are
hari
friendliness or the high on some trade
they behave in one way in situation a
completely opposite way in situation
beat and here we have people were low on
some trade
and they show exactly the opposite
pattern of behavior
notice here
that neither the trait nor the situation
alone predicts anything if you average
across
the two levels of traits
you see there is no difference
between them
if you ever to cross the through
situations
you see there's no difference the action
columns
when you take into account
the person
and the situation
and how they interact
here's another pattern of person by
situation interaction
known as a fan effect because well
it looks like a friend
here we have
in situation a
there's no difference in behavior
between
people who were high on some trait and
people who were low on some three
the differences between these kinds of
people
only four lives in certain kinds of
situations
situations like situation b
the art of the differences between them
magnified
okay so again what you can see here
is that their is
and you know that there's this
interaction
the behavior of people depends
both on the kind of person
and on the kind of situation
therein
just to make this even more interesting
let's go back to disfigure auditor picks
the standard view of all of interaction
ism where we have
personal personal characteristics
influencing behavior
an environmental characteristics
and now we have bowers doctrine of
interaction is in which says
that people
influence
the situations that influence that in
turn influence their behavior
this is every do you have a the u_n_ a
directional
interaction is on
while you were rather a u_n_ directional
view of interaction ism
because if you'll notice
the all causal pathways
all goat in one direction
from the person
to his or her behavior
from the environment
the behavior that occurs in it
on and from the person
the environment
it could be more interesting than that
if the person can affect the environment
while you shouldn't be environment
exhort reciprocal
affect on the carson okay so here we
have the person affecting the
environment
here we have the environment
affecting the person i was at the opera
yesterday when magic flute dual want to
go see a really nice production of magic
flute go see it
but i happen to be way up in the balcony
it was hotter than hell in there
and i was we were trying to get in time
for the end of the first act
you can see people were getting ornery
you know there was a lot more shashi no
children and all sorts of stuff that had
occurred later on
part of the the at the end of the
staffing us in the balcony
well
making people feel bad ok and one way or
another
about or about their circumstances so
that's just a kind of trivial example
that we don't know what i broke out or
anything like that
but again
to think about how the environment
you're in ten shape
your own personal characteristics okay
so here we have an example
all douglas epochal
causal affect
between the person in the environment
people shaping the environment in which
they behave
the environment shaping
or the person
who admits
the behavior
similarly
personal effects ok turned that personal
determinants can affect our behavior
maybe it's also true
that our behavior tend shape us
reciprocal e check the kind of person we
are
probably everybody in this room has had
the uh... lopez had the experience of
you know not knowing whether you could
do something with you could kind of run
that faster ask her for a date or
whatever and then you kind of screw up
your courage and you do it
and at work so what is a all can do this
i'm the kind of person who can't do this
kind of assault didn't advance yourself
before right
observations of your own behavior shaped
your self image bom
also a dead
if the person
ten determine his or her own behavior
why shouldn't behavior feedback
okay to shape the person
as well
and similarly
the environment can affect the behavior
that occur is that
which we know
it can
shirley
we had the behavior that occurs in the
environment
ten affect the environment itself
all
if you will and never be a note concert
world or or or a player whatever when
somebody starts coughing what happens
the everybody's coffee different
i thought it would be a little bear that
has the already transformed the theater
from a nice quiet environment into an
environment in which all sorts of coffee
was taking place right
the people's behavior
can change
the environments
in which that behavior
so i can but we want to think about now
is not that cordial relations among
persons and environments and behaviors
as somehow unit directional when
everything's kind of going off like like
bill your balls
but rather that there are reciprocal
whole relations
between each of these elements in looms
equation
reciprocal causal relations between the
person
and his or her behavior
between the environment and the behavior
the takes place in it
and between
the behavior the person and the
environment
this is
is the essence i have a doctrine known
as the doctrine of reciprocal
determinism
which was although formulated by albert
bandara a psychologist at stanford
university
here we have a moment of silence for
booths and bones
armed up basically
what douglas argued was that
but person the environment
and behavior
constituted dynamic system of k a
dynamic system in which
each of these elements
is our class of the other two
and each of these elements is in effect
the other two we're no longer
identifying clauses as causes and
effects of the facts anymore each of
these elements is serving both as a
cause and effect this is the
or the essence
all got a lot of our dynamic system
so we've actually got
as a part of the heart of the system it
looks like this
there or reciprocal calls the relations
between the person
and his or her behavior
reciprocal causal relations between the
environment
and the behavior the takes place in it
reciprocal calls the relations between
the person and the environment dot
i'll do my best but that's why i give
slides out in advance ok palm
so i can kind of get through the vessel
warlike terms four days
all i'll try to slow down thanks
okay
bartenders just another view of this
also brenda has sometimes called this at
this situation tried attic reciprocate
ality
because there are three elements the
behavior
the person
and the environment and there are
reciprocal causal relations between each
of them
between a person and his or her behavior
between the environment
and his or her behavior
between a person and the environment
note however
that let me say that there is
reciprocal close hourly or
bender is terms reciprocal determinism
we don't necessarily mean
that these causal relations are all
symmetrical
all right we mean is that the causal
relations are bi-directional we don't
necessarily mean that all these calls
the relations or of equal strength
it might be
that the close the link between the
person and b
and his or her behavior
is very strong
and the reciprocal link between behavior
feeding back on the person
is somewhat weak
that's an empirical question
but they've got there
the point is in principle they're both
there
nor
dual all of these causal linkages
work themselves out final tenuously
it's not necessarily the case
that the person is shaping the
environment
at precisely the same time
as the environment is reciprocal e
shaping the person but rather usually
going to be the case
is that things kind of unfold over time
in the same way that one person coffee
nana theater
will lead later to a couple more people
coffin in the theater
which will lead later to a couple more
people coughing too have been theater to
make in the first person to pull off
really self-conscious about having
started this
which will become coffee even harder
okay
which hopefully with the having
in the theater
also there pretty soon
the players can't do what they're
supposed to do
all this takes place over time
but the fact that it takes place over
time isn't what's important what's
important is that the causal
influences org bi-directional
everything is a clause in this system
and everything
is in effect
okay that's nice in principle
but everything is affecting everything
else
when everything is fine what it is
more or less libel taneous lee to be
thought of as a clause and effect
things can get complicated
very quickly
for that reason
they're going to do in these lectures is
to engage in a strategy known as
analytic composition we're going to
break this
this complex system down into basically
three
parts
well it's going to be six parts but
we're going to talk about
free first
first we're going to look at
the reciprocal relation between the
person and his or her behavior
then we're going to look at the
reciprocal relations between the
environment and the behavior that takes
place in it
and then finally
we're going to take a look at the
reciprocal relation between the person
and the environment
there's going to be a kind of dialogue
between
each of these elements person behavior
environment behavior
person
and environment
and there were three of them
and these constitu what we michael for
three dialect x or the three dialogues
in social interaction
the dialogue between the person and
behavior
between
environment and behavior and between the
person and the situation
okay so that's the framework
very generic very abstract framework
and now we're going to do is taken apart
and illustrate how it works
some actual
research findings
let's look first that the relation
between the person and the environment
domain we would think about this
is pretty much the way traditional
personality also ecology has thought
about it
that there are
people had internal states and internal
dispositions that lead them to be heavy
in a particular way
and in personality and social psychology
were mostly are interested in two
different kinds of dispositions
traits
which are
behavioral dispositions
betrayal friendliness is odd disposition
ted
the friendly this position to behave in
a friendly way
the trade of extra version is odd
disposition to behave in a extroverted
outgoing way
we could think about that includes as
value ative dispositions that is
tendencies
to have
positive
or negative
values
all on on various kinds of things
so
if you're a four or against
the war in iraq
if you're for or against all
racism
if you're for or against nuclear power
plants
does or
attitudes their evaluative dispositions
that presumably lead you to behave
in uh... in particular ways
so what we want to do again is to
measure
these personal determines the behavior
measured people's traits measured
people's attitudes and we do this
basically in one of
to ways
either by collecting self reports
order by doing something more objective
on the self reports all right
we can administer u
psalm questionnaires the various kinds
of ask you questions like
how likely for you to smile in the
presence of a stranger
halcon chalo how likely are you choose
to arrive on time for appointments those
or behavioral self reports
or we simply ask you to rate yourself on
one or another
trait dimension how friendly are you
how conscientious r_u_ how
whatever help punctual you are
chart instead of relying on your self
reports herself readings on these
various kinds of dimensions
we could have somebody else to do it for
you
okay we go to your parents
we go to your brothers and sisters we go
to your teammates or your
dormitory mates or whatever
and we have them
you the record the frequency with which
to engage in certain kinds of behaviors
how often does julie smile
during the day
or they can we can simply have them read
your behaviors in terms of how likely
they are to observe you
to observe you smile
what we want to do
to begin
looking at all
followed defects of dispositions on
behavior and the reciprocal affect our
behavior on dispositions
is to measure these dispositions and
that takes us to our next problem
which is
then there are a lot of dispositions out
there
gourmet reports back in the nineteen
thirties went through it on a bridge
thing which dictionary
and actually counted
all the different words in the english
language
that could be used to
discriminate between one person and
another in psychological terms
okay
are trying to figure out how many trade
names their work
all or part anders
student on burke
determined there were seventeen thousand
nine hundred fifty three such terms in
the english language actually
the horrible
there too horrible things here being
discounted
fault they're actually seventeen
thousand nine hundred fifty four
all of the first horrible things they
miss counted the second horrible things
that somebody actually checked them
what happened there
but in any event
yeah i don't know if eighteen thousand
different words in english that ten the
youth ascribe the psychological
differences between people we are not
believe me we are not going to measure
follow all of these
there's gotta be some weight
to reduce this set
all and over a period of decades
psychologists use in a statistical
technique called factor analysis which
is based on the correlation coefficient
and about which you have to know nothing
more
have accidents us leary boost
this list of seventeen thousand nine
hundred fifty four different rate terms
to just five
these five
extra version
having to do with soc ability
forcefulness attar jogger energy levels
adventure in august and adventuresome
this saw
enthusiasm and so on
neuroticism
people who are tense and irritable and
discontented in movie their going to be
high-end eroticism
homeless
if your love will appear
url highly forgiving warm
logged not does stover and sympathetic
with other people that's what agreeable
this is all about
conscientious this
your efficient
organized
the role
not lazy
not impulsive
and finally
or open as to experience
fall
uh...
did agree to a church curious
a magic tive
artistic and so on and so forth
these are known as the big five
personality traits
and they provide a very good
very
eve ficient framework for capturing
individual differences in personality
are between people
all up to a good first approximation
those seventeen thousand nine hundred
and fifty three thirteen thousand nine
hundred fifty-four dislike a logical
differences between people
all boil down
five personality traits
and you might say to you know that's
kind of
that's
we heard that you can you can boil it
down to just these five
but if you think about it for a second
are
if you wanted to know something about
somebody
this is what you want to know
alike all these the big five blind date
questions right
arnett if you've got to go out with
somebody i don't know all these other
things you want to know about him or her
this saw busy all going to see crazy is
the friendly as the reliable it is the
interesting
everything else where there is a good
kessler
whether redress as well or whatever that
comes later all but this is what you
want to know if you're going to spend a
couple of hours with somebody
on any of
went on a friday night
there it is something basic
about
dimensions okay
although it's these dimensions on which
personality psychology has focused
over the last all over the last couple
of decades
just to go through them very quickly
again how do we do assess these things
well first in terms of
self-report questionnaires okay
although
aren't you really like most people you
meet
if you like to have a lot of people
around you
if you are often a leader if you often
feel like you're bursting with energy
all if you do things just for kicks if
you're a cheerful high-spirited person
your ohio an extra version ok so we can
assess your degree of extra version in
terms of
behavioral technology behaviors that you
yourself report on
we can just ask you to use
some adjectives
if you're friendly warman sociable
if you're little aggressive not to
aggressive a little aggressive
self-confident assertive
if your pleasure seeking adventurous
optimistic again you're going to score
relatively high conduct on the test of
extroverted
again
the administer these kinds of
personality questionnaires and what we
get
you get distribution of extra virgin
scores that looks like this this is the
so-called normal distribution what we
sometimes think of as the bell shaper
where there are very few people who are
very low an extra version
very few people who are very high an
extra version and most people somewhere
that'll that's the distribution of extra
version
based on of thousand college students
all fifteen years ago hasn't changed
much
we can assess neuroticism in pretty much
the same way
by our people's tendency to be anxious
depressed
or angry self-conscious and so on
and you get a distribution it looks like
this
not too many people really let one x
drawn on dorado sizzle
not too many really high on dorado
schism falling either but this nice
normal distribution this nice bell
shaped kore
with most people
somewhere
for every other mess
reassess people in terms of
also trust in the our host
straightforward they are hokum pauline
kael modest
how altruistic
then you get a distribution the looks
like that
again not too many people
really disagreeable
we think about it there are about
people who are really disapproval life
just your roommate and a couple of
others
on fewer again on the other side
very few people really haryana agreeable
nis
but most people falling in between this
nice
fell shape
normal distribution
assess conscientious this in terms of
competence
worldliness
dutiful nis all self-discipline things
like that
endure jet
this nice distribution not too many lows
not too many holidays most people in
between
characteristic
dole shaped normal distribution
and then finally
facets of openness in terms of
with you got a rich fantasy life
are with your open a new ideas whether
your open willing to try new things
we'll go to an exotic restaurant you
know stuff like that
and again
not too many people really low
not too many people really high
most people
somewhere
this normal distribution
is a characteristic almost personality
variables
we did find it very few people at the
tales most people long-time in towards
the middle
all you get the same kind of cr
for measured intelligence you get pretty
much the same kind of kirk for exam
scores this normal distribution of
individual differences
is very very very characteristic
of what we find
when we do this kind alvo this kind of
research
had no what we want to do
say
now that we've assess these individual
differences
what are they going to do with the
how can we use these individual
differences
to predict
all people are going to be havior in
specific situations
that's the goal of this
and that's the thought mobile take-up
next time on wednesday
hard to get from
personality dispositions
to actual behavior
in some specific situation
thank you very much