okay last time wiki began our
consideration of processes involved in
thinking
reasoning and problem solving
judgment and decision making
and i began with a basic carter problem
wonder comes up all the time which is
how we form a categories to begin with
and how we categorize objects in terms
of all of the categories that we know
something about
and i described for you
to anne
there as an example of memorable
rationality the classic all proper said
fueled categories uncategorized ation
that has come down to us since the time
of aristotle's psalm twenty five hundred
years ago
idea that categories are proper steps
we are all category members share in
common
thumbs-up all defining features
and when you want to categorize an
object
all there's an algorithm
and all you have to do to is too
all figure out what the features of the
object are
compare those features
through the list to various lists of all
features at the fine various categories
and when you find a match between the
features of an object and the defining
features of a category then you solve
the problem you know the object belongs
in that category
that is a fine idea of plots
prescription for categorization in
principle
but in bless lecturer already
discussed a number of ways in which it
just doesn't work out
that there is a series of problems
with his classical view of categories as
proper sets
and they seem to be law
okay
as part of categorization is a matter of
using proper sets
the wooden encounter these kinds of
problems at all
so what do you know what needs to be
categorized how do we do it
tall
it turns out we do something to all
other than categorized in terms of
but think about categories
in terms of these songs and these
defining features
and warn the
alternative view of categorization
wonder you get a lot of mileage out of
well i was proposed by berkeley zone
professor eleanor rushed some years ago
in terms of what's known as the
prototype view
all categories is fuzzy sets
arm
couple things going on here
first inspect categories are construed
as fuzzy sets not process
proper sets recur in the category are
not there are sharp boundaries between
contrasting categories
bargain russia's fauzi so if you have
categorization
but the owner res between adjacent
categories are not all that clear their
fussing
although it's not going that's the
reason why it's not clear whether or not
or weather
a tornado was approved for a vegetable
or any religion is an article of
furniture or not
rosh argued that
when we categorize we simply don't
categorize on the basis of defining
features rather we define all good but
we did we categorize on the basis of
what she called
characteristic features
features that are correlated
or category membership
but not perfectly
correlated with category membership
and in fact she'd yaar distinguished
further
between two kinds of features
that are relevant to categorization
central features which are highly
correlated with category membership
and
peripheral features
which are not so highly correlated with
category membership
and she argued
federal rather than representing
categories violence of defining features
features that are singly necessary and
jointly sufficient
to define an object is a member of a
category
rather what we do is irreparably
represent categories by
are kind of payment type
are in a prototype in this all
literature
means a kind of
average
category mem member all over the image
of a category that has lots of features
that are central to category membership
and relatively few features that are
central to membership and other
categories
all but the point is
that the features were used to
categorize objects
may not be the defining features of a
category
albendazole warm-blooded vertebrate with
feathers and wings that's the biological
definition of a bird
if you've got those four peter zero bird
if you don't have those for future if
you're not over
but then we think about birds
we don't think about bridge that way we
think about birds in terms of
prototypical birds like robbins
as barros
and pigeons
and evils and hawks we have these
prototypes that are mine and when we see
an object
that has many of the features
other category prototype
we call it a bird
and if we don't
policy those characteristic features
we don't call the object bird
which is why we have difficulty thinking
about chickens as birds
we have difficulty thinking about pasta
riches as bird
we have difficulty thinking about
penguins as birds
and this
prototype view of categorization
goes a long way towards
solving
the kinds of problems of categorization
that i talked about last time
for example the prototype view
permits a lot of heterogeneity within a
category it permits you to have a lots
of objects in a category that don't
necessarily look ball like each other
but most important the palm
the yacht the prototype view
allows for typically affects
it allows for salma category members
to be more technical
category members them other category
members
why
because they more closely resemble
prototypical category instances and
again the important thing here
is that we define
foam
five categories in terms of these
characteristics features
which are not necessarily the same
as defining features
we think of eagles is birds because they
fly
okay but not all birds fly that's not
part of the biological definition of a
bird
we think of a robinson sparrows as birds
because they fly in the same
but flying and singing are not defining
features of the category birds
let's just one of the purple burglarized
difficult work for example fence and
sings
for instance flies off the fence
does all these kinds of
birdie things
even though that doesn't have anything
to do with being a warm-blooded
vertebrate
with feathers and wings
an alternative view of categorization
aldrich dog whiteman talks about a
little bit
abandons the view of walla co dot that
is the emphasis on features and
fireworks
in the proper sethi through
categories were defined by defining
features features over singly necessary
in jointly sufficient to define an
object as an instance of a category
in russia is
fuzzy set for you
categories were are defined in terms of
prototypical features
features over highly correlated
with category membership
but not necessarily perfectly correlated
with category membership and this
example our view
basically says
that you just abandon
for the use of features are all instead
you have a category that's
representative your mind
as a
relatively short list
typical instances
so if i see an object
and i want to know if it's a bird i
don't inspected to see that sings and
flies
which are characteristic features of
birds ok why inspected to see if it
looks like a robin or a sterile or in
the eagle or a hawk
and if it is like all of a bird and if
it doesn't
hi all i don't recall the river
again
both the product ideal of categorization
and the exemplar view of categorization
depart radically from below
article record role classical view of
categories as proper sucks
and they owe us straight the distinction
between what you might call logic
trickle approach to categorization
and what you might call the
psychological approach to categorization
there's one way to do things that's
prescribed by flaw sufferers
we're committed to normative rationality
and there's another way
to do things
that's described by psychologists
who actually look at hull
the mind works okay
so these problems with categorization
suggest that there's another awaited
view human thought then through the lens
all
on normative rationality and in this
lecture today we're going to see some
other examples of that
basically the idea here woods who have
already talked about this let's go on to
albright problem of categorization
categorization is always a matter
although judgment
problem solving the problem being to
determine
what category and object belongs in
when we think about power problems are
structured and how problems are solved
it turns out
algorithms for judgment or only work for
a specific class the problems known as
well defined problems
well defined problems are ones that are
completely specified
with respect to
the initial conditions set by the
problem
the bolt to be reached in the problem
and the intermediate operations to be
performed
did he knew from the initial conditions
to the goals
problems in elementary algebra
or
of are well-defined
uh... in in exactly the slaying if i
said to you
three acts plus three equals twelve and
i want you to solve for x
an algorithm
that'll allow you to do that
you subtract three from both sides of
the equation
and then you divide both sides of the
equation by three
so that you find out
that x equals three
in a problem like this the public this
is well-defined because there is only
one possible representation of the
problem
and there is a only one correct solution
to the problem and there's an algorithm
that'll tell you what that solution is
and all you have to do is apply it
but there are there problems that art
ill-defined
in that they are in one way or another
not completely specified
you with your dole
necessary you don't know all the initial
conditions
you may not know the goal
or you may not know the intermediate
operations
on algebraic example might be ok
unnikrishnan like this
three acts plus three white males twelve
on yesterday solve racks
and he can't deliver exactly because the
value of x depends on the value of life
if the if y equals one xd
as one value
if why he pulls too
x has another value
in ill-defined problems
there are many
different possible representations all
of the problem
there are many different ways to look at
the problem
and a solution to the problem
is going to be determined
but either way it's represented
the solution of problem
is going to be determined
all right
on on
by the are
but what you decide to specify
the initial conditions
walls or the intermediate operations for
what have you and the fact of the matter
is
that most of the problems that we
encounter in the ordinary course of
everyday living
more closely resemble build the foreign
problems
then well-defined problems ok just about
all the kinds of problems that you
encounter
hardly any of them look like
before nobody equations of elementary
algebra
okay most of it look like
first thing you have to be rose what the
goal is okay
then you have to have that you have to
figure out what your condemned the
butcher intermediate conditions are
and then you have to figure out how do
you get from point a to point b
all of these things
are relatively incompletely specified
in other words
most reasoning
judgment
and decision making
takes place under conditions of on the
certainty
okay
and
weakens archived identified a number of
these conditions which we call
conditions of uncertainty first
whenever you have an ill-defined a
problem
whatever you have a problem
that'd mets of more than one
representation
and bus all can be solved in more them
one way okay
when you've got to build a fine problem
there is no algorithm that will solve
that problem of for you
so that's one way in which we think
about combat conditions of uncertainty
but there are other
conditions about certain people
where the problem could in principle be
solved with an algorithm
for one reason or another it just
doesn't work out
for example you may not know what the
algorithm is somebody else might know
but you don't know what the algorithm is
if you don't know what the algorithm is
you're trying to solve the problem under
conditions of uncertainty
or you may know what the algorithm is
but you may have insufficient
information
if three x plus free wine equals twelve
i ask you to solve for x
and you don't know what why is
you can't apply the algorithm anyway
okay
or there may be insufficient opportunity
to take all the information you need and
slogged through the algorithm
to get from
uh... from the initial state
to the goal state insufficient
opportunity either because you don't
have enough time
together all the information and to
apply all the transformations
you just don't have enough
to do it
utah it's a
three x plus free wine equals twelve
sulfur exit sec
wine
i don't want out
five x's five right because they don't
carry a one a couple lunch or whatever
okay
all of these all circumstances
comprise what we call
all the conditions of uncertainty
and the point here is dead whenever you
encounter a problem
broadly defined
under conditions of one thirty uses not
going to use an algorithm either 'cause
there isn't an algorithm you don't know
what it is
or you don't for whatever reason
you're not be able to
to to employ so what do you do one of
those circumstances just stop
without
all we know no
that under conditions uncertainty
we shift to another moment all of the
reasoning another mode of problem
solving
all of that has to do
with the application of water known as
judgment
heuristics
judgment heuristics our approaches to
reasoning and problem solving
that constitute
inferential shortcuts
or judgmental rules are followed
these rules of combat bypassed the
principles of a logical inference okay
and all by bypassing the principles of
logical inference
they permit
plus to make judgments under
various conditions of uncertainty
now the interesting thing is
judgment heuristics and able us to make
judgments under conditions of
uncertainty but we tend to use them to
make judgments under conditions of
certainty as well when we make tudjman
civil all kinds
we tend to gravitate towards judgment
your respects as opposed
judgment algorithms
usually
of reliance on judgment heuristics as
opposed to judgment algorithms
is a good thing
because
you can get a reasonable
alaska a
of solution to a problem with relatively
little time involved relatively little
after involved
the problem is
remember what i told you about
algorithms last time
when there's an algorithm available
and over the world currency
that you get the correct solution to a
problem
when you switch to judgment your
respects
that bypass the rules of logical
inference
you may never have that guarantee
judgment heuristic may get you to a
solution of problem
or it may lead you
to make
some one or another kind of error
and in fact
psychologist
in further the kinds of judgment
teristics of people use
from an analysis
of the others that they make
in reasoning
problem solving
judgment
and decision making
daniel common
who recently won nobel prize in
economics couple years ago all for this
work
and his colleagues the lately must first
be common was here at berkeley for many
years risky was down the road and
stanford
before his untimely death
although
identified for commonly used a judgment
heuristics
four commonly used teristics that are
used for various kinds of
permits these
it had to go out
microphone okay
anyway
four
judgment to respect that are commonly
used in a wide variety of reasoning
domains there are lots of other judgment
to respect so i'm not going to give your
whole catalog from of them but i want
you to appreciate kind of what these two
or teristics are so that you get an idea
of how things go over a congenital
representative s
although it to respect that's commonly
used in making judgments of
categorization
also making judgments of probability
capability with respect that's made in
making used commonly in making judgments
of frequency
or simulation
ought to respect that's commonly used
for making judgments of probability as
well
and anchoring and adjustment or
heuristic that's commonly used an
estimation
let's see how each
of these
first the representative mr rustic
which is used as i said categorization
in a sense
you've already seen the representative
mr respect
in our discussion of
prototype or probabilistic approaches
to categorization
where there's an algorithm
just compare the features of the object
to the defining features of the target
category
and see if there's a match
but we don't do that instead we judge
that things are all fruits or articles
of furniture
body
day look-alike and that's essentially
on what goes on if the represented in
this
quality respect
here is a good example of it
there's a problem the continent frisky
studied quite a bit
in families of six children
which is the most likely sequence
of boys and girls what's the most likely
sequence of boys and girls that joel
observed
a girl followed by a boy followed by a
girl following two boys followed by a
girl
three boys and a role
followed by three girls in a row
avoid followed by a girl
followed by
boys in a row
in families of six children
which is the most likely sequence of
and girls
most people
that this sequence girl boy girl boy boy
girl
is much more likely
then this sequence three boys followed
by three girls
which in turn
is much more likely
then sequence of a boy agrawal followed
by
for boys as well
very common result in a five pulled you
the personnel you know that psychologist
poor these kinds of tricks he wouldn't
answer
all of the right
back when people were naive
all of this is the kind of data or that
the gave and of course this is world
okay
if you think about it for a second
the probability of any particular
newborn being a boy is one of two
these probabilities are completely
independent of each other
okay
so the probability that you were born a
boy or girl didn't have an have anything
to do with the probability but your
order brothers or sisters
were born boys or girls
therefore
the probability of the sequence girl boy
girl boy boy girl
is about
one-and-a-half times out of a hundred
the probability of free voice followed
by three girls is also about one and a
half times out of a hundred
and the probability of a boy followed by
a girl followed by four boys
is again about one-and-a-half times out
of a hundred
buffering probabilities in question
or precisely equal
if you have six children of family
the chance that the sequence is going to
be this
is the same as the chance that the
sequence is going to be that
but it doesn't look without getting okay
we think that the ways and girls appear
more or less randomly in families
and so
when either so we expect the sequence
two-b_-one that looks random
this sequence girl boy girl boy girl
looks more random than this sequence
three boys followed by three girls
and so we judge that this is the more
likely probability when in fact it is
not is a classic illustration
of the home
of the above the use of the
representative maintenance to respect
people are not actually calculated the
probabilities
okay which is something in ohio to do
that's an algorithm for solving this
problem just calculate the probabilities
one-half raised to the sixth power will
do it every time
but instead are picking judgments about
the way things look
about
how closely in event resembles
the image we have
the of the entire category
all this is a the representative
representative nancy respect
all underlies a very common on problem
known as the gambler's fallacy
we know that on a roulette wheel half
the numbers are red and half a numbers
are blacks
if you were asked people which of the
following runs is more likely to end
with a red
red blue red red
red black red red black red black
by blacks in a row
blacks in a row people will generally
say
that these two sequences are more likely
to end in a red then this sequence why
this one looks random
profanity this one looks random
and you figure you really can't tell
with the move next one's going to be
black or red
whereas here
you think that
well in a random sequence it ought to
straighten itself out ok so if you see a
local long-run of blacks you figure that
are ready is more likely to come up next
huge numbers of people lose money
gambling
by making judgments like this
it's a fallacy of course because all
there is no
a fact on the probability of an event
being black or red
depending upon the
of them on the of previous events not of
that's a fair roulette wheel
anyway but i fixed roulette wheel that
you're in big trouble
but the fact of the matter is
the probabilities or the same in each of
these cases
again
gambler's fallacy occurrence
because people make judgments based on
what things look like
whether a sequence looks
random or not
whether it resembles their ideal over
random sequence or not
and fail to actually calculate
the probabilities
so here we have two examples of these
represented in this your respect
being used in
making judgments although
probability so here weakened state the
representative miss your respect
formally
representative is to respect
hoodies used when people
faith or judgements on
the extent to which an event resembles
that's parent population
whether a string of numbers resembles
the whole population of random numbers
or not
or whether an event
reflex salient features of
generating process
you expect that random generator
would generate roughly half poison
roughly half girls and it did kind of
the all-star
intermixed
that's what we think about
a sequence of random numbers
but cores any sequence of five six ten
random numbers may look very non random
that's the point of the representative
mr respect
where judgments are based on similarity
judgments are based on similar to
and there a problem for me it's actually
not a bad idea if i ask you whether an
object is a bird
okay
and on
a you can measure its body temperature
is check to see if it's got a spinal
cord
if it looks like a boost barrel it's
probably a bird right not a bad
militaristic
the problem is
problems crop up when people fail to
appreciate base rates
when people fail to appreciate
the actual probabilities bombs on you
know involved
that's what the representatives
can we do straight
bombarding seen an example of the
representative mr respect in mister
justice graze supreme court decision all
in the art of him in the tariff
activating eighty three
where gray basically said
tomatoes are vegetables because they
were like vegetables
we treat them like vegetables also i'm
going to call it a vegetable even though
botanically speaking
i know that fruits
are all vegetables or betrayals or
fruits
what what justice graded was to set
aside the algorithm
but instead
based his judgment on the degree to
which
tomatoes
reptile resembled all other vegetables
seenu
as opposed to
uh... resembling other
all here are there's another way in
which you see either represented in this
your respect
all in operations the judgments of
causality
in general people think
that causes and of facts should look
like each other
and in public policy debates
you will often see
all people assuming
that causes of a fax will look somehow
like the effects themselves
for example
when people claim
that sex education in schools or the
provisional birth control and schools
will increase the likelihood
of teenage pregnancy
file for example
but that's not the case okay we have
very good data on this
but people think that alter something
sexual emea fact like teenage pregnancy
or teenage sexual behavior
there ought to be something sexual in
the closet like
sex education putting ideas and kids'
minds or whatever
the our debate about violence on movies
and tv is has some of them to m_t_v_ has
some of the same kinds of qualities
the idea that violence
on media portrayals of violence causes
violent behavior to occur
is very very very popular even though
the evidence on that part of the issue
is highly controversial
yet it's very easy for people to
conclude
that violence in society
is caused by violence in the media
again because they assume
that causes are going to resemble on
their effects
all
here's another one a little bit more
subtle
the idea that or it's an organ music
education schools
causes students to are to work out what
you prefer
works because we have this idea of the
highest cheating stealing as somebody
could do calculus and physics and plays
the violin and countries like
shakespeare right
they had this idea of what a
highly-educated of person can do
in fact
although i'm certainly in favor of
artnet norton music education in schools
the evidence that
art music education itself and has this
academic achievement is very very very
controversial
people think it does
because they think that but one kind of
on
of
sophistication
will go with another kind of
so all we are all in all these examples
we have people using the representative
mr respect to make judgments
based on
broke resemblance or based upon
similarity
here's another one
the availability to respect also
described by condiment and doug fir uske
very commonly used to make judgments of
frequency
and judgments of probability
here is a problem that condiments frisky
cept for their subjects
all but i want to do is to estimate the
number of words in english that begin
with the letter k
and estimate the number of words in
english that have k as there
the report
who thinks that the other more of words
in english that begin with caved in her
case or third letter
the honest with yourself
who thinks there are no more more called
likely is the third letter
you read ahead
of the fact of the matter is
most people who don't think
psychologists are tricky take precisely
the opposite judgment
they think that there are vastly more
almost all of the words in english that
begin with the letter k that had to pay
if their second or of second or third
letter
when in fact quite the reverse
their many more our words in english
that have to pay as their second or
third letter
that have as their of burst water
all why do people make this mistake
who couldn't think of all the word with
kay is the first letter
put up your hand it seems to think of a
word
and stone who can't think of a word with
kay is the second letter
that's the dalaberti heuristic ok it's
huge
the to think of words that have k is
their first letter okay
it's not so easy to think about words
that have k is their second or third
letter ok there are more of them but
it's harder to think of them
that's the essence of the availability
to respect
when people make judgments based on
the ease with which instances can come
to mind
here's another example study by common
for city
known as the committee problem
given a group of ten people
how many different committees of two
people can you create
given a group of ten people
how many different committees of eight
people
can you
when presented with this
problem most people
drawing
that you can create many more committees
ought to people
then you can of eight people
though if you think about it for a
second
you know that every time you create a
committee of two people one of a group
of ten
you have automatically created a group
of eight people
that's all that's left
there also
a committee of eight people so there are
in fact exactly as many
committees of two that you can create
from a group of ten
as there are committees of eight
that part that you can create from a
committee of ten it's forty-fourth in
both cases a few
going to have to apply the bulb
polynomial there from you can just kind
of
think about it for half a second
all but that's that that that's the
basic answer
and why do people make this mistake
and make this mistake because it's use
the to think about with these either
generate committees
so you think okay you got all call
you've got a committee of person any
indian b and c and c indeed
india the indian our friend and after
the indeed
on very easy to generate lots and lots
of committees
but when you try to do the same thing
with eight people use it
alternators person
a b_ c_ d_ e_ f_ g_ age
and then there's a person b c d e f g
expired cd that's really are
rotate
it's just really hard you can keep a
straight and so you think well gee you
know
he easy enough
i could be a lots of committees of two
so there must be
the ability to respect
our current when people make judgments
based on the ease with which
instances can be brought to mind
okay
all and that's not bad idea
in the ordinary course of thing
of the ordinary course of things highly
frequent events ought to be easy
to come to mind or to be easy to
retrieve of from memory
the problem is
that dot role availability teristics
ignores offer
factors
that can affect
home although the availability ok like
just
limitations on human information
processing capacity
one reason
why it's difficult
to generate committee of eight from a
group of ten people is that the capacity
of short term memory is roughly seven
plus or minus two
pretty much exceeds the capacity of
short term memory
it's hard to keep the things in mind on
dot com
at a time
all about money make our judgment of
availability tweed onsite
all yeah well it's really hard to do
that so i'm going to discount the uh...
the fact that it's hard and i'm going to
say well they're probably more
remembers of body we don't do that
we ignore these other
kinds of uh...
these other kinds of factors
so that's the availability tourist
representative s
faithful where rebate judgments based on
the resemblance or similarity
the availability to restrict where we
make judgments
based on ease with which we can
bring instances to mind
related to the availability to respect
is what's known as the simulation
heuristic
simulation heuristic also being calm
uh... used in judgment so probability of
various kinds also being used in
judgments of causality of various kinds
here is an illustration
from carmen and frisky
known as the on doing problem
what what you imagine two different
travelers heading for the airport
they're scheduled to take different
flights out of the airport
that because of the way airline schedule
things the planes are scheduled to leave
at the same time
these two travelers meet outside the
hotel and they agreed to share a cab to
the airport
the cab gets caught in
a traffic jam
as tabs often
and the cab driver turns on sat i'm
sorry guys i think you're going to miss
your plane
the two travelers then get to the
airport
thirty minutes late
travel or me okay
gets to his gate
and finds out that his plane left on
time
traveler b
gets to his gate
and finds out that his flight was
delayed and left five minutes ago
and the question is
who's going to be more upset person pay
are or person
who's going to more upset under those
circumstances
the okay
wine
that's in doc exactly the right answer
people think these are big vastly more
upset than a wise be good to be more
upset
just missed it but will cable but what's
the what what's why would i think it was
still missed it
these yes go ahead
okay bob why does that matter
okay something like that
easy total think of ways in which you
could have caught five minutes off your
time if only i haven't brushed your
teeth
if only i hadn't thought stop to call
your husband if only i hadn't thought
stock for that extra cup of coffee or
whatever
i would have gotten in a different have
and i would have gone to the airport and
yes my claim would have been delayed but
at least i would have been on the plane
here it is the third simulation
heuristic us
you what you have no guarantee
that any of that's going to happen
you know for all you know the traffic
jam was worth five minutes before that i
was five minutes later
for all you know the plane might have
been delayed off for only twenty minutes
at the post of twenty five minutes or
whatever
you simply don't know
you base your judgment
on the ease with which you can
various kinds of circumstances okay
in the simulation heuristic we base our
judgments on the ease with which we can
imagine a plausible cid theo
the difference between simulation and
availability
is that availability is always based on
use of retrieval from memory
it tried to think
english words to begin with the letter k
or whatever
but in simulation we have the ease with
which you can construct something
the indian national usually
or sold out
all here do you think about just trying
to concoct plausible scenario was and
again the problem here is
that while it may be easy to construct a
plausible scenario that might have led
to a different state of affairs there's
absolutely no guarantee that that
scenario
would have of what would have occurred
use
people use the simulation heuristic all
the time
how many of you have misbehaved in high
school instead to your friend
my parents are gonna kill me
okay
i'm going to be grounded for life or
whatever it is that parents do to kids
these days right
that's the simulation heuristic ever
really easy to think about how your
parents are going to react to something
and it's going to be awful of the
world's going to come to an end in
you're going to die
these things don't usually happen
that way right
but the stimulation heuristic is easy to
imagine how your parents are going to
react
or and they don't necessarily are they
don't necessarily do it
all
if you think about it for a second
something like the simulation heuristic
all underlies
many of our own motion all responses to
events
there's a whole class of a motions known
as the counterfactual emotions
frustration
regret
and indignation are really good examples
winner
the emotional state
is determined in some sense by your
comparison between the actual state of
affairs
and
what might have been
if you think about from frustrations one
thing you know
that's one thing that you'd
kind of debt
what you want in life for
within any particular instance
but when something occurs that didn't
have to happen that way
that prevents you from
get into a particular fraternity or
getting a particular date on friday
night or
or getting a particular job or whatever
that's when you really feel frustrated
really feel regret about sub is not when
you do something better stupider
some negative outcome
you regret
doing something bad when u could have
done something else but if you can
imagine i'll tell you only had said that
or whatever
that's the simulation heuristic
and i've been
the ability to army
najib things be different than what they
are
imagine how things could be different
from what they are
is what leads us to have
these kinds of particular
i'll these kinds of particular emotions
so represented in this
availability
purist on simulation
here it is the fourth of condominiums
for cities
almost all of that all judgment to
respect
known as the anchoring and adjustment to
and this is very commonly used
when we try to make drug for estimates
of various kinds will be tried estimate
the frequency with which
all of them super
here is a problem that condiments risky
used to of to a study angry adjustment
called the extrapolation problem u_s_
people very quickly to estimate
the result of the following
multiplication pick one group of
subjects who say
what's so what's the uh... producto
a time seven times six times five times
four times three times two times one
you get an estimate adult google
multiplication
do the estimate
bigger deliverables subject
and you say what's the product of one
times two times three times four to five
point six and seven times a day
when you do that
befallen results when you get people
behave sending version of the problem
one times two times three times four
times five times six times seven times
eight
their estimation is much lower
then when you give them descending
version of the problem
eight times seven times six times five
times four times three times two times
what even though of course
the two problems are exactly alike
they're exactly identical the products
are exactly identical
how does this happen
it turns out
try to estimate this you start out one
times two times three times for you
could try to do it at your head one
comes to his two times three and six
times for its twenty four e keep all
that kind of straight in your head
but when you try to do with the other
way
eight time six is fifty four times seven
is that i can even do that in my head
okay
or i could do it on my head but i don't
want to do in my head and it's getting
really vague
so what happens here is that people are
making their estimates based on what you
might call early data returns one times
two times three that's a relatively low
number so you think the final product is
going to be relatively low eight times
six times seven a daytime seven-time sex
is a relatively big number so you think
that the final product is going to be
are relatively big
and corinne an adjustment
indoochawla estimates
anchor final estimates they hold them
down they hold on where they are if the
initial estimate is bad than we think
the final is going to be big
if the initial estimate a small then we
get we think the final i was going to be
small is called anchoring an adjustment
nishal jostle additional estimates
anchor a final estimates
and in making final estimates we engage
in insufficient adjustment
from and nishal
our customers here is
another example of this
called the united nations problem
comment first be studied this one as
well
they went off the people on the street
on said
i like 'em doing a survey i'd like you
to estimate the percentage of countries
in the united nations that come from the
continent of africa
went to one group of people inside some
people say it's ten percent what do you
think
toward other triple subjects is that
some people say at sixty five percent
what do you think
peoples as the mets
depended upon the information they were
provided about what other people say ok
when people we're told that some people
say it's ten percent they gave all lower
estimate then when they were told
that some people say its
five percent
so here
nishal estimate
anchors
the final estimate
there's insufficient adjustment from the
additional estimate now you can say what
cool down the road told me in some
people say it's ten percent
antonio hole was
for all you've got a complete idiot
at intel representative sample of the
population says it's ten percent or
anything like that has had some people
for all your does your brother
this works out this way even
when the august even when the initial
estimate is given by this bit of a
roulette wheel they actually did this
experiment
where they say they are
sump all of the budget tell me at all
what percentage of the united nations
members come from a comment about her
weight perceptible in spindle roulette
wheel
and a roulette wheel would come up five
or six for forbes objects and
thirty four and thirty eight of the
birth of thirty six for other subjects
the people of dot the five and six would
give a lower estimate that the people
who got the thirty four and thirty five
even though at some roulette wheel for
god's sake
the than this show as timid encouraged
the final estimate
so and that's what the anchorage
adjustment is all about
final estimates are overwhelmingly
influenced by initial estimates okay
uh... where the initial values serves as
well as as an anchor
and of course that's not a bad idea and
put the kerrigan estimate something that
the big your initial estimate is
probably going to be big too
if you're going to have straight
something small your initial estimates
profile public under the small as well
but there are problems it's not an
algorithm
it's not guaranteed to give you
be correct answer
because there could be problems in the
formulation of the problem some people
say it's ten percent what do you say
that's no way to ask people this
all or the partial computation might be
misleading one times two times three
times four vs eight ten seven times six
times five ok in any event theories
insufficient adjustment from the a
from the foam from the uh... initial
value
so there we go
represented s
availability
simulation
anchoring an adjustment or an agreement
insufficient adjustment if you will
four ways in which across a wide variety
wide range of problems
wider range of decision context
people depart from
uh... normative rules of logical
inference
people you can use these judgement she
respects
widely in everyday life
either because
un alberta isn't available to them there
is no longer rhythm
or because they're insufficiently
motivated or they don't have enough
information to use this over them
but kinds of problems that we had
counter
the ordinary course of everyday living
or technically
ill defined problems
there's either not an algorithm
there's an algorithm that for one reason
other the we don't know about or we can
use or under those circumstances
rely
instead on judgment teristics like the
ones the condom and for ski define
okay will finish this up next time thank
you very much