okay let's continue our discussion of
psychopathology in psychotherapy
but before we do that
but a reminder that next week next
thursday we have the final examination
in this course
going to be thursday morning we don't
know where you had
i don't know where yet somebody may know
where's yet but i don't
but it doesn't matter
or it could be here it could be at the
uh... basketball arena that's where
we've had these exams before
all get that'd information to you just
as soon as i get it
all
do you have reviews that i've been
thrust into the website that was an
experiment this year that's worked out
so well i'm going to do it for the final
as well
so we'll have that most of the course
website by friday that's plenty of time
offer your studying i think i know all
the students who have are disability
accommodations now
if i don't
gotta get that to be pretty fast
on and will have the same arrangements
as usual for alone for the exam
just a couple more details about the
exam river it sooner to part format
there is a non killed a portion of the
exam that will cover all the materials
since the last all goat since last
midterm
chuck lectures and chapters on
psychological development
lectures and chapters on the stand
psychopathology in psychotherapy but
also will have a couple of questions
drawn from the appendix on statistics
on that document portions would be
exactly thirty six items no more no less
all along
speculative portion will be the
remaining sixty four items
covering the whole shamir
beginning onto to end
so i will be exam will be a hundred
mobile choice
questions that's double the size of our
day after the midterm so three hour exam
you have plenty of time ought to
complete the exam
on usual roughly half drawn directly
from the lectures roughly half drawn
directly
or from the text
armed
and make sure when you come from
wherever we're going to have the exam
make sure that you come with the proper
red scantron form
okay
we are not the improper read one or the
green one book
the right one
alms and uh...
to be cured that is just haven't filled
out
with identifying information beforehand
all a couple of other deadlines are
discussion sections
although continue through monday the
last day of class next week
this weekend next in discussion section
you'll be doing course evaluations
all get the discussion section grades
posted by tuesday
all of the eleventh of all
of uh... december
if are there are any
errors
shall we call them errors all of them
discussion section graves
you need to contact you're geoscience
very quickly
palm of for this
and request of request reconsideration
the reason we usually do with
one-week deadlines for these kinds of
things at berkeley finals the final
grades are due within ninety six hours
of the final exam
so of there just isn't enough time
to give people weekdays correct things
on and so on
so uh... all
check your role
check your section great in the course
website
sometime after monday and uh... there's
any issue
pick up your g aside before
too soon
or p pieper dissipation that's going to
be completed by next monday the ten th
and make sure when you've finished your
are p_p_ purchase a patient
that you would find your credits dislike
one
because what happens at the end of the
allowed at the end of the semester i'd
get the download our roster for this
class the shows all the r p p credits
that have been assigned to this class by
the students in the class
if you haven't
assigned your credits
i don't know what they are okay i have
no way of doing that
are consult the or keep you blue sheet
for good instructions
but make sure you assign your credits
to uh... looks like one
any quick questions about the are
final exam business
last time we were discussing the origins
of
mental illness but question of the
f_b_i_ logy of mental illness
and i set out a time framework for
understanding
hire people get
become mentally ill
known as the died after so stress
framework
and basically the idea is
that there are two
factors
that are important in causing
mental illness to occur
neither one of which is sufficient
four all of them for mental illness
but the two of them have to interrupt
altogether
in a way that's similar to all
directions that we've seen
the first of these is that i got a
suspect or
which is some characteristic of the
individual something that the individual
carries with him or her
on could be genetic and could be more
moral it could be constitutional
it could be called it the could be a
promotional the could be anything but
it's a more or less stable
characteristic of the individual
that predisposes is him or her to sign
the particular formal of mental on
illness
leaves the person habitable
to some form of mental illness believes
a person
at risk
are despite a slight episode so the
ideas are people adapt to whatever the
study offices factories they make a
relatively good a relatively poor
are adaptation
but an episode of mental illness
does in a car are less that person's
current level of adaptation is
challenged
by some
knew of that
this is the stress component in the diet
offices stress model
so the idea is your venerable or
something
then something happens
that precipitates or an acute episode of
mental illness
but the stress doesn't cause mental
illness and everybody
it all neeku causes the mental illness
people who are carrying our particular
predisposition or die offices factor
and last time i gave you a number are
the examples of
right out of the death as the stress
model on inaction
time-dependent show you how are how it
worked
i won't go over all of that all mel but
just to review
all remember that poor schizophrenia
and for you in a poor after
to distort so-called major depressive
illness we know that there is a genetic
component to these illnesses we know
that because
model psychotic twins all show higher
concordance rates for these mental
illnesses then dies i got a twins do
that's prima session evidence for a
genetic or inherited component in these
two forms of mental illness
d concordance rate for schizophrenic and
for major affect a disorder
is fat less than a perfect one hundred
percent
by the logic of behavior genetic studies
that means that there is also important
billions in schizophrenia
an important variance in a yuna polar
depressive disorder
that's contributed by the
now i'm sure impairment
okay
so you've got in these behavior genetic
studies of schizophrenia and audit
beautiful or affect of disorder evidence
for both a genetic diagnosis
there's some genetic predisposition
just as a friend here and two major
press of illness
but you ought also very clear
that that genetic determination is not
decisive
it's not decisive because are if one
twin
has schizophrenia
there's only about forty fifty percent
chance that the other twin will have
schizophrenia
something the differentiates them
that something is in the not shared
environment and that seems to of reflect
the stress factor
then continuing wall with those studies
from the heart of the actual castings
group
we thought that you and all
adolescent conduct disorder on major
formal personality disorder that affects
on adolescence and and young adults
we saw that all
levels of enable any activity
fault seem to be a dot at the suspect ur
and a history of maltreatment
seems to be ustrust
factor
so it's a particular combination
on enable eighty activity
and maltreatment
seems to lying at the heart of
adolescent conduct disorder
or if you're carrying particular form of
the m_ a_ l_ a_ gene
but you're not exposed
to also on long history of maltreatment
you don't get adolescent conduct
disorder released about more likely to
get it
then dog then somebody selected at
random
it's the dialysis and the stress in
combination
similarly another study from cast these
group of depression on depression
looked at another gmail known as the
five h_t_t_p_ gina never could
but geneticist provocative
cockamamie names right you will have to
worry about
where they come from
all
and there are two different wheels of
this gene mall at short and long you get
one from each year parents
on it turns out that if you've got one
of the three short versions of the five
h_t_t_p_ lol allyl
combined
with a history of lots of stress
then it's that combination
of the genetic diagnosis
and at the stress in your life
that is likely to precipitate an episode
of depression
and similarly there was a study by
foxtons nathan fox of his colleagues
on pathological shyness
not ordinary garden variety shyness
we're talking about serious pathological
shyness
here
again
the short only on the five h_d_t_v_ gene
is implicated as a dialysis factor
social support
for the individual among family of the
family and friends is the or
is the environmental factor here
and it's the combination
of the genetic predisposition with the
environmental factor all low levels of
social support
that seems to me
the pathological shyness these are all
examples of how
some kind of genetic
dialysis will leave a person vital to
some form of mental illness
and then some specific stress or
will
combine with that genetic play out this
is
to precipitate a particular episode one
thing i want you to notice here is how
specific this is
it's not that there is a jeans somewhere
that says we're going to get mentally
ill
itself
and they may gene that seems to be
involved in adolescent conduct disorder
but doesn't seem to be involved in
depression
it's the five dekhti thi gene
that seems to be involved in depression
but doesn't have anything to do
with adolescent conduct disorder
moreover even stressor factors or more
of a specific tune with a particular
all before the mental illness we're
talking about
it's a history of maltreatment
that is critical for adolescent conduct
disorder
not stressful dot gov of the amount of
stress in the person's life or the
amount of social support is the amount
of stress and the person's life
that is critical for depression
not the history of maltreatment or not
the level of social support
so it's not as if there's some funny
jeans somewhere that leads to mental
illness
or some
gendron eric factor in the environment
that precipitates the of episode
the dialysis and stress factors involved
in use different form of mental illness
appeared to be different
here are two more examples
where we seem to have evidence for a
biological play out the cis
interacting with environmental stress to
lead to particular forms of mental atlas
this one is a favorite of mine
psychosomatic ulcers
are there are people who get also
resolved regions in the of pollen in the
young gastrointestinal lining
all there's a lot all history all belong
of all psychosomatic medicine
that attributed these of or that these
ulcers
to stress
stress as you know from chapter three of
glickman not to mention or earlier
lecture
stress stimulates the secretion of acid
into the stomach lining
if a lot of that as it gets into the
stomach ache and eat away as the stomach
lining and callers on called cause it
all sort
but about twenty years ago now a group
of australia medical researchers
discovered that there was a particular
bacterial infection h_ pylori by this is
what it looks like
a particular apartheid
that is found in the d
uh... within the intestinal tracts of
people with all serbs and that led them
these guys won the nobel prize for
medicine ought it was last year waited
long enough they finally got it
all
well for them for the for this discovery
which at the time seem to overthrow
the idea that stress was involved in
authors
and to suggest that there was a purely
or biological cause of ulcers
that won't which was infection by each
of apollo right
but it turns out make up for a long
story short
you can find this bargain in about
eighty eighty five percent of people who
have all sorts
but the dirty secret is you can also
find the spoken about eighty or eighty
five percent of people who don't have
all sorts
so it but the bacterial infection is not
been itself
because of all services
it turns out we now have a good evidence
from laboratory studies
all of this bacterial infection all into
racks
with environmental stresses of various
kinds especially prolonged
emotional stress
leading to prolong the activation of the
autonomic nervous system
and it's
accommodation
although h_ pylori infection plus
pro-life environmental stress that leads
to or the development of ulcers
or at least orthonormal a little rat
model laboratories
and as well as we can tell
you know
you know in rats as well so here's one
more example and i'm going to give you
one more example
of died at the system stress little old
that different in character
enough
we usually think about phobias as fear
reactions that are accounted for by some
kind of learning experience
you go over the world you have some kind
of
although
terrible experience in some situation
and then you find yourself with an on
the reasonable unwarranted fear of that
situation
that part classical conditioning model
of obvious but very popular for about
fifty years on now
all day and it turns out that that's a
pretty good of account of of other of
the phobias
with one exception
and now it is
epic kinds of phobias that we meet opera
with in the clinic
or not
representative of all the situations
that or scary
all when the hall but when we cease all
phobic patients in the clinic
we don't find that they have
phobias about heights
they have for the is about closed spaces
they have phobias about being in the
presence of other people and especially
ball being watched
really makes you nervous to be watched
sometimes we got the social phobia
all they have four beers about various
kinds of animals but it's not usually
dogs and cats the people have will be
used for
snakes
and spiders
and other things that
don't have much about
alm basically
so the idea here is
that the phobias that we have though
that the object so we have for this for
are not arbitrary set of the objects
that we could also
moreover a lot of people have things
like snake phobias have actually never
had a bad uncomfortable to sneak to do a
detailed history have you ever been
bitten by a stick
hall
had never been surprised by snake
no every conceivable state
gold enough but still they have that
they will have his pathological for your
of of snakes
and when you trace it back it turns out
that that there's been some wild
encounters someplace nothing that would
seem sufficient
to trigger before being
martin seligman
all right and his colleagues came up
with all with an interesting idea
what happens is we are prepared by the
brochure lol revolution
to acquire a strong fear reactions to a
certain classes of stimuli okay
demand but in the air with very little
slower with with very little support
biederman close places even dark places
been in the presence of squiggly little
animals without legs that run close to
the ground
all of those cuts of things
and dot you can think about that
evolutionary preparedness
of for your response
as having some of the same kinds of
functions aphrodite offices
if you've got that's almond
evolutionarily prepared
predisposition to fear
just a smallest encounter
arms are with the above with the object
may be enough
to trigger the development
of a very severe
or for your or reaction susan my neck
out now what northwestern university
actually showed all of the of the show
the importance of conditioning
or a lot of preparedness
in a series of classic studies that you
did some years ago now
on of the acquisition of snake phobias
in rhesus monkeys this is the laboratory
model
all four all for total bs in humans it
turns out that rhesus monkeys who are
born and raised in the wild
or or free of snakes
every one of them
they're just afraid of sex
all and that has usually been
interpreted as a are
as a prewar yard
innate
reflexive fear which as you can imagine
if you're a little rhesus monkeys live
in the jungle all you want to avoid boa
constrictor zand cobras and dole and and
and other kinds of uh... and other kinds
of out of it
it makes sense is just a pre water
after it of your response
the only problem with this is as my
naked noted
is that
rhesus monkeys that are born under the
laboratory harder for his next
is not afraid of specs help culpa sings
the bekaa effective on c_n_n_ the other
day is good for the boa constrictor
it's like that but then they don't don't
mind
on snakes all at at at all
of however
if eight lab raise rear other rhesus
monkey
is exposed to of the deal is exposed to
a snake
then the animal will acquire a snake
local stapled it very quickly
well monica did a very sparse evidence
permits which i bought friend i don't
have time to talk to you about notified
half an hour
ought to do these experiments right
but i've got a very nice account of them
in the uh...
in the uh... lecture supplements
and when she looked at
all
a hollow rhesus monkeys could acquire
eight for your response to stakes
simply by being exposed to another
rhesus monkey that was already afraid of
snakes
and then to take a long story short she
arranged this experiment in such a way
that
the market was afraid of snakes was
exposed to a snake out of the view of
ladner monkey
all the lab rear monkeys solved was
snake and that the other alarms and the
other monkey being afraid
levered monkey didn't have any encounter
with a snake at all
but immediately after being exposed too
the palm
to the weinberger monkey
all of of reacting with fear to the
snake
belabored monkey became afraid of snakes
that's very interesting just one
exposure ought to go to get this
but in a different on the experiment
all-out sheet arranged by virtue of part
of the television monitors
to show a monkey reacting to a snake
but the test monkey
thought the market was reacting to of
vase of flowers
if we're just a straight up all of the
heart of the acquiring phobias
all through social learning was just a
couple of them straight matteo
seeing somebody
alm
be afraid of the presence of some object
you'd think these animals would become
afraid of or vase of flowers to but they
didn't
they already became afraid
when the monkey
though that the model monkey was exposed
to snake or a snake like object
so these animals seem to be
prepared
to become afraid of snakes
but don't be called operators actually
become afraid of snakes unless they were
exposed
to some kind of fear stimulus
but it doesn't work for other kinds of
stimuli it only works
for snakes and snake like stimulant
sojourn the idea here is
is that preparedness
or old friend from our program learning
lectures
is that like a diagnosis off factor for
phobias
there isn't a bad predisposition
to be afraid of heights
to be afraid of dark places to be afraid
of enclosed spaces
to be afraid of certain kinds of animals
but we're not naturally afraid of these
kinds of things we just have in napa and
innate disposition
to become afraid
when we're going to become afraid in
those various kinds of circumstances
that's when begat
the young
that's when we get the full dick
reaction
okay
schizophrenia
depression
conduct disorder
pathological shyness
also hers
almost and
phobias
all
although
conditions all mental illnesses
where we seem to have
a biological died at the cis
that leaves the person or the animal
venerable to psalm form of mental
illness
and and dot biological dialysis
interacting
with some kind of environmental stress
and that's the way to put up with the
stress theories of mental illness are
usually presented
that there is some biological dialysis
and the psalm environmental stress
that interactive produce an episode of
of mental illness but it turns out
of the all of the big dialysis factors
are usually biological but they don't
have to be
and the stress factors are usually
environmental or a psychological in
nature but they don't have to be either
so for example
we know that they are logical stress
orders
in the history of many people with
schizophrenia
and those have to do
all of them
prenatal or perinatal complications into
individuals who as adults
come down a schizophrenic
have a much
stronger history
of prenatal and perinatal of the birth
complications
that goes all the knows who do not
these complications are not enough
by themselves to cause is a friend a a
but these kinds of biological stress
sores
combined with
the biological predisposition
predisposition to schizophrenia may be
enough to trigger
an acute episode
all of the illness
moreover
the stress errors bart these that the
diagnoses are often biological
have to be
in some forms of depression
we said we seem to our will find
that individuals or rendered vulnerable
to some forms of depression
by psychological factors
not by
oh not by biological ones
the first person to discover this
erin backed him back at the university
of pennsylvania
on won the last earl warren a couple
years ago all four all for this work
that discovered
that individuals who are depressed
seem to share in common
wahl trial that all believes
that bob beckel refer to as the press or
genic scope that out
remembers camara are
pre-existing beliefs of expectations
that people have about the world that
terry them around on in their heads
and all the best argued
that
individuals with depression
have a cognitive dialysis cognitive
vulnerability
because they have this negative view of
themselves
negative view of the world
as a negative view of the future i'm no
good the world's a bad place in the
future socks okay
that's the general idea that the general
importance of the beliefs of these
people carry around with them
but it's a psychological diatoms as it
doesn't cause the depression
but if somebody who has the
you will of the world
that has some unpleasant unhappy
stressful events occur to him or her
what he or she is going to do
all according to beck's theory
is to
become actively
depressed so here you have
a psychological going out this is
in terms of these two presage an extra
models all people
houses negative view of themselves and
the world
and when something bad happens
then they become depressed
if you don't have
this negative view of yourself in the
world and something bad happens
you don't get depressed
according to the expiry you might get
angry
you might get determined
but you don't get depressed
similarly linnea gruesome learn a lawyer
and their colleagues in a very intent on
backs cognitive theory of depression
argued
people are rendered vulnerable to
depression
by virtue of having a particular style
of making attributions about events in
the world a particular style
of explaining the events that occur all
ill in their in their world
and this particular traditional style
involves making stable
internal and global attributions
stable a dutch additions
attributions too
factors that don't change
as opposed to variable
factors to do
internal attributions
attributions div two factors
that are part of the person
as opposed to
part of the world outside
global attributions
attributions that apply to all sorts of
events as opposed to
specific attributions
or that applies only to well particular
kinds of ends
and the general idea here
is that there are people kal believed
he's responsible flare
the things that happen to them
especially the bad things that happen to
them
and then when a bad thing does happen to
them that's when they get depressed
if you think
you are always responsible for the bad
things that happen to you
and a bad thing happens do
of course are going to get depressed
but if you think but somebody else is
responsible for the bad things that
happened to you
you're not going to get depressed you're
going to get angry or or something else
so the idea here is
but in bex theory
it's a very happy
thinking
peptide that predisposes his people to
develop start of depression
in are abramson diana lawrence theory
it's again
me i think you know it's a psychological
vulnerability factor
and then when something negative happens
then all
then the depression
yes bom
with gets precipitate
so here it is another example
where you can look at the interaction of
dialysis and stress
factors
we know for example that sudden changes
in parmar all endowment
ten trigger an episode of depression
changes that occur in the cessation of
pregnancy for example or with childbirth
or with entering
menopause this is one of the reasons
why depression is somewhat more common
in women or that it is in in men
we know that these
read that these sudden changes in
biochemical on and on in government in
hormonal endowment
we'll have various kinds of behavioral
consequences
bill alter the person's mood state make
amber or depressed
all will lead to reductions of activity
levels all again all lowered activity
levels as one of the non
motion also in terms
of depression
so that i want you to imagine now
isn't one of the lowest is if there is
also hormonal changes a biological
stress or
occurs to somebody who is
carried around in his or her head
baxter presage an extra model
or abramson's
onto presage attic
action the usual style
under those circumstances what they're
going to do
is to
interpret
the changes in
event levels and their behavioral
consequences
inouye
that may lead to
the onset of an episode of depression
okay
so it's a hormonal changes
but it's the interpretation of those
changes
in combination
that produce the depression all and
depends on
how you interpret these changes going to
determine whether you're going to get
depressed
just to
review the bidding here for a second
you should recognize by now
but the died out this is stress
framework for understanding the origins
of of the origins of mental illness
is a very and
on
or old familiar
person by situation interaction
dialysis factors
whited out dialogue circle in nature
like genetic
tore psychological in nature
depressive gen x_ camara or depressive
genic attribution all style
these are attributes all of the person
there's their of features
whether they're biological features or
cognitive features that the person
carries around are with him or over
it doesn't matter whether there had
their origins in the person's genetic
and almond
or whether they have their origins in
the person's history of social learning
they are still
factors that are
internal too
the our person
their bioethicist actors
stress orders are of course
features of the environment
stressors are things that happened to
the individual
either happened to the individual
by virtue of
something biological
all
terry nichols trust or since qasar
fretting
hormonal changes in some forms of
depression
or date of the stressors or
psycho-social in nature
our history of maltreatment or any of
them very very all thought the severe
all loss or whatever
again
you've got the interaction of something
about the person
whether it is
something biological or something
psychological interacting with something
in the environment
whether that is indeed biological
environment or in the psychosocial
environment
to precipitate an episode bom bom
to precipitate an episode of gentleness
so that's the diapers the stress
framework for psychopathology
let's take a break for a second
and see if you have any questions about
that before we talk about what you do
about mental illness
once you've got it
any questions about the diocesan struts
framework
what's the difference between the
depressive gen x_ camara are going to be
a traditional styles
they are
those are true lol tornado formulations
often what the predisposing cognitive
factor is
in depression they're two different
theories of depression
next
focuses on these negative view of self
other and the world those are these
depressive gen x_ d'amato
the abramson and the lori view
doesn't act does actually focus on a
negative view of the self
it is a
characteristic away of explaining events
in the world
in terms of stable
internal
global factors
i'm always responsible for everything
also
that the what what books they read oz is
emphasizes negative view of things
what do you personally welcome
emphasizes is this
tendency to explain events whether
they're positive or negative in a
particular way
in the same way that you could have
two different theories of schizophrenia
implicating different neuro transmitters
were two different theories of
depression implicating different kinds
of hormones these are two different
cognitive theories of depression
now interestingly
abramson and all the way were students
of backs
okay twelve they weren't direct students
of expert date he was a very important
of or the person in their role
calendar in their education
so they but they tend to see
back-end abramson in milan deloitte and
to see their theories as complementing
each other just kind of
emphasizing different aspects
all this
cognitive vulnerability to depression
with an answer
anything else about i doubt the system
stress before i go out
the delta some stress framework isn't is
a
detailed accounting
for a hollow somebody becomes mentally
ill
how an episode of mental illness happens
now let's try to talk about
how we do something
upon an episode of mental illness
once it's occurred
and again
aldy
up as the stress framework for the
understanding the origins of mental
illness
gives us a way of thinking about how to
intervene
to treat mental illness as well
so for example
unep a sort of mental illness
results from the interaction of dialysis
and stress
where neither the dialysis nor distress
or are themselves
sufficient or by themselves sufficient
for mental illness
what you want to do is peter eliminate
or reduce the dialysis
or eliminate or reduce
the stress or is
and that way
you will
of the mental illness okay
humanitarian or reducing the diagnosis
or stress
ought to lead to some kind of
cure okay
killer understood right as if it writers
in the medical model as eliminating the
underlying pathology right that's what a
cure does it eliminates the underlying
on the pathology
it's not enough just to suppress
symptoms
in the same way that if you've got a
fever your doctor just doesn't which in
a cold room
okay
gives you an antibiotic to get rid of
the clause of the fever if you've got
the symptoms of schizophrenia or the
scum of the symptoms of depression
we don't want to just get your rate
yourself higher on some happy the scale
we want to get you tune no longer have
the barbie underlying pathology
that is causing you to feel or said
are completely or
in the dining out this distrust
framework
would probably require
doing something about both but i doubt
this is factor
and the stress all factors
now in mentalist
we don't have to make yours
we've got some
but we don't have too many cures
rather in mental illness
at this stage of our knowledge right now
mostly
the best we can do is to reduce
you live in a
various kinds of symptoms that's just
the best we can do
error
if we can't
reduce or eliminate the symptoms of
mental illness
will be trying to do is to teach the
person
two cult as well as possible
a chronic
and again that's exactly the same
approach that we take
medical illness
if you've got some kind of infection you
go to a doctor
he or she will prescribe antibiotics
that'll get britain
all of the infection if you're lucky
but there are some come some forms of
illness
that do not admit of that kind of cure
diabetes
for example
is a chronic met up with medical
condition
our person what ideas
has to watch his or her diet may have to
take injections of insulin or something
else like tat fork the rest of his or
her life
but they preferred ideas
the resident cure but there are
treatments
reduce the symptoms of diabetes
and also a local person
to cope
with this chronic condition same thing
goes in schism in schizophrenia
depression
any other form of men of of mental
illness
if you can cure it
correct
if you can't apply treatment that is
known to reduce the symptoms
and
help the person to cope as well as
possible
or what's going to be a chronic
condition you're going to see those
three themes
if you can cure it
if you can't
at least address the symptoms
help the person
to cope better
on in the rest of electric today
and on wednesday
wasn't always the case
treatment for mental illness has buried
for a long time
all
or in the eighteen th
specially the nineteen th in the early
part of the twentieth century
there were no active treatments
for mental illness
instead mentally ill we were more or
less what hollows
in large mental hospitals
alm
home
classically called insane asylums
whittled called on those anymore but the
world would call the mental hospitals
but there were places
where the
all mentally ill
people with
severe mental illnesses schism franny al
depression and so on
work kept away from the rest of society
in an environment where they could be
cared for
watched
protected prevented from harming
themselves or or
role or other people but until
well after world war two
there were no really good active
treatment for mental illness treatments
that even tried to approach radio acya
work
alm
in the early part of the twentieth
century
all we began to experiment with various
forums on psychotherapy which were
intended to
contract
hard to help the person cope
with various kinds of of psychological
deficits okay
psychotherapy
it's a psychological treatment that is
but that is really trying to attack
mental function right to get a person i
think better
to have more appropriate emotional
reactions to have more appropriate to
rise in gold
walls and door and so on
and then after world war two getting in
the nineteen fifties
we begin to get the advent of a set of
biological therapies mostly in the form
of drugs
that are intended to of cr correct or
act on in some way
the presumed biological substrates
of various kinds of mental illness
and especially beginning in the
mid-nineteen fifties and continuing
today
witnessed what
can only thought of as a pharmaceutical
revolution
in the treatment of mental illness
a proliferation
of more
or less specific drugs
better intended
to attack
oh more or less specific forms of oil
moralist specific forms of mental
illness let's look at what some of those
drugs
are
first we have a large number of drug
treatments
federal employees
in the treatment of all of our
schizophrenic
most of these are so-called
anti-psychotic medications
where's psychosis is a euphemism here
four zero four of the for schizophrenia
all attendees mostly take the form of
major or minor tranquilizers
now if you don't have to memorize all
the names of these drugs
these are drugs that you will encounter
in your reading
you know encounter on t_v_ elsie ads for
suffered for firm firm for many of these
kinds of drugs
and these are drugs that are
use for the treatment of a wide variety
of total missus but they are especially
prominent in the treatment phone call
in the treatment of schizophrenia okay
authority scene
mela role
held all or close a real alarmed and and
and so on on these are all essentially
tranquilizers
that act to sedate or the person
and most of them do this
all by
acting upon the nor transmitter system
to reduce levels of dopamine
theo
alone in the in the brain
for the dopamine hypothesis of
schizophrenia schizophrenia recalled
symptoms of schizophrenia reflected
excess levels of dopamine
it's interesting
that the feet of buyers names and all
other
on drug treatment for schizophrenia
seemed to enact specifically on the
dopamine uh... system
similarly we have large number of drug
treatments available now for the
treatment all of major
on or the depressive disorders
on the first of these to call them to
all come into play
were known as try cyclic antidepressants
just about piece of drug or or the
terminology
but i don't senate one you'll see
references to these are you reading
which increased levels of nora prepare
for it
and serotonin
remember the north board motto a mean
hypothesis of depression
that depression reflects abnormally low
levels of nor epinephrine and serotonin
it's interesting
that these affective drug treatment for
schizophrenia act to intrigues
just those neuro transmitters
nor epinephrine and on
and serotonin
okay here's another group of drug
treatment for schizophrenia known as the
m_e_l_ inhibitors like nor gil and
parwnation
we know that there may also deactivate
weapon effort in serotonin
what you're depressed you don't want
anything
d activating your levels of nor up in
our friend and serotonin so these and
they are going to have bidders
inhabit the activity
of the nato
affectively
increasing levels of north and her
friend and serotonin in the uh... in the
brain
and that most recently we have this new
class of drugs
known as the selective serotonin
reuptake inhibitors the as i saw arise
there all the rage now
prozac zoloft axle three good examples
of them
and the day
specifically act
as their name implies this specifically
act on serotonin
don't have any affect
on nor epinephrine
these drugs can be a very effective
for the treatment
of all of depression
very very effective
and interestingly
these all of these affective drugs
have
a fax on the nervous system that are
consistent with the prevailing
biochemical
of uh... of depression
on these drugs all work
either in the north and efren
on north africa
or answering tone in
or on both
finally one other problem other example
drug treatment for anxiety disorder
of a large number of drugs
on available since the nineteen fifties
that are good for the treatment of
anxiety disorder
so these are very old like bill tone and
on the back window
orders or little bit on of more recent
michael of the peace corps
that x
and so on
these are all mostly
sedative drugs
or barbiturates
spends about two things
they'd all actions to date the nervous
system
and again one way of thinking about
anxiety
is that
the auditors on over arousal of the
nervous system
what these are drugs will do
is to is to come
the nervously the nervous system down
so i get
for schizophrenia
for major depressive disorder
for anxiety disorder and for other cup
forms of anxiety disorder like panic
disorder as well
the pharmaceutical revolution
has produced
a large number of drugs
that seemed to be affected
in the sense that
dave reduce
or eliminate
the symptoms of various forums of mental
illness
they provide symptom relief
and they also permit individuals
in an earlier age
would have been hospital hospitalized
move out of
institutions for the treatment of mental
of the mentally ill
back into their communities
and back with their families
this pharmaceutical revolution
has been
buried very very important
and very very effective bme that respect
for at least
and again one thing i want to point out
here
these drugs seem to have specific
affects
in the treatment of specific forms of
mental illness
we have one had
theories biological theories of
schizophrenia
of depression an anxiety disorder
implicate the role of the nervous system
and especially implicate the role of
various neuro transmitters
lo and behold defeat uprisings
which are very effective in the
treatment of schizophrenia act on the
timing system which theoretically
is that the wrote
of schizophrenia
the tricyclic antidepressants
which are very useful in the treatment
of depression
are act on amato amy no transmitters
levels of which
are all
are implicated in the cause of
depression
the benzo die as a games which are
affective in the treatment of anxiety
disorder
seem to work on another stall the the
returns that are known as gaveled on
which again
over activity of gabba has been of
thought to be a biological cause of
anxiety disorder
so at least in theory
these specific treatments
attack
presume to biological basis all of these
specific
disorders
where we have
pretty good byob bring pretty good
understanding of the underlying
biological deficit in schizophrenia
in depression and in exile disorder
these drugs seem to specifically
go after
those trying to affect
however
there are some problems
the reliance on the pharmaceutical
treatments although in the treatment of
mental illness
the first is
are powerful psychoactive drugs
each of which has unpleasant or on
desirable side-effects
various ways
although you know anti-psychotic
medications
can often produced
tremors of that resemble the symptoms of
parkinson's disease
they can produce all sorts of other
movement disorders
lots of annoying
or or the side effects
these drugs
which are in truth affected in the
treatment of certain kinds of symptoms
can cause no symptoms to appear
and that's not
kind of drug
uh... to have what you really like to
have
is a drug that'll attack
various kinds of symptoms or underlying
pathology without creating problems all
for the person
similarly
there it is
payton
take in some cases
lack of specificity in be affects of
these drugs
the selective serotonin reuptake
inhibitors
which would theoretically be appropriate
for the treatment of depression
because we think depression involves
abnormally low levels of serotonin
also turn out
to be effective in the treatment of
anxiety disorder
which doesn't
as far as we know involved abnormally
low levels of serotonin
it'd in addition to the practical
problems created by the side effects of
some of these substances
there is a theoretical problem
that sometimes you've got a drug like a
necesario right
that's good
for a condition that if the radically
ought to be good for
depression
but is also good for a condition like
anxiety
but it shouldn't
the so good for so we don't know what's
going on here
fireflame
these drugs although very affective in
the treatment of
symptoms
do not by any means
resulting in any case for for the
illness
we know that because when patients
going after medication they very
frequently experience a relapse sold the
drug works only so long as it's being
taken
it's not like an antibiotic
which have been taken just generated
infection
okay you have to take an antibiotic for
life
most cases
these art of these treatments
have to be taken chronically
if they're going to be called if they're
going to be affected
what we do it under those circumstances
what we do is
we turn to the other side of the
treatment equation we turn to
psychosocial interventions
i bow which i'll talk on wednesday
thank you very much see you wednesday