okay
last time we focused our
discussion of and thanking
on
deed normative rational choice model
forward judgment and decision making
and the psalm exceptions to the
rational choice model
that type of form of these various
judgement she respects
let's review the bidding for a second
and just remind you
that according to the normative model
altered went and decision making this
couple down to us
through about twenty five hundred years
the fa la sutti
human beings
rational human beings make judgments
based on logic
and based on the laws of probability
decisions rational decisions are always
decisions made in the self-interest of
the decision maker that is
you do it you just make decisions that
are good for you
regardless of whether they're good for
somebody else that's rationality define
self-interest is defined in terms of a
principle of optimality the basically
says
it's in the
rational self-interest of the decision
maker
to maximize his or her games
and minimize his or her losses
and rational self-interest is also
all
on displayed in a principle of utility
that basically says
you want to maximize games and minimize
losses
in the most efficient way possible
these
ideas these principles
give us
what me think of in economics
as the doctrine of rational choice okay
and here's another view of
rational choice
comes through from read hasty and robin
doors to
written uh... wonderful book on this
topic
is his first off
rational choice is what is one of the
based on
the decision makers current assets
but things that he or she hasn't and
right now
not what you might have in the future
will come to that the second
and not what you had in the past but
what you have
the second point
is a rational choices are based on
possible consequences of a choice ok you
don't know rational choices are made
all in terms of
good choices are bad choices in the
abstract but rather
rational choices are defined in solely
in terms of their consequences
and when the consequences are uncertain
but sometimes the consequences of a
choice or really clear if i'm going to
kick
this podium i'm going to hurt my toe
okay we know that that's the case
all but sometimes
consequences are uncertain
and then inr
or rational decision maker will evaluate
these consequences based on a
probability theory
and then basically
all of and any rational choice
is by definition adaptive
also along with its constrained by the
probabilities
that are available okay so long as is
constrained by the actual probabilities
all of these outcomes
and the values associated with each of
these aliquot okay so that's what a
rational choice is all about
and as i say it's up to sun normative
description if you will to maybe a
prescription
of how people all up to make choices if
they're going to be havea rationally in
the world
it turns out however
that there are a number of ways in which
we violate
wonder another of these precepts of
rational choice
some of them
could just think of kind kind of come up
with on da on introspection
sometimes we make choices out of habit
when i go to my closet and i pick out
the shirt dot i'm going to wear on a
particular day all i'm they say it all
you know i wore the shirt last week are
all i have a moral issue of the wild
issued story or whatever
at a rational way of thinking about your
but if i suppose there are really what
blue shirts
alm dot is just making a choice i would
have had
or to choose on the basis of conformity
to make choices just because of other
people are making that choice
or just because alm
that is the most frequent choice the
people make
is not irrational way of making a choice
because it's based on what other people
do
not on what you are rational
self-interest is
and then finally
making choices on the basis of what of
parties say you shouldn't do
also
not is also a departure from rationality
again because one of parties say you
should do
might or might not be in your
self-interest
rational choices
are always justices
that maximize
that users games
and minimize the troopers losses
so if you simply make the choices that
say or religious authorities are
cultural ortiz make you do
that may be a religious act
that may be a culturally bulb
appropriate act
but it's not rational
within the of within the definition
of rational choice theory
finally last time
i described for you a number of judgment
heuristics
rules of twelve
shortcut
decisionmaking routines
that we on for you know why i brought it
circumstances
to categorize objects made judgments of
similarity make estimates make all
predictions about probability and
causality
all about
judgments and frequency
all of that we used commonly
all which
in one way or another also
violate the principles of rational
choice
and these are
departures from rational choice
all are not obvious
okay it's not obvious that the way that
making choices a lot of habit is
irrational
colleges are is obvious
but there are departures that are all
on discovered for us
by psychological research
but a person who's been more in this
last lecture on judgment and decision
making on thinking but before i do
i want to see if there are any questions
left over from last time
about these four
comic judgment teristics represented a
mess we're judgments are based on
degree resemblance to a degree of
similarity
availability
we're judgments are made
based on the ease of retrieving
instances from memory
simulation
where judgments are
made based on the ease in which you
could imagine something happening
and anchoring an adjustment where
judgments are made based on
early date of return
okay basically as well
but that's what what
any questions about these
judgment teristics
okay what's the difference between
represented in this and availability
on in representative as
you're always basing the making
judgments based on the appearance of
things
what things look like
whether they resemble
something else
so for example in the birth problem
want to ask you which was the most
likely sequence of boys and girls and a
six child family
all there's a tendency to choose
girl boy girl boy boy girl
park that was the example if it was
all because
that's the one that looks random
it's the one that looks right it's going
to need a mix of boys and girls that are
kind of old interspersed together
where raza sequence of three girls
followed by three boys is just as likely
given probability theory
and for that matter a sequence of six
points
just as likely
what probability theory is like but
still
is represented as we make
decisions based on how things look
that's quite different from on undaunted
the availability to respect
where the operating principle is not so
much of what resembles watcher or or the
appearance of things
how fast things come to mind
alm
i'll give you an example for almost
self-rule part of the public welfare
all people who were on employed
think the unemployment rate is a lot
harder
than people who
unemployed
and the reason that people the the
reason that happens the people who are
unemployed
know a lot of other unemployed people
they meet them in the appointed office
they meet them on what they had come to
the mo when they go to apply for jobs
they got me
and talk to them when they're called
registering for welfare benefits and
things like that
so it's easy for them to bring to mind
all mots of instances of people who are
unemployed
but it that none of these judgment based
on the resemblance between
someone employed person and some other
unemployed person is just a matter row
how resilient could bring instances wine
so it's really
more like retrievals speed
what you retrieve
anything else about these teristics yes
does availability views of the
availability heuristic also depend on
how recent the instances
well yes in the following away
because something that happened recently
is going to be fresher in memory
than something that happened sometime
ago probably
okay
and so
on pure relying on their you're on the
uh... work with on the availability to
respect
your judgments are most likely are are
likely to be biased by the most recent
thing that happened with the most recent
i mean fought about
sov about something like that
so again
yet you've got something that's just
recently happened it's fresh in memory
all of that's going to be easily
retrieve from memory just by virtue of
being fresh
all and that thing is going to bias
uh... by richard road
exactly exactly right
that's because the availability to
respect is based on rick and ease of
retrieval from memory
and anything
any factor
affects
ease of retrieval for memory
is going to affect their judgment
anything else about these tourist
it does the anc readjustment heuristic
depend solely on dated evidence
yes
but data is defined really broadly
remembering my first example of the off
of the united nations problem i said
ask you what so what's the percentage of
u_n_ members from the comet of africa as
some people say ten percent what do you
say that was data
that some people say ten percent
but in the more radical version of the
question
where i generate that number by the spin
of a roulette wheel
well it's not very cryptic
but it's still dated still information
that you've been provided with
by the way they are very good example
rb anchoring an adjustment to respective
social cognition
is the privacy of first impressions
it's very difficult to overcome
somebody's first impression of you
it's very difficult for you to overcome
your first impression of somebody else
if your roomate sets you up with a blind
date
and said all we are she's wonderful
she's good luck eighteen inches really
smart and she's very witty and stuff
like that
and then you made a rigid just turns up
like bmp axe murderer or something like
that
your impression of the end of the
biggest she's a very nice axe murderer
i'd stat that's hard to get away from
the initial anchor
by the same token if you need to be
reintroduced to somebody in your during
that period of shoe impression of them
was that there are awful person
weeks and weeks and months and months of
the points is not going to completely
overcome
that first impression so there you have
a really good
real-world example
all be anchoring an adjustment your
respect at work
anything else about these
let's move on now to talk about another
liability and all in knowledge and uh...
judgment and decision making
that is illustrated
by all of the public phenomenal framing
that it which is the for put on a
framing
illustrated by the disease problem on
another
all problem all studied by versity in
common
and it goes like this
you want one general magic that you're a
public health official
and you're facing the impending opelika
some deadly disease sorrows
bird flu
something
and based on past experience
on the disease is expected to kill six
hundred people
okay so those are the assumptions going
into the problem
there's this deadly disease
coming soon
and it's expected to kill six hundred
people
so now as a public health officer
you'll have to choose
between
true or alternative programs
that are available to you programming
eight and program be
if program and is adopted
it is a certainty that two hundred
people will be saved
guarantee
that two hundred people will be saved
if program be is adopted
there's a one-in-three chance that all
six hundred will be saved
and attorney one of three chance
that no one
of those individuals will be saved
so those that's the problem
and now the question is
which program do you choose
when continents versity
posed this problem two subjects
they found that subject
overwhelmingly
preferred
program today
where there was a certainty
that two hundred people will be saved
all of our program be where there was a
one-in-three likelihood
their was that all will be saved and had
to work on the free chance
that dude project is on the three
that no one would be safe
in other words
people overwhelmingly by you
what lee
june three two one ratio preserved
certain games that although that two
hundred people would be saved to risky
gains that there was some chance
that nobody
would be sick
what's interesting about this is
that from the point of view of rational
choice theory
those two choices are precisely
equivalent
because in rational choice theory the
way you are supposed to our value a
choice is is to take a value on the
outcome
and multiplied the delicate bianco by
the probability of tax cut that outcome
rational
decision making
you've got a dog they'd be expected
value
obituaries
and multiply it
calculate that by multiplying the value
of the outcome by the probability solar
program and eight
if you're certain that two hundred
people will be saved
value of the outcome is one
probability of one times two hundred
two hundred
but if you look at program bay
where there's a chance that all will be
saved
value in touch to that is given by
all of them the you know
the outcome that six hundred people be
saved
multiplied by the probability of that
outcome
one-third which gives you of value of
two hundred
sobil rationally the outcomes of these
two choices are identical
in both
chicago drug cases
your does the your best guess
is the two hundred people are going to
be saved
there's no rational bases
for choosing
between the two
so one
conclusion about human judgment that
flows from an experiment like this
is that people tend to be risk overs
that in general people pretty far
over they sure thing
to and outcome that has the nearest risk
attached to it
if you say program a it so sure thing
the two hundred lives are going to be
saved
i want that program
on as opposed to one where i say while
there's a one third chance of all be
saved but there's a two-thirds chance
that non will be saved
well there's a general idea here
that people tend to be a risk averse
in their decision making
they tend to be risk averse
but it turns out said people are not
necessarily risk averse
they will except
some kind of risky outcome
but it all depends on the circumstances
let's continue with the condominium
firstly example here
once you go back in your role as a
public health officer
you're facing the same impending
outbreak of the same disease
that has the same expectation of killing
six hundred people
but now to go to some other subjects
and you say you have to alternative
programs available
offers
program c
if you would drop this program
it is a certainty there four hundred
people will die
if you adopt
program d
there is a one-in-three chance
that-and on will die
and that there is a to a lot of three
chances
all bulldog
so here you have certainty program c
here you have risky prospects with
program d and which program you choose
it turns out that under this uh... in
this version
of the disease problem
people overwhelmingly preferred prefer
the program that has some risk
attached to it
only about twenty five percent of people
of corporate choose
these certain program where four hundred
people will die
whereas
something like
seventy five percent of the all of those
subjects
will prefer the rescue program
where there is anyone in third chance
that or that lol all will die in the to
interject
the chance of not more
so again
if you would if you are value wait these
of outcomes
who are from the perspective of rational
choice theory
you'll see that these two outcomes are
also
precisely identical
from the point of view of rational
choice theory and program c
you're certain of four hundred people
will die
the outcome is four hundred deaths
the probability is perfect one point no
so the value was four hundred
for program d where there is some chance
that all will die
the are outcome is six hundred s
the probability of taxes and outcome is
two-thirds
you multiply them out
and you get four hundred
again view and rationally
the outcomes of these two choices
are precisely identical there's no
reason to shoes one or over the other
yet people do
people do
prefer in this case
to take a chance
they prefer
the risky
our choice just to put it
more graphically here
if you were in the problem in terms of
how many wives will be saved
people overwhelmingly or risk averse
they preferred a shorter thing
to the rescue prospect
but if you frame
our problem
in terms of how many people are going to
die
the subjects
by almost the same amount
overwhelmingly perfer risky
a prospect and again just to make it
clear the expected values of these four
programs are all precisely identical
in programming
there's a certainty
that two hundred will be saved
so there's a certainty that four hundred
will be lost
in program be the or expected outcome is
the two hundred people be
calm
i saved four hundred lost
program c there's a certain period of
four hundred will be lost that means two
hundred will be saved and program the
there's a two-thirds chance that all
will be lost
that means that for be expected value
is four hundred people wars and to two
hundred people policy
before problems art
exactly identical
from the point of view of rational
choice theory ok and so the question now
is
not the people risk averse
on that that they want certainty under
some circumstances
we'll take a risk under other
circumstances what's going on here
question
hardly ever hardly ever do people br
noticeably that these are exactly the
same
now of course
most people have not taken an elementary
economics course either
object
this is not something you're talkin'
like the second week ovid elementary
economics course to do these kinds of
calculations
but the general idea behind all of the
rational choice theory is that even
though we haven't had formal training in
economics
you still do something like this
you calculate
the of the probabilities associated with
various outcomes to get the values of
them
and apparently people are not doing this
comments first he made themselves quite
famous
alm of and sometimes they would collect
data like this in airport waiting
lounges okay with just ordinary people
but every once in awhile are common
communism important mathematical
psychologists a list first people when
he was a lot of they were going to
meetings of all the american economic
system technician
or the american statistical association
impassable questionnaires worldwide maj
imager public-health officer
and people will still do this
train the p_h_d_ level statisticians
and trained p_h_d_ level alban economist
making roughly the same kinds of choices
that you and i would make wendy
uh... begin
okay so what's going on here
armed the under the first thing to
notice
is that there's a good there's among
poor indifference in the wording of the
problems
their choice between unprogrammed a_t_m_
program be
is a choice between two nd programs both
of which focus on
gain
attached to the choice
how many law it will be say
programs see andy
focus on what some
how many lawyers will you lost
and it turns out
died when the problem
focuses on gain
people tend to prefer assured gain
and they are risk
overs
but when the focus of the problem is on
losses
people arrive birth to a certain losses
and they prefer to take
or risk
that is just
of empirical fact about people's
judgment uh... all uh... behavior
people are not police risk averse
people or risk averse in the context of
games
but they are
risk
prone if you will
in the context
losses
here's another example something very
similar to the coldest some cost problem
kind of interesting made this one famous
too
electoral magic to people attend the
concert
all person a by the regular ticket for
twenty five dollars
person be buys a ticket outside the
concert of hall all from the scalp or
for a hundred dollars
both tickets are nonrefundable
thought the concert when you get in
there the concert turns out to be
terrible
britney isn't even lip sync he well
late-night or something like that
all up and the question is
which concert goer is more likely to
leave
egg is more likely to leave
day is going to say
i paid off hundred dollars for this
ticket i'm sticking it out
portrayed
but the problem is you've already spent
that money
the money is
gun
if you make a rational choice based on
what's in hand once again this is
terrible concert
and you should just get out of there
it only turns out
that it depends on
how you've got in
to this
situation sunk cost
alton the reasoning
is something that you see a lot of
economic decision making it's a kind of
thing that you see also
in political
uh... decision making
when an investor
on invests in a stock
and then the bottom falls out of the
stock and the investor said on the
refuses to sell the stock because had
might go up
that's the part that some cause behavior
when a military leader was is a battle
and sends more soldiers into the battle
okay because
well just lost a lot of sold but also in
some more soldiers in that some cost
kind of behavior
instead of making choices based on at
synechron
you make choices based on that history
of how u
got into it
disease problem
and the some cost problem
are both examples of a broad phenomenon
known as framing affects
and
the importance of framing affects is
that they shall s
judgments are not invariant over a
different descriptions of a problem
in a rational choice theory
judgments are simply are not a rugby
algebra
outcall multiplied by probability
it doesn't matter
how the problem is worded
outcome multiplied by probability is all
you should do
it's exclaims white equals z and you
compare
disease
and it doesn't matter hollow the problem
is described
all rational choice
is a abstract
principle
decision making
so again
the fact that
there are at least framing affects in
judgment and decision making
violates normative rationality
because of the principle of rational
choice
that rational choices ardent order are
determined
by end abstract representation of the
problem they're supposed to be
determined
by the algebra
and they shouldn't be they shouldn't
depend
on how problems word
but we know that's the case
we know that from the disease problem
and we also know that
from things like
the song we are some calls
but trying to explain these
alm
kinds of affects
condominiums for ski
advanced an alternative to of or the
restaurant choice theory
which they called prospect theory
and more than anything else it's this
theory that one forget economy
the home nobel prize in in economics
first we couldn't get it because he was
deceased in nobel doesn't go to
all deceased people
and prospects theory
is a psychological approach
not on that matter kal approach
it's a psychological approach
the human judgment and decision making
that attends the capture
how people actually make judgments
rather than
hollow they might make judgments
in some kind of abstract world and the
first thing
is that people base their judgments on
the subject of utilities
not on objective values
so for example
if you give me anti-choice between
forming ten dollars
and eight ten percent chance to win a
hundred dollars
their equivalent
mathematically certainty of ten dollars
versus of one in ten chance of winning a
hundred dollars
valuable those choices ten dollars but
that's all i want is a sandwich for
lunch
all take the certain ten dollars got
back at smith a sandwich
if i'd but if i lose a hundred dollars
i go under it
so it's the subjective utility that
matters here
not the objective of value of the choice
the second is
we don't multiply
all balanced
by object of probabilities
rather we multiply utilities by
subjective
probabilities and by which all of the by
which kind of interested means
that we tend to all overweight
very high and very well risks
very lol risks
looking better
then they were really are
okay
very high risks tend to appear
worse
then they really are
we overweight
very high
and very
or very very well risks
all
of so that
again it's not what the that's not what
the mathematical probability is that
it's attached to it
if or did you
of the probability is another
uh... example of framing
and then finally
we don't have a value weight utilities
in some kind of absolute sense
remember rational choice theory says
that decision should be made by you
on the basis of
what is ian and right
instead
we tend to
of value wait our utilities against
psalm reference point
okay
although
i paid ten dollars for the stick a
personal appeal hundred dollars for this
ticket
or or or whatever
for any effects
off that these
valle of the these reference points
so if i you know the disease problem
framed in terms of lights to be saved
that will change the reference point
if i give you the same problem
framed in terms of whites to be lost
that will also
alter the reference point
so again
what happens here is that framing org
frame it affects will make prospects
or worse
then they really are
if i say it's a sure thing the two
hundred lives are going to be saved
that looks better than it really is
if i say it's a sure thing
that four hundred wives are going to be
lost
that's bad naf it looks worse that it
really is
hull d
or the other companies represented
mentally
not how the outcome
is calculated
mathematically that really makes radio
really makes a difference here
so let's stop for a second and take any
questions you might have
about the disease problem and framing
effects
doesn't the fact that you're only making
the decision ones
alter open situation well no apparently
not
because that's how the that's how the
problems framed and if you think about
albeit a public health officer
in all-stars only comes around once
you know maybe if you're lucky
uh...
so when stars starts coming around here
you have bob the background on what we
know from
your some other place vietnam urself
tried or wherever we're we're worth
resources already added no break is that
what
we can predict that we're going to lose
six hundred people here there are two
different things you can do
so you don't repeat these things over
and over and over again
all again
from the point of view all rational
choice
you only make decisions based on what is
in hand
and what's in hand right now with
there's a disease coming
it's expected the kill six hundred
people and you have these two programs
available
one which has
certain prospects
and one which has risky prosper
doesn't seem to matter
there are lots of variance on the
disease problem
lots and lots of errands on the disease
problem
and the outcome is almost always
something like this
how you've framed choices
is going to determine
what choices made and that shouldn't
happen
according to russia which we theory
because according to rational choices
our choices are always determined by and
abstract description of the problem
explains why
question doctor
well they work well
quality
it's not me
by disease buffet breakfast
but the choices are exactly the same
from the point of view of rational
choice theory
because rational choice theory says
or rational decision maker will take the
value of the outcome
and multiply it by the probable take the
outcome and multiplied by the
probability of tax that outcome to
calculate the value
what rational choice theory says people
want to do
again
if they re
if the two choices don't seem like
they're the same
your right
they don't
seem like they're the same
but from the point of view of rational
choice theory
they or precisely
mathematically identical
the fact that yeah you are
but they don't look that way
i was just something interesting
our judgments are based on how things
luck
not by
he's kinds of calculations okay
if the departure
from normative rationality
but in fact
the to joyce is are precisely the same
mathematically just
just in the old river
when you do the expected value per se
the op-ed hog
the probability is one
because of the program c
it is certain that four hundred people
will die
so with one times four hundred
okay people's four hundred
and then
in program d there's a two-thirds chance
that all will die so it's two thirds
time six hundred equals four hundred
one more question i'm going to finish
aren't there a waiter frame the problem
that would lead people to make
overall rover actual choice
uh...
it would be interesting i don't know
whether anybody's done this but
what you are what you might do
is to
present people with all four of those
choices at once
if your present and people with all four
of those choices of once they might be
big mike think about the program word
does about the choices were deeply
vendor
than they do
hong
but again
one of the
points of this whole analysis of
judgment tourist x
is it simply
about some of the liabilities of human
judgment will help people be call more
rational decision makers
so that knowing something about the the
yacht
the framing effects in the disease
problem the next time you're actually
faced with a problem like this
you'll say
well you know these really there's
really not a very good choice
and then you might go
you might make your choice based on
all other values
for example you might say
by third if there is program and there's
a
there's a certain do the two hundred
lives will be saved
that looks like a better
game to me
then the risky one
it's not
mathematically
but if you are a public health official
for example
responsible to the voters you might say
i made the choice
gave me a guaranteed uncle
that you'd like
and that's what the principle thing
but that's not all rational choice
that such a record not and barb russian
choice in the case in the in the
framework of rational choice theory that
may be a correct choice
i trusted you could defend to the voters
the fact of the matter is that the
choice between two
programs that are mathematically
equivalent
let's finish this up
a little bit because prospect areas in
the end of of the story okay
the first is just to review the bidding
when we think
about
judgment and decision making
we usually make all this the assumption
that decision makers are rational
in that they want out
optimize values or optimize of
optimizing tool
even if they haven't taken a nap
econnect an economic scores
even if they haven't taken a course in
probability and statistics yet that
somehow decisionmakers intuitively
understand alm believed that the
principles of statistic
and the intuitively understand that the
principles of logic
and apply them as best they can
the kinds of facts that i've talked
about today
at last time
show us that these are some shins are
not
valid
so now the question is
what do we make of this
some psychologists have concluded
that people are j-list
irrational
on
who called this the people are stupid
school of psychology and there are
psychologists around to really do
believe the people are fundamentally
stupid
are dead people
don't know anything about probabilities
they don't know what's in their best
interest i don't know how they don't
distinguish between gains losses
they just do all these things on
if you read in the psychological
literature
on you'll see that
directors fund
talk about
will emphasize that people don't think
logically
or frankly that people don't think too
hard about everything
that people mostly or wander around
behaving automatically barbie hated on
automatic pilot
on you go down the you go down the
street
friend comes up and says
hi john what are you doing what you're
saying
are doing fine thanks you could be dying
danielle still say i'm doing fine thanks
because that's carlos habitual thing to
do it all think about it too much
and also
that or one apart of human irrationality
comes for the fact
that we let our emotions on our motives
are feelings on our desires yet in the
way of our thinking okay
freud's idea about human irrationality
that call it wasn't so much the people
were stupid and i can say that i can
sense
of onboard our cognitions were dominated
by your feelings and our desires
so there is this general
conclusion
that sounds like religious all mukul
what want to draw
from evidence all of the sort that i
just presented onto you
that people are fundamentally irrational
they don't care if they don't think too
hard about anything and when they do
think you are they don't think we write
all along
that people are mostly behaving out of
habit
and that people really don't aren't too
aware alvo of what they're doing all it
neither
on that is a trend that you can see you
know
but in some quarters of psychology
there is another approach however
and this is a approach that was
pioneered by herbert simon who is one of
the first psychologist to win the nobel
prize operetta nomic finance
of sometime ago a long time ago and that
is an approach that's total beds bounded
rationality
signed then argued that despite the
evidence for judgment for judgment
interest x
despite the fact that we don't have a
grice based on proper set principles
despite the fact that we show framing
affects it and and in judgment and
decision making still
people arbor
fundamentally irrational
and it's a big book
rationality is constrained
by to different kinds of boundaries
first is
in the real world
most problems offer although presented
to us in the real world are ill-defined
problems
that is
most decisions
occur
under conditions of uncertainty
where problems are not well defined
the information we need to solve
problems what all is off
may be available but it's not economical
to get at it
all or the arc
beyond judgment procedure that we need
to apply
may be available but it's on economical
to get to it
one way or another
these are the kinds of circumstances
they create judgment under uncertainty
and when judgment is made under
conditions of uncertainty
that's abound that sorry are constrained
on human rationality but the other point
that signing made doesn't have to do
with the description of the world
outside the individual
world of uncertainty
but rather
a description of what goes on inside the
head of the individual
and simon simply pointed out
the human capacity for information
processing is limited
in daud george miller's terms
the magical number seven plus or minus
two there's a reason telephone numbers
are limited to seven digits
that have never mind area codes our
country codes reason that they are
called telephone codes are limited to
seven digit
is that that's just about all they could
hold at our heads of whatever one
particular time seven items of
information
even of all the information that was
needed for to make a judgment were
available to the
on to the decision maker
we don't have the processing capacity
to be able to
to pay attention
to all that information
moreover
we don't necessarily have
human information processing capacity to
perform
what might be very
are complicated computations
calculations on those kinds of uh...
things
all
so i would argue
that human beings were irrational
within limits
limits that are set
both by the nature although uncertainty
in the world
and also by
limitations on information from a
processing plant has to be
the in the in the human mind
instead of
maximizing outcomes therefore
simon argued in fact
button people make
decisions
either people or organizations
they do so not on the basis of
optimizing outcomes
but rather
what he called satisfy sing
remember rational choice theory says
that a rational decision maker or try to
maximize games and minimize losses
and simon says if you look at what
people do either individually or in
organizations they don't do this
rather what they do
is to engage in what he called satisfy
sick
uh...
and within satisfy seem what you do
it is you identified all the outcomes of
a choice that are satisfactory
or identified the outcomes that are
satisfactory
and then you choose between them
you could choose between the randomly if
you will
org you can choose between them
based on some of their own
and some other although the principal
all barry schwartz who is a psychologist
who studies judgment decision making
says
or what is called broke radical
reformation of the college admissions
process is that
rather than trying to make really
fine-grained
necessarily fallible distinctions among
all the highly qualified applicants
for a propeller blade to a particular
school
what admissions officer should do
is simply identify of pool of applicants
who would be okay
and then choose randomly
you make everybody's
a lot nusier then rather think all
here's a story with
six eighty jr s_a_t_s and out of three
point five g_p_a_
and here's another person with a six
hundred eighty two
s_a_t_
and a three point forty p avoid just
don't know how much wars and wanted to
let go
in st
bulb on the same pool
pick one
the other one gets to go to u_c_l_a_ or
something like that
double bs perfectly satisfactory outcome
either way you get up dot bunch of well
qualified students
the public health example the disease
problem public-health officer might say
program a m program be their precisely
equivalent
okay
but program as the one that the voters
are going to like
they'll kill me they won't reelect me if
i'd choose program be an everybody's
laws
perfectly rational way
to make a decision
alm
and nam
on in affirmative action
to take another example of
organizational decision making
you might have
all majority applicant and a minority
catholic and
who are both
perfectly
equally qualified for the job you could
only hire one of those you might say
our organization values diver sity so
we're going to be in this instance we're
going to choose the minority applicant
over the over the majority applicant
because we want to have a more diverse
workforce the two are
equal in their croat in their i'd
the book either one would be
satisfactory employees
choose among the satisfactory outcomes
based on another principles
so there are lots of ways
to satisfies
and started slicing simon points out
perfectly rational way
to operate
under conditions of
judgment under uncertainty
and
a limited information processing
capacity
so in fact
bounded rationality is
are rational approach
although due to problem solving
on grid giga rennes r_ a british opened
sorry german although psychologist has
made this point
if that's what
judgment he respects mei
in principle violate
or rational
all of norms for a logic
but if you think about it for a second
judgment heuristics are often the best
approach toward two-way radio tual
problem either because the problem is
home
uh... you'll defined as opposed to be
well-defined
or because
the algorithm that you'd used to do is
to solve the problem
is somehow on economical
ought to apply
yet around serb points out
yes it's rational to optimize
but it's also a rational to would jack
dot org
through due to a dejected khatami's
into human decision making
as long as you're willing to pay the
price for ever
okay
heuristics
inject great economies in the human
decision making
if you are not willing to pay the price
for an error
then you better
find an algorithm
someplace but most of time
mistakes don't cost us that much
most of the time when we use these broad
kinds of decision
doesn't cost us that much
if i say to you what's the percentage of
countries all of them u_n_ members were
perfect dog content developer cut some
people say ten percent what do you say
and you say twenty five percent on the
proper answer is forty five percent
terrors
did make that
allowed on the day that you could make
that the risk
so what you can do however
is you can reduce
the likelihood
that reliance on judgment teristics will
lead to wearers by giving by allowing
people to appreciate eight
how they actually makes decisions
using principles like these
and b
what some of the liabilities or attached
to those modes of decision making are
rational decision maker is not somebody
is not just somebody who applies the
principles of aristide gilliam logic
are rational decision maker is this it
is a decision maker who will gets
satisfactory outcomes unit economical
way who wonders stands how he or she
makes decisions and understands what the
costs and benefits or
and that's what you now or
next time will begin our discussion of
personality and social psychology