okay every girl
are you may recall we had an exam last
week
thanks to the geoscience for taking care
of the review session and the exam
itself in my absence
when we restored the system
we identified four items statistically
that word that items that is bad for
whatever reason it doesn't matter what
reason
on
items thirty five forty forty seven
forty nine
and that we do when we identified that
item is that we re score
that items correct for all responses
so if you what you are
answers alcohol in the preliminary
scoring ki
and you found that you got any of these
items wrong
you've now got a right
okay so give yourself one point for each
item art that you got wrong
and that's your final exam score
we won't be restored any other items ok
we used
objective statistical analysis
to identify items that uh... that are
bad
i've almost finished entering a grade
still be finished by noon today
and you can check your grades are posted
on splint
volatile has to
how would two
uh... reconcile any discrepancies
that you may have
encountered
here's what the distribution of
performance looks like
usually when i teach this class the
average score an exam is somewhere
between sixty five and seventy percent
correct
which i think is pretty good
on the means whoever this class was
considerably better than that which i
think is
all of this is the distribution
average score thirty eight point three
three which is roughly seventy seven
percent
home
when you get this nice little
distribution here
model with mostly scorers ranging
between thirty five
thirty five and forty points
i'm not too many
appear
not too many
down there
pretty good distribution matic not quite
a normal distribution but
we don't expect the normal distribution
we expect the discussion that's
towards the high-end
anyway all all will be
unclear were
well i have tried post the scores are
going to go back to pose some more
feedback on the exam
and then if anybody has any questions
about any of the items that
has not been addressed by the feedback
are just post those questions for me
website forum
and will deal with them
any quick questions about
anything at all
i hear
i have been avoided any other way but
yes that's right
this is the restored
mean in medium
okay
in the course so far once we got past
they even added me in that through the
allergy in the function of the nervous
system
we began to take up particular
psychological functions
function of learning and the function of
perception
and one of its points
i think
should've gotten across
is that both learning the agm perceiving
end on memory
and both learning and proceeding if you
think about it for a second
change memory
we think about learning as a relatively
permanent change in knowledge that
occurs as a result of experience
and it's the capacity for memory that
all of our knowledge to be permanent
changed we have to have some mechanism
for retaining
what we've learned to through or through
experience
on november
if you think about these sources of
information for perception
in the u_k_ in gibson's ecological of
your perception there's information that
comes from the stimulus environment
that's all impact by the perceptual
apparatus
and then barriers
knowledge beliefs expectations and stan
and all sorts of things stored in the
memory of the perceive ur which combines
with stimulus information
in the process of constructing the
mental representation or p_r_ of the
distal stimulus
warning depends on memory obviously
perception not quite so obviously also
depends on perception
but it's also the case
that memory changes depending upon what
you proceed
that perceptual activity changes the
contents of the memory system
so that there is some lasting trace
of what you've experienced
what we sometimes call
an anagram sobel piece of technical
jargon
in the study of memory a memory trace
that persists after the experience is
over
that'll wallace odd that experience to
continue to influence
experience thought and action after the
stimulus
has some has disappeared
so in a very important sounds
memory is the
cognitive function of stories knowledge
that we've acquired
through learning and perception
but also memory is important because
memory freeze our behavior from
controlled by the president's stimulus
environment
if you didn't have memory all you'd be
able to do is to react to whatever's
currently in the the environment now
whatever it is that you're experiencing
but memory
allows us to respond to
past events
as well as events in the current
stimulus and barman
and memory are also gives us the means
to reflect
on our experiences
also the week so that
uh... we've
plan for
for future encounters
so memory is the psychologists is a
psychological storehouse of knowledge
let's look for a quick call for a moment
at the kinds of knowledge that stored in
memory
in cognitive psychology we've gone make
a couple of distinctions about the kinds
of knowledge stored in memory
the first of these distinctions
is a distinction between declarative
knowledge on the one hand
and procedural knowledge of on the other
declarative knowledge is the technical
term that we give
factual knowledge of all sorts
any kind of factual knowledge it's a
fact that automobiles have four wheels
and run on gasoline or diesel oil it's a
fact that bicycles had two wheels
it's a fact that i had chicken for
dinner last night it's a fact that i was
in vienna on friday those are all facts
about the world the reader true or not
true
that factual knowledge
is what we call declarative knowledge
by contrast
we have another category of knowledge
that's known as procedural knowledge
which consists i am
the directions for goal directed action
directions for goal directed action
if i were wearing loafers today
but if i had twice shoes on and i one of
the time i shoes
the procedure for time shows
primer shoelaces
is a piece of procedural knowledge
are those of you who noted politics
square roots without using a calculator
that mathematical procedure is part of
your procedural knowledge
your knowledge of the rules of
english grammar or spanish or chinese
grammar
or whatever language you know
all those also pieces of coal
pieces of procedural knowledge
so we think this fundamental distinction
between
and rules
declarative knowledge had procedural
knowledge
and then
we begin to think about other kinds of
things
one where all the way of thinking about
this
all claret of knowledge
can be stored in sentence like
structures that consist of
a subject
boverb and an object
alright had chicken for dinner
our columbus discovered america
somtime five hundred years ago tommorrow
or whatever all declarative knowledge
can be represented in sentence form
procedural knowledge has a somewhat
different format it has a format that we
call productions
and productions have a kind of yes then
the quality to it
suppose you're driving a standard shift
kar and you want to get it moving
forward
what you have to do is you have to
ship i'll put the car into first year
and the way you do that is
if you're sitting in the driver's seat
you press down on the clutch
one superstar in the clutch
you shift in the first
then if you've shifted into force
then you let up on the clutch while
simultaneously pressing down on the gas
pedal
visa rules for driving a standard shift
kar and they can albee represented in in
spend format
that specifies some glow
and salem action
that will achieve the goal under certain
kinds of conditions
if you want to drive a standard shift
kar
than the first thing you do
is pressed down on the clutch and so on
this procedural knowledge takes through
broad forums
our first of these are motor procedures
where the actions that are performed the
actions that are governed by the rule
take the form of some kind of over
behavior
okay if i want to time i sure lace is
the first thing i have to do was pull
them tighten and cross them over
alm
and what these minor procedures do
is alter the objective publicly
observable state of the world
after i performed at first action my
shoelaces are crossed when they work
before that's something that they were
everybody could see
it simply objectively true
but these mental procedures ok alm the
bar codes of mental procedures are used
to
called dodd govern perception and memory
they take the form of a
mental transformation if i save you
what's
three divided by e_r_ too
and you say one and a half you haven't
changed the objective world in any way
what you've done is we've taken
your mental representation of three
divided by two when you've got one and a
half in your head what these mental
procedures do
is to alter the subjective
private
mental state of affairs
alter your alternative
you motion will
or motivational states so we have first
in this hierarchical classification of
knowledge
a distinction between declarative and
procedural knowledge
then two kinds procedural knowledge
motor procedures and mental procedures
similarly
we have two types also
part of knowledge
the first of these recall episodic
knowledge
and at this is essentially
autobiographical memory
at a sonic knowledge of his knowledge of
eve instead of occurred at a particular
place and a particular time
each event
is associated with a unique
in the space and time but you can think
about autobiographical memory
as factual knowledge
about your personal experiences
it's a fact that i had chicken for
dinner last night it's a fact that i
graduated from colgate university
it's a fact that i was raised in process
network those are all facts about me
by the same token
uh... we have or other kinds of
procedural knowledge
that aren't really facts about events
bible reader but rather are more
abstract or conceptual all of the in
nature
and this is what we call semantic
knowledge
and semantic knowledge constitutes what
kind of mental dictionary if you will or
mental encyclopedia
that retains knowledge
although the abstract conceptual form
that doesn't really have anything to do
with our personal experiences
i know what a chicken is
okay
and that now that knowledge of what a
check and it is
has nothing to do with the fact that i a
chicken for dinner last night
although i don't cut it
what's on television on sunday nights
and that has nothing to do with what
alliance might what on myself
might have thought might have watched so
we have this distinction
between episodic and semantic forms
of declarative knowledge
in these lectures
we're going to focus on episodic memory
we're going to focus on
hot what is that we remember
you dance and experiences
the carter was
at a particular point
in space and time
we'll talk about semantic knowledgeable
talk about procedural knowledge a little
bit later on
when we talk about clogged and language
for the purposes of these lectures
we're going to just we're going to
define memory as
episodic memory
autobiographical memory memory for
the things that people have experienced
and the people's mother and the things
that people have dawn
and a most of the study of memory
or at least forward the first hundred
years of this study
focused on
all the kind of the opposite
of the question of memory and that is
the question of forgetting
what causes us to forget the things that
we've forgotten
and we
are credited for from our knowledge of
the rules of forgetting
all harwood is that we remember the
things that we remember
usually we all understand remembering
and forgetting
events
in terms of at least three stage model
of memory
that distinguishes along
and encoding stage
by which
a trace
some experiences
encoded in memory or laid down in memory
of storage
days
by which
that new memory is retained
in storage
and a retrieval
onstage
by which
that's stored information is brought
back into argues in some way
so here we have
these three stages
in memory processing
and encoding onstage with volley the
story of a memory trace
this is
typically thought of as a byproduct of
perceptual activity
and the general ideas a perceptual
activity
leaves in memory
selma representation
some trains of what's
been proceed
then
storage the storage phase
has to do with the retention obvious
memory trace
farm
so that it's available for use
but it's not necessarily something that
you're thinking about all the time
might not always thinking about the fact
that i had chicken for dinner last night
and not always thinking about the fact
but i was born in processing your
but when i turn my mind to it by flying
that piece of knowledge okay
on that
that knowledge is our venerable even if
it's not right in my heart the forefront
of my consciousness at any point
but then
through to retrieval process
what we do is we recall ever
in some way
information that's been in coded and
stored in memory
so that we can use that for various
kinds of purposes like if somebody came
up to me on the street and said what am
for dinner last night
aiken searched my memory of the car and
that was funded remember what that
sunday's took a day
or so
what we do is somehow we activate that
late knowledge
gain access to available not lage
so that we can offer make use of it in
one way or another
we're going to do in these factors as
we're going to go through these pages
intern
and show you how they work
what the principles or that involves
under that are involved in the sayings
but the basic point for now
is to understand that any particular
instance of forgetting
cannonball by failure
at any all of these three stages of
memory processing
either acting alone
or in combination
so that you might forget an event
because you failed to uncover the memory
trace of that event to begin with
nothing gets in
you're never going to be able to
remember it okay
or perhaps u_n_ coated the memory trays
but for some reason
that race was lost from storage knocked
out of storage
or perhaps the uncoated traces is stored
but for one reason or another
you can't retrieve
the home
the land and stored the storage race
always some combination of incoming
storage and retrieval factors
view love the causes of forgetting
if you think about it for seconds kind
of analogous to elaborate okay
you've got a lot of radha look for a
book and you don't find it
and you have a library for a while we
don't own that book
okay librarian
never in coated that book the report on
the shelves
or the librarian might say well we
bought that book a long time ago with
somebody stole that were in fact
it or something like that
it's been lost its not on the shelves
anymore all
or you might find that it's actually
then purchased
put on the shelf pareshaan for the wrong
place
if i block has been stored in the
library order then where it's supposed
to be are now that i find it
still there but you're never going to be
able to retrieve that information
this library metaphor of memory is not
quite right for reasons all talk about
next monday
but it will take you all lonely and
understanding
the prophecies by which we incurred
information memory
retain it in memory storage and retrieve
it when we want to get at it
later on
sahai study memory use all based on this
three stage model
but typical way in which psychologist
study memory is by use of what we call
the bronco learning paradigm
apparently was invented long ago
all volume which still
dominates the study of memory
what we do in a verbal warning
experiment is that there are really
three different phases
there is first a study phase
analogous to the encoding the stage of
memory processing
and what we do in this and in this our
study phase
is we've simply present to the subject
analyst stalled for millie or words and
ask them to do something with that made
we actually ask the person
to memorize the list of words
it's important that the words be already
familiar to the subject because of a
teaching you know words
what's that
that semantic memory i mean large in
your mental dictionary right
but if i present your word you already
know
your task is to remember what the word
what is that you remember to add a
particular time
the event
but would not be the event that you
remembering
is a print is a presentation all of a
particular word
and it will be called as the boarding
paradigm because a classically involves
words
but you could use anything that could be
pictures are copies smells it could be
stories that could be videos
anything you want to do
in the process is still the same
south after the subjects had an
opportunity to study some material a
list of words for example
then we move into the retention phase
which it is intended to capture the
process season memory storage
and what we might do then
as the person to retain that information
for a more or less long period of time
or we might present the person was some
kind of distracting partner task
then you could start in these lectures
armed
we want to
we want to focus on what's known as
long-term memory
memory for information
out to the person's attention has been
distracted from it
it doesn't have to be really long term
instant experimental psychology
long-term memories that anything after
about thirty seconds
or short term memory
is probably best
all represented
by the memory that you have
for information a telephone book you
want to look up somebody's phone number
you go to phone book you look at all
when you try to keep in mind while
you're dialing the phone
that's short term memory we're not
interested
in these lectures
we're just in long-term memory
remembering your
sophomore year in high school boyfriend
or girlfriend phone number
oh or the phone number of somebody that
you met
last friday night
or whatever
and then finally
uh... we had the test phase
after there's been some encoding
after the material is
billion memory storage for a while
then we asked the person some kind of
question
all of that requires him or her to make
use of that newly stored knowledge
that is the retrieval all phase
and that usually consist
of various kinds bulb all various kinds
of memory tests
okay so let's just throat gothic
procedure onto a quick example of this
going to show you a list of familiar
words
and what i want to do is to repeat each
one intern just
do-it-yourself after i read it
after i've read the entire list i'll
give you a three digit number
but i want to do is to take that number
subtract seven from that
then from that difference seven again
seven again seven again
until
on a tell you
here are the words
anger
brad
just do it yourself cold
grow old
ang
mountain
needle
slow
spider
now takes seven sixty three
subtract seven from that
subtract seven again
seventy m
seven again
and in just keep going until i tell you
to stall
another seven
now we'd ask you do just right down the
words that were on the list
you know i can turn this in
and those of you a print out the slides
can just look at them
that's called cheating
anyway there is the list okay
the point is
you've been kind of these words every
one of these words was familiar to you
before you enter the class
and what we're asking to do is to
remember warm words we presented what
words you experienced at a particular
time in a particular place and you
probably got five or six of these on
average maybe seven
all if your
girl if you're really paying attention
but that's how this kind of expert
that's how this experience girls
so we could ask gum lots of different
memory tests
what words just study just remember all
the words on the list
or we could ask you a more specific
question
whenever the words of are on the outside
of the screen
over the words on the right side of the
screen
what were the words were printed in blue
what were the words that were printed in
red
was there a word on there that's the
name of an animal
on it if there was an animal name was
its spider or snake these are all the
kinds of ways
in which we contest
ust a person's memory
for something that he or she
has studied
so again
the idea here but the bravo learning
paradigms which is
what we're going to talk about for the
next couple of days
is that need to list of words
and each word on each list represents an
episode of experience
and in memory research
but we tried to do is to very the
conditions of study
retention
and testing
very the conditions of encoding
storage and retrieval
so that we can figure out what
principles are governed
each of these processes
and then what we do is we observed the
effects of each of these manipulations
on the person's or memory
for the list of words
so
what are we discover
the first thing we do
all of this to try to on understand how
weird is that we encode information in
memory
so for the purposes of this discussion
just assume those subjects perceived an
object or event study to work
earlier list of words
and then what we want to know is
how does a mental representation of that
event
once perceived
get stored in memory
the classical
also all
answer to this question
is that information gets stored in
memory as a function of of rehearsal
on the idea here izzat memories a
product of perception
the more you do to rehearse that
information
on the better your memory will be
if you look up a telephone number
and you think of it over and over and
over to yourself time after time after
time
then the idea is that you all remember
that telephone number better you won't
have to look it up
again
we've encountered this principle before
if remember our discussion of
thorndike's law is level learning we
read again remember that one of four
nights big laws was the law of exercise
weary thought that
stimulus response associations were
strengthened
through use and weakened
disuse
the general idea behind the importance
of rehearsal
and this is something that was studied
even before thorndike came around
five a german psychologist on ninad
adding house all who's part that
albright purcell was so important in
memory
that the uh... enshrined it as one of
his fundamental all fundamental laws
here it is what had been hosted
at a house and then took a particular
paradigm and for the study of memory
known as the nonsense syllable paradigm
he wasn't interested in the words
he wasn't interested in stories are
pictures or anything like that
he asked the all to well eoc actually he
was is on subjects old yest insult
to study
the most
meaningless material you can imagine
he constructed syllables consisting of a
confident of all of the constant
music also involve concentrate grams
remember he was german have no meaning
in german
all words like that
brought syllables like dad
jacks
marble
tab and wall
ania somewhat hundreds of thousands of
these
on and then conspired gather them into
lists actually of his valet
gather them into all this
alms and then he tried to memorize
these lists of nonsense syllables
instructs the real work
so we'd recognise memorize dilution
followed by jack's
followed by marble
fall a bike have
followed by wall
are you may think of this is completely
boring which forest it is
all
evian houses
method
juarez
given to him buying another principle
dewitt study in the context of learning
this was a time insight that that
psychology was dominated by the
principle of association by continuity
so every most thought
that associations will be formed
between nonsense syllables that occurred
close together in time you get an
association between dash in jax
another one between jackson mob another
one between marvin have
maybe a week or association between dash
and mall but between jackson ten and a
very weak association
between dash in-wall
because welder just not is configured
so that was the idea and puttin up in
the traditional estar framework
ambient house view would
ought to have had the view that you
choose
nonsense syllable
with four of us ten dollars for the next
month in seoul
which would in turn be or response
to the nonsense syllable that went
before it
and what he did in one of his
experiments
is simply buried a number of repetitions
the number of times he worked his way
through this list
one-time two times five times ten times
whatever
and then after a standard retention
interval
twenty four hours in the case of eddie
house
he would then try to reproduce the list
verbatim
so we very the condition of encoding the
number of repetitions
held the retention interval constant
and then
had simple test
of all basically savings in relearning
as he tried to memorize the list again
and four how fast it went
here is that the house is dead
we have
brand new list of the zero prior
repetitions eight sixteen twenty four
all multiples of
here so
on
and this is the amount of time it took
him to memorize
that is to relearn
each of these lists with a brand new
list they took him some twelve thirteen
hundred seconds okay what's at twenty
minutes
onto to memorize the list
but if the list that already had eight
repetitions of took her last time
to reword it
if the listed had forty-two repetitions
less time
if the listed had sixty four
repetitions
it ok even less time
so here
memory
measured in terms of retention
varies as a function of the number of
times the list was repeated
this is the data that supported
abby houses for screw all log memory
which is
the law of repetition
and if a wall that is completely
consistent with the way
all associations reviewed at the time as
associations
based on principle
kon tiki woody all been strengthened
through australians
okay
so that's fine
and that lol remained pretty much in
place
for almost all hundred years
until two canadian psychologists fordice
craig and michael walk-ins
formed the following very interesting
experiment
they presented subjects with a list of
familiar words
and they ask them to do very simple task
all of us objects had to do
was to be prepared to report
the most recent word that began with the
letter
key is in peter
okay that's all you had to do
so you couldn't subjects with a big nor
all the words
that didn't begin with the
and once i know word appear at the
beginning of the letter p
they could forget the ordeal
sold what rock rake and while black
instead
west a very the amount
of rehearsal given to each word
and then as subjects to recall all the
words they had seen
here's how the expert on the web
first were on the list might be keys it
begins with p
so the subject has to be prepared to
report
next words chair
connect nora dot word
that's where the list is potato
person can now drop keys
from memory
and
potato
eg
window
forget the tail now all you have to do
is
the most recent keyword
radio
spiral
here's position forget punch remember
position
parking
forget position
remember party
notice that there are different numbers
off
neutral words
interspersed among these critical words
and this is basically how creko watkins
tried to control repetition
peas
that's one repetition of a reversal
potato gets four
gets three
position
one repetition and so on soap i come
watkins then dead
was to plot
retention
in terms of the subjects ability to
recall the words
as a function of the number of
repetitions
and here's what they got
nothing like what i've been how scott
ambient house got us straight
negative curve
dot showing
oscar clearer
all relationship between our repetition
and memory
but in the cricket walk-ins list
you can see that items that god knows
repetitions remembered pretty much as
well as items that got three or sex
repetitions
items i got five repetitions were
remembered pretty well but items they've
got twelve repetitions work remember are
as well
there's really relationship
in this along
uh... in this experiment
between rehearsal
between repetition
and elem
and and memory
so we have a real contradiction
between the results of cricket watkins
on the one hand and the earlier www
results results almost ninety years
before
all by and it helps
well how to explain this
i couldn't walk ins dot adele our
distinguished
between trudy types albright whistle
maintenance rehearsal and elaborate
rehearsal
if you think about it for a second
makers rehearsal as just wrote rehearsal
and all it does is
maintain
and item fresh in memory
if i ask you to recover
word product you save yourself product
product product product
and i think forget product remember
position
your figures opposition solution
position position
all you're doing is keeping that item
active involved in the home what we know
is short term memory
but there's a second time of repetition
or second type of rehearsal
evian that cricket watkins called all
that sort of a rehearsal
and that involves taking a night and
you're trying to remember
and linking that to orders things here
that you already no
okay
this allot started rehearsal strep
is a isn't encodes information in of
long-term memory
and if you think about it for a second
when you're doing something like this
you're just engage in a row russell
you're not engaging in any kind of a
labrador rehearsal of at all
alm
so that
what eddie house was but what was once
thought or the discovering was something
that was not really about rehearsal at
all
it turns out we don't know
that painting houses subjects
when faced with meaningless
try grams like
anjaan do jabber whatever
tried to think of words that sounded
like tacit right
they conducted these nonsense syllables
to things that they already knew
when you actually have
engage in
part maintenance rehearsal
there is no relationship between the
amount of rehearsal
and all and long-term memory
but if you engage in although a bit of a
whole lot reversal
you can remember something for a long
time
are you still teach-in at the university
of wisconsin
when i would live in madison i had a
travel agent whose name i've actually
for gotten dogs something or somebody
but his
phone number was two five six four four
four four
five remember that i don't know if
wisconsin now for almost thirty years
on all of the twenty years rather all
but i remember that because when dad
told me his number
he said
two fifty six
that's four raised to the fourth power
yeah kinda like the new information does
something you already know yet remember
forever even if you'd really like to
forget it
on your just go is going to go to going
to remember that god that uh...
uh... in information
so here in krakow walk-ins when they
grieve stricken their subjects to read
over her soul
there is no relationship between role
reversal of long-term memory but when
you when gays in the last word of a
reversal you'll find a very solid
relationship here's a demonstration of
that
from
dan all with gus creek and his colleague
and auto loving also
in which they presented subjects with
familiar words
the word trout
and ask the subjects to perform
particular kinds of tasks on each of
these words
for some words
subjects performed a structural
in which they were simply asked
to make a judgment about the physical
appearance of the word sometimes known
as a orthographic processing test
use the word printed in properties are
lower case
on does the word contain a particular
letter
or how many work aligns are there
didn't work
on nothing about the sound of the word
of the medium of the word or anything
like that just about the physical
appearance of the word
and all other conditions
the subjects were asked to take a phone
mitnick
or an acoustic judgment of the word
for example they were asked whether
would wine with some other word does
trout
rhyme with weight
well not really
order in some conditions their estimated
category judgment
is the word what type of fish
this case yes trumps or
all
org there might be a complex linguistic
judgment
like what the word fifth in the
following sends
he met a blank
in the street
he met a trail of the street
probably not two persons ok with
perfectly good english sadness but
not a very good
off it
for the senate
sold yen word after word after word
subjects were asked to make unorthodox
affect
on acoustic
a conceptual or a linguistic judgment
about the word
and then craig and holding surprise
subjects with
uh... memory test is that ok now that
we're going to do is surprise surprise
is a memory experiment
we want you remember all the words that
we presented
onto you
words that were given a structural
encoding
where all the subjects did waters
make a judgment about the physical
appearance of the ordered
they were not remembered very well at
all about fifteen percent of the items
but if the subjects made an acoustic
judgment about the word
if they
volvo rested by the rhymed with some
other word
memory jumped about
almost four hundred percent to almost
sixty percent of the items
when they were asked to make a category
judgment it jumped up to about eighty
percent
and when they were asked if it would fit
into a particular sens frame
memory jumped again to about ninety
percent
in this experiment
the already emptied tasks structural
phonemic category and friends
are intended to control the young mailto
connection
that's made between the event that the
person is trying to remember the word
that the person's trying to remember
and something that he or she already
knows
in the structural case
there's not very much
called and not not very much linkage at
all
savor the word is printed in upper lower
case won't even reading the word
here at least you have to pronounce the
word yourself and link it to the other
word
dollar-billion in the rhyme
question
here you have to look at the category
knowledge once you say trying to get the
kind of fish
that were not the conflict everything
you know about fish
okay and then in the sense task gets
linked to even more alva even more
information
this is known as the depth of processing
affected memory
the idea that structural processing is
very shallow processing
category and sends processing is very
deep processing and it illustrates what
we have come to call the elaboration
principal in memory
the first great principle of memory
which is that memory is a function
of the degree to which a new event
is related to pre-existing knowledge
the more you try to attend act-up
some new saying that you've learned
with something that you already know
the better you're going to be able to
remember it
all later on
which is one reason for example wayy and
study skills classes your it ought to
just
standby chapter
the scanned chapter headings first
before you actually go on and read the
chapter
because the chapter headings give you
all
framework for linking the stuff that you
already
it doesn't matter exactly how we
defined elaboration
you can think about elaboration terms of
the amount of attention that you pay to
the event
you could think about collaboration in
terms of the number of features
that you extract from an event
visual features
acoustic features meaning features and
so on
or just the number of links
with your cree existing knowledge
however you define elaboration
the point of the elaboration principle
is bone marrow that that's better
for memory
the more you establish links between
something new
and something you already know about
the more likely you are to remember
that event
so now we have
true different modes of processing
occurring at the time of of all over her
soul
wrote reversal
in which you simply keep an item fresh
in your mind
two five six one flow pour four four
four two five six four four four four
whatever
and that maintains the item in inactive
state in what we call short term memory
but doesn't guarantee
that that item is going to be retained
in long-term memories
and then the other motor processing
the elaborate iv homeowner processing in
which we try to link individual items
with things
we already know
elaboration is one of two
important process easy
governing
of the encoding phase
of memory
processing but it's not the only one
the second one
is illustrated but this list
here's another study list
lion
blows orange
finger
elephant
and purple
that when people remember these kind of
the list like this
what they usually do is i don't remember
the words in the order in which they
were presented
letter that you regroup the words so
that i removed from
that's the same conceptual category all
the number together
body parts
finger month
four-foot it out of those lion
elephant
rat
articles of clothing blows
code
tied
and the colors
orange
amber
and purple
here you're doing something or other
than
taking individual items and linking them
to something you already know
what you're doing is you're taking
individual items and linking them truly
each other
who said what bill bunch of body parts
here
there are a whole bunch of colors there
are a whole bunch of all
lable
alone four footed animals or whatever
through the extent
reorganize the material
solace to focus on and process the
relations among individual items you'll
remember individual items even
so
on here is just an example of that
cluster carrot clustering of items by
categories
is a very prominent
uh...
fighting in in this kind of literature
you can see here
that over trials
recall
increases
but also people's tendency to cluster
items by category membership also
increases
there's a correlation
between clustering and recall
and this correlation
illustrates
or second principle
uh... memory encoding
which is known as the organization
principle
in the organization principal memory is
a function of the extent to which
individual items are related to each
other
memories of function
of the extent to which individual items
or related to each other
so now we have two principles
elaboration an organization
and just in summary let's compare the
two
yeah operation principle is a principle
that is idm specific
it's concerned up only with the relating
of individual list items to pre existing
knowledge
organization
more relational processing what you're
trying to do is to process the relations
among items
and mouth and finger
the role body parts
having discovered that i got three body
parts on the list
it makes it easier for me to remember
one of those
both the elaboration principle
by which we link newell information
to information
previously stored
and of the organization principal by
which we link
individual items it wouldn't for mation
to each other
reflect
what the british psychologist frederick
bartlett
effort after meaning
after meeting
the idea here is
that we remember things better through
the extent that we try to make sense of
either by elaborating
them against preexisting knowledge
or organizing a bunch of them together
inter of their relations
ambient house is a mistake
a mistake that a lot of people were
making or under the influence of those
so
old stimulus response there is a warning
is that he was studying
bomb
memory for items that are devoid of
meaning
and still
his subjects tried to make
meaningless material meaningful by
saying all that syllable resembles this
word that i know or
those are my best friends and nishal
czarist anything like that their book
that that will create meaning in the
items
why don't we try to make sense what's
happening
when we tried to relate
new things to what we already know
when we tried to relate new things to
each other
when we engage in a labrador
and organizational activity
that's when we remember
collaboration
an organization two principles that
govern yun coding stage of memory
processing
next time we'll take up the storage
space
thank you very much we'll see you on
wednesday