okay let's begin let's begin by
reminding you that there is an exam in
this class next week
on wednesday
although the review in class all by the
geo size on monday i've already
distributed an announcement about the
narrative review that i posted to the
course website
i've got some accommodation notices for
his students in the d_s_p_ program but
if there are any others that i should
have
gotta get those to me as soon as
possible so we can make the appropriate
on arrangements
the exam as announced will cover all
required reading some lectures to date
so the introductory resolve lecture and
quite mins chapter one
the lectures on biological basis of
behavior in playthings chapters two and
three
a lecture on where lectures on morning
and lightens chapter six
and lectures on sensation and perception
which are today and wednesday
and glickman's chapters four and five
we will not be having questions on the
statistical appendix on this exam
but we will have some questions
on that material
on the final
exam
there are lots of resources for the exam
as mentioned there's going to be a
review and our class on monday
all of the jia sides are not going to
temp to covered all the lecture material
or all the textbook material
but they will be here and available to
answer any
gault less than a questions that you may
have
the study guide for the globe in text is
pretty good
all a very good guide to
not only the uh... content of the exam
but also the style of questions whiteman
was one of my teachers
like like to think i think like he does
along
there a lots of materials on the course
website there lecture supplements there
are copies of past exams
all of which with the answers most of
which with some analysis
in addition if you have any last minute
questions ready questions at all
or if you post them to the forum on the
corps on the block or so of course
website
by noon on tuesday
either rider the geoscience will all
do our best to get a response to you
are backed by the end of business
birthday okay so there are lots of
things
available
on the exam format slice of the class
dictates multiple-choice testing but
even if we did that the dead and will
probably do it
'cause multiple-choice tests of the best
s
their objective
they're reliable
there's no worry about whether the g s
all i was tired when he or she was
reading your exam
or whatever
on the just pages run through the
computer and dog that's it
all roughly half of the questions are
drawn directly from the lectures roughly
half were drawn from the text there's
overlap
all make sure
that you come to class with the proper
red scantron form
which you can buy your ta as you see
bookstore and other venues around campus
i know they are
let's have the right pat brown's grill
and bring a couple of number two pencils
because you can fill these things in the
bank
you've got a filament
this is what the scantron form looks
like this is the front
this is the back i've already got an
example of that on the narrative
i'll review that i all posted to the
course website
but if you have any doubts
one year there were two different red
scantron forms
all of this is the one
it's about four or by
eight or nine or something like that
that's the front
the uh... that's the back
all focus of the exams as always is on
basic concepts and principles
at this level of the course for just
trying to give you some appreciation of
how your minds work
also they're not going to be questions
about the key details at least i don't
think they're picking details
qualm
i took the exam the other night
i passed
of
we also don't ask you about specific
experiments
however i might naman investigator all
might refer to an experiment as a way of
helping you retrieve the basic concept
of principle that's associated with that
experiment ok so if i talk about
garcia's experiment on taste aversion
learning tougher stand it should go off
in your head is
the arbitrariness assumption and the
preparedness principal if i ask you if i
could ask about caymans experiment on
the block in effect buff first thing
that you go off in your head is
alm association by contingency
and predictability in surprise okay
that's how that works
so we want to recommend recognize the
implications of studies
but we don't need you to memorize
studies
themselves
okay ought that's pretty much all i have
to say about the exam for now any
questions about
format of the exam yes
know the statistical appendix that
you're not going to be responsible for
on the midterm
is the appendix it's in the back of the
book
but it was assigned in the readings for
the introductory lectures along with
chapter one
it's in the back of the textbook
all appendices always in the back of the
textbook
so if it's not on the exam i wouldn't go
looking for it right now
i don't worry about the statistical
appendix for now
you'll have plenty of time to worry
about it
farm anything else about the exam yes
at the issues the bookstore
okay
all or there were other places around
campus site
when i go getting a bunch of pat brown
squirrel i see them at the cashiers
fifty
okay dot that's appear
ok anyway it's fifty
and that's probably doable in the fifty
minutes you've got okay
armstrong
just get here get settled in
pass out the exams take the exam turn in
the exam
phone
and that
all bombeck shore
you keep a record all of your
answers on your exam for you don't turn
in the exams you just turn in the
scantron forms
because
right after the exam the our preliminary
scoring key will go up and you can check
your answers
okay immediate feedback good
psychological principle of learning
anything else about the exam
okay if you have any other questions we
can catch them up on wednesday or just
post into the course website
okay last time we talked about some
basic phenomenon of learning
and one of them major
earth thrusts of those lectures
wires that were in a man's not just a
matter of what changing behavior
bringing behavioral responses
onto the control of various
environmental stimuli
rather we want to think about learning
in terms of a change in the knowledge
that an organism acquires new knowledge
about the world
that at the very least
animals that to predict and control
what's going to go on and its
environment
that's true for the dogs and cats in the
riots and rabbits usually used an animal
condition experiments
but it's even more true
humans
we understand now that human beings are
cognitive beans
our behaviors
go well beyond
mere associations between stimuli and
responses
we do a lot more than reflex taxes
instinct
conditioned responses
instead our behavior is based is
intelligent
it's based on our knowledge about the
world
and so what we have to do
if we're going to understanding havier
is we have to understand hollow
organisms
specially humans acquired knowledge
paul would stored in the mind
how it's used in various ways
and how it's communicated to other all
other people
and that's what cognitive psychology is
all about
what we're going to be talking about for
the next dong
for the next many weeks uh... in this
course we want to know how organisms
specially humans
acquire information about the world
store it
and communicated
and the first step in that process is
acquiring knowledge about of the world
for me mental representations of
ourselves
for me mental representations of two
things that we experience
and then
on making use of those representations
in various ways
this cats that question that has been a
devil philosophers for our couple of
thousand years
all which is to say how is it that we
know the world how is it that we are
quite that we get knowledge about the
world
and in full of sooty at least
all the philosophical responses to this
question philosophical answers to this
question boil down to
one of two answers
there's a group of philosophers known as
nativist
who argued that
our knowledge is innate
that it comes to us independent of our
sensory experiences into the were born
going
everything
we're going
to uh...
to know
and at the r_d_ contrary point of view
is what's known as empiricism
and basically the idea behind empiricism
is that knowledge is acquired through
experience
or through our reflections on experience
now we now know that there are certain
forms of knowledge that actually already
in eight all language was technologies
in some important cincinnati we now know
that
but by and large
fault scientific psychology
comes down on the side all the
empiricism
the idea that most of what we know about
the world we know by virtue of
experience
especially sensory experience
and that's why
all psychology has spent so much time
trying to figure out
hollow sensation and perception
let's first make though some elementary
distinctions between sensation and
perception
sensation
asks enhancers are basic
very very simple question
the job of sensation
is simply to detect the presence
all of us on the
object or event
the environment
basically sensation answers a question
of
is there something out there
okay
alm
when i see you by sensory mechanisms are
detecting the presence
of you in the environment
and almighty center mechanisms also tell
me
there's a lot of you
so sensation basically says is there
something out there
and how intense
okay very very very simple questions
perception the next stage in the
information acquisition process
tries to answer some much more
complicated questions
where is the object
is it in the left of the right as an
awkward and as it near or far
what what is it doing is it's static is
that movie knows that bending his rigid
and finally what i did
what's the identity of this object
what category of objects does it belong
to
all blocked all are it's all dictate
capacities what can it do to me
and not
any less important
what can i do with it
so sensation
the tax
the presence of an object in the
environment
perception
identifies and categorize is that object
forms the mental representation of the
object
which is the knowledge of the object
we have
in our minds
we can see of a little bit better i
think the relations between sensation
and perception
if we examine what i'd like to call the
basic vocabulary of sensation and
perception
or which is
uh... vocabulary that cludes
distal and proximal stimuli
and track instruction
the dust all-star annulus
is the term that we use
to refer to
any object or event
that occurs in the environment
fiscal stimulus is any object or event
that occurs in the environment you're
all distal stimuli to me
uh... your
smiling faces your attorney in paper
rear coffee in all that stuff
art distal stimuli
approx little stimulus
refers to the energy the pattern of
energy
is evident by the
distal stimulus
and falls on my sensory receptors
sold for example
although if i had that there's a tree in
my environment
that tree
all people reflects light
and that light falls on the retinas of
my arms
fault if the tree is
blowing in the wind it's going to
russell it's going to make some noise
those sound waves
or remitted by the tree
and they fall on the alone dot on my
dears
if i'd catch
the tree
but texture of its bark
the smell a bit like a bit so eucalyptus
tree or a pine tree or whatever it might
take a bite out of it the taste of the
tree
all of that stuff
dot that though that those
notice of the proximal stimuli that
impinge on my sensory all mechanisms
so the testosterone it was is the object
proximal stimulus is the pattern of
energy
that is re radiate order reflected by
the object
that falls on my sensory receptors
and it's the job of the sensory
receptors
to perform trans duction
transduced or transform
stepped proximo stimulus
into a pattern of neural impulses
the rods in clones in the rep moby ait
take a light waves and transform
transduced
light waves into
on dural impulses
the basilar membrane and the cochlea of
the year
take sound waves
and transducers at
into or pattern of electrical impulses
so okay
all of that
is what
sensation does
taking a proximal stimulus
repudiated via distal stimulus
transduced into into a neural impulse
which is then transmitted
all bio various afferent nerves into the
cortex of the brain
at which point
perceptual processes take over
to inform on mental representation
all but
distal stimulus
a mental representation
of the tree and image if you will of the
tree
that exists in my mind
that represents paul or depicts if you
will on the tree
that's outside
are both the physical features of the
trees at paula's at shaw ridges that
green doesn't have leaves on it or
whatever
and also
the home beyond the meaning of the tree
perception
forums this mental representation
an adult life is that
so that i don't defies
and categorize is
the object
so no the question is
how do we get
from the stimulus to the percept
how do we get from the pattern of
stimulus energies radiating off the
distal stimulus
transduced into a pattern of neural
impulses
sent to vote for various call cortical
sites in the brain
or create a mental representation
of that distal
or stimulus
one important view of this process
one take if you will on this process
is known as the ecological view of
perception
and it is our associated with two
psychologist a husband and wife team at
cornell university
both now gone unafraid james j gibson an
owner jack gibson
jimmy and jackie
gibson
are very very very famous very important
perception psychologists
all who gave us this ecological view
what they did the sims argued
was it that way we get from sensation
perception
the way we get from
distal stimulus in the environment why
it's called the ecological view okay
presided for the percept are occurs
because
every statement was
provides all the information you need to
perceive the object or event in the
environment
every stimulus
provides all the information needed for
perception
and what perception involves
is extracting this information
from the pattern ald
stimulus energies from the pattern of
proximal stimulation
that falls on sensory
of on on the center receptors
another name for the ecological view is
direct
perception
sometimes called directory elizabeth
moore usually called direct perception
and again
it's called direct perception
because within the gibson's view
everything you need to perceive the
world is supplied by the world itself
supplied by the distal stimulus
and the pattern of proximal stimulation
falling underwritten on your row center
receptors
and there is no need
for any kind of
so called a higher cognitive activity
there's no need to make inferences
there's no need to make use of judgment
of memory that stored in your mind
already
nothing's you already know about the
world
no need to or
to engage in any kind of problem solving
activity
all the information you need for
perception is supplied
the home
by the stimulus
itself itself
and it turns out
this is a very powerful viewer
perception
it kind of culture
for are a lot
of how perception works
it could account for
it you know as you'll see in a minute
forth the basic principles of depth
perception
answering the question
is the object of perception nearer to me
close at hand
or is it
away
the ecological deal can also
our count four
most of motion perception
answering the question about
the distal stimulus
is the object
stable in the environment
or is it
moving around
and finally
olympic candle account for what's known
in the trade as the perception of
plasticity
which just says is the object rigid
isn't flexible
in various kinds of ways
what i'm going to do
all used to demonstrate the ecological
view a perception
by focusing in depth perception
but your textbook lightnings text has a
very nice account of motion perception
along similar lines
not so much on the of on the perception
of all plasticity
on a typical perception course you'll
get allot of that
so again
what the ecological viewer perception
says
is that if you want to know rarely
object is
what it's doing
and what it's basic form is
the object itself
the enviroment itself supplies all the
information that you need
all for this song of for this purpose
but there is a trek
in the ecological view
and it's one that's important to
understand
and that is that the ecological view
defines the stimulus
very broadly
to include not just the object that
you're looking at if i'm looking at one
of you
okay
you're the distal stimulus invited in by
sensory field
but so is everything else
okay
so the idea here
all the information needed for
perception is supplied
body
this dog by the distal stimulus but
thing you're looking at
but also by the surrounding the stimulus
field
all the context
that surrounds
father at object
although basically or the environmental
context i'm looking at one of you
everybody else in the room such errors
everything else
of while provide some of the context
and also
information from my own body
as you'll see
or in a minute provides some of the
stimulus information needed for
perception but the idea is that
it's also in the world
everything you need for perception is
provided by the stimulus environment
provided that you define the stimulus
environments
broadly enough to include both the
object of regard
and its context
both information in the environment
and information
deep receivers
let's see how this works
when we look that
perception of distance
how do we know
whether their called whether an object
that we're looking at
is close to was
far away
it turns out
there are a number of cubes
provided by the stimulus environment
that do a very good job of telling us
whether an object izmir or or far away
and
one of these cues
is known as convergence
it's a but we call the binoculars q for
the perception of distance because this
is a cue that requires that we have two
lines
doesn't work if you've only got one i
look at it cover one are you up
you lose
the convergence cues
and the convergence q
basically comes from the fact that when
you focus your rise on an object
you're always turned inward
okay
also if i'm focusing on you here my eyes
are turned inward
if i'm focusing on you back there my
eyes or returned
but if you think about your work cut
high-school sophomore geometry for a
second
it turns out
at the angle of convergence is different
when you're focusing your eyes on a
nearby they object
then if you're focusing arise on an
object
far away
so that the angle of the two vectors the
angle created by the vectors the eyes go
into the object
indicates is a very good indicator of
distance for up for you
thirty or forty feet
here's the diagram
that shows that this is the case here
are two wise
converging onto wa objects
object they won
and object eighty two
and you can see
that if the eyes are focused are
converging on this nearby object to
anyone
the angle of convergys is relatively
large
if the eyes are focusing on this
relatively far away object
paid through
the angle of convergence is relatively
are small
so you jeff depth information
because you get feedback from the
muscles of the arise that tells you
whether the angle of convergence is a
big angle or a relatively small angle
big angled means the object is nearby a
small angle means the object is far away
so here is a cute to distance
cute in depth
that's provided by the stimulus
environment that we haven't talked about
the white waves radiating off the object
yet
a stimulus environment
but summa signals information has been
provided by by own body
that is the muscles in my eyes or
sending feedback to my visual system
about the angle of convergence that
provides information as to whether the
object is close
here is another q
alm
that paula is also a binoculars q for
the perception of distance this is known
as the retinal disparity
it's also sometimes called binoculars on
disparity
and it comes from the fact
that your eyes are separated by a
distance of about couple or couple of
inches
and by virtue of the fact that your two
eyes are separated by a distance of a
couple of inches
each
alrighty receives are somewhat different
image of the object
in question
and so what happens is
these to slightly different
two-dimensional images
which are on the retinas of the allies
are then diffused into a
three-dimensional image in the brain
but basically the idea is
all of the more disparity
or less disparity
is a q
for the perception of distance it's
actually the fact
that each on receives a somewhat
different
your view of the object
that produces
the of
the illusion
all of a lot of seeing things and depth
here is a demonstration
on here you've got
you're left died
and you're right on me
and you're looking at these three
objects
object death is far away
object he is in the middle object c is
all it is very close
and what you can see here
is that each of these are key to these
dogs ripple retinal views
is a little bit different
okay and then
ubu individual when the two images or
sent to the visual system
they are or their fused into
here is that there is an example of this
just do this is a demonstration
hold your left
index finger a full arms-length
okay
hold your right index finger
at half alarms length
and close your right on
closer right on
now align your two fingers using your
left on him
so that both of them coincide with the
cross
okay do that
now having done that
close your left aryan open your right
away
your each of your lives gets a somewhat
different view of these objects okay
and it's the disparity between them that
helps to create
on image of the world
enough in-depth
okay so we've got now these two
different views
convergence
and retinal
disparity
there are other accused for the
perception of distance
that are not binoculars in nature
but instead are more documentation or
meaning that they all do require that
you have what i
if you close one eye you still get this
information about depth and distance
one
molecular q for all for depth or
distance is known as accommodation
and this q reflects the fact that when
you will focus on an object
lands of you're alright changes shape
if you focus on an object that is nearer
to you
your lens has to bolger gets that
and if you focus your eye on an object
that is distant
full lens will stretch out
flattened
again
this accommodation is produced by a
muscles in the army
okayed the federal way itself is
produced by muscles of the special
muscles in the eye
and these muscles send feedback to the
visual system
that tells the visual system
whether there
flatly both ends
making a bulge in the lens
in order
too
in order to
bring the object into focus
here is the diagram of that we've got to
whites here
and we've got an object that is close-up
here is the lens of the are you can see
it's become a little bulge
inept back here
and hear you've got an object that is
relatively far away
and when the i_e_ focuses on that
the lens has two planes just like you
and all like a projector for example or
two or as a sort of some cameras
all you have to do so uh... something
very similar
but again the point here is that there
are muscles
doing this bulging and flattening
they provide feedback to the visual
system
that's part of the stimulus environment
this is the information that's coming
from the body of the perceive ur
in the same way
that the angle of convergence
columns from the body of the
perceive her
case all accommodation is one such
so-called mon ocular q for the
perception of distance
here's another one very good q for the
perception distance known as relative
size
and this relative size occu basically
reflects another aspect of geometry
known as the the size
distance rule
if you hold
the distance
between the observer and turn wild
checks
constant if you hold the distance
constant
the size of the object
will be of of will be
directly control the size of the object
of that the of the image that the object
tests on the retina
so object size will be a function of the
image size if you hold distance constant
if you hold side is constant
aldrich distance
is a function of
the embers of the image size
if you hold size constant
on target that far away will cast a
smaller image on the road no
than an object that's of clothes if you
hold
distance constant large objects cast a
large
image on the rattler
small objects cast a small image on the
bottom of the retina
if you hold size constant
close objects
a large image on the retina
distant objects
cast a small
all image on the road
so you could take this information
about the relative size of of of the
rebel images
and that is information about
uh... about distance
good example of this comes from
professor palmer's of dot book here we
have a dolly
and we have to trees
a close-up three
and a tree that's far away
the image all the clothes tree
is larger
then the image
tree okay
so when u
seat this is what the rebel image of
those trees would look like you see but
one triple larger image
are closer to you
the of them smaller image relative size
is an important q
distance if we have to objects that are
pretty much the same size
the one that passed the larger image on
the retina
is going to be closer
than the one
the tests
the smaller
on the road
so relative size
is another q to distance and
it's eight mode ocular q you don't need
to wise to get this q
all you need is one i
onto to have retinal image
rebel size
if u to distance
here is another
more doctor weir queuing for the
perception distance
known and superposition
and superposition simply refers to date
obvious fact
obvious ones to think about it for a
second
that nearby objects
will call it off
views of more distant objects
all you have more distant
from u than this podium and at the
podium
cuts off
your view of me cause sits in front of
me right
science looks very simple but it's a
profound q
i know move infront of the podium
and you know one closer to use in the
podium is because no one blocking your
view of the podium
superposition
is a very powerful q_-two distance it's
something cuts off
your view of something else
then obviously it's closer to you
then that other raj ect is
this is a cue that artists have used at
least since the medieval period
to or to depict distance
and it's also a q
that artists can have some
here's an example
just kind of schematic example of
superposition
you see the orange
won't block
closer to you
than the green blocked because the
orange q cuts off your view of the green
or square
here is a painting by the french
surrealist painter renee migrate in-car
plunge
in which he
playin swept the superposition q for
distance
woman riding a horse through a forest
this tree cuts off your view of the
horses hind quarters
woman
but the woman
cuts off your view artistry
and of course is four part
cuts off your view
of this tree picture that doesn't make
any sense okay as a depiction of the
world that doesn't work
but it's although i'm by screwing around
with a superposition q for distance okay
i'm a greater safety autolearn this
culinary arts school
and look what i could do with that i can
make this really interesting painting
all of that you know the more you look
at it the autre it looks
and it's or because the distance
relationships
between the horse and writer on the one
hand
and the trees on the other hand have
been home have been played with
so superposition
is all is another one of these important
to all accuse
another when ocular cupid a perception
distance one that
began to be used in painting in a
renaissance art and is now a very very
important in realistic painting
is linear perspective
and the idea behind linear perspective
is that when objects are arranged in
linear perspective
are there are perspective lines
that conver
torrid a valuation point
and all jokes along those lines or
of for shortened or accordingly
on here is a mix of famous example
apiece renaissance art raphael school of
aphids
aristotle
socrates bunch of other people
all used to be able to name them all
can't do that right now
all pointed at the event
notice what's happening here
you see
these people
closer
to you
this person somewhere in the middle
these people
forever alway
and then in the distance
this arch way behind them
unit this is a a canvas this is a
two-dimensional painting of course but
you see add asst three-dimensional
singing
and the reason you see it as a
three-dimensional singing
is that raphael has carefully
constructed these images saw all along
all along perspective lines here's our
kind of rough and ready analysis of the
painting
if you follow
these lines from the tops of the columns
down
you see they converge right here in
dead center in the center of the
painting
if you take phone lines
suggested by that tiling in the floor
here
and follow them write-up again they
converge
right in the dead center
of the painting and then
various objects
are now
for shortened
as you move along the perspective lines
so here's a character here
person and white
who is about
toll
and hear is onto
authorities okay
who is painted as shorter than that
about how we work
if you were that far away along the
prospective lines
here's a person in the middle
and
that's well thong behind it that figure
is somewhere inbetween
the height of the speaker and the height
of that figure
these perspective lines when you talk
art in
grade school
they taught you to do this right cannot
draw these lines you know i've been told
make sure that everybody is arrayed all
along them this is a doubt that uh...
technique that was basically discovered
in the fourteenth century
people didn't know about it before the
fourteenth century and it's been used
ever since
to depict
that and distance
in the home
into dimensional space
and it turns out that our visual systems
use the same kind of information
what i'm looking at you no especially
from looking down this road
i get this nice perspective line the
converges back there are a little bit
people up here
you're pretty big
people back there
your pretty little right and it all fits
together all but with a full of the
regular for shortening along the all
along the prospective lines
so linear perspective
very very important to you
although
wrote again since the renaissance at
least painters have tried to paint
scenes
as if
you were looking at the scene
through our window on the frame supplies
that window here is our painting by
marguerite that all basically
salt blob of plays on this principle
on you've got it
canvas
island evil
it's a canvas of the field
with you treated it
and notice that this shrubbery here
is continuous
with the shrubbery that your view
the window
again
all of those artists with views
cues like
all than your perspective to create the
image
the painting
is just what the world would look like a
outside
if you were looking at it
e window
here's another example of a great way to
do this
on uh... mine but these titles are the
he was a surrealistic titles don't have
anything to do with the painting
alm
but you can see again here is the easel
here's the canvas
there's a cluster of houses here
in the painting we have the horse cart
and most of the house
little bit of shrubbery here
but it's continuous with
the rest of this on comic readers
lighting up
his perspective lines
so was to create delusion
that you're looking at the world
the window
canvas
here it is another migrate love
marguerite don't you
on the promenade suv euclid
all work the greatest on something very
interesting
with altman with the lines of
perspectives so here we've got another
these all another tenders right at the
scene
what do you know the window
there is this
are tolerant here with the conical our
top on a condom
disneyland
power
and then there is this long boulevard
receding are receiving them to the
distance
you can see here clearly
the visual perspective lines
the vanishing point
creating
the law the illusion the that the uh...
the impression
that these houses down here
farther away from the viewer
than these houses or or or here
okay see i was done that
notice however that does
conical power top
is exactly the same
in shape
and size
as
the conversion lines
in this boulevard
these are exactly the same shape and
size
but you don't see these is converging
lines y
because my brief has used the principle
of superposition
get you to see this power as being in
front
of this all
uh... that this apartment building
there is no superposition q
on here
rather you see these as prospective
lines and the world going out
or the distance it's a very charming and
i think illustration
of how
all written realistic painters
mccree would probably
turn over his grave if you've heard
nicole more realistic painter but that's
what it is
datatable boulevard right
all
on to use these
accused the depth
to communicate on all of the
depth and to represent
depth distance
here's another q that's commonly used
elevation
distance from the horizon
when you look out at the world
distant objects up here are closer to
the horizon then nearby objects to
just next time you look at the world
check that out
and you'll see that it's true here it is
all dusk a medic depiction of it we've
got a horizon here
we've got a tree here
we've got a tree here on these trees are
the same size
all but you perceive
this tree as closer to you
that industry distant objects or closer
to the horizon
near by objects
here's another example from a professor
plummer
here's an array of trees
a horizon
some alums
and some clothes
and notice that these trees
appear closer to you
than these trees
there closer to be streets are close to
the horizon a pure farther away
and that this cloud
appears
farther away
that these clouds
again the clothes closer to the horizon
so it's not a matter of up-and-down ok
thought about urban high on though
the image or lowered the image
it's a matter of
where you wore
with respect
horizon
on governor qal from a perception of
distance known as aerial prospective or
atmospheric perspective
and this that this q works because
uh... in the air there are best
particles are sometimes water particles
are under liquid particles
onto a fraction
the light okay
all and produce the kind of blowing
but more distance
there is between you and the object
the more cost and water there is in the
error between you when the object
and more willing
all actually occurs
here are two really good examples of
this
this is a photograph of the blue ridge
mountains and north carolina
one of the reasons the blue ridge
mountains look blue it'll look blue if
you're sitting on a blue ridge about
looks very green cause
trees are grain
the reason at the blue ridge bones look
below
is that these all of the chinese on
these moments or a minute ago kind of
oil
that alter frac slight in the distance
here's another example the supporter
preferably cottage one
in guatemala
and on a close by you see your this
green
and that is to go to his art would look
at the more distant volcanoes
you see the baby turned blue again
that's because even in such a pristine
environment as we got to climb
there's still a lot of doston stuff for
the year and that creates gluing of what
would otherwise be green
but below where it is not for the way it
is to make along the story short
on these are always
are good cues on to distance
and finally thickness finally and i
think you've heard dog for a productive
is texter gradients
and that simply means
that there is more texture apparent in
an object that's close at hand
then there is in an object that's for a
way
when i look at you like to see
kind of into done he reckons he can
individual hairs and things like that i
could see your shoelaces
what i look at somebody back there i
don't get anything like that i know the
releases on that shoe but i'd just
see them
on here are some photographic depictions
of this would be seen
these rocks are closer
to the observer
you can see a lot of detail
these rocks same kinda rocks farther
away
they blur into the distance
here it is a elva crowd scene of the
football stadium you see a lot of detail
on here
in the objects utter farther away much
less so that there is out
gradient of texture gave a more texture
the more detail you can see the closer
the object all
host of the objectives
and then finally
uh... we have are shadowing
as an index
to ardent adept
this calmness
from the fact that
or visual systems evolved
in an environment where there was only
one source of light
the sun or the moon
and it was always
pretty much always over had
when u_n_ evolve a visual system
in an environment where the source of
light is always overhead
the pattern of shadows
communicates
dot all of the depth and distance okay
so here
these
three circles here
you perceive them as convex you perceive
them as coming out
all of the screen
towards you
whereas use block received these
circles as concave
and dented in to the screen
going away from you
against evil pattern of light here
these are illuminated casting a shadow
there's a shadow here
and this is eliminated
that's an impression that's created
simply by
hollow polite works you can see this
very clearly
to flip it upside down
these used to be on the bottom these is
to be on the top
but no okay
what was once convex is now a concave
as and what was cool what was once
convex
what would what one's concave is no
convex all because of the pattern of
light
so dead
it's the pattern of light radio off the
object
that communicates
and what's
so we've got no it's wholesale accuse
saamne binoculars in nature
requiring tour guides
someone ocular in nature
requiring only one died
somewhat ocular in nature
because the information is provided by
the always themselves in the muscles
attached to them
and all others optical in nature having
to do with the pattern of light the
falls on the retinal i'll be all right
these inferred these fused together
create
the perception of depth
or distance invasion
as the gibson's whitewater reminders
highly information
if you need to four perception of
distance
is provided by the stimulus itself
provided you define the stimulus broadly
enough to print to include
figure
as well as the ground
information
in the light
and information in the muscles as well
information
coming through the perceive ur it
information in the body of the procedure
all the information for perception is
provided by the stimulus
not quite true
and soul explain on wednesday
thank you very much