okay
okay last time we talked about
psychopathology more or less abstractly
talk about how we think about the fire
gtm
how we are think about deviance of
normality and all of that
what i want to do today is together will
boil that more concrete about the
particular forms of mental illness that
we observed
and how we think about them
last time i find that out
making a point
psychiatric diagnosis like any kind of
that medical diagnosis
this is centrally inactive
categorization
when you have a patient purification
aristocrat restrict clinical
psychologist
you have a patient who's got some kind
of problem
your the first thing you have to do is
to figure out
what kind of problem it is
okay that st dot that's what diagnosis
is and in figuring out what kind of
problem it is
you essentially categorize
the illness
or categorize the patient
and into baltimore diagnostic categories
and for the next question is how do we
think about these categories
well classically
we think that we thought about these
categories
in the class accordion categorization as
proper steps
diagnostic categories
features defining features
symptoms that work always present in
various forms of disease
date these symptoms diagnostic symptoms
essentially function does
defining features of the various
diagnostic categories so that you get a
system like this which is the classic
diagnostic system where you'd have a
mental illness divided into
to big categories psychosis and wilson's
and then psychosis divided into two
subordinate categories manic-depressive
illness and schizophrenic
and schizophrenia divided into various
kinds of subtypes
and again in the classical veeru
there was a strict separation between
categories you were even argue either
had manic-depressive illness three had
schizophrenic
you're either had some form of psychosis
three had sums for monroe says
if you're a schizophrenic
you had one or the other of these four
forums on sc is a prettier
rigid distinctions
between
all the various kinds of categories
but it turns out
just as there are problems with the
classification that
birds and fish
just like a problem for the
clarification of fruits and vegetables
there are problems with a classification
of mental illness when we look about
those problems are
for the same time for problems
so for example
in psychiatric diagnosis weather made
her
issues affecting cycle about psychiatric
diagnosis
is that many patients
all right well shadow only a partial
expression
antoine syndrome or another
separation might have
all offensive just organs
and then had a meal
but not shallow ambivalence or alter zm
so disrupt rule before cardinal symptoms
of schizophrenia but not the other two
well you do with such a patient
what you do what you're doing such a
patient it'd you begin to
hedge categorization so i won't happen
was that
the diagnostic off the vocabulary
got extended
to have
bad terms like skilled personality
excuse article personality
for people who
kind of had some of the symptoms of
schizophrenia but didn't have full-blown
through the frontier okay
and suddenly as
output the category of paranoid
personality developed
to classify people had delusions
so that they had that feature all
paranoid schizophrenic
but they didn't have any of the other
or part of features of schizophrenia
they didn't have
of the associate disturbance they didn't
have the actor dhoni or whatever
so joe status
thirty tomato
both kind of absolute that's really more
like a vegetable that it is like a fruit
so
well out there uh... there these
gradations
in the audit in mental illness
so that patients didn't really look like
any of the diagnostic categories
the second problem
what have you had
you don't do that kind of many patients
who seem to have
who's going to come back in the
expression all true world war two forms
of mental illness
remember that according to the classical
bulow categorization
you're a good one category or another
later a fish or a bird
your fruit or vegetable the realistic
or or a triangle affiliate you can't
beat
truly care but i am into different
categories dot mental patients about
their who clearly
didn't seem to blow into different
categories
so for example
on very frequently encounter patients
who have similar symptoms associated
with schizophrenic
c alm
follett assertive disturbance
and also some of the all symptoms
associated with affect of disorder
sojourn what happened was that the
diagnostic vocabulary was enlarged
cargo to cover these kinds of combined
expressions
suddenly got terms like giver aspect of
this error
for patients who
resemblance to the front of you have to
be involved with illness represent bles
fiza freddy in some respects
that resembled affective disorder in
rather respects
and they also or borderline personality
for which now has an entirely different
meaning that its origins
was intended to to cover people who work
right on the board of wine
between schizophrenia
bulb donna de fective disorder solve
this problem partial and combined
expression
which we said before critique of the
classical view of categories is proper
sets
i got out of the comes to us again
when we look at the nature of the
diagnostic categories
by third problem
ourselves for what
all of the more interesting problem
openssl respects is the instability
diagnostic
of out of psychiatric diagnoses
if you're up and then i will let em know
okay
if you're a square r square we are not
going to change into something else
dot people with various forms of mental
illness
moving in and out of categorization
so for example you can be in the acute
trainees of schizophrenia
the kind of a florida
although the phase dot uh...
representing the initial of the initial
episode
why debate then move into requested
phase of the disease
heart
the disease night but i thought you
might be calm
gigabyte
all we're going to what's known in the
medical traders in remission
and the question is what do you do with
a person who is categorized as
headed for the friday at one point but
that doesn't seem to have schizophrenia
and other ppl
hydeia categorize these individuals
well
of these problems
all part of began to
school
all bother people called a quite a bit
and that they decided to do
once to style
eyes the nature of psychiatric
classification
instead of presenting
mental health workers
witless solved defining features
symptoms that we're defining features of
various categories of disease they'd
these at the do you have a general idea
now is that
rallies
there are more alike
categories defined by family resemblance
that look more like prototypes so we
have onset of also orthodox disorders
the organic brain syndrome so a
personality disorders or whatever
but none of these is the sociated
with any
singling necessary
and jointly sufficient
are defining features
instead
what we've got now how r diagnoses as
forty sets
god illnesses
that are described in terms of
characteristic symptoms not symptoms
that always present in every case of a
particular
well form of illness
but symptoms that
tend to be present more often
all of them out
of say that you know i have in the
diagnostic all thug a clarification
scheme
and allowance for quite a bit of
heterogeneity
within categories
you'll have one patient with
schizophrenia who doesn't actually
resemble
they would watch on some other patient
along with uh... with schizophrenia
so that there were no
no clear boundaries
between one form of mental illness
and dog and another
you can see this situation
very clearly
when you look at heart with
schizophrenia is currently diagnose
when pataki still afraid it was first
introduced in the early part of the
twentieth century
alaska's i thought it was defined in
terms of bloggers four days
associate disturbance and had only a
ambivalence an autism
and blow asserted that
everything every patient with
schizophrenia habit these for character
these four symptoms and these four
symptoms
deferring to the illness of
schizophrenia
but we don't think like that are anymore
in psychopathology
instead the diagnosis of schizophrenia
can be made
if a patient has
to learn more abenney
so-called
characteristic symptoms these are
classified as positive symptoms
positive symptoms are stars symptoms
that
you know people have and
well people
okay there
their of their president
in art of the negative symptoms
art are things that are absent in the
old people but president in the home
oh yen-dollar
that i have some video people present
and well people you'll see what i mean a
minute
these positive symptoms delusions
at all of the day believe solve all our
various kinds
hallucinations
hearing voices for example
disorganized speech not being able to
communicate your means all of the
affectively
are grossly disorganized speech
if you're a delegation in very pod
all occurring salvos of behaviors
these are symptoms
in many patients with schizophrenia
but tend to be absent
in people without schizophrenia so
they're called positive symptoms
these negative symptoms aspect of
flattening
i am all this is related to blow his
concept of edwardo near
many through the front of patience
all just don't seem to show much affect
they don't express much out and i think
they don't
smile a lot they don't smile flown a lot
to be there for that matter all energy
up
or difficulty in maintaining her
ideology u_s_a_ stream of thought
is bullish and difficulties and all
indian motivation
again
most people don't have flat affects most
people are very expressive if there are
in there a motions
most people don't have difficulty of
home of maintaining a train of thought
don't have any difficulty getting up and
going
but again
not every fifth affronted patient it's
going to have every one of these
in fact
because the diagnosis of schizophrenia
required
all the way that a patient have
two or more these characteristic
symptoms
you can't have it you can imagine
when a patient with schizophrenia who
has delusions and affect in flat name
another patient
who had solicitations and disorganized
speech but not delusions and not affect
a flattening
itself as a step
the diagnosis of schizophrenia on now
and again these dot these are two or
more characteristic symptoms
have to be accompanied by
evidence of social or occupational
dysfunction and they have to persist for
more than six months
but the point is
all of the class these are now
characteristic symptoms symptoms that
are all only imperfectly correlated with
category membership
you could have
who had the same
illness
schizophrenic ah...
who look very different
from each other
similarly when you look at major
depressive disorder
all
here at the diagnosis now requires that
a patient present
five symptoms firearm or symptoms over a
period of two weeks
depressed mood
diminished interest in things
or weight loss
all in fact meal or hypersonic leaders
are one form of sleep disorder or the
other
a lot of agitation
all the rest of energy
easy alton easy feted hope it's called
easy to fatigue
our feelings of restlessness
or inability to concentrate
are perhaps suicidal thoughts
but again
not every depressed patient is going to
show after these symptoms
in order to be diagnosed with major
affect the disorder
all you have to show or you have to show
five or more of these symptoms
so that you can get
two individuals with depression
gordon look very different from each
other are not of heterogeneity
in these diagnostic categories
tumour examples
anxiety disorder
all
obviously
dusty fits its name
well u
gotta have excessive anxiety
but even excessive ags already isn't
sufficient
to be tapped to be go
diagnosed with anxiety disorder
there have to be
all some extra symptoms here
and any three will do here
so you can have
one page with anxiety disorder
who has restlessness
and is easily fatigued in his irritable
another patient with anxiety disorder
who has sleep disturbance
and muscle tension
and has difficulty concentrating
patients will look very different
from each other even though they're
carrying
the same diagnostic
ul label
here is the last example of this
post-traumatic stress disorder
all
there's only one necessary to develop a
symptom over here
and that is that the person actually is
exposed to travel
whether it's the trouble of work
where the trial of natural disaster
or the trial of being victimized
although the victim of some kind of
crime
exposure trauma alone
is not sufficient
qualified person for diagnosis of
post-traumatic stress disorder
they actually have to show some
symptoms of disorder
but again
the symptoms that they can show all very
very valuable
so that
one
person with d_t_s_ the will have
recovered memories of the trauma
another
all patients with d_t_s_ d
very distressed when he or she comes
into contact with the
dramatic incidence of again
oh seven out
this is a p_t_ esti will try to avoid
thinking
our boats at all about their trouble
orders will open simply detach
themselves from the source of the trauma
alone and just not some not so that's a
different ways
of has been keith usd
and the same illness
but very very different manifestations
of the illness we've moved
for a living
from diagnosis in terms of
singly necessary in jointly sufficient
defining symptoms
so that we know
all diagnosis is
more of an act of judgment
okay
we can't just look up a patient symptoms
of a cookbook anymore if they are you
got the four days you've got to get a
friendlier
you have to figure out
or what the pattern
of all of those old symptoms it is
and hello
how serious they are
so no we have body of research that
looks at the diagnostic process itself
and it turns out
then when you look at the kinds of
factors
that all affect clinicians certainty or
confidence in his or her psychiatric
psychiatric diagnosis
at the same kinds of factors
that after that us that affect a
person's
certainty or confidence
that they've classified some natural
object correctly whether itself
tomato oral
or whatever
so for example
if the patient presents
lots of characteristics features
you're more certain of your diagnosis
that if the patient only presents just a
few
if the patient presents
whole lots of feet are symptoms that are
also characteristic of some other
diagnosis
so that symptoms characteristic
alternative categories
that your confidence level will go down
he won't bow you won't be sure anymore
or exactly of whether you classify the
person correctly or not
the textbook cases
now that we learn frogs
when we learn how to make a diagnosis
all we don't we no longer expect
every patient bc it looks just like the
patients that are described in the
textbook instead
the textbook cases service something
like category prototypes
when you think about whether or not
whether or not eliza birder or whatever
you're going to say it all out called a
bird of the kind of looks like a sparrow
you don't expect backwards to look
exactly like sparrows
okay are the same way all of the of or
ordered all up
textbook cases our presided
just as
idealized examples that have lost of the
symptoms are characteristic of water and
other diagnosis
and relatively few
symptoms that are characteristic
all alternative
diagnoses
so that's how we get from symptoms the
diagnosis
we have
diagnostic categories
that are
are set out in terms of characteristic
features
and as with any other active
categorization
your job is
do the best uterine
make the best judgment you can
are matching
the art symptoms presented by the
patient with the character of these
symptoms are characteristic
of various
of the various diagnostic
categories
but that's not where at the process
stops
diagnosis psychiatric diagnosis is
always made in terms of symptoms
does the person have delusions does the
person experience hallucinations does a
person have excessive worry or is the
person excessively sad or or or whatever
altogether
we don't think that
the symptoms are just
evidence to the diagnostic process
but we want to do is to get to
underlined pathology
again in terms of the medical model
symptoms are not the disease
symptoms are closed by
the disease and what you want to use
that what you want to do
is to use them to other symptoms
to figure out not the only way in
pathology is
this is true for a medical doctor
patient comes in and says doctor i had
chest pains
that's the symptom
okay
then what you want to find out is one of
the person has quality of our heart
trouble
and if the person s for trouble
what kind of heart trouble it is you
always want to explain the symptoms
in terms of some underlying pathology
and in fact caucus balaji
no different from a medical pathology
these underlying pathologies or revealed
essentially by laboratory research
by experimental research of various
crimes that tried to
to try to find out
what did what the disease process really
is
disclosing the patient
to have the symptoms all of that he or
she is having
and again
that's parlayed exactly grandmom hidden
in the medical model
scientific medicine treats
diseases
it doesn't treat symptoms
new radio positioning is hey i've got a
fever
he doesn't put you in the refrigerator
to cool you off
okay
doesn't treat the symptoms
he says well you've got some kind of
infection so i'll give you some
antibiotic
the same kind of thing goes on
in the armed even though i've been in
psychopathology
now for those of you are photo following
along with slides are gonna skip
a bunch
for inferno
and yeah i don't know instantly
summary all the kinds of underline
pathologies that we talk about
u_n_ all is not in mental illness
in medicine
the underline pathologies are clear
sometimes the lesions to some part of
the anatomy
person suffers a lesion in the brain
coral broken bone or of war or whatever
sometimes there's a physiological
malfunctions
or some part of the bodies of operating
quite right gavel or say a heart murmur
earth something like that
o'rourke there may be some in veterans
of suicide
mark though some infection
that's gotten into the body and that
basically has to get out follow somehow
that wasn't the kinds of underline
pathologies we talk about in medical
illness
if you're
kandahar problem or a long problem or
cancer or or whatever psychopathology we
have a somewhat different list
first the underlines pathology sometimes
comes
in terms of what we call
psychological deficits
better intended to be
somehow analogous to
alm
not the psychologically analogous
two of
physical structure and function
set we fans liked
there is some patients
attentional functions
just aren't working right
okay
for their other mental patients who are
having difficulties atmosphere of memory
determined their vote with their motto
that whatever apparatus they have for
our
for remembering things isn't working of
right
are usually
uh... at least in principle
there's some kind of neural substrate
here is the reason the patients are
having difficulty
with attention
or thinking or remembering
is because some part of their brain
autism working or properly that i think
we're talking about
psychological deficits
deficits in the operation of one or
another psychological function
cases have psychopathology
mental functions are operating just find
a person's thinking clearly uh... and as
god good attention
doesn't have any problems of memory
what what what the undermine pathology
really is
is something like
fault some kind of
arnelle adaptive mental contents of the
person just
has the roar of idea about things
inappropriate thoughts
believes their expectations
as when
depressed people believe that are
everything above all the world autism is
bad
already reported expectations is when
of phobic individual although it has an
inappropriate fear of snakes
on sometimes the feeling of persons
emotions or or motives
our car somehow inappropriate
we think about these kinds of natural
death of mental contents
as often reflecting all some kind of
problem of social learning that the
person just
acquired some piece of knowledge
that's really good in the new in the way
bucknell adaptive of behavior so again
by analogy to the medical case
we have problems of
also
psychological structure
problems or psychological function
and that
because of some forms of mental illness
where it is just
persons not thinking right
uh... person's got bubbles wrong beliefs
all roaring expectations or whatever
palm
and we discover these things five means
are they are called set of methods
that we call experimental
psychopathology now i'm just not going
to talk about experimental sort of
throaty today
i what to do something else on entirely
or or
she's operably here
although so
though some friends of cycle of a star
psychopathology
there's a psychological deficit that is
fundamental in schizophrenia
we think it's something that has to do
with the attentional system in childhood
autism we felt there seems to be some
problem
thirty-odd in the in the uh...
mechanisms that relate the child
to to other people
and depression
the psychological deficit affects the
armed
the uh... of the the emotional system in
various ways
and an attention deficit disorder
there's again a problem at all
behavior tential system
but it's one that's quite different from
the problems we see in schizophrenia
so if you have forgotten so i have
mental illness
the underlying pathology it's best for
eleven terms of is psychological deficit
a_t_t_ fact in the psychological
structure
or function
uh... reforms of psychopathology
they are there aren't any psychological
deficits they died the mind is working
perfectly well
it's just got there and stuff in it
in five years
people have unwarranted fears
in obsessive-compulsive disorder
all again there are on warranted for
years and behaviors that the person
tries to
are that used to ward off the art of the
new york appeared event
some forms of depression
are best for help in terms of person
just having inappropriate
malad active believes about him or
herself and the world and then certain
psychophysiology oldest orders like are
psychosomatic ulcers
why we have a person whose feted
inappropriate reaction
who are to stress
again
mental functions are working ok it's
just that the person has
now look at it
inappropriate
thoughts feelings or or or desires
now that's how we think about mental
illness but the psychological level of
analysis
but as i said earlier
it's also the case for some forms of
mental illness
but there are a bad logical
abnormalities
that cause
the psychopathology to occur to begin
with
all here to bury good examples in
schizophrenia
very popular
all all hypothesis about schizophrenia
is that
milestone
altercations with with a prettier
have excess activity in a particular
neuro transmitter
also known as though i've known as
dopamine
higher levels of dopamine
or apparently at the heart all of our
schizophrenics
dopamine is in our transmitter that's
very importantly involved in the body of
the attentional system
and for depression
are there may be an underlying of the
biological abnormality
affecting another
neurotransmitter
are not to actually to north of effort
and on and and serotonin
apparently all levels of these nor
transmitters
seem to be responsible for at least some
forms of depression
so we get
psychopathology
is analogous to a medical pathology
there are symptoms are closed by
so i'm a underline disease
okay
which we can describe in psychological
terror
and sometimes find the source of
informal under laurin all underlying
biological abnormality as well
so the next question is
has mental illness come from
okay that is the question of ideology
where we got these psychological
deficits
where we get this these inappropriate
fear is inappropriate author all
obsessive behaviors and on and so on
all then it turns out
all that
also when you look at the origins spots
like a pathology
question about the elegy
you see the same kind of interactions
between nature nurture
between biology experience between genes
and the environment that we fall
when we were looking at
the development of a personality in the
last set of lectures
the production of
the predominant framework for
understanding
the origins of psychopathology
is known as the day that this is stress
model
which has
through components to it
that i got the cis
and stress
the diet offices component is
essentially any predisposition
to sam formal five mental illness
this predisposition does not clause the
mouth of the mental illness to a car
that it does leave the person
venerable
to send form of mental illness or that
increased with
for that form of of mental illness
the idea is
that people
acquirer
one way or another
seven died at the system leaves the
address for all of the first time for
mental illness
the dialysis alone is not sufficient
cause
the mental illness to occur
ladder
each individual medics and relatively
good
or relatively poor adjustment
to whatever today at the cis factor of
dot is
pre more evidence that
term from medicine refers to
what the person's condition is before
the onset of illness
so some people will adapt very well
to whatever dialysis order caryn
or others board adapt although well at
all
but again
the died after cecil alone does not
cause the disease
but i got the cis
it also causes the disease
or only in the interaction with the
second factor
which is known as the stress factor
and i think that i have to some stress
model
we define stress
as any
eve event
that challenges the person's adjustment
stresses any event that challenges the
person's current level of adjustment or
current level
of adaptation
and it's the stress
combined with udya offices that then
leads to an acute episode of illness an
acute episode of is a prettier
oregon acute episode of of depression
or whatever
but again
stress of the stress factor all alone is
not sufficient to cause mental illness
to occur
rather
the stress factor only causes mental
illness
the unbearable individuals
in individuals
who are who are carrying
a particular
dari offices factor
it's the dialysis
at the stress commbank
that precipitate
but at the sort of mental illness
neither one alone
is sufficient
now you see in this kind of framework
before when we talked about
the interaction of the person and the
situation
you can think of the dialysis
as every
characteristic all of the individual or
a characteristic of the person
you could think of the stress
as uncharacteristic of the environment
outside of the person
and as a indicated before it ever
lectures on personality and social
interaction
you could think about that this is the
stress as independent of each other okay
so here
we have
individuals who were low and i got the
since
someday offices
here individuals who were high
here individuals who have
low exposure to stress
hari exposure to stress
and the two factors that this is the
stress just add onto each other
so that
the more data since you've got
but more stress you're subjected to
the more likely you are
to have an acute episode
of storm form
of mental illness
burnt
because they'd i thought that this is an
stress interacting with each other
began a multiplicity of our relationship
so that
if you've got a low levels of dialysis
even with
high levels of stress you're relatively
unlikely
have an acute episode of mental illness
but if you've got high levels of diana
pisses
even low levels of stress
precipitate
acute episode again
there just to remind you that you've
seen this kind of
alms out there that that this kind of
booked on grass before
when we were talking about the person by
situation russian this is just another
example
so for example
all you can imagine that there are
various kinds of patterns
of the relationship between guyana
persists and stress
if you've got if you're carrying a
substantial dialysis for seven form of
mental illness
relatively little stress is going to be
required
to precipitate an acute episode and by
virtue of that high degree of dialysis
you made bog bog make
are relatively poor adjustment
even before
the acute facility
family
if an individual is subjected to test
radical level stress
even the middle of a war zone for
example or be in the middle of some
natural disaster
then you might get
the stress levels that are so high
as to precipitate uh... audio an acute
episode of mental illness
even in people who are relatively low
organ risk
so they can cut it compensate
for each other
so if you have got out this is levels
that are more or less mobile
the likelihood barbecued episode
is going to be a function of the amount
of stress
you experience
if the amount of stress you experienced
is more or less within normal
limits
that nearly all the likelihood of having
an acute episode
is going to be determined by the amount
of play out this is
your carry
now let's just illustrate
with the couple's dog concrete
actual empirical examples how this of
how this works
first
let's look at our old friend the twins
study
okay
to look at dramatic
glad i got the seas disguise a prettier
here we have summary data
for three major forms of mental illness
schizophrenia bipolar affect of disorder
so-called manic-depressive illness
and you know polar affective disorder
and we have letter cold concordance
rates
offer these illnesses
for but i don't think i think i'd
ethical twins
and for does iconic fraternal twins
concordance rate simply means
death warrants win
as a particular illness
what's the likelihood that the other
twin is also going to have illness and
what i want you to see here is
that even for a major mental illness
like schizophrenia that concordance rate
is remarkably low
okay
if when twin has schizophrenia
there's only about a thirty eight
percent chance that the other twin will
also have schizophrenic
same thing four
all occurred before at for affect a
disorder on two major depression
depressive illness
if won't win has depression
forty percent will be a forty percent
chance that the other twin will have
depression
here from all installed bipolar disorder
so-called manic-depressive illness
but even better
the concordance rate is far from one
hundred percent
presumably in these three forms of
mental illness
part of the dialysis is generic in
nature
that there is some kind of hereditary
factor that his accounting ford that
that is
disposing people filter this form of
mental illness
that genes are not
decisive
because individuals who are genetically
identical
can be very different from each other
with respect to whether they actually
terry are the disease
are you have an example
where it appears to be the case
that there is a genetic factor
we don't know exactly what it is
actually we don't have any idea what it
is
there's a bit
bogged evidence like this strongly
suggests
that there is a genetic factor
that will leave individuals at with
for schizophrenia
or at risk for bipolar disorder
or at risk for depressive or a disorder
because it
what makes a difference here
apparently
the different environments
in which these individuals
or car or a living
so what kinds of unfolded and all
environmental factors all might there be
it turns out
that there is a good relationship
between socioeconomic status and
schizophrenic suggesting that
no distress associated with low
socioeconomic stratos
but there's no socioeconomic status
alm orthotic people
all
this in people with schizophrenia
there is the history of copied failures
profound loss is profound frustrations
again
of stress factor
itself is insufficient to cause
schizophrenia
but which may come back in with a
genetic diagnosis to lead to ons gov
august of episode
similarly family mala jostled
and our communication deviance within
the family
are these are all environmental
contributions
they don't have anything to do with the
gene
or they they seem to be environmental
factors in the background of many
schizophrenic patients that seemed to
precipitate
are beyond beyond set
all of the of the illness
here's another example
not the flat major
our foremost mental illness and harrison
conduct order disorder
all right this is work by upshaw i'm
casting at the university of london all
and his soul and his colleagues
who are interested
in the interaction of dialysis and
stress
leading to
antisocial behavior disorder conduct
disorder
in the auto invoice
and they suggested on the basis of there
are the bear analyses
that there's a particular gene
particular for became known as the
n_r_a_ all a gene
which promotes
arm a particular of horrible modeling
oxidase okay
that
deficits factor of judah genetic
diagnosis factor
for all pretty social or the behavior
disorder
at that
this gene in another seth is not
sufficient
closed conduct disorder to occur
rather
face although the proposed
individuals caryn this genetic dialysis
if they're exposed to
or higher levels of stress like a
history of not all of our of
maltreatment
that that would be a dof
of the pushed and pushed the child over
the edge
org into
into a syndrome of antisocial behavior
disorder that they're actually able to
study this
on in new zealand
well it in a daughter that authority
group of
more than a thousand new zealand or
their children
because of the vote in new zealand
health system works
these kids recess
or every other year
from the time they were three
until they work
well into into their twenties
and watch has been his colleagues did
when i was too
duet genetic analysis
and determine wider these
children
bad of particular version of the nato a
gene or not
and then also
on assess the history of maltreatment in
the family
and then determined whether any of these
kids
actually met the diagnostic criteria
for adolescent
disorder
here are the results of the study
physically to levels
the so that the their children
were classified
unter meserve two levels of m_ a_ l_ a_
activity
low levels were high levels
and then they were also classified in
terms of their exposure
altered mental history of maltreatment
at dot at home
where they had no limit
or maybe some or very very severe
and you've got here
the number the percentage five children
with various combinations of and they
have a activity and a history of stress
the percentage of them
that actually allowed deadly diagnosis
about a less than conduct disorder and
that you see here
is a perfect example rb interaction or a
diagnosis and stress
well levels
bible elliott activity
that's the dialysis factor that's
carried on the jeans
combined
with so history of severe
maltreatment
eighty five percent of those kids will
end up with a diagnosis of adolescent
conduct disorder
here heart children with that
buddies but exactly the same two that i
think that this is low levels of a daily
activity
levels of maltreatment
and watch
lower
likelihood of actually developing
conduct disorder
are individuals with high levels of the
railway activity
and even when they're exposed to
severe
levels of maltreatment
at home
thirty all likelihood of actually
having allison conduct disorder is
relatively low
it's the specific avaricious
combine
this any specific stress
that leaves
the illness
low levels of their own if you don't
have the dialysis
you're very unlikely to get the illness
but even if you've got the diagnosis
only if you're exposed to
high levels of stress
the adolescent conduct disorder on
actually all occur
on here is another example again from
test these laboratories are very very
active all of the laboratory
but even at the
the upon diagnostic category does major
depressive illness
and they had a all hypothesis
that the specific gene known as five h t
t
albeit it is implicated in the on and
the price of all the details
all again
on it so it's involved with m_e_l_
homes and
again they didn't think that
the genetic it padberg
diagnosis was decisive
rather the genetic
endowment interacts with a history of
stressful life events they thought
to produced by
alot to produce
depressive illness
a case like dead at the same kind of
study
but they didn't then they went to the
debate in the cargo study
assessed
the dialup the uh...
give the individuals in terms of their
genetic endowment
this gene five h t t dean
or comes in basically
four forms
powerdvd get consider member get two
chromosomes
two shorts
or shorten along along in a short
or to lawrence
also did
hurt dot org
individuals who've got at least one
short only all of the five h t teaching
here individuals who don't have any of
the short a little
and i think that we counted the number
of stressful events
experienced by these individuals
from the ages of twenty one to twenty
six
and then determine
whether they were depressed at age
and hear are the results of this
prayer individuals with the short
version but the five h_d_t_v_ genotype
that is they're tearing at her one
or two
short oleoyls of the gene
here are individuals who are carrying
the lawn
version of the five h_d_t_v_
arjuna type
and no or other classified as well in
terms of
harmony stressful events the experience
during that five year period
known
three were for
and that once again what the pattern is
like
the short version of the five h_d_t_v_
dean
appears to be a genetic diagnosis
fork the passion
that carry majhi nh does not
bomb
mean necessarily that you're going to
get depressed
it's or delete this genotype
even combination with high levels of
stress
but notice
that if your ex if you're exposed to
high levels of stress
but you've got the loan
version of the five h_t_t_p_
you're no more likely to become
depressed that if you've got no stress
at all
is these specific interaction
other particular genetic endowment with
any history off stress that leads to
part of that that leads to depressive
illness
are better able
excellent example
also beat out advancers stress of the
model
both doesn't distrust model inaction
then they are
again this is from of the kathy's poem
or laboratory
or if you know we have to have the
simpsons trusted pathological showing
its
this is not just normal shyness the
citadel
really
withdrawn
are part of the heart of the inhibition
of the presence of strangers
and again that that the farthest
etiology
was implicated part in this
also they are going to assess
the president's all of the short version
b_-five h_d_t_v_ or a gene
and then looked at all agreed that these
individuals in terms of
in terms of social support
in their family environment
here is
pattern of
shyness
here we have
high levels of the haber lynnette or in
addition very very high levels
of although the showings
low levels ovr shyness fear and the
level of social of support
look at the pattern of results
if you're carrying the the short
version of the farthest e_t_ gene and
you have a low levels of social support
you know very unlikely
fitted to develop pathological shyness
but if you've your terrain short
version of the gene
but you've got very strong social
support in your family and in your
neighborhood
you're no more likely to develop
pathological shyness all of them dot
than anybody else
similarly
if you've got the war
version all of the gene
even if you're in or very poor
social environment
very low levels of social support
you're not going to
or score high in behavioral innovation
it's a specific
lakshman
between genetic diagnosis
and sawmill form alva larval
all blown though
between genetic biographers
and some kind of stress or
well social support
marv albert history of maltreatment
history of stress or whatever
but this is how the day after so
stressed model all works
here is another version from the same of
from the same study
people terrain
short version of the gene
much at risk
the arm
for pathological shriners
when the gene
is combined with low levels volvo
of social support
this is the way it goes
all the way all of them that this is the
way it goes all the way along
or finish the thought next time
dot i want to just prepare you
because usually we think about that the
system data battles and stress as bad a
logical and environmental respectively
that dialysis is always something like a
gene
and distress or
is always something in the social
environment that's not necessarily the
case
and i'll make that point
on monday
thank you very much
have a good weekend