okay but return to our consideration of personality
social interaction
but before we do that
let me remind you that there's of second determine
this class next week
on Wednesday the fourteenth
on ordinarily I do exams on Wednesday send
in class reviews on mondays
but Monday it turns out to be a holiday and
that has really screwed up the schedule on
of completely
also we're going to have a look upon changes
here
first they detonated scheduled for next Wednesday
November fourteenth
it'll cover all the material that we've been
working on all
since the last lecture
the betrayal of memory
on what and language and on personality and
social interaction
but order on the schedule we cut it in class
review sessions scheduled for Wednesday
it's just too soon you not ready for a think
let's review session on
oh a week before the exam I know that
on randy sides are usually do for lectures
on personal and social interaction
and it's just too much to try to compress
it different
well instead of going and let's review one
Wednesday this week
all we're going down have of fourth lecture
on personality and social interactions said
and I'm going to provide on a court web site
you written all review narrative to go along
with love with the modified flights that worked
out really well let's line
exam scores were very good
though all going to make that the in practice
well remember there are lots of reports that
three times the rate in review fashion will
go up on the web site all
of whereby Thursday only further than that
a study guide for the glide impact is available
for you
all sorts of materials on the on a court web
site
and in addition
if you had any questions about any of the
material in lecture or the readings for the
course
you can't police those questions forum on
a quote on a court web site
and i'll get to it and for very very quickly
within twenty four hours
the deadline for both of those questions is
do it on Tuesday the thirteenth but the day
before the them
on if you have any questions the role
just put them to the the forum on a court
web site
and will get the ball
we'll get the majority
on the ground format famous before fifty both
of which were after this ball
computer scoring it down
all right we have a road directly from the
lectures rock we have drawn from the pact
on it and you need to bring in one of those
raids can't run forms that we talked about
on people
and a couple of number two pencils
that's what this can't run for a look like
two different sides
though many questions about what going to
do
we're not gonna read in session on Wednesday
the polls they would review instead
deborah going to have a fourth
lecture on personality and social interaction
any questions about that yet
well these are not committed to the midterms
are gone through with it
though
what we've been covering since the last mid-term
is the work of memory
thinking language
personally and social interaction at them
on
the final exam however is cumulative and walk
over
anything else about this
when yes
the on know the appendix remember called is
going to be tested a on bell final exam
but again it's just the material things the
last mid-term
what language
person on air force one correction
they'll have a chance to this later knowledge
of the statistical appendix on the %uh on
the phone with them
okay last time we focused on what I call the
dialect it between a person and his or her
behavior
on the one hand
how
personal actor the youth of the individual
his or her trade said attitudes
leave the person to behave in particular way
but also how the individual's behavior
the back
touche
and change the characteristics of the individual
him or herself
and now what we want to do
don't you think that model you look at the
next
by elected
the diet elected between the environment
and behavior
how features of the environment
shape the behavior that occurred the night
in borrowing
and then hollow
the behavior that occurs and the environment
and the back
to change
the environment
on it fell
well first let's look at the influence of
the situation for the environment on behavior
here is a classic
demonstration and social psychology
of social influence on behavior
mcdermott by phone and hash no now defeat
all
on nonconformity
what after it was to present with objects
with a
but that ordinary simple looking perceptual
pat
it showed on the a standard line like that
line day
and then they come the onset of three comparison
lines one
to and three
and the subjects path with earthly to identify
which comparison line
once the famous in line
as the standard line
very simple
and of course
if the sometimes
all the dust beyond beyond judgment was
but easy one as it is in this case
other times the judgment was a little bit
more difficult
but it's a very very straightforward task
what action that dead
what's true very the conditions of testing
well the subjects
performed that have
working on loan in a laboratory room so they
were isolated
and other thought it
were all would perform its past
the and by a group setting
where there are a number of subjects he did
around the young around the table
now the front it was cold
that these other individuals to deter on the
table
were college students just like himself
work more
on undergraduate back when actually that swarthmore
college
bomb but in fact
everybody else around the table with a confederate
all of the experimenter
they were referred to suspend
for following a script that had been prepared
why did her mentor
all for it all for for them to all of for
them to follow
and what did what did that
on the phone trials
they had not been rendered a judgment
that was the one that a mostly opposed
own judgment
well here
it's pretty obvious that
comparison want to
it's the same the line as of as the standard
line
the thought it would say I think it's going
to
and all the other subject
with day
I think it's line three
or by the or the thing I think is what one
then there are some trials
the confederates announced their judgment
for
and the subject went wild
and the object of the experiment
what's the city
whether the subject weather and under what
circumstances
the object would
could before
judgments of the other subject
and and make and ever
in on in his own in his perception
here are the basic results of the experiment
when
subjects are wrong alone they rarely made
an error
okay that almost always identified that the
of the correct person
however
when they were run with one another individual
who occasionally made in a row and his judgment
the error rates increase
if they are wrong with two water individuals
occasionally made a row his judgment
but subjects
all conforming responses increase
but I think we've got to be
three or four were fifteen other people
conformity increased quite a bit
well here
three all other people in the room unanimously
taking the wrong line
well as the answer
the subject of the is good for me with their
on of judgment
about thirty five
the time
this isn't a factor on the environment on
behavior
okay
but what and what's happening here
is that the objects
response
is being the dorm be be determined
by the behavior of other people in the room
even when they are judgment or wrong
if there are enough other people the rule
making that judgment
the subject
is conforming
on on there
for their role in his judgment
but what's going on here
is there is an effect on the environment
number of other people in the room who are
making that judgment
on the subject and the
to and four
there is another version
of what the on at the ash conformity experiment
they are the subject is on a difficult test
in a nice elation
or they're tested allies court of a of of
a group of seven
and what else did and that's one
only in this version the experiment
bond funds subject on from trials
the confederates arguing that honestly oppose
the subject
they unanimously give wrong
on other trials
the majority of the group
it is the wrong answer
but there is anything though this center
we thought we would get the would give the
correct judgment
hello again
here's the standard blood
the correct answer is to
on here
on fix of the thump thump trials
but from the Fed and
object will
of the six with them and confederate will
they warning three
but one of the confederates will day
the warning to
they were the results of that it's burning
when the
confederates or unanimous
in their own his judgment
the subject will conform to adopt five
well detroit
however if there is
what's the single the center
that's the thing will defend for from the
all from the view of the majority
and for me
drop down
to a very low level about five percent of
the trial
here is a perfect of the situation
on behavior
the object is much more likely to conform
when confronted with the EU and that about
but the unanimous majority
on if there's even just the fabled the Fed
just the the presence of just the federal
defender in the group
if the bill
should we do
the of conformity
but to a baseline level
there is another burst of this experiment
on performed by age are prepared for charlotte
bennett
here at the university of California
little bit different path
the public for that you
on making judgments of color
they're presented with little color patches
and they were asked to determine
whether the patch was
your blue
or whether a with a mixture own lou
and well
agree
there were filled with the phone to providers
the naive subject the group
and the way it is sad for me to set up the
patches are usually blue your blue
that with the usually say
and then
in the group
they're either there's one two four confederate
who wrongly George
the package
to be who green
what we want to know if
under what circumstances will the subject
we're obviously a doll
and for him to
the of wrote his judgment of the party
and you can see here
that when
on
object to what alone there's very little
and for many
when the earth
a minority of one
not too much
and for many
nor did to
not too much conformity
three people don't think that move green
the subject
the ferry its blue green
in fact it's blue
and that's with objects with a if they were
running low
these are classic
the thought of experiments
all demonstrating the power all the situation
on behavior
the are influence
five of a majority
groups allies and group unanimity
on the behavior
on the subject
here is another
all a demonstration of the effect of the environment
on behavior
our ashes the experiments had to do with osha
lynn Martin and
this is authority that has to do with the
physical environment
and this is bonnie anderson nineteen eighty
nine
in which is simply plotted the race of violent
crime
murder and rape
on
as a function of season
and what you can see here
is that the rate of violent crime
those up
respectively in the farmer
and falls off
in the winter
on much less violent crime occurs in the winter
beth over
this is an environmental effects
there's something about the summer that brings
out mayhem
on in people
don't know exactly what it is
all black
the big the difference whether it's winter
reformer
the on of the ambient temperature whatever
warm or cold
%uh of on of whether crime is going to occur
or not
what more example of very famous example of
the influence of the environment of behavior
has to do with what's known in social psychology
is the frustration aggression by up with
also you know a problem that goes back a long
ways in psychology
what John dollar debt you melor
well I had an idea
aggressive behavior
fighting of various kinds
what is in fact a brief like serb response
to what they called frustration
they do find frustration
any off the cold the goal completion so there's
something you want
and that
that desire is frustrated
a reflexive response to frustration is aggression
interview
I had some experiments that suggested that
thought that that was right
but there were some problems with the all
all that with the experimental results
we need to everybody should
all of the frustration aggression of the
five-letter berkowitz at the yale university
all of all of Wisconsin
and ongoing work with
we buy
the original frustration aggression that office
that a couple of different ways
first to broaden the definition of political
frustration
refer to
and the of birth of a band
that is
perceived as intentionally harmful
well if somebody
both of them to you
and makes you feel bad
as long as you perceive that think if anybody
was intentionally you that that's what berkowitz
called frustration
but more important
work with argued that aggression was not a
brief like the respond
to to frustration
remember that reflexes
our response is that occur
regardless of the details on be a book in
third
a burqa with that
that's just not true
in the first place
all aggression occurs in response to frustration
only when the person is angry
okay
and is more much more likely to occur as the
response to frustration
when the environment
contains a lot of
the generational came with that deal with
that were suggest aggressive response
and work with them ran an experiment
off a missive permit on what's known as the
weapons the fact
the demonstrate
it was the young influence of situational
pews
on on
on %uh of aggression
on again and typical social psychological
form
a object of naive subject
at a confederate of the experiments were
were brought altogether and all you know that
it makes for a better world
and the on what the subjects were told
was that the they would be working with his
partner
they were told it was a confederate of its
permit are they were told it was just another
college student
they're going to work on problems
and then
after they were of the problems for a while
they be given an opportunity to evaluate each
other's performance
and we're never going to balance it out and
performance be good
all of this for a second
by deliberate electrical shock
on to the job
these subjects got to deliver one to ten electrical
shock through the partner
the Pentagon is the valuation of his performance
and a partner or was able to on do the same
thing
the experiment was arranged
well that the confederate always evaluated
the subject for
but the confederate
the liver a number of electrical shock through
the thought that these are not life-threatening
electrical shock
not like what you do when you
what you get when you stick your finger on
walls market
all what their rubber stamp
all of shock
and the confederate
but neither did the subject one shock which
was
pretty good
or seven shocks
which was intended to make the subject
angry
and then the subject was given the opportunity
to evaluate the confederate in turner
by retaliated against the confederate by delivering
a number of shock
again
the subject
he's getting on newshour
irv punishment is getting federal electrical
shock
okay
that's going to make him angry
and now
on he gets to retaliate
but the wrong if any man
is decorated in one of two ways
in one condition of the experiment
the on the room is decorated with sports equipment
badminton rackets
there is a yellow there's a bed that night
and that on the table
they're bad that in all one of those things
called bernie's okay
well hang it around
in the other conditions its permit
there are drugs everywhere
in the room
that I shot gun on the Wall there's a revolver
behind the bookcase fell be beyond the glass
case
on all court them
and across quo in the room if I remember correctly
all sorts of things going on to win on
and what work with the really interested in
what does the subject to
the pending on the room at the subject
is it
and what happens here
is that
in a controlled conditions
okay
with under very good control condition of
the subject for not anger
there is very little
all aggression directed
towards the confederate by the subject
however
when the subject our anger
there's a lot more aggression directed toward
the subject
they're the giving the beginning the confederate
five shots on average as opposed to close
to the two or three
shocked on average
the all
the amount all aggression
it's increased
when
the subject is in President all weapons
but suppose
the bandits equipment
well anger
it was said
aggression
but anger illicit more aggression
when they're a situational humans
two
all of the data to an aggressive response
if there's what's known as the weapons the
fact
and like the ashford four minutes per man
it is a classic demonstration
of the power of the situation
the control behavior
people are
more aggressive when they're angry
and when they're not
that's a personal the permanent
all behavior
you know when they're angry
I'm much more likely to address against the
one
if their or
situational Q
to aggressive response
it's been a delight this
that makes people worried about
the relation between media depictions of violence
and actual of the violent behavior
on the park old war of people
the idea that
there's a lot of violence in the environment
that's going along with that
on the violent behavior
role model from the people in that
the board
here is one more
on demonstration of the effect of the environment
on behavior
this is another classic and social psychology
known as the helping experiment
all budge on darlington be able at night
on darling of Latin a all brought subject
in to the laboratory
for a very straightforward experiment
in which they were simply stated in at a table
in a deal in a little room
and that's the film out a number of paper
and pencil question here
that was it
from the point of view
all of the %uh of the subject
but the figures seated
when the individually alone in the room
or they were seated with other people they
were given a packet of personal the questionnaires
the to fill out
and her mother left the room
on on thing no of the nearby know it can be
done it
after the experimental leave the room
there is a staged emergency
in one condition of the experiment
harmless vote
Paul begala of the start filtering into the
room through a ventilator
on chat
our in the other of of version of the instrument
all after the thought it would work in for
a little while
they hear an enormous crash
from a nearby room
and then the person holding out
I think I've broken my way
the object of its permit is this the whether
people will actually doing something
in response to that emergency
and smoke is going through the ventilator
chapel that to get up and do something of
a that
when they hear the crash of a person's they
help by broken my way
will they actually go to render assistance
the of results of the experiment were quite
were quite dramatic
when subjects were alone in the room
they were very likely
assistant
or to read and think assistance in the case
of the smoke
or render assistance in the case on the on
advocates of the crash
however
when thought its work
it'd in a group
of individuals
barry
on likely to do anything about the we just
sat there
well the smoke was coming in through the bentley
here
and on is a little bit more healthy behavior
in the foot version of the experiment
but Phil
all
when the all
leon forty percent of the cajuns
well did did the subject
and the help
but here again
we have an illustration
of the effect on the environment on
behavior
in the that permits
people were
much more likely
to help if they were alone
and when other people were in the room
in these experiments
the presence of other people actually the
presence of other people the environment
actually deterrent
helping behavior
oh that's thousand always happened
on top and
the president's of other people the environment
can
the silicon
behavior
here it is
all that experiment on run by Brian and pass
of the dog and never to abortion for the experiment
first looking back she conducted on California
highway one the pacific coast highway
all where a yellow of of you know college
student
was of station
well by the side of the road
with a call or with obviously flat tire
she's just
this in nineteen sixty seven that the back
before
opal psychologist on women could change the
world powers
on but on the cotton curtain and got understand
the time here
all quarter mile up the road
there was
another person
with a car all pulled over to the side of
the road
and they obviously flat player
but there was also an the another driver
would stop the help that person
and the question is here
I don't what the effect of observing one person
help another
on people's
and at the
you want to help
there is another a lot more on Monday in a
burst of the expert
by the expert on earth about the salvation
army christmas catalog the kind of fee and
on between thanksgiving and christmas
and the subject for coming across
people just ordinary people were coming across
the parking lot
the idea of the expert or arranged or
but when to very conspicuously put money
the and the donation
of their cattle
and then the question is
what's the effect
on this modeling
on other people
the
the building
here or the on
but the results of the experiment
when there is no model
people were very unlikely
the stop and help
the woman bit
the flat player
when there was a lot
quarter mile up the road
twice as likely
to %uh to hell
when there's no model
people
the salvation of donated to the salvation
army cattle only about fifty percent of the
time
but when there was a model
for donation
model leone the donations went up
to about seventy five percent of the poor
again
this is an affect on the environment on behavior
the presence of other people
and what other people were doing
those are pictures on the environment
of fact
the behavior
of people
in that environment
the literature of social psychology it is
on demonstrations
all of these
situational
or environmental
all of fact on behavior
when you go through
the social psychology chapters of gleckman
you all see that
the again the the young the young traditional
model for social psychology is is being numb
what do you call it here
get away from aspect of the environment
and see what the effect of that manipulation
is
on the subject
but it's a also the case
that the behavior of of people
changes
the environment in which that behavior takes
place
instead of looking just at the effect of environment
on behavior
let's look at the research ripple effect
all the if you're
on the environment in which should take place
and we'll be getting that examination
on
address the confederation of something that
you remember for all learning
remember we a talked about instrumental or
off
behavior
in our discussions of learning
and if you think about it for a second
instrumental and operate behavior
changes the environment in which that behavior
explain
when thorndike's at
press
panel inside the puzzle box
that behavior
change the environment
from one in which the box was closed
to one in which
the box
that behavior
changing the environment and permitting the
state
when PF getter
or changes for pigeons
or rats to get a palette of who would if they
press the ball or that cokie
but behavior
of Pakistan
or press in a bar
changes the environment
well one in which
food is unavailable
to one in which
it's available
already
in our discussion of learning
we've seen how behavior could change the situation
of their remaining of instrumental behavior
is that
it'll be here
it changes the of changes in situations though
that view
organism
instead of flying from kind of me
family
and what we're going to talk about know
we want you know what you think about that
person
as a part of of the situation
persons in situations are not a separate if
you buy in of that as you might think
whatever the person dawes in the environment
it's going to change the character
all of that environment
the they're going to change it for other people
in the environment
change it
for him
or for
well if we go back to darlene let me
on helping
of of experiment
number the basic result of disability
was that people were much more likely to help
when they're alone
that may all or
on what when they're tested in the president's
of the group
and the question here is
what is that about being in a group
it's first
helping the leader
why shouldn't that but the fact that people
are a group
all of them make it
even less likely
that they will kill
in the case of emergency
darling of Latin a offered a it's an interesting
analysis of the situation
in terms of a concept
but they called pluralistic ignorance
is that what
the fact of the matter is
that even these to the test in situations
were from what and did you want
okay there's the local who are coming in through
a ventilation duct
but it's not clear whether that's not just
that kind of temporary situation the risk
of a clear out very quickly
or whether it's something that you really
have to worry about
yes there was a crash and there's somebody
asking for help
but this is a busy laboratory building there
are lots of people around
all maybe she doesn't need our help
maybe somebody is already on of helping
but what happens
is that what works
faced with an ambiguous situation
it is not true role
to wait
the thing that that ambiguous situation
clara fall
that decide that you waited
in audience away
and one of the ways we do that is by look
at other people the fee what they do
if you're walking through a park
on a of and audit in berkeley
and you think through kids
whiting
together
men have an actual and if you want to want
to break the fly at all
but you're also going to look around
the %uh
their parents are there
the take responsibility
we're going to look at the fight for a while
to see that the theory is fighters the visitors
horseplay of of among some kid
that situation is very ambiguous at the outset
you want to try to clarify it
for a while
no put yourself in a situation of barley and
let me thank you
you're in a group
%uh ostensible emergency is occurred
you don't know how there is an emergency it
is
well what do you do
you wait for a couple of minutes
what everybody else in the room doing
they are doing exactly what you are doing
they're waiting
for a couple of minutes
you are looking at that for clue
they're not the one that either
they're looking at you for clue
you're not doing anything
the fact that nobody is behaving the fact
that nobody is responding to the situation
hope that the fight that situation
as not an emergency after all
well here
all were nobody really knows what's going
on
the fact that nobody is is is on is responding
helped to define the situation as not an emergency
lack of action is the behavior
no what of action in a situation
change is the definition of the situation
from one being
the potential of merchants the
the one being
a on
so about on non emergency or whatever
that goes for the
modeling situation as well
people are driving down California highway
one
and they see somebody stopping to
help somebody changes of of the the change
of heart
the behavior of that model
it is changing the situation threatening of
for everybody else in that situation
showing that
it's possible that help
you ought to help or whatever
bottles behavior
is changing the situation
for other people
well here again
we have a case
the if you're in a situation
changing that situation
here it is another example all be reciprocal
all that of the environment the so-called
relation between
the environment and behavior
this is politics
why in the back room