okay
highbeam discussed these physical basis
of the mind and our brain
and the rest of the nervous system
were not on a position to talk about
what it is that the line dollars
and
it turns out that a major function of
the mind is to acquire
and use knowledge
too
produced adaptive behavior of various
crimes
what organisms to especially human
beings
is we are quieter
knowledge in the form of
various kinds of mental representations
of the world around us
so we need to forum internal
representations of the world
that's the job of perception
store it
stories representations for later use
that's the job of memory
too
reflect on and transform and manipulate
this knowledge
that's what goes under the rubric called
on the reasoning and problem solving and
twenty mintues fighting and choosing
we use this knowledge
in or behavior
what's known in the traders are chin
and then we communicate
this knowledge to other people
using the medium
language
so
major functional blindness to engage in
these climate of operations
to mediate
adoptive all of the here
or to mediate
munir actions between the individual
and
the world
traditionally
this knowledge was construed in terms of
associations
associations of various kinds
first our associations among events
that is
all associations on
boa between events that occur in the
environment
and between the all of these events in
the organisms response to them
but also associations between the
organisms actions
and there are facts on the environment
so if you're president gauges and some
piece of behavior
what happens in at the world outside
these are the kinds of associations that
formed the basis or traditional views of
learning
and uh... and thinking
it turns out
that some of these association some of
these stimulus response associations
or innate
their pre wired
they calm as part all of the organisms
endowment
and we usually think about there being
three general types
all of the d_n_a_ responses to
stimulation
the first of these that we've discussed
before
are simple reflexes
that involve individual muscles example
we discussed before was the patellar
reflex
refute tap the patellar tendon
knee-jerk
our response
uh... that's in innate reflex it's the
wave my nervous system and yours too
is owner is built but there are lots of
these is our repertoire another of
one that you'll see a lot of reference
to
is the idyllic reflex
when you go to your ophthalmologist rear
or or your optometrist
after annual audit sam what he or she
will often do is bob
prajam pick as a little machine the
presents a puff of air
to your accordion
and there's a natural response to blink
onto that puff of air
that's an innate reflex
nervous systems wired to do that
all reflexes
are very simple stimulus response
associations
that are in it
and they involve the activity of
individual muscles
single muscles a single set of muscles
in the iva produces the i believe reflex
there's a single set of muscles in the
heart attacks is d patellar tendon
that all produces all of the patellar
reflex
both reflexes
are we also have taxis
okay
the singular is taxes
and these are innate stimulus response
patterns
that involve the entire body involve the
entire
skeletal musculature
all of the organism
also that the organism
basically move
in response
the psalm
stardom to some stimulus or another
we generally think of taxis is coming
into congress
positive taxis
where the organism moves toward some
stimulus
negative
taxis
where the organism moves away
stimulus
and there are all
also
photo taxis which are orientation
responses to light if your route on your
back yard after dark and you've got a
candle going or sell or a flashlight or
whatever
almost will tend to move toward the
light
they're just plain a positive
photo taxes they're moving toward
alight stimulus
on some of the invertebrates
worms and things like that can find in
your garden
we all engage in what's known as a
negative
geo taxes decline up things
okay
so they are orienting negatively
towards the stimulus
of oval of gravity
intial
wermer something will encounter a
barrier
that wouldn't all
okay and try to try to go over
taxis are also very simple stimulus
response connections
but in contrast to reflexes
they involve the entire skeletal
musculature or pretty much the entire
skull musculature
all of the organism
and you see these taxis
all felt prominently in the behavior of
invertebrate organisms blogs
of various crimes
and then finally we have more complex
innate stimulus response connections
are known as instincts
or fixed action patterns
these are innate patterns of behavior
that are shaped by a pollution
on to help the organism
audience of orthodox to a particular
requirement
are like reflexes and taxis
they can be very very complicated
okay
on
very complicated patterns
of stimulus and response
here is all it'd be a good example
on food bedding
inherent goals
this is work by nico ten bergen won the
nobel prize
for this work very important in the
history
also ecology and behavior
on herring gull checks baby erin goals
can't feed for themselves they have to
be fed by their parents
and the role of the wave parents to
those who love the way the adult bogdan
goals do this
is by
we graduate eighteen pre digested food
into d'amato of the uh... i'll be out of
the check
are but they don't do this naturally
look at what they do that they would
actually but they don't do it
all or what what about ically
instead
the uh... dot herring goal
cong
thieves the herring gull checked all
leave wednesday
engages in what's known as a food
begging response
by packing
that a
reddish or orange reddish spot
on the lower mandible of the adult
so what happens is there's a adult
there's a check
the check will
the all lower mandible of the uh... of
the adult
and the dogged old will
respond by
delivering food into with a mild of the
check
the cheque is responding to the presence
of
spots on the mandible
and to be dulled is responding to the
ordered don't go to the goal check
if the check doesn't bag it doesn't get
fed
okay
but as ten bergen found out
that chick does and peg unless there's
an appropriate really seems phyllis in
the environment
here's an experimental ten bergen did
in which the looked at the all food
begging behavior
all checks
when they were presented with on adult
with a
usual
of red orange red spot on the lower
mandible lots of food begging behavior
here the all adults
had their of spot painted black
okay
are just it's removable rate but it was
painted black and the chicks still
packed allot store begged for food
when the v_ bill was painted blue
they also
are begged for food quite a bit
but when the bill was painted white
remember that herring gold bills are
kind of yellow wheat
on you'll see a too much there's less
of begging behavior
and when there's no spot when the
when the spots been painted so that it
blends right into of the bill
there's very little baking behavior at
all
so the relief instead he was four
of the four foot begging on the part of
the check
turns out to be
are contrasting spot on the lower
mandible
it doesn't really matter what color it
is as long as there's a contrast as long
as there is dark against are
as long as a stark against white
the animal all day
but notice that this is now a very
complicated sequence of behaviors
but check
has to beg
the adult has to have the right feature
on its bill
if the adult doesn't have the right
feature the check isn't going to bed
if the check doesn't bag
then the chickens and gonna get fed this
is a characteristic feature
all these instinct for fixed action
patterns
that they usually involved
are very
discriminative responses to stimulation
with the patellar tendon reflex
it doesn't matter what you hit my
patellar tendon with
it can be a hammer like my doctor does
it could be a book
it could be an automobile it could be
anything you hit my patellar tendon with
and all responded megs actually the same
way
but here
there's got to be that contrasting spot
or nothing happens and it's gotta be
responded to with a pack
nothing on nothing happens
so these in haiti
behavioral responses
discriminative all those stimulation
are shaped by your pollution and the
point here is the point i made last time
too
that apparently evolution shapes more
than body morphology
evolution also can shape
patterns of behavior
all permitting
all various species to adapt
to their environmental neesh
and these
instincts were fixed action patterns
built-in viable lucien
are fine
they allow organisms to live in their
particular environmental nations that
works fine so long as the environment
doesn't change
but when the environment changes
this behavior that's been slowly shaped
by evolution over
the alliance of evolutionary time
ten column to be malad apto
very good example of this
is all a positive photo taxes in baby
sea turtles you've all seen this on
nature programs and lynn martin and
television
on sea turtles female sitter rolls come
up
onto the ashore
orbit
dig a nast above the tide line in which
they
deposit their regs and they go back out
to see and do whatever it is too liberal
on sea turtles do
the of the baby sea turtles when they
hatch what they end up doing to crawl
out of the nest
and they run
to the seas so that they can start
swimming
on doing all those other things that sea
turtles or are supposed to be doing
now it turns out
although
that these babies theater roles are not
actually running toward the sea
what they're running toward
is the light of the moon reflected upon
the water
it is a positive
follow taxes they're running toward
a source of light
and that's fine
all
so long as there is and that the other
source of light around
but in modern society there are often
lots of other sources of light on the
beach
there might be automobiles on the beach
there might be a loyal refinery nearby
there might be a hotel or a casino
nearby
and what will happen is
the sea turtles well-run towards those
lights
as well
and if they run pride they happen to run
toward the sea everything works out
hunky-dory for the sea turtle
but if the if the turtle ads are running
for the oil refinery or the casino or
the all-terrain vehicle that just
happens to have its lights on at that
moment things are going to go very well
for the of them for the sea turtle and
so that creates a serious thought threat
ought to
to the species okay
so what happens now
is that also this example illustrates
some rb
limitations
all of these innate responses to
stimulation
represented by
fixed pattern action patterns
in order for the instinctual behavior to
occur
this stimulus must be physically present
in the environment
for the baby and for the sea turtles to
run to the sea the mood has to be out
there has to be
arap actual moon whose light is
reflected on the water for the herring
gull check to get food there has to be a
contrasting spot
on the all lower mandible
volvo be adult
the second point is
bibd because sleeves on
these are two
behavioral responses these instinctual
behaviors
had been shaped by a balloon shin
the organism isn't capable by virtue of
these innate response patterns
to respond to a new stimulus
is not the guarded
the eve the stimulus is their or it
isn't
on
you can't have
on conservation workers steady note by
the sees a huge hurdle here hurdle come
this way you know they just can't
respond to that at all
put another way
these organisms
by virtue of agreed individual organisms
art and acquire new responses to
stimulus
this response pattern has been built-in
byob aleutian it's pretty wired
and they're not able they're not be able
to modify on this in any way
and then finally
there was a little opportunity for trial
and error learning
sea turtles have one shot at the ocean
if they make it ok now might they might
be eaten by a shark or something but
that's another matter but if they don't
make it they don't have any mechanism
for turning around and say opt must go
the other way
now there's a fence here are some they
have no way of all of acquiring all of
those businessman response
know what no opportunity for trial order
learning
the pattern has to work the first time
the individual
isn't going to make it there was a
question here
yall yes ten evolution change the
response yes evolution can change the
response
but not for the individual
okay aid not for the individual
and b
not for the species are either accept or
breaks to really long periods of time
so you can imagine that
although maybe the light reflected from
the moon is a different kind of light
than the light that comes from the
incandescent bulbs with oil refinery or
a hotel okay
and you can imagine
that over
hugely long periods of time
that there is another variation that the
sea turtles of respond to moonlight will
live
and sea turtles the response of casino
lightbulbs lip
but they
that assumes that there were in such
behavioral variability
and b
that assumes that the species will last
long enough
for evolution
to habits
that that the pic its a fact
we're chillin species everyday
by virtue of environmental change
what's the big news besides the iraq war
but polar bears
we're going to see the last polar bear
in the wild in about thirty years of or
not careful
because their environment is changing
and there is out
there's not enough time left over for
barrister discover a taste for bamboo
shoots or whatever it is that they're
going to
i'll have to live on
these instinctual behaviors these fixed
action patterns are very very very
powerful and they're very very important
for n_p_r_ adaptation of the art of the
species to which the bargain
but in addition
to these instinctual behavior patterns
built-in by evolution
we need to have a mechanism
for individuals for individual species
members
tomato fly their responses
the stimulation
and that is what happens
by virtue
learning
traditionally
will revise this definition later
but traditionally redefine learning as a
relatively permanent
change in behavior
errors as a result of experience
or relatively permanent
change in behavior
that occurs as a result of experience
this definition is intended
to eliminate
changes in behavior that occur from the
ingestion of drugs
take some psychoactive drugs or
something i might change your behavior
but that's not learning
change of behavior
that occurs as a result of injury if you
injure your leg and you can't run that's
not learning it's a change in behavior
but style learning and also
on changes in behavior darker just by
virtue of naturally shin
uh... we brutal with those in our own
or definition of learning
all but
all again
there's a change in behavior that
occurred as as a result of experience
all organisms that have nervous system
have at least on capacity to to learn
all laureate learning is especially
important invertebrate
organisms that is organisms that have a
spinal cord and of course it's
especially important
and off
in mammalian species and primate species
like ours
but what kab whatever kind of species
you are
if you've got a capacity to learn
learning permits the individual organism
to acquire
behaviors
under new
circumstances
and allows individual organisms
to ad
behavioral responses
to the environment to whatever
repertoire of stimulus response
or associations
has been given them
by alarmed by evolution
okay so we're not gonna to actually talk
about learning formally
but if they're in equal or questions
about these instinctual behavior is the
zone
fixed action patterns would be happy to
take 'em now anything at all
know the charles to do the turtles come
on daytime no they don't
on the reason they don't is it's too hot
there also responding to
changes in ambient temperature
so it's gonna be
below a particular temperature
and then there's gotta be some
light out of a band that if there is
then they start coming out of their nest
but there's gotta be some kind of light
and fortunately
there's almost always
some kind of moonlight being reflected
on the sea
reports but once a while you might get a
new moon
that's really weak
or lunar eclipse or something like that
by a large it's a pretty good mechanism
very good ya evolution is a very smart
in this way it shape this behaviors of
the animals get to the sea
very good cute of where the c_e_o_s
uh... but it's just not so good anymore
because of these kinds of changes
anything else about these fix action
patterns yes
do humans have any positive
or any kind of taxes at all
we might
probably dole
really
notice
our behavior is covered by lots of other
kinds of processes
or where you see them isn't
invertebrates
well that really
let's be honest ok about an anti moth
person but most don't do much else
except fly toward white
and so you can have noticed that
calm
cockroaches okay
cockroaches have what looks like a
negative photo taxes you'd walk into
your
friend's apartment or something like
that eternal light cockroaches scurry on
art that's what they're bill to do and
date prev pretty much don't do anything
else except
the and run away from late
that what it what but believes the adult
sea turtles to do what they do adds
another instinct entirely
alm
when they're ready to to too
dot drop the regs they come up
on and our it's interesting that
p_p_o_'s b uh... female sea turtle will
calm above the title bout the high tide
line
because of you
two-year-old nest below the tide line
weld the eggs are going to get washed
away so that's another behavior that's
been shaped by your pollution
generation after generation after
generation of female sea turtles
the ones that laid their legs of the lay
their eggs above the high tide line
their progeny survived
and they had a tendency to lay their
eggs about the high timeline
arms as well to kazakhs are the same
thing gritty use that example
except that polite example loves me talk
about
environment change
and there are lots of these instincts if
you want to really wonderful
all of the read some time
look at nico ten bergen's book the study
of instinct that's autor effect pockets
real theft of reading
yes quick
all can you learn from and yes you can
learn from injury of course you can
learn from injury you stick your toe
hand an electrical socket you don't do
that twice
but what we're talking about here is
injury can produce changes in behavior
like a bite
stomp on your foot you've got a limp
around for a while
but the fact that you've got changed
your behavior that's not learning that's
just
the fact that you were injured
we're looking at morning
relatively permanent change of behavior
that occurs as a result of experience
not get a good idea but what i'm talking
about
when i talk about this first form of
learning known as classical conditioning
ok let's go right there
on and
early forward one form of learning
accidentally discovered by a russian
physiologist named yvonne pablo
who was studying the physiology of the
digestive system and dogs
this is work for which pavlov won the
young or old price in physiology and
medicine
and his technique was quite simple
he's confine the dog in this harness so
it could move around
he inserted a fistula little played into
the alm
uh... into the mouth of the dogma
collects elevation
and then they would introduce argue
would introduce into the mouth of the
dog
our drive me powder
on iseries as a result of
reese reflexive response to which the
dog would salivate celebration is a
reflexive response to the introduction
of dry food into are
well into the mouth
and that's what pavlov was studying
initially pavlov's dogs celebrated
all leave when
the powder was actually placed in their
mouth
but as the experiments went on
pavlov noticed that his dogs would start
celebrating before the pollard was
presented
they start celebrating just to the site
of the powder
then they'd starts elevating just to the
site of the experimenter
eventually they'd start celebrating
to the sound of the experimenter coming
down the hall
ought to start on
to start the experiment
dos y_ was what pavlov observed
was that this
reflexive response the stimulation
was also starting to occur
in response to a bands that were in some
way of sociated
with the delivery of food
the site of food the side of the
experimenter the sound of the
experimenter and so on
pavlov
we called these
psychic
reflexes which he didn't mean psychics
like you know
psychics in the yellow pages
but he simply meant
that this was a reflex that occurred to
be idea
of the stimulus
remember how we define reflexes and
uh... and and instance before that the
stimulus has to be physically present in
the environment
pavlov discovered
sometimes the stimulus doesn't have to
be physically present in the environment
the atom of the organism
will all respond
simply to the idea of of the stimulus
and it's the idea of the stimulus that
will blow
a reflexive
responds
this is the basic procedure
for what is now known as classical
conditioning that's pavlov and lots and
lots and lots of other people
on have studied it
so what will happen here
is that in the first phase of a yard
oven elementary classical conditioning
experiment
the on the experiment levees to stimuli
there'll be a bell there'll be some food
and its perimeter will ring the bell
them ring the bell again and maybe put
some food a dog smoke ring the bell
again
maybe bring the bell again put some food
the door as well
all of the just kind of
going off randomly
then in phase two of the experiment
the situation changes so that the
ringing of the battle
is always followed immediately within a
couple seconds
by
presentation of food
to the most of of them of the animal the
dog
and you do that for a number of trials
and then in phase three you take the
food away into entirely
and you just present
the bell and what pavlov discovered
was that on
early trials here in phase two
or where the bell is followed by the
food
not too much celebration occurred but
gradually the animal came to salivate
too
ringing all of the bell so that in phase
three of past royal
your present the bell alone and the
analysts elevating as if rude
had been presented or two
org in its mouth
this is the procedure of classical
conditioning
where the ringing a bell
a stimulus that did not
originally elicit any kind of salvation
comes to elicit
the salivary response
like young
just like the me poner o would have
itself
so this procedure now
illustrates basic vocabulary of
classical conditioning which consists
of
four terms
first with have
the on conditioned stimulus
youn conditions stimulus is a stimulus
that reliably evokes
summary flex
on apart
the organism
on condition stimulus
and environmental event a stimulus
that reliably evokes or reflex on the
part of the organism
presenting drive me powder in the mouth
of a dog
evokes elevation of the reflex
tapping my patellar tendon
reliably evokes
a knee-jerk
reflex
putting bob
putting up off of on air
i get on the cornea of my life
reliably evokes
untie blink reflects so that's the
unconditional staples
the other conditioned response
is dot reflex
that's real liable evoked by
the on conditions stimulus
the celebration
kneejerk response
the idol inc
okay so the unconditionally sponsor is
the reflex itself
the young conditions stimulus is the
event the stimulus event
that elicits
that reflects
then we have the condition stimulus
does not
in another itself
you listed any reflex on the part of the
organism
if you ring a bell
alm i don't celebrate
ordinarily
on by
me doesn't jerk ordinarily my idols and
blanco orderly just blows in
had any effect
on my behavior
if you repeatedly pair
the condition stimulus with the un
conditions stimulus
bail
welll
bell
then what will happen is a precondition
stimulus the bell will come to a vocal
eight conditioned response likes
elevation
that in some respects
resembles
the on condition response
so what happens now is that the
conditioned response is the response
that's evoked by the condition stimulus
after many parents with the un
conditions stimulus
and it's a response
the condition response
usually
resembles the unconditional response
doesn't have to
it usually does so that's the basic
vocabulary
of classical conditioning
and we can use this basic vocabulary now
to work our way through
on some of the on major phenomenal
the first phenomenon of classical
condition one we want to talk about
is acquisition
acquisition is the process
by which
air-conditioned stimulus
acquires the power
to a bloke
are conditioned response
the process by which
a condition stimulus acquires the power
to a vote
air conditioned response
this happens
by virtue of what's known as
reinforcement
reinforcement which in classical
conditioning
simply means the pairing of eight
condition stimulus with a non condition
stimulus
carried a bell food
bell food
dole food
bill from
over and over again
the bill will come to elicit sell a very
alone some kind of celebrant response
in general
we measure the although
acquisition
other conditioned response in terms of
its strength
and there are two
big measures of strength here one is the
magnitude of the condition response
how many drops of saliva
does the animal
in response to the bell
on initial trials not much later trials
lots and lots
condition response is growing in
strength
or we can simply
measure the strength of the condition
response in terms of the probability
that the animal will give up
the condition response
that is the probability that the dog
will celebrate
bomb at all
though that's the acquisition
phase of the kind of goes like that
on the first trial of acquisition
we might
present
a condition stimulus a bell
that rings for a while
and then although that's a little bit
after the onset of the bell
we preserve food
into the most
of the of 'em
of the organism
and what you can see it here this is the
very first trial of acquisition
the animal doesn't respond
when the bell comes on
bike does begin to respond
as soon as the food is presented
this is the reflexive
response to salvation on trial one
there is no
as yet
no response to the bell
then couple more trials ten more trials
maybe
the condition stimulus comes on little
bit later second or two later
the food is presented to the mouth of
the dog
but notice
that now the animal is beginning to
celebrate
after the bell starts ringing
but before the food is presented
this is
first appearance of a conditioned
response a response to the conditions
stimulus
the on condition stimulus
and then
carousel
for some more trials maybe twenty trials
now you can see
the animal is
emailing the conditioned response
immediately after
the onset of the condition stimulus long
before long in these terms
long before the do you know the food has
been given
the acquisition of a conditioned
response
looks
pretty much
like that on the first trial
nothing happens
as trials go on
pairing of the condition stimulus in the
on condition stimulus bill food bell
food bell food
then the will start
responding to the bell as if it were
flute
responding to the bell
because it's been sociated
there is a typical pattern for the
acquisition
all of a
conditioned response
here we have number of trials
here we plotted the probability
soliciting the condition response
celebration or whatever
on early trials not much
conditioned response
gradually
pru reinforcement
condition stimulus acquires
a lot of strength
to elicit the are the condition response
this is acquisition by virtue of the
pairing
of the condition stimulus
the bell
the on condition stimulus
response
so that's what the experts what the
acquisition phase looks like
in acquisition
the condition stimulus acquires the
power to a poker conditioned response
an extension
the condition stimulus
loses
the power to evoke
conditioned response
and it does so
by virtue of the lack of reinforcement
now what we do is we disconnect
link between
the c_s_ and the u_s_ the link between
the bell and the food
so that now
the bells presented but the food stop
presented anymore
bell nothing
and what happens is
conditioned response eventually lose
that strength you have a question over
here
ol okay
well let's see how that
again on extension trial one
first time the bells presented in the
absence of food
the out of the doesn't know the
situations change right
gives a strong conditioned response
after
ten extension trials
condition response
has been weakened ig and we're
presenting the bell but not the food
conditioned response has been weakened
and
after some more extension trials
conditioned response drops out entirely
here's
the pattern
typical pattern by which
on extension occurs and you see it
pretty much the mirror image of of
acquisition on early trials
condition responses very strong and then
gradually weakens loses most of the
strength early
of the
early an extension
and then as extinction trials are
carried on
it drops back through zero for at least
fact before
acquisition
by virtue of reinforcement
the condition stimulus acquires the
power to elicit a conditioned response
extension
by virtue of the lack of reinforcement
the condition stimulus
loses
seem
kind of power
it lou that in a funny way
if an animal acquires a condition
response through reinforcement in the
acquisition phase
and then
that that condition response
disappearance during extinction
if you take the animal out of the test
apparatus pointed put it in its home
page for a while
and then bring it back into the test
apparatus
and just presented with a condition
stimulus just ring the bell
what you're going to see
is some spontaneous recovery
all of the conditioned response
so if you get the animal some rest after
extension
and then a retested with a condition
stimulus alone
you will see
some degree
condition response been given
so that's what we mean by spontaneous
recovery
there haven't been many new acquisition
trials
there been known in trials in which the
s_ and u_s_ have been paired with each
other
it's just that
are conditioned response spontaneously
recovers after only
and so here we go
here's the acquisition phase
the conditioned response growing in
strength
here is the expansion phase
the condition response
bruises strength
now we have an interval of rest
we test
the condition response again
and we see that
there is some strength there
and now for karaoke further extension
trials
the are conditioned response will again
go back
ought to uh... to baselines what's known
as spontaneous recovery
and spontaneous recovery is itself
to extinction
you can just keep carrying out
these extinction
uh... trials
the next
off phenomenon that we look at
diary acquisition of the conditioned
response
after you've extinguisher condition
response by taking away the
reinforcement
if you start reinforcing the conditions
stimulus again by pairing it with the un
conditions stimulus
bell food health food
health food
then what will happen
is that
the animal
will start showing the condition
response
all over again okay the condition
response will grow in strength
but what's interesting about this
is that on ac was there are no react was
ish in trials
when the c_s_ is once again paired with
the u_s_
the adult will condition up again but
what condition faster
than it did onion itial trials
even though the response was
extinguished
the animal will relearn the conditioned
response
faster on subsequent blog trials
than it did on the initial trial
this is a phenomenon known as savings
and in relearning
spontaneous recovery
and savings and rewarding
revealed through important of barber
tuneful
features
that reveals something very important
about extension
and that is
conditioned response
isn't really lost
during extinction
it's not forgotten
it's not as if it member was their
arcade
it's bare
the animal still has the capacity to
make the association between c_e_o_'s
and u_s_
all otherwise it wouldn't
we learn it
of faster
the second time around
at a question back here
if you do this if you do this over and
over and over again the animal doesn't
get confused it's a very good question
beneath the i will certainly what's
going on here
reasons of all talk about next wednesday
okay
on
that's not exactly what happens what
happens is
at with the way i do when you repeat the
cycle
the animals catch on
more and more quickly
sold out
let's go back here for a second
so that
if u
repeat the acquisition phase
the animal shows savings in relearning
it says all ok bells followed by food
now so i'm going to start salivating
than when you repeat the expansion phase
the animal extinguishers more clearly
it shows savings in extinction if you
will
the animals that out okay
bell doesn't
is an associate with food anymore
on so i won't celebrate
and that's not what the animals actually
saying but
that were africa more flies in here for
purposes of the discussion and then when
you turn the connection back on
the animal will catch on to that
immediately
so do you get lots of savings in
rewarding
and you get lots of savings an
acquisition
the animal will
adjust its response
very very finally
to what's happening around okay
bell and food or associated now so i'm
going to celebrate
alright fell into a darn associated more
so i won't solve it
and that basically works like that
there are ways to confused animals with
procedures like this
but we're not going to talk about those
today
quick question yes
does it depend on how old the animal is
hidden doesn't really depend
no
baby animals can show classical
conditioning
infantrymen skin shock classical
on
on its supposed all
teacher who did classical conditioning
experiments with college students
volun
and under those circumstances of college
students can just think too much
about the situation the usually screw up
these experiments
on
but the on and always doesn't really
matter
doesn't really matter
as long as the organism is capable of
sensing
stimuli
and performing the response
really doesn't matter this is a very
very very elementary form of learning
and it's widely available
fall so what else we have to say here
okay
so we've done
acquisition okay
here's savings and relearning
youbet acquired a response extinguish
the response
there's been some rest little
spontaneous recovery now you put the
animal on reinforcements goggan schedule
again
the animal was shows savings and
rewarding
re acquired the response
faster
acquired it
first-time
so thats
the point here that condition responses
are lost during extinction
cuz they come back became a comeback
faster
here is another phenomena content finish
this of beef before our time
generalization
all-day condition response
once a conditioned response has been
established
then all you can
transferee if you will that condition
response to other stimuli
what will happen is
once a condition response is established
the animal will also give
the condition response to all other
stimuli and the environment
provided
that they are similar
to the stimulus
to which the animal was originally
condition
this is what's known as the
generalization
gradient
here is an illustration of it
we
badge in the reconditioned
an animal
to a tone of about six hundred fifty
cycles per second
frequency
and then tested the animals response
lower tones
and two
higher
frequency tomes
what will find
is that the adl responds best today tone
to which it was over
emission we condition
but it will also respond pretty well
two tones that are close to the original
tone
in frequency
and there's a
progressive
drop-off in response
as the test phones all become more and
more dissimilar
so the generalization gradient
is a gradient are
similarity
between protest stimulus
and the original condition stimulus and
the idea behind generalization
the more test stimulus resembles the
original c_e_o_s
more conditioned response you'll get
the more dissimilar but estimate was his
to the original c_e_o_s
the less
of a condition response
finally
we have
phenomenon known as discrimination
which of the which show
accounts for the essentially a check
on on generalization
here what happens is we take one
condition stimulus
say
or bella lago particular frequency
reinforce tab with food
heiko
ido food and i'm not a rebel with
another frequented mobile okay
and we don't waitin four seven four
ido food
mobile
no fool
what will happen is
the animal will come to make a
discriminative response so that it gives
those conditioned response
oli too
be condition stimulus which has been
been reinforced
and it won't get the conditioned uh...
response
to the stem condition stimulus that's
not reinforced
here is a schematic of what
discrimination learning looks like
condition the animal for awhile okay
five hundred cycle per second
is ul paired with food
the to under fifty cycle per second
bills not paired off with food
for a short while the animal just
responds the bells
but pretty soon it begins to make the
discrimination
response to the reinforced m ellis with
the reinforced so yes
continues to grow in strength
the response to the or unreinforced
two years
draws
that threat drops out
this is essentially extension
this is essentially acquisition
this is expected essentially extinction
so what happens now
is that
by virtue of
these basic prophecies ok acquisition
generalization
discrimination
stimuli calm to revoke
and inhibit conditioned responses
even though they themselves
have not necessarily been associated
the uh... with the conditions stimulus
okay
so that's what's going on in eleven
classical conditioning
by means
by means of classical conditioning
processes in general what happens it
said a reflexive behaviors
come under the control of environmental
been events
classical conditioning phenomenal art
ubiquitous in nature basically any
organism that's got a nervous system
will show at least from of the
phenomenon
classical conditioning they may not show
them all but they'll show at least song
in each of these cases
were xd in control over reflexes to
other environmental events i start
giving the patellar reflex to the sound
of a bell instead of just the blow of a
hammer
pavlov believed that all forms of
learning where basically on on variants
on classical conditioning we now know
that that is too extreme
but we do understand now that to a very
large extent
the laws of classical conditioning are
the lawyers of our emotional lives
by virtue processes like classical
conditioning we acquire
our fears
or a versions
our joys our preferences the things that
make us happy
the things that make a sad the things
that make us afraid
some of those things make us that way
innately of most of them make us that
way because we have learned to respond
that way to these events we've learned
to respond that way to these events by
virtue of a process very similar to what
pavlov's studied as classical
conditioning
thank you very much have a good weekend
i'll see you monday