okay let's finish up barnard discussion
of the biological basis of minded
behavior
with particular attention to
those structures of the brain and makes
thinking and everything else possible
last time i described it
for
examples of
so-called localization of function the
idea that particular mental and
behavioral functions
are associated with the war or performed
bari particular parts of the brain
and i reported out that
here in the frontal lobe
we have an area that's devoted to
voluntary motor behavior the controls
the movements
of the hands of the arms two legs the
feed the various parts of the body
here in parietal cortex
we have asked the so-called so meadows
sensory area
which receives
sensory impulses from various parts of
the body of specially the skin
the sense of touch
here in the temporal lobe
we have
what's known as the primary auditory
projection area
which receives
auditory messages from the ears
and then finally back here
we have the primary visual or cortex
which receives sensory messages
the audience
just in passing
want to point out that bizarre kind of
substructure here that's interesting
we've already talked a little bit about
differentiation of function within the
the all frontal motor cortex
and the perot idle some out of sensory
cortex
in terms of the
motor and sensory hormone kya list a
little man in the head that shows where
all these little areas are farm
located
but all again jata memorize this but you
should just know
that even within the occipital lobe
there is quite a bit of specialization
of function
sold-out we have a different areas of
visual cortex
that are devoted to things like the
processing of color information
the processing of movement information
and so on
you're not responsible for this and just
trying to show you how the thing is our
other thing is built
these study of stroke patients also
reveals
certain the areas of the brain that are
specialized for speech and language
we know this because
aphasia up
on a disruption of normal our speech and
language functions
is a very common
all
symptom
all other patients experience following
a stroke
all in but these are
though the symptoms of official
languages order vary greatly
there just be speech just flew in seas
were
the intended words just don't dollar
come out right or there's a lot of labor
to the speech
our problems with meaning
of phasic patients will have difficulty
repeating
words and phrases that are spoken to
them
they'll have difficulty understanding
spoken all words
they have difficulty naming objects and
sometimes they have difficulty with
reading and writing as well as with
speaking
but when we talk about a fishery usually
talking about
aquila problems
and
there ought to result in a wide variety
of different kinds of official
but the true that are of most interest
to us at this level of the cores
arbor identified in the nineteenth
century of first body under all of this
name roca alm or an open experts
so-called expressive aphasia and second
bio german neurologists and very cute
so-called are receptive aphasia
in brokers aphasia the patient's speech
shows a lot of just flew in sees that
the patient is just not speaking
normally the way most of people do
but voted the best those speeches slow
its own grammatical
it's all a lady bird
home
it's inarticulate words don't quite come
out right words don't get fit together
in sentences quite p_r_
quite the way they should
however
the patience
comprehension
of the speech of others is perfectly
fine
the persons having a difficult to
getting speech out
but isn't having any difficulty
understanding the speech of others so
that the person can respond to commands
and things like that perfectly on
normally
or they don't seem to have any of these
kinds of problems
by
on the other hand haitians weapon
verities aphasia
the so-called receptive aphasia
not only have problems with speech
production
or speech expression
but they also have problems
understanding
the speech
of other individuals they can't
follow our commander steak and follow
instructions
because they simply seem not to be able
to understand
what other people are saying to them
moreover
the patients with verities aphasia
so-called receptive aphasia
also have expressive problems
but they're expressing problems are
different from those that we observed
in so-called brokers aphasia
improper south asia
patients have a lot of difficulty
speaking but when they speak
their speech makes sense you can
understand what it's all about might be
hard but you can kind of get the meaning
that they're trying to convey that
by contrast in verities aphasia
the person speech may be very fluent in
some abstract sense all the words come
out final speech comes out fine but it
doesn't mean anything
all of the again there's a problem with
producing meeting
as well as understanding
the meaning
of the speech global of others
in either case there is no damage to his
corresponding skeletal musculature
the speech apparatus is fine for example
the hearing all
although title pathways are fine
clearly the difficulty reside somewhere
in the central nervous system
and we've known since the middle part of
the nineteenth century
that in fact
these two nd forums love aphasia these
two particular forums of language
dysfunction
are associated with damage to two
different parts of the brain
role 'cause aphasia
the expressive aphasia where the person
has difficulty speaking but the speech
makes
sands
is associated with damage
indo portion of the frontal lobe right
here known as brokers area cause
he discovered it
altman brokers area
which lives just adjacent
the motor cortex of leave frontal lobe
sold brokers aphasia and expressive
aphasia
is associated with damage in all areas
adjacent to the motor cortex
by the same token although
barricades aphasia the so-called
receptive aphasia
where the patient has difficulty
conveying meaning
and has difficulty understanding the
speech of others
is associated with damage in an area
known as a very keys area
which is located in this region
mostly up here in the temporal lobe may
be extended a little bit
into the of
into the parietal
through different areas
when damaged
produced
different
forums on
speech
dysfunction all sometimes we think of
brokers area as a speech area
and we think are very diffuse area
ansel language area snot exact that's
not quite right but it's well it is
pretty close
noticed
just off the
of
but to make the point
on notice where brokers area is ok it's
right down here
or very close to the lateral fisher
and if you remember or a little of among
killers
orval man in the head
and you look at that to be
motor
cortex here in the frontal lobe
you'll notice that the areas all of the
frontal all primary motor cortex that
control the movement of the face the
lips majeure and the tongue
right here again very very very close
to the
farther to the lateral fisher
so when you again look at
when you look at where broken syria is
trying to make sense
this is up with other various speech
that projects into
the po precisely
those portions of motor cortex their
control the speech apparatus okay so
damage here
no wonder
people have difficulty all
of people have difficulty speaking in
fact if you look at it of from a young
somewhat broader perspective
you can see
that speech
and language functions
actually requires
the coordination although i'm number of
different all of a number of different
centers
here are the pathways for example
that are involved in speaking
all word that is spoken to the patient
first
the word has to be that received by the
primary auditory area okay
the information is
transmitted to very dickey's area which
tries to understand
the all the above the word
then
the intention
to speak that word is transmitted to
brokers area which organizes
the speech at a breakfast
and then passes information to prime
absurd to though you know of those
portions of the primary motor cortex
that control the speech apparatus
so here we have one too
four different areas that our prod that
are involved
repeating
is
said
the patient
similarly
if you want to play of a person to speak
a written word
the visual input is first processed in
the primary visual area
then information is past to bear
dickey's area which involved which part
of the house at least in part the job of
understanding what's being the red
has to brokers area which organizes
the speech
and then
the appropriate areas of the motor
cortex
which actually executes
the speech act
different centers
show you art illustrate a point of going
to make a little bit later on
which is that it's not right to think
about the brain as a whole bunch of the
independent machines or organs
each going off on their own perform in a
row little functions
most complicated forms
of human thought an action require the
coordination
or the integration
all of a number of different bomb
of of a number of different of
all the brain areas
so again this is just an illustration
of how a number of different aerobraking
arrears
work together
the perform
even so simple
a
giza behavior
as repeating the spoken word
repeating
a written word
okay so now
we've got
brokers area
and verities area
added to the motor cortex the samanta
sensory cortex
the primary auditory area and the
primary artificial larry what's the rest
of the brain doing
welp for a long time
these all other areas of the brain the
best bulk of the frontal lobe
and the best bulk of the temporal
parietal and occipital lobes or simply
called association areas
and the general idea was that these very
large portions of the brain
had the function arg integrating sensory
input send amid per da performing memory
and out and thought process these all
kinds of prophesies are involved in
learning and memory and thinking that
language and uh... and so on
although there was uh... what at one
point
the idea that fault
maybe there was some specialization back
here
that the poster or your association
cortex
that is
though you association cortex of lies
behind the central fisher was basically
heretofore perceptual integration that
it would take tactile
an auditory
and visual information kind of put it
all together
whereas
the frontal
on association area that is the part
that lies in front
all of these of the central fisher
was basically involved with problem
solving
we've already seen
prefrontal cortex right up here
is something that is very very very well
developed
you
you know in humans
but the note the notion of association
area is a little bit misleading
because we know that all
the there are portions of so-called
association cortex
that are also dedicated
to a particular kinds all of our to
particular kinds of mental functions
palm
so for example
there are lots of different neurological
symptoms
that we can observe in associate all of
the resulting from brain damage
we've talked about amnesia the problem
of memory as in the case of patient
h_m_o_
we've talked about of each other
speech problems as in brokers aphasia
and verities aphasia
but there
some patients after brain damage will
show they lexi i don't have difficulty
and redeem
a graph here they'll have difficulty in
writing
they calll julia they'll have difficult
e with them
arithmetic another mathematical
functions
they prac ceo where they'll have
difficulty engaging in various kinds of
actions
they can all understand what they're
being asked to do
but if you say to somebody
grabbed a pen
they can't seem to execute
that particular argue havier
orc barbados symptom known as acting
knows you know
which is a alm uh... lack of access to
various kinds of knowledge they can't
identify objects that are for military
ought to be familiar to them loans and
uh... and uh...
all identify what does what therefore
it turns out
that each all of these symptoms
more or less is associated without but
damage
to a different part of the brain
or these symptoms may arise from damage
to
a couple although
different
what particular
parts of of of the brain
suggesting
that there's a lot more going on and so
called association cortex
than simply formulas and ciation
that there's a lot more functional
specialization
in the brain
on than simply primary sensory areas
and of the various kinds of of language
areas
in fact no
we believe that there is so much
functional specialization in different
parts of the brain
that cognitive psychology in cognitive
neuroscience has adopted what might be
called doctrine of modularity
the idea that different
so-called hotter mental functions not
just elementary mental functions like
thinking about my god
on hearing and uh... and uh...
at the scene
different mental functions are served by
different so-called mental organs you
can think about
on the mind is being divided up into
specialized organs
and you can think of each of these
specialized mental organs
as associate id
with a different
the brain
all i think this is not the theory uvm
on their organization that was proposed
by
are jerry fodor painful loss of for
orble
of psychology alone linguist
uh... used to be at m_i_t_ now is that o
rutgers
and photo argued
that these modules these specialized
mental modules
had particular set of properties
first is
that they are domain-specific
which is to say
that each mental module
processes all the other certain class of
imports
for suggested
that there were modules dedicated to
processing
language
different module dedicated to processing
visual inputs
different module dedicated to auditory
perception like for the perception of
music or whatever
and then each of these modules would
provide an output
maybe to some kind of central executive
but the idea that there are a different
modules for different domains of
information processing
different modules for different domains
of human activities
our second of
of for government
of the second property bs mental modules
is that they are
what fodor called information only
encapsulated
which means they take all the what's
given to them by some kind of important
mechanism and there isn't any input
from other are domains
they're going to see an example of this
in our lectures on sensation and
perception
where all show you some visual allusions
where
things don't look the way they are
the visual perception is not an accurate
representation of reality
all
then when you know that
when you know this is the puns allusion
or this is the plugin dorf allusion
whatever you still see the allusion
knowing that you're seeing something
wrong
does incorrect status that's because
these visual allusions
are created
the activity of
dedicated mental magda modules that are
dedicated to visual processing
on knowledge from uh... residing
elsewhere in the system
can't get in
to affect
their operations
for third property of his mental modules
is that they are what folder called
hardware
and what he meant by that
these mental modules are not assembled
from more elementary functions
they are themselves the basic units of
psychological function
of soul
these kind of stand-alone and not in
that sense
all another property is that
at least hypothetically
they are innate
that is they call not with the organism
as part of its basic
information processing equipment
you don't lured to see visual loosens
the way you see them
it'll really learn to use language the
way you learned of use language you've
use of use language the way you do
because your brains of bill to do a leg
which
you see the world the way you do
because your brain is just built
innately to see the world
that way
on other property is that
these or mental modules operate
automatically
they can't help but do what they do
okay there's no
switch you conflict to turn them on or
off
or whatever they get an input
they do what they're supposed to do and
then creative output
for some other part of the system
and then finally
most important for our purposes
all photos suggested
that each of these mental modules
was associated with a fixed
no role
architecture
we need each of these mental modules was
associated
with a particular locus in the brain a
particular
piece of the brain
performed each one
of these functions
now this doctrine of mel of modularity
is no very very popular in psychology in
cognitive neuroscience and there's a lot
to it
all
on so it is the dominant view of brain
organization
these days
so that
youth can octopus is from the new york
times a couple of years ago with as good
an illustration on as as any of what's
going on
the result of
studies on
rain
behavior function
reveal hey
map all
specialization a function or a cerebral
local localization
has some of the features of the old for
knowledge us map but very very different
functions
off our located in very very different
areas just by comparison this is the old
for knowledge us map i discussed this
last time
wrong
here it is a doll
on some of you are functional
specialization
uh... as i've just a couple of years ago
is a part of the brain
that goes approximate mathematical
operations way ask you to guess what
twenty three times fifty eight is couple
thousand
that part of the brain
that the right right here is what
performs that there's another part of
the brain that's involved in the
anticipation of pain
here's another part of the brain
that's involved in all
all pleasant
our sense of touch
there is a part of the brain that
performs exact mathematical calculations
where you sit down sick
twenty three times before than ok
carried one ca
the five over all that stuff that you do
when you multiply
that is being apparently being performed
by a part of the prefrontal cortex or
right here
here is a part of the visual cortex
that's dedicated to the perception of
speed
there is another part of the visual
cortex
that's dedicated for the perception of
motion
here is a part of the
visual cortex actually right here in the
junction between
the art of the temporal lobe and the
private loeb
that's involved in face recognition
i want you to memorize all these
locations ok that's for another class
but what i do want you to get a sense of
is that now dubbed the brain
which we
wide once thought was justice huge
had a monolithic
oregon that sat on top of the spinal
cord
is now are really a collection
i've dedicated organs
organs each of which is dedicated to
performing a particular all particular
psychological function
and if you open
randomly
annie hall major scientific journal
nature science
bulb the brain cortex whatever
every month you'll see somebody
reporting
on what date one of the leaders the
discovery
of a new center in the brain
on is dedicated
particular
elemental
mental function
this is
the kind of thing that we're now
developing along the way
from an on differentiated piece of
tissue
the brain turns out to be ideal
integrated collection
of mental modules
each of which
is performing or particular
or the beginnings of a particular kind
of mental activity
where do
these mental models come from
well so far as we can figure out
they are apparently our product on the
evolution
usually we think about evolution as
operating on body morphology on the
appearance of the body
fish evolve fans
mammals evolve arms and legs
birds evolved wanes
darwin's finches evolve different kinds
of beacuse depending on the island in
the galapagos chain that they are live
on
but it turns out
that evolution
dosn't just shape
abad
evolution also shapes the brain
and evolution also shapes mind and
behavior
the general idea
is that these different specializations
on module that
process these the speed of motion
module the prophecies saw approximate
mathematical computations or whatever
these constituted
a kind of mental toolbox
all which all allocated are adaptation
on union but i wanted to give our
as we were
splitting off
frome or from our hominid ancestors
and especially
that poem
diesel
these are particular mental structures
immersed in what yeh pollution every
psychologists call
the environment of early adaptation that
is the environment where humans first
began to emerge
in the east african savannah song
following beginning about ah...
almost two almost two million years ago
so that's the general idea behind
functional specialization
modularity of the mind
of mine consisting of a
toolbox
of specialized implements if you will
each of which
has been shaved by evolution
and that's what that's as far as saw
that that's all good as far as i can go
but if you think about it for a second
there have to be some limitations on
module or
you thought the idea that they
rain is just off
toolbox of specialized tools
tent the before story
off for one thing
the brain isn't joyous a collection of
independent pieces
fault called the dedicated
to any particular function
the first thing we want to do
is to
distinguish between
psychological functions
various kinds of operations of the mine
and the contents
onto onto which these operations are
applauding
mental functions mathematical
computations perceiving speed perceiving
motion all those kinds of things
may very well
the localized may be performed by
particular
pieces of the brain
but as far as we can tell
mental contents
what you are thinking about when you
think
what you perceive when you see something
the precise thing that you remember when
you remember some of that in your past
those do not appear
to be on a localized
on knowledge of particular things
particular wallet of memories of past
events
they appear to be distributed widely
over
the over the cerebral cortex also that
they're not on particular memories like
what you had for dinner last thursday or
what your grandmother told you i hear
that your high school graduation those
memories are not localized in particular
bundles of your runs
those memories
are represented as a
pattern of neural activity
that is distributed
widely
over the cortex
so the first limitation
on the doctrine of modularity is at the
doctor modularity may apply to functions
but it doesn't seem to apply to content
it may apply to
how you think but it doesn't necessarily
apply
you think about
the second limitation
under doctrinal modularity
dog illustrated earlier
and that is that there is an a counter
posed doctrine of whole ism
which is to say
that in the ordinary course of everyday
living
or experienced block an action
is mediated by
the integrated
and coordinated activity of a number of
different modules
think about that example that we used
before
speaking are written word
or speaking
spoken word
there's not by speaking the spoken word
module in the brain
some piece of the brain that just does
that it doesn't do anything else rather
even that very simple
peace love behavior is mediated by the
coordinated and integrated actions
at least four
different
mental modules
one that's involved in hearing or that's
involved in understanding when it's
involved in organizing speech
and one that's involved
in executing
so again
all along
there had uh... there's that kind of
limitation on on modularity
based third limitation on modularity
compounds in the forearm of what onto
neuroscientist called equal potentiality
the adult brain maybe a highly
specialized
but the image for a brain
seems to have
all lot more
on
ability
carry out different functions in
different parts of the brain
there is what we call all plasticity
in brain development
and we know there is for example
bar because children
may have suffered a stroke a little kids
can suffer strokes
that doesn't happen very often but it
does happen
but it's a staffer who suffer strokes
can recover language function much
better than adults who suffer
and apparently this is because there are
on number of different centers in the
brain
that can perform various coverage
language functions
and if you destroy one
early and often development
there's the possibility that some
quarter doll of module
can take over
that all of that function folk early in
development several different areas
seemed to be capable of carrying out
particular functions
functional specialization
appears to get fixed
as the brain mature words
and the brain brain doesn't
finished developing until well after
birth well into
all of the teenage years or outdoor
at least
on which point
the brain loses some degree of
plasticity
so that if you're an adult
is suffer brain damage you may lose some
function
and you may have a lot of difficulty
recovering
from that function
even in the case of adults
there is some possibility
all recovery
volvo function
or get nine use the example the other
day
of senator thames considered north
dakota
who suffered a massive brain hemorrhage
lost his speech function all lost
basically his old uh...
along function on the right side of his
body
what's known as the right place penny
please you
over the last eight nine months
johnson has recovered are great deal of
his speech function
he's never going to be william jennings
bryan on the senate floor as he himself
admits
his speech is pretty good if you heard
of the other day or on the news when you
returned to uh... when you return to the
senate
all and that suggests
that even in the adult brain
there is some degree all redone dancing
though that
at least under some conditions
buffer damage to some part of the brain
function performed by that part of the
brain is not necessarilly irretrievably
lost because
some other part of the brain
the ability
may have the ability to take over that
function
may not perform it small hall
perfectly
will do
so again
once you understand that but doctor
demodulator is the only dean
or understanding of
all how brain behavior relations mind
brain relations or or or organized
but modularity is not the whole story
there are various kinds of limits
on modularity
another reason to doubt an extreme
burgeoning
all the doctoral modularity
is that human beings
didn't stay in the environment of early
adaptation
human species even worse than the
african savannah
saw hundred eighty thousand years ago
all but very quickly
all we began to move out
of this event
to all other environments
out to ourself a show
and australia
into
the middle east and east asia
opted to europe
and then over the land bridge
into north
and south america
ads
humans migrated to these new parts of
the planet
we moved into
adi very different environments
the environment all relief
on adaptation
and now of course we're living in
incredibly different environment fears
got station at the south pole
the international a space station
where we have human beings living in a
more or less permanently
environments that are as different
from the environment
overly adaptation
as night is fall from day
the very fact
that we have that were able to survive
the way we survive in
italy
and norway
and iceland
as well as on the african savannah
must be attributable to the fact that
we've got more than simply
'em toolbox
that evolved to help us to meet the
demands
of the environment of early adaptation
on in addition
box of dedicated mental tools
we also must have
something like
general intelligence
general
problem solving capacity
of general capacity to
uh... meat
unsolved
no problems
that are opposed to us
by the new environments
in too rich
we are what we you know we've moved
and we also have to have
a capacity for learning
we can't rely simply on innate
mental modules
in order to get along
in order to survive in new environments
in order to adapt
the environments that we encounter to us
we have to be able to acquire
knowledge and we do that
by virtue
process that we're going to do
all discuss next time or puller team by
which we can acquire
new knowledge
experience
okay before i do anything else any
questions about drug adoption of
modularity and functional specialization
and all of that
anything at all
is there any kind of hierarchy about dog
the organization these modules
well you'd think there would be
okay
but so far dot appears not to a bit of
function but they are dot topic of much
research
what dot
sarkar neuropsychology and cognitive
neurosciences been after
mostly these days
has been to identify what these modules
are and what they do
the general idea behind of the general
method in cognitive neuroscience
put somebody in sale
i'm alright machine and watch their
brain well they perform some particular
function in hopes of identifying
particular part of the brain that does
is that ok
follow
assemblyman all of these modules into
what kind of hierarchical organization
yet there has to be something like that
but there hasn't been that much
attention paid to that workers nation
level i think that's
that's worked that really has to be done
all in the future
got an answer
okay yes
yeah well the idea is that these modules
evolved
in the environment
overly adaptation
and it's the same way that our physical
features evolved in that environment
helping us to survive in that
environment
the ideas that our mental
features also evolved in that
environment
the helpless survived in that particular
and uh...
you if you read in evolutionary
psychology
you will sometimes c_r_
of there is very much
well certain kinds of mistakes we make
amid talk about some of these in the
lectures on what language
and the reason we make them is because
our brains evolved in a particular
environment and now we're different and
barman that we still are using these
holdover
farm
these modules did evolve early on
think about the modules for speech and
language
for example
have to be bold very very very early
on the environment of early adaptation
but the point is worried oliveira
anymore
or at least not all of us who live there
anymore and the fact that we can live in
norway and icelanders number space for
them and parked the car and uh...
uh... and other places other that
environment
must mean
there's something else going out
and what that the other thing is i think
is forrest
not only not only got
last set of specialised mental tools
but we have
general intelligence we have a general
problem solving ability that we can use
to attack
new problems
that we encounter
and not only do we have
innately specified mental toolbox
as the doctor modular he says
we also appear to have
the capacity to learn new things
things that
uh...
nobody knew anything about
in the place to see nora the african
savannah
like how to drive a standard shift kar
contemplative you had a question
look at your brain that's hard to find
memory questions where did we find
memory
particular memories of what you had for
dinner last thursday tonight or what
your grandmother said he had high school
graduation or whatever
they don't appear to be located in
discrete
bundles of neurons the ways say
there's a broker's area
that those speech
or a very dickey's area that dollars on
language we know that got time to do
this
all we know that based on the some orkut
classic work
by a psychologist at harvard university
named karol lash elite
back in the nineteen th
and what do you actually did
the very
as not to the squeamish but they'd be
experiment was a very simple
straightforward sperm
you would take laboratory animals
these were caps
and he'd
they'd be naive cats they're just kind
of raised a laboratory that had never
had much opportunity word anything any
teach them something
you'd teach them how to
open a door to get out of a cage recoton
hot oppressive bardo
to uh... get food reputed to run a maze
or something like that
and that's all we teach them
and he had the idea
are very and on the lesion methodist
study he might be able to find where a
dot piece of learning was located in the
brain
but what he did was after he taught the
animals to perform this task
he then
lesion
their brain
he would take out
various parts of the three bo cortex
refer moments
in various areas
and then
let them he'll
and then retest them
to see if they could still perform the
task
and what lastly discovered
was that
loss of function
loss of ability to perform the task
was correlated with the amongst
partition that he removed from the brain
but it wasn't correlated
any particular locus
though it's not as if
if he took out the parietal lobe the
animals lost with a lower
or people got a frontal
you have a whole lost what they were
the amount of tissue
but not the precise location
at that level actually
to home
to formulate what he called for wall of
mass action
wallmaster sounds like something to do
with a political demonstration right
all but what the law of mass action
basically meant was
in learning
use your all cortex
that learning is stored in the cortex is
a whole
clearly
there was
the animals had to navigate visually
through the maze
and so you
visuals of though the visual area of the
occipital cortex would be important
what as long as he stared at spirits
mother cortex
they've been to be able to form
particularly well
and that led him to conclude
particulars
as we know
localized in particular parts of the
brain
rather
followed represented in the brain as a
whole
that's the idea
are those of you who are interested in
engineering you know a whole wanna hola
graham is
lessig annoyed about hola grams or more
more recent invention
a hologram as though they deserve
representation or you can take a lot a
lot out of it you can still preserve the
information in the representations
and he thought that all of the brain
kind of function
like that
had a question here
there are broke at the idea of what does
is what's needed to have to do with
broken verity
the ideas that brokers area
evolved to manage speech
and verities area evolved to manage
language
and if you go back to
real modular
map here
general ideas that you'd send these
dedicated areas of brain
evolved in such a way is to perform that
function
and your main point is
that there's got to be more too
rain than that
because
we can do things other than these things
weekend all address the demands of
environments or other than the one in
which we wold
there's really been no evolutionary
changed in humans than
adam and eve couple a jeans here in
there
all but we are very different
from the people of five six
thousand years ago
and those differences calm by virtue of
the fact that we have
general intelligence not just to do a
bunch of dedicated tools
the ability to learn
were not relying simply on uni
anything else but that yet
well the general idea is that at some
point
somewhere along the somewhere in
adolescence
terrain becomes more or less fixed and
its architectural and then it's
very difficult
some kind of recovery function
but it's not impossible again the main
senator johnson
lost his speech functions
all you they were just god
on that part of it that that part of his
cortex is
pretty much
but he can speak okay
also this kind of these
there's gotta be some possibility now
that
what exactly what it is isn't completely
clear remember
but the speech and language functions
tend to be localized to the left
hemisphere
there's a reason for thinking
that there isn't there a read on dan
structures in the right hemisphere
everytime usually use
and that maybe they can take over some
of these functions if the left
hemispheres structures
or loss
moreover
in neuroscience there used to be a
doctrine that said there's no
recovery
from central nervous system damage has
settled
but one of the system damages forever
we now know that there is some
possibility of urogenital
in
central nervous system tissue
damage
peripheral nerve tissue
that repairs itself
if you damage central nervous system
tissue the general idea it's been that
that's gone forever
now again you don't want to push this to
watch don't go up riding a motorcycle
without a helmet tonight because there's
no real genesis okay
but apparently
the brain the spinal cord haves some
capacity to repair themselves
very very very
restricted
conditions
though there are lots of reasons for
good another reason for recovery
function is that
but damage may be severe but not
complete
but there's just enough
tissue left over
to be able to perform function of psalm
allotment and some level
again
there is
the ability to recover some functions
the younger you are when you have the
damage
the more likely you workin
who want to experience that kind of
recovery
anything else we got a couple of minutes
here
a confidentiality
what interest between our
confidentiality and recovery of function
ekkuva tension elderly really refers to
the fact that the image or brain
is not rigidly special is not yet
rigidly specialize
and because the image or brain is not
rigidly specialized
there's more ability
or an image or brain to recover function
than for a much more bring to recover
function because they mature brain
not be rigidly specialized yet
maybe some other park and take over the
function of what otherwise your loss
that general idea
okay tax time will take up prostheses of
learning
thank you very much
see you wednesday