okay
last time we began to discuss
the
problems with the traditional stimulus
response or s our theory of learning
one of which comes from
a classic study of taste aversion by
garcia and his colleagues
errant gallery called the white garcia's
colleagues did
was to take a compound conditioned
stimulus
bright noisy sweetwater
and parent
either with a food chocolate bird while
the animal was drinking which elicits
immediate
unpleasantness
or with x radiation
delivered while the animal was drinking
which
all of you a sense
delayed
on pleasant news
and that what garcia did was to
test
the animals
fear in the presence of the water
by giving them to different sources of
water to drink from to choose from
either bright noisy water water
accompanied by the light minorities
or sweetwater water flavored with
saccharine
and as i showed you last time
the animals that were shocked
preferred the sweetwater
intended to avoid the bright noisy water
whereas the animals that were
irradiated
tended to prefer the bright noisy water
and to avoid the sweetwater
what we have here at this and citizens
interesting
instance
of the violation of the arbitrariness
assumption
because
all three all of these
balance
have been
parent equally well with the un
conditions stimuli
yet it turns out
it's easier for an animal to learn about
the association between light and noise
and shock
that it is to learn about the
association between
paste
and shock
and it's easier for the animal
to learn the association between taste
and nausea
that it is worth a learned the
association between light
and always
and nausea
now last time i argued
that this experiment
violates
the result of these experienced by first
and foremost
violates the arbitrariness assumption
of the stimulus response learning theory
because the arbitrariness assumption
says
you can take any condition stimulus
and paragraph anytime conditions
stimulus and get conditioning it turns
out not to be the case
it's much easier
to condition
fear of shock
or avoidance of shock
to light and sound that it is to taste
it's much easier
the condition
all version two x radiation
for nausea
to taste
than the light and sound
apparently rats are built
by evolution
to associate taste
with the gastrointestinal consequences
of what
ingest
and they were built by virtue of
evolution
to associate
the alone
our sights and sounds in their
environment
so not only though do these results
violate the arbitrariness assumption
they also violate the assumption of the
empty organism
because they tell us that we have to
know something about the organisms
evolutionary history power it is built
as a biological
creature
to understand wanted can learn and what
it at work
and then i think i said in passing last
time
this is an experiment also violated
the assumption of association by
conjugate woody
and the reason for that is the elements
on the compound condition stimulus are
all equally contiguous
for charter
and they're all equally contiguous
the x-ray
okay
yet
some of these stimuli
get associated with these on cat what
some of these conditions there like a
dissociated
with these different on conditions there
like and others don't
moreover
if you think about it for a second
the arable may feel before chalk
certainly does deal with which are
condones of like it
but the adult docent feel the x-rays
when they were being
deliver okay you don't feel those things
but what the animal does feel is the
nausea
that occurs much later
so if we have a condition
in which
and but the commission stimulus the
taste of the water
ken get paired off with nausea
even though there's a big delaying
between the taste
and the dawn steel
so this violates
the assumption of association by kon
tiki audios well
by showing
that an association to be forum
between events that are widely separated
in time
what i want to do today is to pick up
on
problem of association by kon tiki
already
and demonstrate
in some other ways that it is not the
right principle
of association
here for example is what's known as the
standard paradigm for classical
conditioning
this is a schematic diagram of a century
what pavlov did
and for that matter what everybody else
does
huang
held with who studies boat
classical conditioning
we have conditioned stimulus the battle
is presented
at roughly the same time as the food
dole food
bell food bell food and by virtue of the
repeated paryant
of the bell and the food
the adl comes to celebrate to the battle
in the same way as it celebrates
to the photo
i remember the standard exploration of
this is
that because the ballad of food are
presented
close together in time
that's what association by conjugate
woody means
close together in time that an
association is formed between them
all well and go ahead
except that
here it is another paradigm in classical
conditioning
known as delay conditioning
and here
the onset of the condition stimulus
occurs
and then some
time later
the odds that all of the un conditions
stimulus occurs
and the fact is
that even though the onset of the
convention stimulus
and the onset of young condition
stimulus are now separated by an
appreciable da way
you still get good conditioning you
still get the animal
responding to bell
all it the way it had responded to the
following
they could say well alright
the onset of the condition stimulus
is delay the onset of young condition
stimulus is delayed
with respect to the onset of the
conditions that those
but there's still this period of time
when they're together
where the animal is getting food
and the bell is still on
all right
leads us to
on a third
paradigm in classical conditioning
known as trace conditioning
where the bell comes on
and then it goes off
and sometime later the food
comes on
and then later the food goes off
there is a delay between the offset
of the condition stimulus
and the onset of the on conditions
stimulus
there are no longer presented together
at any point
in the procedure
but you still
fairer amount all
classical
conditioning
you still get the animals celebrating
for the bell
as it's elevated
to for food
and to kind of
nail down the point
here is a fourth variant on the
classical conditioning
paradigm
known as simultaneous conditioning
where
notice that the audience that of the
conditions stimulus
occurs at exactly the same time as the
onset of the on condition stimulus
and the offset of the conditions
stimulus occurs at exactly the same time
as the offset of the unconditional
stimulus
as this
line indicates
no condition occurs
how could that be
if conditioning if forming an
association
was a matter of associating temporally
contiguous events you ought to get very
nice association between
the conditioned stimulus and the on
conditions there was
because the tuesday lawyer or a career
at precisely the same time
you can get more contiguous than that
there's no conditioning that occurrence
and if
for their demonstration needed
here's a paradigm known as backwards
conditioning another variant on
classical conditioning
where the odd condition stimulus comes
on the food is presented
before
the condition stimulus comes on so it's
food bell
food bell food bell
and even though there's some overlap
and even though the onset of the food in
the onset of the bellacor pretty close
together
enough in time still noel conditioning
occurs
notice that in backwards conditioning
the temporal arrangements are exactly
the same
except that they've been reversed
shortly followed by dole
whereas in the standard paradigm
it's bell shortly buffaloed by food
when the bell as follow by food you get
conditioning
when the food is followed by the bell
you know
conditioning
even though
temporal relations
or otherwise exactly the same betu
ulm of events
are occurring
close together in space and time
let me say one more thing about
backwards conditioning in fact what you
get in
backwards commissioning
is not just be the lack
of a conditioned response
you will actually get the in addition
other conditioned response or a police
oppression of air conditioned response
we see this very clearly enough paradigm
known as fair conditioning where tone
paired with shock
the tones so yes
is followed by the shock
u_s_ okay
and what happens
when you do this
is that you get
they could that one of the physiological
responses to beyond commission stimulus
shock
heart rate the celebration the alleles
were frayed
and when you're afraid
your heart rate or speeds off
that's a physiological index of fear and
what happens is after repeated parents
of the tone and the shock
you've got
heart rate a celebration to the tone
as well as to the shock that's air
conditioned
for your response
now that's true if u
golf ball use the standard paradigm
where the toll follows shock
you'll get the heart rate deceleration
of the tone
what's known as a condition for your
response
but if u
the arrangements
the reverse
where shock comes on and then the tone
comes on
you don't get heart rate the celebration
during the tone
in fact you get its opposite
you get heart rate deceleration
for the tone
okay the suppression of a condition for
your response
why would that be
one hello hello
that's right exactly what's happening
off the hours in the starter paradigm
the tone communicates to the animal yet
i got shocked
okay
in the backward paradigm the tone
communicates to be out of all that you
not being shocked anymore you're not
going to get shocked for a while
it's consul most like the safety signal
so here in backwards conditioning
you will get the
in addition or the suppression all volvo
video of a normal
of course the condition
condition response
what these
points illustrate is that associations
are not toward according to a principle
of
contingent of of what kinda get woody
instead
associations are formed
by principal all contingency
bike i think you honey we mean but the
condition stimulus and the young
conditioned stimulus occur together in
space and time
co-occurring space and time
by contingency we mean
that the conditions they millis
pretexts
be on condition stimulus
then the standard paradigm for classical
conditioning
where the c_s_ and the u_s_ occur close
together with the c_s_ preceding the
u_s_ by your short interval
but couldnt believe was seen as the u_s_
are both contentioned and contiguous
they occur close together in space and
time
bop more important
the condition stimulus
pretext
the onset albion conditioned stimulus
and delay conditioning
and then trace conditioning
we degraded
but continuity
between the c_b_s_ in the u_s_
they're no longer appearing so close
together in space and time
but it's still the case
that the c_s_ predicts the u_s_ so it's
the c_s_ comes on first
and then the u_s_
comes on later
where the c_ as in the u_s_ are
contingent but not contiguous
you still get
okay conditioning
notice what happens in the simultaneous
case
the c_s_ in the u_s_ they're contiguous
with each other
therapy reno's close together in space
and time is anytime stimuli possibly
could
but the contingency has now been
degraded
when the bell comes on at the same time
as the food
or the tone comes on at the same time as
the shock
this the c_s_ ism predicting anything
anymore
on and
in backwards conditioning
where the u_s_ comes on and then later
the c_s_ comes on
what the c_s_ is actually predict
because the absence
of the on conditions there
so we get conditioning
so long as
yes and the u_s_ are in a contingent
relationship
regardless of the continuity
even though
on that as well as long as the c_e_o_'s
predicts
the u_s_ you're going
to get or they're going to get
conditioning
so what we're looking at here now
the importance of the information
that's provided by the condition
stimulus
to the adult
when the upon conditioned stimulus is
contingent on the condition stimulus
then the conditions they're most is
providing information to be out of all
about what's going to happen next when
the bell comes on
the bell tells the animal your gonna get
fed
when the tone comes on
but only tells the animal you're gonna
get shocked
but in the final taneous case
what the tone tells the animal is
european shocked
any other will already knows that
okay
doesn't mean that information is got no
use
offer that information so condition
occurs because
and all the f
the condition stimulus provides
information about the u_n_ conditions
stimulus
where
beyonce condition stimulus is not
informative about the on conditions
there goes
condition stimulus or the conditioning
simply isn't going to
let's take a break for a second any
questions about these various paradox of
what the report rations are
association by contribution
appears not to be the principle of
association
association by cob by contingency
the principal it's not whether the c_s_
in the u_s_ occur close together in
space and time
that's important
what's important is at the c_e_o_s
predicts the u_s_ yes
sure
in delay conditioning where i my
in delay conditioning
the asset
all of the on conditions stimulus is
delayed by some interval
notice that this
interval between onset of csn onset of
u_s_
is longer
then in
the standard case
so there's our domain
between the onset of the one in the
onset of the other okay
notice that there's still some overlap
the condition stimulus is still on when
the food comes on
trace
conditioning
the convention stimulus is gone
before the food comes on
it's called trace conditioning because
it's as if you have to have a trace of
the c_b_s_ and memory
for conditioning
to occur
that interval between the offset of the
c_ yes
and beyond said
of the u_s_ that makes a difference
between delay conditioning
treats condition
anything else about this
well what
what rates conditioning n delay
conditioning both do
is to degrade the conjugate our country
guilty
the interval
the time interval between the onset of
the c_b_s_ in the onset of the u_s_
is now
longer
then it is
the standard case
but in all three of these cases
the onset of the c_s_ still
is a perfect predictor
the u_s_
and that's what's important
arnaud if there is that's because of a
slip of my head there isn't more
response these are supposed to be
identical
there's not there's only more response
there's only more response because bugs
c_s_ is on longer
from apple is
if you look at it just in terms of
probability response it's the same
one more question
no in the in the yard in the center
pairing the c_s_ in the u_s_ are both
contiguous and contingent
they occur close together in time
and the c_s_ predicts the u_s_
them
delay conditioning
continuity is degraded
they no longer kirk so close together in
space and time
but the c_s_ is still a predictor of the
u_s_
traits conditioning
they also
not so contiguous any longer
they don't occur so close together in
space and time
but the csce still critics
the u_s_
in simultaneously conditioning
they're perfectly contiguous
beyond sets of the offsets are exactly
at the same time but the c_s_ no longer
predicts the u_s_
no condition occurs
and then finally in backwards
conditioning
the interval between unscented ross that
is supposed to be the same here as in
the standard case just that it's
backwards now
so there are as
in some sense there is contiguous is
they are in the standard case but the
c_e_o_'s no longer predicts the u_s_
what the c_s_ predicts is the offset
of the u_s_
now let's add a very and on this just to
try to make it even clearer
let's look at another famous experiment
in the are conditioned literature
by leon came in
on what's known as the blocking affect
in the caymans experiment
he used a compound stimulus
noise and light
the onset of the noise the onset of a
white exactly the same time
onset all seven always also polite
exactly at the same time
and then
this compound condition stimulus
is paired
the on condition stimulus
what happens here of course is the
animals going out of a choir a condition
for your response the animals going to
acquire
air-conditioned response
this compound stimulus but what came in
did
waters to decide to test the elements of
the compounds of condition stimulus
separately
so what he did here
was to condition the animal
to be afraid
in the presence of
the compound stimulus noise white and
then just test the animals response to
the white alone
and what came and discovered
was a big apple gives
solid for your response
the elements that's true for the noise
or as well
even though the animals been conditioned
a compound conditioned stimulus
it shows a condition fear response
to each
of the elements
but now what came in did was something
all little tricky
you break this up a little bit
in the first phase of the experiment
he conditions the animal to nahis
terrible shock
noida shock
noise shock nor a shock for several
trials
then what came in did
was to introduce
the light
as a compound condition stimulus
so now what
noise of light
noise a light
noise and light
and then what came in did
was to test the animals
respond condition for your response to a
white and he thought that there was no
condition for your response
to the light
contrast
the absence
the condition
for your response
when the animal's first condition to the
noise
and then to the noise unlike compound
the animal doesn't respond
the after the light
compared to
the first uxbridge of experiment where
the animals condition to light employees
right from the get go
and then
shows a strong condition
response
what seems to be happening here this is
not depiction of kuala caymans actual
results
where animals are condition to the noise
alone
and then get test responsible light
if their condition of the noise alone
they don't show when he peered of alike
if they are conditioned on the compound
alone
they show after your response
from all white
but if they are conditioned first of the
noise
and then to the compound
they show no more fear of the light
then if they had never been exposed
for the white at all
this is known as da blocking affect
conditioning an animal
all
but no worries
blocks the acquisition
of conditions for your
the compound
and what that tells us
is that
there's something very important going
on
it's not just association by contingency
that's important here but that
conditioning apparently
only kerns
when the on conditions stimulus
surprises
the organism
conditioning only occurs
when the unconditional stimulus
surprises the organism
when the organism a surprised by
something new that's happening tomorrow
hey i'm getting shocked naal
what the adult dogs
is to search
the environment
for a projector of this event
so i play on getting shot down and try
to farah when this can happen silicon
grit my little rat teeth or whatever it
is that the animals going to do
and then what happens
is that when the animal fines
predictor all of the unconditional
stimulus
it focuses its attention on that
and ignores
or other events that are irrelevant
and id nor is all other events
that or on that are redone did with what
it already knows
so to go back here for a minute
noises parable shock
shock is the surprising event noise it
is a really wild predictor of that event
the animal figures that out
during phase one
in phase two noise and light
are paired together with shock
but the others already got a perfectly
good predictor of the shock
he knows when the noise comes on is
going to get shot
so he ignores the animal ignores
polite
so that when you test the animals
response to the white alone
it has an acquired andy
kind of fear
conditioning occurrence
when the on condition stimulus
surprises the organism
conditioning a curve
when there is an event in the
environment
that can serve as a reliable predictor
when an animal has a reliable predictor
of this
previously surprising event
it focuses on it egmore is everything
else
no matter how many times
polite is paired with the shock in this
circumstance the animal will show any
fear
whose will never acquiring a cure for
that shock
fifth i don't know about this
on or you know about this
by virtue
so that just goes to show
that what's happening here
coren classical conditioning
it's not just that environmental events
like water the power to a bloke reflexes
which is what i said at the end of last
wednesday's lecture okay
that's not just what's going on here
and classical conditioning what was
happening is at the organism is
developing expectations
about what's going to happen in its
environment
it's dot you'd it's developing the
ability to predict
by virtue
on condition stimuli
what's going to happen
with respect
to on conditions stimulant it develops
the expectations
the on condition stimulus
is going to predict the on
on the on conditions there
awkward questions on the blocking
experiment
the point is
no condition occurs
when the c_s_ is redundant
with unknown c_s_ and that's exactly
what we have here
by virtue of phase one
we've already got unknown c_s_
the new c_s_ is just redundant with the
first one
no conditioning
now that's for classical conditioning
let's look at the same kind of thing
in the instrumental case
here we have a phenomenon known as
learned helplessness
study by
martin seligman steve mayor and richard
solomon at the same solomon i told you
about
before
what they're doing web what what this
experiment involves
variant on the avoidance learning
paradigm
that i told you about before
where you have dogs and a shuttle box
anatole incomes on
and later shock is going to come on
and the animal can escape
and avoid the shock by moving from one
side of the shuttle box to another
and what i told you last time
was that animals dogs learn this
perfectly well they were in this very
very very easily
although and alright not outlined for
you
ma worries
to process
theory of avoidance learning
by which
for morrow argued that
first half of the thing that happens and
avoid the story
is that the animal acquires of
conditioned fear to the tone
and then the animal acquires an
instrumental response
that gets rid of the shock and turns
love the tone
if that's the case okay
but the first process of avoidance
learning
is the acquisition
fear to atone
seligman and his colleagues
are predicted
well they knew better but
for the purposes of the experiment they
predicted that
if the animals already afraid of the
tone
then avoids warning ought to go even
further
even faster because you've already got
the first part of the two processes or
accomplished so what they did was they
took
the dogs
and they put them in a pavlovian harness
standard pavlovian
art of the conditioning a procedure
and then just presented the animals
looked on par with which shock told for
chuck
tone for chart
on in the same way
that pablo pared the bell with food
dole with food
filled with food
on and they were able to show
that in this in this circumstance the
animals acquired a very solid
conditioned for your response
to the tone
it's on the morning they already know to
be afraid of the tunnel
then they put the animals in the shuttle
box
where the tone came on followed by shock
the animal could escape
or avoid the shock by moving back and
forth from one side of the shuttle box
to another and what they discovered was
that in carving contrast to the
predictions
of the true process of of my hours to
process pirie
avoidance learning
the adults who were treated in this
particular way
did not acquire
the avoidance response okay they failed
avoidance learning
very retarded
on the part of these animals
here we have
a lot of what one of their experiments
boys or in the shuttle box
these animals were treated
some battles were treated with
fall
one signal
inescapable shock with just a shock came
on
they had no kind of predictions at all
okay
and then some animals
all broad got a signal
on shock
and here
art the results of the expert
control animals that didn't get any
treatment at all locais
they make the avoidance response really
fast
here are the animals that got the
all the inescapable shock
the prove the pre shock treatment
and you can see
there are lots of a skate failures
and when they did when the animal's did
make a mistake they took a long time
doing it
this is the phenomenon of learned
helplessness
preconditioning
to the condition stimulus
actually retards
acquisition
of aneil of avoidance response
here is another
example
on another version of this
on the animals or of these are control
levels that they'll get any kind of
pre-treatment
okay
alone
we have
animals that are actually allowed to
escape
when that shock comes on
and then these are animals that are
yoked to these animals to get the same
amount of shock
but they're not allowed to escape the
just get the shock delivered to them
then everybody's put an avoidance
learning situation and what you can see
is that there are lots of escape
failures
when there's a statement of everyone
wades for moderate onward helpless
so what happens here is that
your regatta illustration
not of the role of predictability
so much
as the role of controllability
when the alamo is in the patent lawyer
in harness
and he's been subjected to
standard pavlovian fear conditioning
tone followed by shock
coleman followed by shock
colin powell by shark
once the animal learning
the first thing in the animals for his
lease learning to predict a shock ok
tone has followed by shock
but what else is e-learning
tone as followed by shock
and there's nothing i could do about it
he's learned
that this is a situation in which it has
no control over the shock
and what happens now
is that the animals
generalize
this negative expectation
when they're put into the shuttle box
where the same thing is happening a as
before
columns followed by shock
helen's followed by shock tones followed
by shock
whereas a standard dog a dog that hadn't
been given this pre-treatment
run around and eventually stumble on the
escape of avoidance response
these animals literally sakin the
shuttle box and took the shock
they seem to be on
they seemed not to know that there was
anything that they who do about this
so we can
in instrumental conditioning
it's not just that voluntary behaviors
calm under the control the barman
forbids
in the same way that in classical
conditioning
animals learn to predict
the events in their environment
in instrumental conditioning
animals learn
control
of beds
in their environment
prediction
and control
is what's been learned
in classical conditioning and in gone
had been instrumental conditioning
so that's basically what's happening
whipple learned helplessness experiments
exposure
inescapable shock
during the pavlovian fear conditioning
situation retards acquisition
overboard his response
apparently
because the animal learns through the
classical conditioning procedure
okay the toll in the c_s_ is predicting
the shock but the situation is
uncontrollable
those negative expectations of control
now would generalize
from the
pavlovian situation
you avoid learning situation
okay any questions either about the came
in blore we're going to do what works
for me today
or came in blocking experiment or the
word helplessness experiments anything
at all
in the lower and helplessness thought
the situation
they were in that their environment is
in control
remember when we talked about the
differences between classical an
instrumental conditioning
one of the difference is is that in
classical conditioning
reinforcement
independent of the animal's behavior
they'll follow by food tone followed by
shock no matter what the animal dot
where residents to mental conditioning
reinforcement depends critically on the
animal's behavior effective thorndike's
cat does impressed that pedal
it's never going to get out
of the are part of the other part of the
box
the prior
pavlovian or classical fear conditioning
basically
taught the animal
the toll was going to follow be followed
by shock it was nothing to do what it
was uncontrollable situation
whereas if you just put a navajo in an
avoidance learning situation
in the shuttle box
what it will do is it will not only look
for a way to predict
what's going on
it will look for a way to control what's
going on
these animals had already worked to help
us out of animals
had already learned
control
anything in their environment
tone was going to be followed by shock
no matter what they did
was out okay
anything else about helplessness or the
block it's permit
though the animals fear or diminish once
they realized the shocks unavoidable
well what happens
to be honest with you
what though that the fear that the
animal show the condition fear is
eventually replaced by what you can only
call depression
if you've ever looked the diversity of
said dog
these are very sad dogs
on big big
dave whimper day looks said that kind of
a book kind of downturn faces just
bother
there at their mammals after all they
have
facial expressions of emotion just like
we do
on seligman himself has suggested
learned helplessness
can be a laboratory model for some kinds
of depression
and indeed in some depressed individuals
not all depressed individuals but some
depressed individuals
we find that they show and your
all life-history
uncontrollable
the things just
that things happen to them they seem not
to be able to control them at all
on and that's why you think that the
press
when bad things happen to you
and you can control those bad things
you either get determined
or you get angry
but when bad things happen to you
and you can control them
eventually what happens is you get
resigning
and that's what these animals they just
kind of get resigned to this whole thing
als they'll sit there
now i i want to point out
these experimenters were not
intentionally cruel to these animals
these exp six burns didn't go on forever
okay
and in fact after these experiments the
animals retired to a very nice farm in
eastern pennsylvania
where they lived
very nice dog alive
afterwards
palm barked at all
for the purposes of the experiment
this was
not a good thing to do
fortunately seligman and his colleagues
did the experiments right the first time
they had all the controls in place
right from the get go
nobody had to repeat their experiment
with the new batch of dogs to clean it
up
wrong
again seligman is quite clear
that if you're going to do these kinds
of experiments
you have an ethical obligation to do
right the first time so that nobody has
to do it again
is depression irreversible
the depression is irreversible
unless you take some active steps
what's element and his colleagues ended
up doing
was taking these helpless dogs in the
shuttle box
grabbing them by the harness and
actually dragging them from one end of
the shuttle box to the other
and eventually the dog's got the message
okay
that they just took a while because in
the first place if your dog or somebody
dragging your from one and the only
wonder what the hell that's all about
but eventually
the animals got the idea
okay just a couple really really really
long time
but eventually they recovered
because
that they could control the environment
after all
but in a standard helplessness situation
on b denied the animals just don't take
any opportunity to learn
uh... did they have to be shown
that the circumstances are quite
different
and just to make the connection to to
depression again
there is one important all
uh... the psychiatrist guarantee backed
him back
all who won the last girl ward a couple
years ago for or his invention of what's
known as cognitive therapy for
depression
and all
back noted that a lot of the press
people come in and say oh i can't do
this i can't do that i can to the other
thing that's part of their depression
all and back strong invented a therapy
in which
he systematically taught patients
they could do these things
and when they learned they could
actually do the kinds of things that
they thought they couldn't do
their depression began to lift
in much the same way that helplessness
began to lift in these dogs so this is
this is an experiment that actually had
a
to wedged positive soared to it
the word helplessness experiment showed
how certain forms of depression
occur
and also
helped show what we could do about
that particular form of depression
anything else about these
okay we've now undercut
also four obvious options all of the
traditional stimulus response theory of
learning
we've undercut the assumption
of association by kandi geary
showing that content you want to use and
the principle of association contingency
is
we are under caught the principle of
arbitrariness
by showing that certain com stimulus
response associations
are much easier to form and others who
do you can't just select
c_s_ is in the u_s_ is arbitrarily
and expect animals to learn them
we ought to cut the principal all of the
empty organism
by showing
you have to understand something about
the animals biological structure
how it's nervous system evolved
to understand why
pigeons can learn some things but not
others why rats can learn some things
but not others
but now we've shown you
experiments are also undercut
the assumption of the empty organism
by showing that you don't have to just
know what how the animal's brain is
wired
you also have to understand
what's going on within the animals mine
what does that expect
what does that think is going to happen
next
what expectations of control does it
have
these expectations are prediction
and expectations of control
are critically important
all for understanding
the behavior of animals in learning
situations and then finally
especially these last experiments the
cayman blocking experiment
and the seligman learned helplessness
experiments undercut assumption of the
past aboard
animals in these learning situations are
not being conditioned
by the environment
caymans rats in the blocking experiment
are actively searching
for a predictor of shock
they are surprised by the shock
there look at around to try to predict
salomon's
on the dogs arc
trying
to learn what control but what they what
they can control of their environment
animals learning situations
are actively searching
for prediction
and control
there's nothing passive
about the learning process
the final point about traditional
all all of the theories of learning
all which'll reinforced some of these
other points
content on concerns the role of
reinforcement
it's kind of a corollary to stimulus
response learning theory
learning only occurs
when a conditioned response is
reinforced
in the presence of a condition stimulus
in pavlovian conditioning
the conditioned response to the talk to
the bell
is reinforced by the press into the
presentation of food
in all within our thorndike ian
or instrumental conditioning
the conditioned response oppressing the
paddle is reinforced by escape
traditional learning theorists
held the view that reinforcement
was a sensual to learning and that in
the absence of reinforcement no learning
would occur
either in a classical
or the instrumental case
endure
edward seat haldeman psychologist at the
university of california berkeley after
whom pullman a hall is named with a very
simple experiment inmates running the
rats i'm sorry for the quality of
assault try to get out
all of a better view of it i thought i
had done this
this is actually a picture of coleman's
on maize
he results kind of schematic diagram of
it
in this experiment
all
scattered standard may fourteen
experiment
involves putting a ratna start box
putting a piece of food in opens cheese
or something
in a gold box
and the animal will learn to navigate
the maze
to get from the start box for the gold
box
and the traditional view of this
learning
is that lauren the owls learning of its
way through the maze
is reinforced
by the food that it finds in the
goldilocks okay
without that reinforcement the argument
went
no learning whitaker
so what poland did was paid very simple
experiment
in which he had one group or rats
that was
but in the goal box and reinforced for
finding their way to the there in the
starbucks reinforce refining their way
to the goal boxes the usual way with
food
another group of animals
was just allowed to run around in the
maze
they never found any food in the gold
box they just were just put in the maze
and they were allowed to explore it
and that and that there was a group
all was putting up in the maze for
awhile allowed to explore the maze for
some trials
and then
overflowing
reward was introduced in goldilocks
here are all
goldman's
results
we've got animals being tested over a
period of sixteen days
here is a group that never got any food
reward
and you notice that there are more in
very much okay there is no real change
in the amount of time
it takes them to get from the start box
to the goal box
here is another group
this group that is regularly rewarded
for food right from the start and you'd
see that they've gradually progressively
learned
their way
the gold box this is a standard
instrumental conditioning
kind of outcome
but look at what happens with this group
that received no reward for the first
ten days of the experiment
and then dale by the solemnly
when they got to the good did to log a
particular place in the uh... in in the
old days
they found
of food reward
what happens here
is that for the first ten days
these animals behaved just like animals
that are getting any form of reward
that's not surprising
they are not getting any food reward
okay
but no
on bail darden
their behavior changes precipitously
once they discover
that there is food in the box they now
begin to behave
like animals
that were regularly
rewarded
these are most
apparently
learned over the first ten days
how to navigate around remains
they had no particular reason
if you will
to yet quickly from the start box to the
gold box
on day eleven
they suddenly found out hate there's a
reason for me to get from point a to
point b
okay i get visa cheese
and now they start running really fast
it becomes clear from this experiment
that over the first ten days the animals
have learned a lot about the mains
even in the absence of reward
but they all leave put this learning to
use
when there was our reason
it was they don't want to put this
learning to use weapon they could
usable learning to find their way
quickly onto this is a phenomenon known
as the latent learning
and poland argued that learning occurs
in the absence of reward
what re will reward does is get the
animal to act on what it's learned
get the animal to behave unicorns
its word
so finally we can say
with the late morning experiments it
makes it very clear what it is a steel
or in the morning
in classical and instrumental
conditioning all these various variance
on these experiments the animals are not
simply acquiring associations between
stimuli and responses
rather what these animals are doing
requiring expectations
in the classical case expectations about
the outcomes of events
tones going to be followed by food
in the instrumental case expectations
about the outcomes of their own behavior
pressing a pedal is going to cut is
going to be followed by of landscape
predictability and controllability
what's happening here is that animals
are not just changing their behavior
result of experience which is our
traditional definition of learning
these animals are acquiring knowledge
about their world
knowledge about what's going to happen
knowledge about what's going to control
what
dollars and labels them to predict and
control the world about them
will say more about how organisms
acquire knowledge next week when we talk
about sensation and perception
thank you very much had a good weekend