okay
no no reason not to get started let me
just review the bidding for the exam
wednesday
i think i know all the students who have
disability along accommodations
and you should have received and you
know for me about those accommodations
before the weekend
home so if you
think you have a d_s_p_ accommodation
and you didn't get an email for me
work without the u_s_ rest is up for a
sentence
on and if you still don't see one
get in touch with me right away
so they're going to twenty five short
answer questions i mean really short
answer question now one word maybe but
no more than three sentences is required
to answer each question perfectly well
and that's really over looking for it so
you need to kind of
get yourself ready to kind of moved
through you examine
almighty advices
look through the exam answer the
questions you can answer
is fast as you can do it
and then go back at work on the ones
that you're having a little bit more
difficulty
and that's what a covers all the
material today
both the readings and the gamble
lectures
i had to make room for some extra
lectures so we'll do endorse the asian
coma
after thus after spring break
frankly
makes more sense anyway
and there are lots of resources
available we're doing this holiday
session
alba lecture list rations electra
supplements are off on the course
website
home to one or how wide construct endl
great exams
that information is on the exam
information page along with all the
other it previous exams and previous
offerings of the scores
on and
if you don't get your question answered
today
posted to the midterm exam form on the
home topic in new york
vspace website
you do that by noon tomorrow you have an
answer by five o'clock
lets move through this and they
relatively straightforward fashion okay
on the exam is always focused on general
concepts and principles
i'm not going to ask you to solve the
mind-body problem
okay or something like that
i don't think that's an appropriate exam
question it might be fun for a term
paper but it's not an appropriate exam
question
but you're never going to solve the
mind-body problem unless you understand
the basic concepts and principles that
we're talking about the scores
and so that's where the exam
how do you focus
bomb
all for the introduction introductory
lecture
that's what we talked about
more or less what the
reading such as they were from robbins
who will
all were all about
so anything there
anybody got a question
it's what
there's a reason but i'm repeating
because food webcast and i'm not sure if
the thus were born picked them up
the puzzle istook reserved that comes
out of the vienna circle but it doesn't
refer specifically to the vienna circuit
are in fact long before anybody heard of
the vienna circle people like
john b watson were saying
psychology campion saigon science a
mental life because it's it's subjective
in science has to be objective
and the guys who kind of fall in the
positive is the reserve are just shy
about consciousness
because they worry about that particular
point
home consciousness doesn't seem to refer
to anything
in the third person
situation
that's exactly what it is
anything else about this
and consciousness just to say conscious
shyness is a theme that runs through
this whole courts
because
consciousness makes
some psychologists in cognitive sciences
you can imagine how members are made by
the concept of
unconsciousness
not to mention on conscious mental one
or when we get to it
later in the course altered states of
consciousness that just drive some
people bananas
anything else about the introductory
lectures we can come back to this later
okay then we talked about introspection
what it is that goes on in the mind what
these qualitative std subjective states
of consciousness
are all about
and kind of how they classify them
i talked early on about this idea that
mental contents can be classified into
basically three
different kinds of things cognitions
emotions and motivations
an idea that comes from
well comes from plato but
we get it from cond
and it seems like a pretty good idea
although james's introspective analysis
of consciousness
then which there has never been anything
more beautifully done than that
what the philosophers worry about when
they introspective things like quality
quali oh and dogs are intentionally
and then we get to the scientific
approach which
really begins in the nineteenth century
was cycle physics
and the general idea that
you can tied mental states too
something objective like stimulus
conditions
or whatever
and then we get to the structural as we
try to figure out what the basic
building blocks
on qualitative experience or
any questions about this
yeah the question is
papa bell miller's doctrine of specific
nerve energies but the broader question
is how do we know we've got a mud ality
of sensation how do we know there is
vision and auditioned and got station
and all factions and all of that
and you could say well
we get the stimulus release different
sets rima delhi's compro
you could say well they come from the
stimulus
we see electromagnetic radiation
and we hear
palm mechanical vibrations an error and
all of that stuff
but it turns out they don't come from
the stimulus to come from the break
they come from the nervous system
and what miller proposed was that eve
sensory modality
was associated
a particular set of neural structures
and to be
activation
where the passage of a neural impulse
through those particular girl structures
all leads us to have vision as opposed
to what dition
go station as opposed to a faction all
or whatever
vote the specific nerve energies isn't
really the right
idea i mean
just for the for the history of it
miller thought
that different nerves the auditory nerve
the olfactory nerve whatever
carry different kinds of neural impulses
and that's wrong
all nerves contained would carry the
same in polls
on a roll in polls
so he was in right about that but the
name doctrine of specific nerve energies
is come down to was have been preserved
in this idea that every modality of
sensation
and for that matter every quality of
sensation within a modality
is associated with a particular neural
pathways
that's what that's all about
okay by don't if i don't answer
correctly you've got to let me know
the structural has tried to add a y_ is
complex
sensory experiences mostly
they worked on a motion to but that most
of the work done sensation
into their
fundamental building brought walks
tried to reduce
every conscious
experience
to some relatively small number of
elements
that couldn't be reduced further
so for example if i showed you something
purple you'd probably say well i see
some red in there that i see some
bluewin that
but if i show you something red you're
going to say
i see red in that
dep any further down then red
and that tells us that read
redness is a basic quality of
fish or sensation and that's what
instructions tried to do for tasted
personnel and for all of these
uh... all these things
same idea fall inspired
basically all inspired by the try
chromatic theory of color vision which
they didn't get
all the colors of the paint store
from just three
make these guys has tried to do it for
anything else
without okay
yeah i could do that rebel assault does
it a lot better than i do
all who's got a couple of pages of all
at one of his chapters on that but the
general idea was
the structural iso argued that you could
pick every sensory experience a
decomposing
into its elements
all and that
identifying those elements was
sufficient wonder stand what to send
what what the sensory experience was
and they pushed alters said well wait a
minute
all sensory experience isn't
just decompose the bolt with salomon's
because
what's the quote
the whole is greater than the sum of its
parts
for the structural issues
the whole is exactly equal to the sum of
its parts
british talked psychologist said there's
something more there is some kind of
inherent organization or these things
relate to each other in particular ways
that lead to have the lead you to have a
percept
that is a really decompose the wall
intuit's
in the into its constituent elements
so that's the gestalt us critique fault
structure was on
and the behaviorist had their own
critique of
of bald
volvo structure was on
which basically began with the idea that
different
structural is laboratories gave somewhat
different results would people
introspective and they said
we can do with us anymore
let's just look at reps
anything else
ticket
yeah well
probably would be used those terms quite
that way
palm
at those ribbons will does
the idea of causal inertness is really
the most important idea i think and
that's the idea that
concert we make
have consciousness
consciousness doesn't to enter into the
causal scheme of things
and that's because
uh... in the physical sciences alm
fog this the physical universe is a
closed system
all of that you've got a billiard ball
he hit the billiard ball with your with
with reports tech and that goes across
the table and it's all up its legal the
though the edge of the table
and it bounces back and hit some pool
another pool beloved herbal
and send the flyer but around all that's
a closed system
anders energy that's being dissipated of
energy that's been
on for the transmitted from one object
to another that's just the way the
physical world operates
home
and all
people have a lot of difficulty figuring
out
how minded
thought all of the hasn't image a real
substance the way gary hart did could
ever possibly under into that
so the physical universe is a closed
causal
universe
it's not open to mental
influences
all of them for that
reason
poem
mind his closet we ever trick of what
you think tab possibly you have any
effect on what goes on in the world
that's the idea
yes so you're probably due to a position
of epa phenomenal ism
all which
there's a philosophical position the
says we have lines we have consciousness
but doesn't do anything
on
thomas huxley use metaphor was those
steam whistle on the locomotive
that it just doesn't make the locomotive
gao
flows off steam
okay yet gotten to the first part
well perhaps my ideas so let's
not surprisingly didn't get into a
crisis
what then
not when these structural astride two
we've got got their their observers to
introspective
they wanted
observers to describe the qualities of
the sensory experience to which some
stimulus gave rise
so far showed you
up although the failure of the
patch of purple
i don't want to say it looks like a plum
that's describing the stimulus
all but the structural s wanted people
to do was to describe their experiences
also to make the stimulus errors to
describe the stimulus instead of the
sensory experience
sore exposed to say
i see red and icy blue when i see a
little twinge of green there
when you show me this
this purple thing
and
where i think the structural is when a
wrong there was that
they trying to strip mental states of
their content
they tried to strip there but the mental
states of there are boldness
if you show me a patch of purple and i
say it looks like a plum
that gives it some intentional content
of refers to something in the world
palm
and james
pointed out
after brent are loaded
mental states are interesting precisely
because they've referred to things in
the world outside the money
they've referred to
they've referred as something other than
themselves was the way james put it
and the structural seemed to me
not get that
they seem to think that mental states
referred just to themselves which is why
they forced or observers not to commit
the stimulus error
i think it's all relatively minor point
it's not his biggest lead critique
the gestalt critique of introspection
that the whole is greater than the soul
of sports
and it's probably not as profound as
they
behavior is pretty
but it's more correct
than the behavior is pretty as we know
the behaviors for wrong about everything
not as long as freud but they were wrong
about everything
it's hard to be wrong about more than
everything but really managed
you know somebody once pointed out that
the city's wong about everything isn't
that's even worse than chanson
okay anything else about this
we can come back to him later
so let's talk about mind-body problem
and its various fault various ways
and he got even though we are trying to
move away from palazzo pro prompt lost
me here
all in our cognitive science anyway an
important role before suppresses to ask
the questions and check the answers
palm so our discussion about the
mind-body problem really has to start
philosophy
eyes it's come down to us from descartes
on and
the various ways in which different for
lost furs have tried to deal
with this cartesian distinction between
mind and body
so
on
this isn't of course in the philosophy
of mind so we've already taken that when
you could teach it better than i could
uh... it's not of course in the history
of philosophy but there is a vocabulary
here
different kinds of interact with the
different kinds of volunteer willie's om
and materialism and idealism and all
that
that i want you know
have some familiarity with
but basically all of this gets us to
the great cartesian impasse
the idea that you got my name's and yet
god
and you know that somehow they interact
with each other
but i can't figure out how it could
possibly happen
and image a realist
and image a real substance like the mine
could possibly
enter into a causal
a maturing universe
that's the problem
anything about this
right
go
nobody ever said i got this right
spanos i but i think about span ozone as
adores just because of this position a
property dualism
you seem to think that objects had two
different kinds of properties mental
properties and physical properties that
comes close
to dualism
close enough as they say for government
work
alm
now his brother and that's exactly what
he's trying to strengthen explicit
were all everybody in this room is a
materialist
in the sense that
we believe the role there is a physical
world
but we have to try to
most of us think that anyway
palm
all but uh...
or at least as a sign of scientists were
materialists okay
but still somehow we have to make room
for this thing that doesn't seem to
belong there
and
that kind of shades in the dualism for
me
it's less important that you classify
span ozone as the duelist or a
materialist
then it kind of understand what he went
through trying to solve this mind-body
problem
and the than the solution he came up
with
that's what's really important
so i'm never going to ask you a question
that would say here's a list of forty
percent here's
three categories
and slot them one into the other
i wouldn't do that
okay
biological naturalism
i'm going to answer that question two
ways
first that's a wonderful question to ask
professor sorrell
a someday
what doctor risa dot there's a second
way
and that is
that i think
swirls attempt to grapple with this
is
no different from anybody else's attempt
to grapple
on and that
amid what one of the wanna professor
sarolst felt all philosophical methods
from has earliest work right up until of
the most recent and this is not a
criticism
he tends to cut through received two
categories
quote from strolled someplace it says
whenever
philosophical vocabulary seems to uh...
forces to too
completely contrary couple positions
there's probably something wrong with
the vocabulary
and he's probably right about that so
what the first thing sural does is to
say
the reason you get into an old list
trouble
is because you think about mind and body
as somehow different kinds of things
and he says
let's see what happens if we don't do
that
if we think about mind and body as
basically connected in the following way
that binders are causal property all
brains
okay which is basically what he says
somehow
or bar mental states
caused by
our brain states
and exactly how they receive other
another interest in principle and sales
work itself
also once we figure out that
then we just going to kick the problem
over to the nor a biologist to let them
figure out how how it happens their job
to do that not mine
fall and i think that's also both of the
perfectly reasonable part of the
proposition
that will look like the dualism too a
lot of people
fall
but he insists it's not
and the reason he insists it's not is
that he says
i don't
except the fundamental distinction
between body and mind so you can call me
a duelist
to other people that will look eurostar
shave off epa phenomenal isn't
yacht well were or reduction as a
benefit that that that's that that's an
interesting impression for people to get
because through insists he's not either
and up a phenomenal list
nor
a production is
he believes that mental states are
caused by brain processes
palm
but he believes that
mental states play a causal role in the
world
and he doesn't think you could reduce
mental states
true brain processes
all this to the first one first
though that the second one first you can
reduce
mental states to brain processes
because mental state third given off
first-person description
i'm in pain i see green are you feel
awful today or whatever
and brain prophesies are something that
can be developed
of third-person description of the
complete description the brain process
so you can reduce mental processes the
brain processes
without leaving something out and if you
have to leave something out
then it's not a successful reduction so
that's his position about that as i
understand it
and sorrow was not a mecca for novelist
because he believes that mental states
play a causal role in the world
in fact his left
two or three books have all been about
how recreate rock a large portion of the
world
through mental activities
so for example
alm
to use his example
this is a dollar bill
because i say it's a dollar bill
or rather this is a dollar bill because
the president says it's a dollar bill or
somebody like that says it's a dollar
bill
but it's just a piece of
cloth fibers
you'd objectively
by what sorrel would call inactive
collective intention ality
we'll hold make this into something that
has
that really is there really is a dollar
bill
and had really will buy you a dollar's
worth of peeps over a dollar's worth of
whatever it is becca that you want in
the real world so it's not true that
mental states don't play a causal role
building the visible universe
i've told that's just because there is
hard to pigeonhole but the reason is
hard to pigeonhole is because he doesn't
accept this distinction to begin with
my own problem
no he is not a mystery and either
all of the and that he's not a mystery
because he assumes that the norrell
biologists will solve the problem
he says
the neuro biologist will never solve the
problem is if they keep asking the wrong
question
and the wrong question is a question
that's frame by this cartesian dualism
that we somehow have to they have to get
over
my own problem
with full swirls biological naturalism
is that
i'd he doesn't
in my view
alm
connect up
the biological naturalism the comes
through with his
critique of
glossing consciousness
with his later
form or work on on on these social
where the cognitive construction of
reality
in this way
if you say as he does
minding his own causal property of
brains
brain processes cause
mental states to work or
that suggests that brain that mental
states are and a fact
a brain processes
and what you really need to do now is to
find some way for that affect now to be
a cause of something
especially
so there's gotta be some dugout although
some mechanism for the states to come
back
into the brain
uh... in uh... in some way
and what you do is he'd say well you
know course inform midsole machinery on
it and all that but it uh... it seems to
me he leaves that part of it out
when he's trying to solve
that the this mind-body problem
that's a problem he doesn't want to
leave out exactly because he
but he believes that
mental states have
nair
i'd i what i think differ if i said he
was anything other than a biological
naturalist i would get really hostile
phone calls from the dark of night
what i don't think he's a friend right
and i don't know i i wouldn't want to
promote a misunderstanding of friends
work
ulm especially my misunderstanding
reference work
sorrel is hard to pigeonhole
okay is just hard to pigeonhole
you've made himself
hard to pigeonhole
and the reason
he he's hard to pigeonhole is
he doesn't want to be in any pigeonhole
he doesn't want to be trapped by this
vocabulary that we got
guardian the sixteenth century
thong and
can understand that
yahoos it's it's fair
anything more on this
functional as a man behavior ism should
seem extraordinarily similar to you
because functional is a misbehavior
they come on a different traditions
palm
all food psychological behaviors and
comes out of the animal learning
laboratory
philosophical behaviors and really comes
out of the other circled sage aaron and
don't go burrowing owl and uh... and and
and those guys
and functional as i'm really kind of
comes out of the computer metaphor of
the line
also they have different rooms but they
though psychological behavior is a man
philosophical behavior as a man
mobile call computational functional ism
fallen uh... really all basically have
the same
underline idea
there are still millis imports
and there are response outputs
and that's really all that matters
poland and yeah i bet that level they're
basically the same
calm
just one of disciples like
talk about this a little bit more
lecture supplements if you've read it
there's another kind of functional isn't
people sometimes get confused with this
cold chicago functional ism
all that it comes to us from people like
uh... angel who was uh...
psychologist of uber secure cardinal
john do we
and for that matter believe james
himself
and our chicago functional ism in
psychology
really is
quite different
it's not computational functions with
all the sometimes people get them
confused
although chicago functions of the really
good functional
all because it says that the uh... uh...
that bushels of ms predicated on
basically three assertions
first of mind has adapted value
organisms
have minds in use minds to
fallen
to art
facilitate their adaptation to the
environment
palm the second is that fall their goods
will be mind and body
which basically says the mind is what
the brain dot is and sold if you want to
you need to connect what you know what
the mind which commit which no but the
brain
and the third point his mind in action
fault which basically says that
or mental states clauses to behave the
way we do
that's that's just psychology
right that's what that's just what
psychologists believe that when they're
being psychologist
palm and it is not susceptible to the
same kind of critique as computational
function was at the kind of
computational cultural ism
you see for example the work done done
it
who basically says there is any puts
and there is no points
and there's this machine in the middle
all about the really important thing is
the imports
and the outputs
fallen anything more on this
yeah i can do that a little better
that's that was a close off in the very
first lecture
but basically
the cognitive revolution
palm trees
laid the foundation for revival of
interest in consciousness but from what
the tension
and short term memory and imagery and
all of that kind of stuff
but at the same time
this major guardians the cog revolution
noam chomsky basically said
language
and for him
is mediated by syntactic across the seas
of which we have absolute no conscious
awareness
and canot only by
so in that sense
chomsky in linguistics kind of
undermines
calm
saw
the the the interesting consciousness
by suggesting that all the action really
is on conscience
and so that we can't know
to accept or
except indirectly so that that's really
all that sort
that's what that's all about
let's go to another one here
c worrying to next
okay i think we did this
anybody have anything more about
these guys reduction is a amid all that
kind of stuff
now this is the position interfere
reddick reduction is a missile position
described to pull and patricia church
one
uh... uh...
of who fall off with
now call themselves liberal philosophers
and basically they say
the there
they're kind of
for publication position is that
they favor a kind of reduction is in the
take stereo that called theoretical
principles of one domain
and connect sympathy radical principles
in another domain
so you take
dog disregard period the psychological
level of analysis
and what you want to do is reduce that
to a theory
at the biological level of analysis
what the brain is doing
when the mind is performing some kind of
activity
now that they did self is no problem
that's how we connect up psychology the
narrow site
okayed by connecting
theoretical constructs of the
psychological level of analysis to
theoretical constructs
at the
biological level of analysis
where the church ones
goal wrong i think
isn't thinking that
more scientific
somehow to substitute the biological
vocabulary and the biological concepts
for the psychological concepts
the church ones do a right
mantle of the dog got our our mental
constructs
i believe i feel i'd want
all of that are kind of folks psychology
that comes from your grandmother
fall grandmother psychology that
sometimes called
on and that if you're if we're really
going to be scientists
what we would talk about instead is
neuro transmitters and sin taxes and
hormones an oxy posted on all of that
kind of stuff
and they've gone so far is to say
that psychological theory
ought to be grounded in
the quote is
our real-world the findings of
neuroscience
implying that somehow
what psychologist who was not attached
to the real world
fault and suggesting that
mentalist a constructs like
thoughts and beliefs and feelings and
desires
caught have no more
onto logical status no more existence
than easter and largest on unfair res
don't think that's right
mean it's not it's not only not a nice
position
fall but it's completely wrong
and the reason it's completely rwanda's
yet although understand what the brain
is due in until you understand what's
going on at the mental level of analysis
to cap possibly understand
hull mind and brain contact
unless you have a proper description of
mental life at the psychological level
of analysis first
if you don't have that
that all you've got is
sparks and
trips at the syntax
for which is flying norrell biology but
it doesn't tell you anything about what
it does
or in terms of uh... in terms of the boy
all i'd prefer to reverse the churchill
and the addictive
and ground and neurobiology in the real
world findings in psychology
or that seems to be a were logical place
to go
that that diatribe
home
were about this
yeah
well but one of the criticisms of
chalmers i think is that you don't
really get what he's saying in the first
place
palm because he seems to be taking to
quite different positions first is
he seems to embrace dualism because he
says mind is real limits there in its
third and uh... and and and and all of
that
but he seems to say that somehow
wind balm is a property of
of a mission
of a computational machine
and hollow you can
do that
how you can get that
is not easy to do and chalmers does it
with what the old greeks would call that
in my view anyway
dusted with a day is x
national
god comes out of the rafters
home swung on oakland on a machine
employing stone of the greek theater
stage in kind of explains everything
poem
and that's what i think happens
when chalmers says well
i'm gonna postulate that experience is a
fundamental feature called
it's not just space and time
all that and and and and all that
experience is also a fundamental feature
of matter
and that
experience columnist with any physical
system that embodies information
more a physical system embodies
information
the more experience
it has
so we've got brains with a hundred
billion or on his own about andrea bill
digo does ileum
connections between of these morons
we process a lot of of lot of
information so
have a lot of
mental states
your thermostat processes information
and so it's got a mental state and the
solar system can be thought of as an
informational system
and so it's got mental states and
anything safety kinda gets to this
parents like ism
you think you can possibly mean that
but he does mean that
fallen and he doesn't then and he has to
mean that because
he's trapped
while you do this
solution to the mind-body problem which
is the postulate experience is a
fundamental feature of the universe
fall
and that's it
really right
i don't think there is anything else
palm
are could be wrong about this flood
i've read the book a couple times i've
heard uncork a couple times
i really liked is on the page on the web
you've got a great zombie page on the
web
uh... everything you'd ever want to no
one's own means is on that page
because it takes us on the argument
seriously remembered is really
really interested in
what it would be what the difference
what makes a difference between our
behaving system that's conscious of the
behavior system is not conscious
when i retire really think that's it
fall and it doesn't fit the dose doesn't
hang together for me
uh... it may hang together for some for
somebody else who swore driven on but it
doesn't hang together for me
perot for my purposes here
nostril dawson of course believe that
uh... that's the wide why does he look
like it i think is the question
okay so
if you know why you looks like one that
you know
olympic some important features in
salisbury
let's go to something else here
then we did the four mind-body problems
palm
most cognitive science focuses on the
first two
how you can get mines on the bodies
and to a lesser extent
all hulled mine skin effect bodies
all right thank also relevant
especially
when we start we start off if we have to
as we have to start off
cartesian dualism just for the sake of
history
alba dot ask questions about what he did
our bodies without lines
that's the zombie problem
palm
and whether you can have mine too dot
bodies that's the problem of
parapsychology
said basically all i have to say about
but those on the argument comes back the
reason i do this will blast in these
lectures
is because
there's a clear connection to
the concept of autumn it has to be
and to the autumn it has to be
juggernaut
because the the argument
by the proponents
the writers on the autumn it has to be
juggernaut is basically that were
conscious armies
that we have mental states
but these mental states played no role
in our behavior because
stimulus is connected to responds
automatically
so now we've got
really upon the holy marriage
between
psychological behavior as a
philosophical dickerson
computational punctual ism
and a lot of a dissident
all them believe
that basically all we've got is stimulus
and response
and i say the hell with it
but that's not enough just to trade to
say that all of it so that's important
to understand
why
the argument doesn't work
and the argument doesn't work because
the bad people or argument that these
social behavior is all automatic
haven't actually done the experiments
the tears apart the contribution of
automatic and controlled processing
and when you do that using something
like two colby's processed association
uh... technique it doesn't turn out that
way
all
it turns out that
past performance reflects off a mix of
conscious and unconscious processing
and all the there may be circumstances
under which ka unconscious processing
automatic processing dominates those art
generally the circumstances that we
encounter revealed ordinary course of
everyday living
fall
and if you don't believe me
wait until thursday night when somebody
asks you won't for friday night
don't just say yes or no usaid let me
think about it for a second
and if you don't you wish you had
okay anything else about
the these topics
moving right along
okay attention
early fpo early yang the
versus late processing carries a lot of
attention
all of this has to do with where
semantic analysis takes place
and whether you can have semantic
analysis before you pay attention to
something or not
all and you underlying question is
how much can you do pre consciously
how much processing can you do
pain conscious attention
so we get
arguments for
the automata city
of of uh... for autumn officially you
can do a lot of pre conscious processing
you could do a lot of processing pre
attentively outside the focus of
attention
so long as they are processing has been
automatons either cause its innately
automatic
or because it's become automata i threw
a lot of experience
most of you when you type you don't say
oh let's see where is for tea
and wears a q
and all the ease some place or that you
just tight
and for that matter those of you who
tracks
have learned to do it not just was not
just with ten digits on a
but you learn to do with two phones
and you're not thinking about it you can
do with the dark
but you learned that suspects a skill
that you learn
and so you can get from your meaning
to the message
to the phones automatically
okay well the process
ppm the context of this questions for
processed association procedure
and the process association procedure is
simply
uh... paradigm
that allows you to separate out
the contributions of automatic
and controlled processing to past
performance
and again i don't expected
get involved in the equations or
anything like that
although if you really get interested in
that you can follow the argument through
in the lecture supplements
but basically that
the processed association procedure is
away for figure out
how will automatically been is
alone
and when you do that in the social
domain anyway you find out
stuff is not very automatic appeal
so that's the connection
yeah that's their debts or early dot
sample from jacoby is work about how you
could use
the processed association procedure to
tease apart
the automatic and controlled
contributions
the contributions of automatic in
control processing
to recognition
uh... memory
and again if you want to if you want to
work for that example the bath over
something like that it's
it's an electrical
doesn't last very long
you have a subliminal mere exposure
affects
yeah out that affect us less but you
can't be a good indian end on the merits
washer affect you get bigger fax
supposed especially if they re
presentation of the of those shapes for
example is
super liberal
is actually in consciousness
student gets subliminal mirror exposure
affects but they don't last that even
they don't last very long
phone
so there are a part of the durham
limitations on that processing as well
the more sublingual the process of the
more the the more subliminal the
stimulus the less you can do with it
uh... that's the general rule
right know that that that that's exactly
right so for example
let's kind of work out a little chain
here your subliminally exposed to the
face of someone
all you don't notice that that that the
face at all
but then in the past
you're exposed in conscious awareness to
that face of the new facing arrest which
one you like better
you say i like this one
the one you happen to have been shown
subliminally one oh that's our conscious
and you've already got of them
association between that face and
something you like
and that's going to carry on later on
so that
exactly it could be a big could do that
it could do that
all but that
does the interval of time between the
sub little exposure and the first
conscious exposures public still going
to be relatively short
still relatively short
alm
the best example of this i know is so it
is all there's a study by your own on it
for the guy named born stain
paul who actually is
subliminally expose people as the
subjects the faces of people that they
would later on
work within an experiment
and he found that they actually were
nicer
to the people whose faces they ads been
subliminally exposed to
but even now dole went to london uk
over duration fifty minutes
experimental period
yet the technical term
palm
wildcards
i think it's not all have to say about
that
and demagogued this business about
implicit memory and it was a perception
and all of that
automatic process ease are unconscious
processes
but the general idea behind automat this
city is an automatically passes he's
still generate conscious memories
conscious percept conscious thoughts
conscious feelings conscious motives
and beall
beall brand of the lectures on the
explicit in the implicit
called is that
the idea of unconscious percept
fidgeting about percept or
representation of a stimulus that
influences your behavior even though
you're not aware of that
representation
looks to be viable there's something
like unconscious mental states
states are about something there about
the stimulus there about the past
or whatever
and that's so
kind of where we are
we're going to use this implicit
explicit distinction in the second half
of the course
when we talk about
information processing can you do when
you're asleep or when you're an
anesthesia
or you r_u_ processing anything when
you're in a coma
stuff like that
so we're going public
over dot time maybe for one or two more
questions
if i didn't get to your question of
something pops up to you as soon as you
leave the building today
just type it in to the forum you do that
by noon tomorrow you get a response for
me by five o'clock
alm
explicit implicit memory can be
dissociated in two different ways first
our populations of people like and music
patients
who don't have explicit memory but do
have implicit memory
exposing them to the memory can be
dissociated bite
compared to the republicans of people
then there are the functional
dissociation
different experimental manipulations
candace sociated explicit an implicit
memory
so for example level processing at the
time of encoding
has a big affect on explicit memory
but has relatively little effect on the
implicit memory
so that's sort of the war another way in
which they could be dissociated
and the same thing goes for perception
and the same thing goes for all these
other
domains as well
so we're always looking for us
ways in which we can split apart
or just so she ate
conscious x promo unconscious x directs
refers to
some mental state perception
memory thinking
learning knowledge
emotion motivation or whatever
okay thank you very much
will see you on the forum we'll see you
on wednesday