okay where we left off last time
was with this problem lol
the extent or what
pre conscious or pre attentive
processing
and the question that bedeviled
attention theorists for a long time
install does to some extent
is how much processing can you do
without pain conscious intention to the
thing you're processing
okay how much processing can be
accomplished
pre attentively
before you pay attention to something
and on
the basic all
all the questions
pose this way
is
preaching are pre conscious processing
or pretend to processing limited just to
perceptual analyses of the physical
structure of the stimulus
which is what the early selection
theories of attention
implied
or can pre conscious processing extend
to semantic analyses of the meeting
all of the stimulus
which is what's all implied by the
all late processing all theories of
attention
and as i mentioned all last time
daniel condom and any common tried to
cut through this
and said look
the yacht
the arp
determining factor here it isn't that
kind of processing that is it is but is
the kind of information is being
processed
perceptual information about physical
structure
versus semantic information about
meaning
dubbo the limits on attention really
come from the kinds of prophecies that
are being deployed
and he argued
allocate are limited to attentional
resources in lots of different
directions
what are called our car rolled
the potential resources or
fundamentally ltd
what happens here on weekend
became number employees relatively
enduring
cognitive dispositions
process information automatically
or
weekend
all did deploy
goal directed
potential prophecies
that are more or less
so the general idea here is
that you've got two different kinds of
information processing activities here
some better automatic
all of that operate on consciously
and some that are controlled operate
consciously and the resign introduces
theory is that
carmen was the first
to articulate this distinction between
automatic
controlled or automatic unconscious
processes
and the general idea here is
limited cognitive resources but all the
mother processes don't take up any
resources
so if you're processing something
automatically you can process a lot of
things that uh... that at a time or so
you can processes information in
parallel
but also depended on the what has been
automata eyes
dollar did give some enterprising stings
but on public place you can do that on
consciously of lord
so common introduced this distinction
between automatic
and overall unconscious and a conscious
or controlled processing that is
basically dominated the study of
attention ever since
it it's that distinction between
automatic and controlled processing
but i want to discuss detail today there
is the young
capacity model of the century
again
of will skip through the talked about
that a little bit last night
already reinforced
what the importance all commons called
the capacity through the tension was
in the traditional view the traditional
viewed as characterized by this
conflict with this controversy between
late or early selection of late
selection please of attention
there was a bill that there was general
agreement
elementary processes
that is
so called a bottom-up
information processing all that
activities
that focus on
hall and a lot i seen the all perceptual
structure of the physical structure of
the state was everybody agreed
that those were performed moral esprit
consciously
more or less outside the scope of the
pension
the debate was
all about another della about
guarded conscious prophecies
all of that had to do with
complex processes certainly that had to
do with
semantic org meaning analyses
and the traditional view was
that these tended to be performed
uh... could be performed
the revisionist view that comes to us
from carmen
that's not the report distinction
there are elementary prophecies that
could be performed pre attentively
get whatever they are
so even elementary mean analyses could
be performed preoperatively
complex processes
can become good can be performed on
consciously to provided that their
automatons
provided
that they're automatons you can do a
lots of complex things called on
unconsciously
pre attentively
as well
and to this prompted this new
that even complex processes
can be performed outside
boundaries of conscious attention
all beyond began to began to take hold
in the nineteen seventies
with a lot of research that was done on
various aspects of automatic processing
here's what we were in
fall
well buchwald of the art of the very
bottom interesting the comes to us from
our data burge handle and
producer nils
palm
from talking about
how we get a lot of it has to be in
skilled performance
and one of the burden samuels argued
was that there are certain complex
skills
that simply cannot be performed
consciously
this if you tried to perform them
consciously you'd never get them done
anybody here plays a musical instrument
a special if you play the musical
instrument well
you know that if you're if you're if
you're playing followed that with all
the line of music on of them clarinet a
red trumpet or something like that
you do not say to yourself
all i just press the key for c_ sharp
now i have to press the key four d or
the british or poor whatever if you did
that if you're playing the piano
you would never ever get the peace or
finish
rather what happens is that skilled
pianist
execute
called all the pieces
all of the automatically more or less
automatically
they don't have to think about what
they're doing all the time
they just play the please
and they
have automata ized
these all of the runs and trails of our
page it was all the other things that
they do basically by
by virtue of the fact that they practice
a lot more than the rest of us do
who were america
uh... near amateurs
so the idea here is
but if you're going to perform something
complicated
you can't do it all consciously or you'd
never get it done
some components of skilled performance
have to be unconscious
la virgin samuels
gave us literally definition of a lot of
intensity may somewhat
when you perform something automatically
whatever you're doing is immediately
processed in the long term memory and
that's the case
even if you're putting even if you're
paying attention
onto
durden do something else
so was killed piano player for example
might be thinking of the overall
structure of the peace
might be looking through the orchestra
conductor to see what he's doing might
be waiting for the violence to come in
although it or whatever
but he's not thinking about the passage
is going to be plane right now
because he's got that
if you will in his uh... in his fingers
now liberation samuels didn't use a
musical example
they used called the the example of
redeemed
which is something that everybody here
in the big in this role
has as a deal that there's a basic
cognitive skill
fiber to the fact that you spent
called something like the west thirteen
fourteen fifteen years
in school
what liberty samuels did was to go to
give an example
how weird is that we get
bulb though the words on the page
to the meeting all the words and are
heads
and they say look
what's that but what happens is
all the information you've got on the
pages what they call graph you make
information
like letters
printed on the printed letters
they said the process over reading
goes something like the following
the first thing we do
is we have this graphic information on
the page and we apply a set of feature
detectors that analyze this griffey make
information into its elementary features
so for example the letter alright
consists of a single vertical line
the letter s
consists of
open
curbs
the letter are consists
of a vertical line
and
and an oblique
the letter q consists of a close
and an oblique light
the letter p_ consists
angel about above the final vertical
line and uh...
and occurred
letter p_ has the same features is the
letter are except the letter or
has this
all that has a citywide
they argue that as we learned to read
what we learned to do
is to analyze
will do get the individual letters
into their constituent features
so we recognize them as
tonight and i sat sun or it's a pizza q
or or whatever
and they argued that these feature
detectors
are intrinsically automatic
that is were built by evolution if you
will
the presence of certain features
individual all good
individual all indicated environment and
we don't have to learn that we don't
learn to detect vertical lines and not
open circles and closed circles
that hold on innately
by virtue of soem automatic prophecies
and of course called
most of the as one of the most of you
will know all of their cuba land weasel
won the nobel prize in physiologic
medicine
by hard actually identifying called
dignity in the yard adat kat visual
system all of a set of future detectors
that through just that
that protect lol
a white dove of dark org dark spots
against white
background white spots against dark
background insults and stuff like that
the general idea is that
these feature detectors operate in much
the same way
but that's not enough to get you really
because next thing you have to do
is to
be able to recognize all that certain
combinations of features represent
letters in the word fiber fee all of the
language all of that
that you know
and those of you probably don't remember
this but if you've taken all of those
old above some certain foreign languages
recently
all you know
that this is a michelly effort for
on if you take russian
for example elementary russian words
where there's a very very different
alphabet or greek
you know that you have to spend a lot of
time
of growth low learning the difference
between all may go and saudi and
five-year-old that kind of stuff
it's a different
it's officially effort fault
and then once you get that one singapore
able to decode the letters
then when you add that as you learn a
language at that as you learn to read
you what you learned certain spelling
pattern codes
i before e_ except after c o it looked
like a let's solve it is a is a neighbor
or way okay
that's a that's the spelling pattern
code
that helps you again
all of the globe read the words that are
there in front of you
and then as the you have to put together
what matters and patterns of letters to
make and fire words and then all put
words together
to make employer called groups of words
and what of
what they are called la virgin samuels
argued
all of this stuff
recognizing letters
recognizing some spelling patterns all
the put it all together into words and
putting words together into phrases and
sciences
that's a nationally effort for
but becomes automata eyes through
practice
as you become a skilled greater you dont
have to think about it anymore you know
it's a p
you don't have to get all the decode the
word letter by letter
nobody here reads all they've been reads
it was caused
cut at talk tax
right you don't do it at
you just recognize the word cat and you
recognize the word cat because you've
read it over and over and over again
follows in two thousand sometime
all in your role
in your experience
but it started out hard
and if you don't believe me that it's
hard to begin but
take a look at what goes on in
kindergarten first grade as teachers
tried to teach kids to read it
most people get it
paul and they both of them and what we
mean by getting it
is a bit on a per work at it anymore
feature detecting is intrinsically
automatic
the rest of it according to this theory
of reading which is off
kind of generic theory of reading
uh... isn't something that's initially
offered full
and uh... bala traumatize through
practice
and that's the model for these things
now that the most demonstration of this
which is known as the stroop
interference experiment which most of
you probably know something hall
that bed shows
that at some point redeemed words which
to starts out as very hard for fall
all goes on on conscious or that you can
go on unconsciously
so for example
all in the dance troupes original
experiment
with the classic an experimental
psychology
all he would ask subjects to read color
names
home
or and all that
and would but the the trick here is
that some of the names were printed and
united colors were different
the color
that they named
and what's troop discovered was that
that turns out to be very hard
here's the data
from home
all but one of scoops experiment
here in this experimental condition
subjects are simply trying to name the
color all of the ink in which a word is
printed
that's all they have to do was named the
color of the egg
palm
all the uh... the trick is
that the word names are different
on here in the control condition the
word names the same color or it's not a
word of all it's just a block of letters
and you can say
that it takes people a lot more time
here in this experiment because that's
the same stroop interference effect
this is all but happened
after subjects did
two hundred trials the day
fort eight days in a row
and you still get
a little bit
of interference effect
alm
let's have a volunteer who wants to do
the stroop interference effect
anybody who saw
particularly feeling extroverted today
why do it
this is how it would be experiments done
this is an experiment in speed a
processing your job is to mainly inc
caller in which strings of letters or
words are printed
and do so in going to do with a lot
would
as quickly as you can
so these are the colors are going to see
that's we're going to call that blew up
there
jenkins
in thailand
green and brown
those of the four colors you have to
deal with
sold for practice
going to show you
short columns just six nonsense words
their dot meaningful words are just
letter strings
and what i want to do
is simply to pull out the caller
in which each of those nonsense words is
printed
do so
outloud
start for the top go down
and do it as fast as you can
you all set
no pressure here
excellent okay
now we're going to the same thing but
they are now there's going to be a
column of real words
rather than nonsense letter strings
and all i want to do is that
name the caller in which the word is
printed
forget that all you have to do
now we're ready for the real thing
okay those are just practice trials now
i've got four columns
words here
and their nonsense words
and called what i forget all i want you
to do is call out the caller in which
the word is printed okay there nonsense
words put so you can call them out
part anyway
start with the leftmost column go down
called to mexico will be no hope
donald uptown and will be finished
ari excellent okay now you know what's
coming
all we're going to do the same thing
again
all but alguna vez this time because if
it's a list of real words but what you
do exactly the same thing what should
tune in or the words
and just name the caller in which the
words are printed
hooker attacked
uh...
that's hard
okay it's very hard now there is some
tricks that you can do with the kinda
squared so that makes it hard to read
the words okay that that that's a trick
but
these subjects didn't do that
it's just very difficult and what's
difficult about what makes it difficult
is
despite the instruction
despite might clear instruction your
clear understanding structured
you can't help but read the words
that's bad they're very familiar working
for bid on time but i still didn't you
really remarkably well
all for all of them
for that both people achieved and a lot
worse
when you get to teach your own class if
you want to do
just remember
classroom demonstrations hardly ever
work
this one worked okay
but there are no sometimes you have
people falling down when they're doing
the strip testable with something
so anyway
that's basically
ald that's basically the strip
experiment here
and reasonable or way about it
all of the power and stroup understood
this even goes as far back as nineteen
thirty-five is that you would joyous
can't help reading the words
you read the words
despite the fact that you're intending
to do something else
they're all a crucial automatically
on note or the reason to get
interference of course is that read the
word
goes to all of the fault of the word but
no
your knowledge of the word
tends to go to your speech apparatus of
the same time as your
knowledge of the color
tends to go to your speech apparatus
and you only got one speech apparatus
right so there's a little bit of
conflict there
but the idea here is
you just can't help with read
farm own words
so what happens is on the basis of
experiments like this
hello birds and other individuals
on order argued for a new view of the
relationship
between consciousness and uh...
and attention
everybody agrees that there is some kind
of a quibbling so some kind of
identification between conscious
consciousness
and attention you become conscious of
something by paying attention to it all
day long
and and and all that
and that there is
some sense to the idea that there's some
kind of pre attentive processing pre
conscious of the processing
and as we talked last time
in early selection theories of attention
the idea was to pre attend a presenter
processing
was confined to perceptual analyses of
the physical attributes
or stimuli
palm
and all the late selection theory said
yeah that's true but you could also get
prepared to processing
detected semantic processing
of the meeting for various kinds of
stability
and that debate between the early
allayed selection there is going on and
on and i'm still goes on
all but what happened here
out of the column and and others
began to
redefine attention not in terms of any
kind of companies are not limitation on
thoughtful on dont information
processing
but rather
redefining attention as mental effort
and the general idea here
is that automatic prophecies
dole require any mental effort
because they don't require any mental
effort they can be executed
outside the scope
or both
of conscious intention
you don't have to pay any conscious
o'fallon not it's not happening
all by virtue rating you're doing in
conscious awareness
and it's not something that you're
consciously controlling on either
and again the general idea is that all
up ta automatic prophecies
all have to have two forces
sol martin immediately automatic reflex
like
the operation of feature detectors
individual system for example
other prophecies because lord
traumatized
by virtue of extensive practice
whether it's the extensive practice of
reading
all of us
or the extensive practice at the piano
or the clarinet for the out with them
or the guitar
all four people who are who are skilled
musicians
and there are a lot of other examples of
this
uh... don't you don't get to see too
much of this of berkeley
but there are some people actually know
how to apply
a necktie
or and uh... that's something that once
you've done it for a couple of years
is something that's very automatic you
just do it
alone
on many of sports
related skills are done automatically if
you're a skilled golfer
or a skilled tennis player
on you just execute your strokes and on
that and uh... and all that were less
automatically
line in fact there is uh... there's over
bourbon legend anyway
that paid attention
laws that who was on such things as your
golf stroke will actually make it worse
on disco kind of
let yourself go get in the flow of it
and there are lots of other examples of
favorite example dissolved writing a
standard shift kar
purists kill driver of the standard
shift kar you're not thinking about
pressing down on the clutch and movie
mode gear shift and odds-on switching
gears when the rpm is get above two
thousand or whatever it is here
you don't have to think about any of
that at all
you just execute
the uh... the are the prophecies
automatically
there is a
formal definition of autumn intensity
kind of a consentual definition
that comes from a lot of theoretical
empirical work
uh... that was uh... dot mostly in the
yard
in the nineteen seventies
and all you've got it kind of goes like
this
order matic prostheses apart
inevitably evoked by the appearance of
all
stimuli in the environment
in the strip experiment
there's a word up their red blue green
brown whatever
and you just can't help relieve
automatically a vote by the presence of
some stimulus
the second
consentual property of an automatic
process
is that
all that is what we call incorrigible
completion
once the process president has been a
vote
it can't stop it just has to run itself
on the run it's helpful
sometime this is described as a
ballistic process on the analogy to a
ballistic missile
which is shot off
admitted to us
goals
malval
and uh... that lands
or a boy
for that matter wanted shot
or what what what what what the
governors ordered
the bullet just travels and philip
falls to the ground by virtual gravity
or hits a target
or whatever
so that's what we mean by incorrigible
completion
fall by uh... the bard efficient
execution
we simply mean
that automatic prophecies consumed
little
or no
cognitive capacities
they require little or no
mental effort
in order to be a executed
alone
ando fourth
or the consentual property
is what's known as parallel processing
it
and the point about parallel processing
is pre sliced li because
automatic
prophecies
consumed little or no attentional
capacity you can do a lots of the
message same time
they won't interfere
propped on cognitive processing that
require attentional effort
the idea here is that you've got a
single capacity of
or or both
of attentional effort
and if you're doing something
complicated
that requires a lot of that capacity you
can't do something else that's
complicated and requires a lot of
capacity but if you're doing something
that's complicated requires a lot of
capacity you can do things
very complicated or don't require a lot
of capacity
phone of these probably his automatic
prophecies
unconscious in the strict sense of the
term
uh... the appraisal use a couple of
times did it and of course
of bye-bye unconscious we mean they
operate outside phenomenal awareness
you word aware when you are aware that
you were reading some color names from
time to time but you weren't aware of
the process of doing it
or and they also operate outside a ball
and terry control it's something that
you can't help
and five strict sense of the term
what i mean there is
there's a general view here
you can't com directly away are all fun
run conscious process
is strictly unconscious is no way for
you to become consciously aware of it
all you can do is to know what by
inference
and we know about these what these
automatic process eased by inference
from things like response latencies
send-off
the speed of speed reprocessing and
things like that
so that's the general consentual
definition of automata city
there had been some other properties
that have been ascribed to automatic
process ease over the uh... over the
years these arb although the more
controversial
for example then hasher and rose acts
all proposed to extend the definition of
water but the city
they agreed
that automatic process these work
inevitably a vote by the appearance of
the environment of certain
fallen or the
or affective stimuli
and they all agreed that automatic
prostheses were officially executed and
that they didn't require any cognitive
capacity
but they suggested
that if you really have an automatic
process
you'd see no improvement
in that process
with training
on you may have acquired
the automatic process
through training
and people once it's automata eyes
it's not going to get any better than
that
only if you're a skilled pianist
all they saw what you can do
onto to with or the only so fast that
the other
going to play or pay joan
as fast as so that you could do it you
can't get better their physical
limitations here
the second all above the proposal
that hasher exacts made was that
there are essentially no individual
differences
in the engagement of these automatic
prophecies of what they are really meant
by that was that
home
things like like you and personality
audra traits and all that jazz just
kinda been matter as long as you are
traumatized the process anybody could da
anybody could do it
they also suggested interestingly
that automatic processing is working age
invariant
that is once you
automata life to process
you can basically kept it
all and it did indicate of with full
that at least with normal aging one of
the fit one of the things we cn alleles
farmers disease for example in other
demented illnesses
is that would be info there in early
stages of alzheimer's disease
all of the than the patients can do
pretty well
so long as they recorded so long as they
were like just on the automatic
processes
but in the late stages of alzheimer's
disease even
the automatic processes begin to fall
apart
but in normal aging
all of the diesel automatic prostheses
seemed to be invariance across age
and then finally these automatic
prophecies tend to be independent of
arousal
small group called you could you could
do when you're dry was that you could do
the when you're excited
and it just doesn't matter
reasoned that doesn't matter is or
dramatic process these don't depend on
cognitive capacity
arousal levels will affect how much
capacity you've got
so arousal levels are going to poor or
or going to apec performance of
conscious processing
but they're not going to practice
beneath the performance of an
of an automatic unconscious process
precisely because
hardy's saw
prophecies don't or consume any kind
haldol
called cognitive activity
so now all this might be really familiar
to you all from other sort of the other
psychology courses
because you've seen something like water
but the city before
in fact the concept the cotton that the
concept of a lot of interest to be in
cognitive psychology
and cognitive science
has its roots in physiological
psychology we have
d_n_a_p_ eight years
uh... like spinal reflexes
that are on a bed that are displayed
automatically
on use of uh... familiar example see if
i could do this without
collapsing the table
if my position hits my patellar tendon
i'm going to give a patellar reflex
and that's a joke it's at the same
automatic stimulus response
min if i have my spinal cord
the of the art of final words
that are controlling the reflex
can't communicate with my brain you're
still going to get
spinal reflexes no
there's just automatic pistol cocked
kind of karna control
and there are other than a tax season
invertebrate animals
alaikkum all of this
of of the flying towards light for
example
automatic
they're just built to do that
uh... and instincts like alone
imprinting decent things like that
that's automatic
loaded they're just going to do it
on condition responses plunder
traditional learning theories
traditional stimulus response learning
theories
were also held to be automatic
pablo once pat one dog
learned the connection between the bell
and the me powder the idea was that the
sound of the belt automatically a vote
asawa very reflex
uh... in the animal
for thorndike's cats or skinner's
pigeons
or once they were in the connection
between the uh... between the key or the
bar press and all of them dot the food
risque for whatever
orbit but
the appearance
of that stimulus evoke the response low
you devote the response automatically
so that that
that idea was kind of carried over into
cognitive psychology and cognitive
science
with the idea
automata city can be acquired through
learning through extensive practice
with some kind of has
called
and then that the other of the kind of
corollary idea here which is not been
tested all that much
all in the laboratory
that one something has been automata
life
you can't
do you want um but rises you can't
make me you can put it back under
conscious control
no later in the course
when we talk about the experimental
literature on medication
we're going to feel probably not true
that one of the effects of at least
certain forms of meditation is to do you
want homicides
processing
so that you can reduce things like the
simple fact
of for example it's very cool
but we're not there
the next although
uh... but next all applaud that chapter
in this
are comes to us from our richard colby
done canadian psychologist now at
washington university
and uh... the for those who said what
the way we've been talking about caught
american controlled processing
we've tended toward the end of flight
automatic processing with certain kinds
of tasks like redeemed
and controlled processing with all other
kinds of tests
unattached
is that that's not quite right
you can it's not if it's it's not kosher
classified
tasks as either automatically or
controlled
rather he argues
every task
some components to it
better performed automatically
and every task has some components to it
better control that better performed in
a uh...
in a controlled fashion
and dick armey said about developing an
experimental paradigms double hours to
separate out
the automatic and controlled components
all performance of any kind of task
uh... and determine
there ought
and determine their relative strengths
let me give you an example of the kind
of thing that
thought he had in mind
here for example
called is all very dog common dalton
haha of the fighting
in the study all volatile dot beijing
memory
which is that there are substantial age
differences
in performance on a recall uh... bill
task three recall past
but there are essentially no wage
related differences
in performance on recognition test okay
so if you get older
these are subject to their six days
you're not recalling things as well
subject
uh... do in their twenties
but if you're just perform or right
below the recognition passport doubled
which was passed through something like
that
there's no age difference on at all
fact it's an empirical fact
or that there is differences and recall
but not age differences recognition
puzzled people for a yelp
for a really long time
and george member avenue c ought uh...
of the san diego and larry jacoby again
argued
maybe arguments over slightly
differently
but they both of them said look
recalling some pena recognizing
something their very very very different
cotton kind of cognitive function
defense first
recall occurrence of as all function all
the retrieval of certain kind of
information from memory
you have to
do that consciously you have to do that
some kind of delivered way and it kind
of looks like it's got a lot of
conscious control
onto it
if i say to you
what you have purdue their last thursday
night faithful
valuable doing thursday night where was
i who was having dinner with and and all
that cuts have got engaged a lot of
on onto that building
called whereas if i give you our
or the two altered of course choice
recognition test
there's just not a lot pole vault home
old that that goes on they argued that
in fact a recognition can be
accomplished by either rogue troop
processing
invade some cases recognition is
accomplished by
retrieval
that is you consciously remember an item
when it's presented to you
but other times or recognition could be
mediated merely by of feeling all
familiarity
and the best way to describe this
feeling of familiarity
is when something rings a bell
you go to a party you look across the
room this easily
scene that person's were before
yeah i can't remember where yet can't
remember when you can't remember the
name
then you find out at your roommate or at
your roommate's girlfriend or something
like that
unhappy tell you i had this experience
once i was standing on a board station
looking
at the people across one
obscene from someplace before
and then i get home later in the day and
it was my across the street neighboring
somehow i forget the subway stations all
that to you
i didn't consciously recognize them at
the time but
they rob bell went off i'd seen this
person somewhere before everybody's had
that kind of experience
all and the idea here is
this kind of recognition by familia
by familie already is mediated by what
we call on automatic priming effect
the stimulus
trigger something in memory and triggers
as feeling of memory
the station
between recall which is always a
function of conscious retrieval
and recognition which is sometimes a
function
on some kind of automatic
prime either a bell ringing process
on lead dog led both member and jacoby
to suggest
that what happens with with aging
is that eighteen impairs only a little
conscious
recollection
material and has no effect
on on various kinds of
a prime minister
so jacoby went on
on board with with some of his
colleagues to study this process
and i'm just going to show you these
depth the since these experiments
just as a way of illustrating
how in general we can separate
conscious for one conscious process
these because that's good let's move on
set the stage for what we do arm
for what we talk about
on next week there's a little bit of
mathematics here
i don't want you to get hung up on the
map
okay i'm never going to ask you to read
reproduce these equations
if you want more information about it
it's in the lecture supplements
but i have to show yes
let's look at what i would add a note
that a couple whom typical kind of prime
minister actresses
priming effect from stem completion test
a magic that i've asked you to study a
list of words
density
and then after you started the list of
words i give you a stem completion
status
farm lol bis dams
part the first three letters all old
targets
old old study targets that were on that
were on the study of us
like do you have
which can compete be completed with
density
and then for crowd control condition
new ones studied low-risk
like nec
that you haven't seen lately
and mobile happened when part whew when
this when when this happens
argues that
if i simply say
but i want to do is complete this
with the first word that comes to mind
that's how would you do stem completion
test
going to complete this with the first
word that comes to mind
most people will complete the with
density
because they're just study density
but there are lots of other words like
dentist
and dental handled and all of that
that work for perfectly good of
completions
but you don't think about you've been
primed by studying the word density
the complete
the stem deanne
that word as opposed to one of the other
all words
so now what you're totally did
was towed the body's aden part of the
addicted technique
which is called the
method of opposition
which is intended
conscious controlled prophecies
unconscious automatic prophecies in
opposition
to each other he starts out the same way
we do in the standard done completion
test
this study a list of words like density
then you have a stem completion test
spectrum consists of the stems of old
studied target
spends all of new
previously on the studied all morris
but he'd prefer to go forms a trick here
in one condition of the experiment
jacoby says to a subject
what i want you to do is the complete
each
stammer with
an item from the study alerts
and if you can't do that
just complete
the stamp with the first word that comes
to mind
also
for example a density
the instruction is too
palm darden is to complete the word
of the complete the stem with the word
that you remember from the study
now if you think about that for a second
there are two ways you can do that
you can complete den with density
because you'll remember you study
density right you can complete the word
the complete the stabbed with a target
by virtue of conscious recollection
but even if you don't consciously
remember
the word
still by virtue of this automatic
priming
of the process density might be the
first word that comes to mind
so the inclusion condition
capitalizes on both conscious retrieval
and on unconscious priming
now we get
to the exclusion condition
in which to colby says stupid subject
i want you to complete
argued stem with and english word
any invoice word will do
so long as it's not one from the study
list
you have to exclude the items
the study was
and if you think about that for a second
in order to excluded item from the study
was
you have to consciously remember
that it came
the study was
so the or did in the exclusion condition
the only way you're going to
called for
diya and
with density
as opposed to
which is supposed to do
completed with the word like dentist is
if
the word density is primed by virtue of
the previous study experience
comes to mind automatically
and
you don't consciously remember
because of you did consciously remember
it
you'd save yourself
i can't use that word
i gotta think of some of their work okay
so uh... this way what jacoby tries to
do is to put
conscious
controlled component
recognized or or both
uh... over of retrieval
in opposition
to the automatic on unconscious
on component
so now what we do is
bob we look at
what what jacoby did was to look at the
age differences
in performance on the inclusion
and exclusion
uh...
uh... conditions of the experiment
and what he get first
something like a standard
age difference
so the young perform better in the
inclusion condition than the old that
you will do
and this makes sense because the
inclusion condition
capitalizes on conscious recollection
and that's something that
elderly people don't do as well as young
people
until you get this
you get different
that looks like a difference here but
it's not a statistically significant
difference
in the exclusion condition
are basically
audit anything the all the performing a
little bit better
young people
okay which is kind of a mystery from the
street willful uh... in a second
but basically here's the pattern a
performance
young
do better than old
in the inclusion condition
the old to little bit better
and beyond
in the explosion condition
and i just called me argues
that you can take
they don't like this
and use it to estimate
the automatic and controlled components
of performance
and you do that
europe formulas were not going to go
through the whole thing
but you can see the logic of it if you
just look here
in the inclusion condition remember
items will appear in the inclusion
commission
are in there by virtue of conscious
recollection or by brit robot arm at a
crime
so we argued
that you can estimate the conscious
component
of past performance
basically by
subtracting the number of
produced in the explosion condition
from the number of targets produced in
the inclusion condition
the more you got conscious control
the more you want to be able to x
consciously excluded
i got on the front yard
and once
you've got c
you can just by simple eligible
find out all involved what what what job
what what what
what the automatic performance
oval but the automatic component of
performances
if you're if you want
with the whole story it's in the lecture
supplements we don't have to do that
here it is bien sur
we called about seventy six percent of
the items in the inclusion condition
compared to fifty five percent for the
old distance from the figure i gave you
before
young hotly recalled about twenty six
percent of the items in the exclusion
condition about thirty nine percent of
the items of by the old
over these figures
make sense
the inclusion tradition
capitalizes on conscious recollection
young have more of it
they were able to exclude better
because state consciously remember of
these items inouye
i'll bet that the elderly don't but if
you will apply to call these formulas
what you get here
all admit you're you're able to ask them
eight
the automatic and controlled
on blood components
on this it seems different from what you
get here
the following
the age difference and recognition
okay huge difference in stem completion
whatever
is due in part early pick age
differences
the controlled component
past performance
there's no age difference
in the automatic controlled by the new
york another component the past
performance
and that's exactly what
for example hatchery veterans acts
would have predicted
so here what we've got
is a technique
the method of opposition
which tries to put
automatic uncontrolled prophecies
opposition
to each other
to generate data
that allows us to
harder to estimate the strength
both abuse of the both of these kinds of
prophecy
because
the young
processing they're able to
include more
exclude
more of the targets
but the than the old or
the old are getting a lot of their
or items in the inclusion efficient by
virtue of something like automatic
and it's that same automatic priming
coupled with a problem in conscious
recollection recollection
that uh... route
that the whole leads them to perform
less well all on the arm
we've got a method here
that allows us for the first time
to actually measure
conscious
past performance
and measure
unconscious test performance
and see
how they compare to each other that's
the important point
of this method of opposition
and this method now becomes used
in the whole raft of cognitive
psychology experiments involving memory
perception language and so on
all of which are intended
uh...
to uh...
the degree to which any particular
broadcast
is performed consciously in a controlled
manner that consumers attentive of the
pension or resources
one consciously
in an automatic matter
that doesn't
attentional resource
in cognitive psychology
the general of the general idea has been
as jacoby ordered suggested
most tasks are performed by a kind of
mixed of conscious
and on conscious
controlled
and automatic prostitute
but when the concept of a lot of mca
city
alm of was doda taken up by
social psychology
a growing number of social psychologist
argued that in fact
controlled conscious processing
relatively little
role a relatively small role
what we do in the ordinary course of
everyday living
that in fact
most of what we do
we do want to matically
we do unconsciously
we do on automatic pilot
thinking about anything
at all
this is all about the tendency in social
psychology that i've come to call the or
commit to city juggernaut
called because it's like that vehicle in
hindu mythology that kind of
carries the goddard
rules over everything in its path
home
you have to part of the next time when
we meet
all describe
how this concept of autumn it has to be
became important from cognitive
psychology into awk in into social
psychology
in a matter that suggested
we're all on automatic pilot
all the time
that are conscious
intentions
are conscious police
or conscious attitudes have little or
nothing to do
what we do in the ordinary course of
everyday living
if basically overspend on tap a
phenomenal ism
that says were conscious automata
we happen to be conscious
consciousness plays essentially no rule
in our behavior
put it on their way
we are orderly lacking unconscious
freedom of the will
but before we do that
we have to celebrate presidents day
so remember there's no class on monday
we'll be back here on wednesday and i'll
take you through
studies of out of necessity in social
behavior