okay
welcome back to berkeley for the spring
semester and welcome to
psychology one twenty nine also known as
cognitive science one oh two
consciousness course
alms i'm john cale strobe
all beer content provider
for the uh... for the semester
all some of you know republicanism
familiar faces
but in case it out
that's what i do have a lot of cognitive
social psychologist
calm
with clinical training
who's interested mostly in problems of
consciousness
especially the problem of unconscious
mental life
over the course of my career done quite
a bit of hypnosis research
also done a fair amount of research
having to do with things likes
and arm
and anesthesia
as a cognitive psychologist punchy
fleeing interest in the study of memory
especially autobiographical memory
and as a social psychologist
and chiefly interested in the study of
this
and you'll see
but i'm lucky
towards the end of the end of the
semester hollow those two interests
converge
if you're just coming to make sure you
got a sellable
sand you should take a seat 'cause we're
going to go the full fifty minutes
okay heart here's a basic information
for the class you're here so you know
all about that
albeit here from lecture monday and
wednesday at ten o'clock
classes will start promptly at ten ten
usual in berkeley time
and called will go
always straight through until
all until eleven o'clock
and that'll include today
my office hours are in my office mondays
and wednesdays after class
eleven o'clock a similar you're over
there
on lawrenceville new
also tried to arrive
here in the classroom
sometime before class ten-fifteen
minutes maybe i'll be standing outside
if you've got a quiet
great questions
and i will also alva stay after class
sahara assault
much like an
with the understanding of how to get
office hours
alm office hours are never convenient
for anybody
faculty were students
so if you can't get to office hours you
can always make an appointment to meet
in person or we can probably transact
most of our business home uh... body
email
an important all element of this course
of the discussion sections which will be
led by to graduate or graduate student
struc tures
let me introduce you are up to them laws
now it there in the back mona kim
all motors are u_c_-berkeley although
that's
was at u_c_-berkeley undergraduate shoes
off on hudson graduate work in education
and public policy and she's now a
graduate student here
indeed our school education
has an interest in emotion research
are christine foursome
although u_c_ santa barbara graduate
are now here at the art of the school of
optometry
greta student studying vision science
on has a special interest in the home
individual attention
bono will be doing the first place i a
lot of the discussion sections which are
out you know a pullman all thirty one
thirty eight
almost you know where that discussion
section
cubicle
all is
and christine will be doing a friday
sections in poland thirty one forty
oh roughly the same area
if you've never been in pullman all you
know it's kind of all
alm just go to the main psychology
department or office
turnaround
and keep going around that circle until
you find your room
that's how you get there
discussion sections will meet this week
policy toward can all get introduced
which others are tomorrow and friday
we discovered
malt
yesterday roughly six o'clock in the
morning
that due to some of the mysteries of
calaveras
three additional sections of this class
were scheduled for tuesday is where i
know where that came from there's never
been nine sections of this class
all of the somebody hit the wrong he
apparently
all of those of you who are still
registered for those so tuesday sections
we will do everything we can to
accommodate you in one of the thursday
or friday sections
on you've already gotten an announcement
for me about that
c_e_o_ raha advisor here in cognitive
science see carol snow
register for cod five one oh two
if you are registered recycling
twenty-nine which i think one of you are
at this point
tuesday section onto the folks in the
psychology department student services
office
also sorry about that confusion but
i don't think would be a semester
berkeley at telomeres didn't screw
something up loyally
that was our turn
okay primary text for this course is
auntie robin swallows sala consciousness
the science of this
all of them subjectivity
it's a pretty good dog pretty good book
you look on the back of the book you'll
see that i say it's a pretty good book
all
onslaught with one of the reviewers on
it
all imports
it's ok it's the best book available all
that saw that that's relatively up to
date and will go through the whole thing
there is a really good
text on north of the flames of
consciousness
slide bill far beyond the psychology of
conscious
which is very old
all published in nineteen ninety two
all for this course who used to have it
privately reprinted i can't do that
anymore for various technical reasons
last time i looked on amazon there was
one use copy available for a hundred and
twenty eight dollars
poem so all of this kind of a
collector's item
all but part of what i didn't know what
mister was to scan it
and put it up on the course website
or if you want to extra resources on of
scientific literature on consciousness
going up to about nineteen ninety two
we'll get it there
this is a terrific book
dalton
just a really really really good book
will also all during the first part of
course be reading some essays by
professor jobs for all of our philosophy
department here
all review we know a number all part of
that
philosophical were less philosophical
treatises on consciousness
people like roger penrose that bennett
david chalmers or and others
all of the they'll be reading that
what they basically as the background to
the lectures condo o on the mind-body
problem
and then just to kind of take us a
little bit off the beaten track we're
going to read a novel
all by david lodge one of england's
foremost all modern or writers he's a
really terrific
uh... writer
specialist in the academic satire
which are proof you want to know what
academic life is like a special evening
lynch read one of his books and you'll
find out
hall
that has its ups and downs
all but what lodged at a couple of years
ago was to write a novel based on all
basically doll doll debates about the
nature of consciousness
on and uh... as you'll see as the plot
progresses
that he manages to talk shows are very
informed interesting way
on about dog dot above the various
aspects of the debate there a lot of the
in jokes
all of that you won't get all understand
now you will understand by the tiger
finished with the course
on and it's just a terrific read
paul for those of you who care about
such things it does have a few erotic
passages
polit is an academic satire after all
palnet
and uh...
did that you can skip those of you want
you won't be held responsible for the
montana exam
but dot if you stick with it
argue all find at least one of them is a
wonderful take gone numb only blooms
soliloquy from joyce and ulysses
all you if you're really interested in
all voted in literary aspects of
consciousness
lodges in academic
all of the literature scholar
what what for many years and uh... one
of the red brick universities uh... and
now in england
and he's collected a bunch of essays
don the role that consciousness plays
and mostly a late nineteen th early
twentieth century literature
well you're not required to get that but
i always plug it because it's a terrific
book
if you're interested
nam literature
okay all those three books raven's full
and sural and the lodge novel
alright billable for purchase of the
issues you bookstore you might be able
to get a better deal elsewhere i don't
know
as all today there will be two copies of
each of these on reserve
on at the education psychology one of
the
old they are available
for those of you who can't get enough of
consciousness
all recommend dog dog couple of other
all of that fact sort of use these as
text in the
in the young
uh... in this class before
revan slow is better than these but
they're not bad
susan blackmore is consciousness and
introduction
and read a carvers or exploring
consciousness
if you've got a lot of money burning a
hole in your pocket
palm
and you really really really interested
in consciousness
you will want to have these books
hold on your wrong on your shelf
if you really have a lot of money bernie
your hole in the park
and you're really really really
interested in consciousness
home
annette blocking his colleagues have
collected a whole bunch of basic papers
on the nature of consciousness all in
the heart of this anthology
and bernie bars
bill banks all have done the same thing
all of these are very thick books you
can use them as door stops
they're useful for killing
all insects all work
walked on
basically
mall most i mean it's important to the
site in new york loftier psychology of
consciousness
open to all the publication of these
folks on this kind of collected here
with their really really really good
books
all we're going to have to examinations
in this course solved midterm lol
roughly uh... middlemarch right before
we break for hopeful for spring recess
called and a final examination
all due to the enrollment and of course
all all of these old examinations we
mostly short answer or they won't be
multiple choice
all but they will be short answer
i said what what choice in question mark
there because
i keep thinking i'm going to do a
multiple choice examiners class and i
never do it
i reserve the right to do it
palm
the final examination will have a
curator portion also should be a second
midterm
and then of the non-committal portion
and then if you would have portion
on that'll give you a chance
to put the whole thing together
called one thing i don't do is make-up
exams all be there for the exams expect
you to be there for the exams
all of the applause something
terrible happens three minutes before
the exam
called you have a flat tire on the
freeway and you can't get in a
reasonable deal with that you're sick
uh... will deal with that
but otherwise so i'll be expected to
take the exam swollen at the time but
their schedule
discussion sections are an important
component of this course
discussion sections or a scarce resource
there even scarcer now than they used to
be with the budget cuts
also law they're available to you in
this course and we expected to be there
both attendance and participation and
discussion section count
cause it's a discussion section of your
not gonna discuss
now mike tyson will not be there
alm
each alert discussion sections is
formatted in such a way that
the uh... do yes i did want our
christine will all present a little but
maybe what richard for the first of
say twenty twenty five minutes or so
on touching on some aspect of
consciousness that we've been talking
about you know in lectures
and then the remainder of the time will
be spent here in the home
day in discussion
in addition important part of the
discussion section are set of real small
writing assignments
or there are nine of these not ten as
advertised in the syllabus you've got
calaveras isn't the only place
person around who makes mistakes that
the typo on my part
on
in which we just ask you to contemplate
a particular question
about some aspect of consciousness
and then post to called
d_r_ courses for web site on the space
some kind of responsible estate all
probly should be less than fifty words
shouldn't be more than two hundred fifty
words
hong
on the various topics
the deadlines for the essays are for
okay it's just like cinderella
right before midnight on a particular
day
all we want those things though
we want those things off
and their graded on a roller none
solved all the bases
so that if you
your response of
for the question posed
who say something
reasonable
and it's reasonably well written no
serious grammatical or spelling errors
or whatever
you get five points
if it's not reasonable
or it's all a grammatical and spelling
bass
alva
but uh... that's basically how that
uh... how that works for sid more about
that in a minute
grading policy there are twenty
twenty-five points available for the
class fifteen points for the midterm
hundred points from the alone
from the although the final
and then another seventy five points
from discussion section
all policy here is that all my classes
if you work in the late at least ninety
percent called for the available points
you're guaranteed some kind of a
if you accumulate eighty percent of the
available points are guaranteed some
kind of b
and if you get
one more than half the available points
you're guaranteed
some kind of see i do that
take the pressure off
some people are kind of experimenting
with of course that may not have all the
background of whatever
if you're living and breathing in and
relatively conscious yourself
you can accumulate
fifty one percent
all deal of the available points
oh so
everybody can get a day
if everybody
does that
all but in any event
that's uh... that's where that goes
okay there's of course website that i
think you know
find a very useful resource all for the
class you get that on b space
those of you who are enrolled or
waitlisted in the class already have
access
log too
uh... that for those
all others may be able to get access to
it dot as well say just login on as
usual
and that'll take you to a listing of
your course lights one of which will say
psych one twenty nine
even if you're registered for cogs
flight one oh two it'll still so he's
like one twenty nine
that's the way that goes
or click on that uh...
and you'll get to called or home page
the move
small looks like this
or without navigation bar
navigation bar down the left
and as you click through the navigation
bar you'll find a whole bunch of whole
bunch of different things
offer example you'll find a win for this
for the course syllabus
this looks pretty much like the one
you've just seen
forum posting number ten has been
deleted
or from this that has another feature
maldives song very useful
as well
which is that it contains links to a
couple of all items on the reading list
the revenues to overthrow land the large
books or the basic required reading for
the course
but there is some topics that they don't
cover
uh... adequately
paula and for that
purpose to hide
waldo put up so mall supplemental
all of the readings that are
that are required
and number syllabus all of us
that is all posted to the court's
website
actually has links
onto those readings otherwise you'll
find them in the resources
section
malval abused days
all those extra review board
required until after spring break so we
don't have to do with it
okay then all of their electoral
aspirations
all yugo resolve them
been introduced to this
before each set of lectures
so i send out obp
post of the course website
area preliminary also set of what your
worst rations
those got modified insults as a series
of lectures goal on
that after the lecture series is
completely concluded
i post the final version of electoral
istration therapy
as they uh...
resource
they're available free part three slides
per page
for those who want to uh... take notes
and there were
they're available six slides
for those of you who care about the
earth
all the
in addition there are those that called
might receive women for their war for
the course
i've only got thirty thirty one lectures
with you i can't possibly cover
the science of consciousness
argued that uh...
in that time
so the lecture supplements contained all
br presentations of these lectures
but they also go far beyond the lectures
on to talk about other along with other
details expanded various ways
you know again few
particularly interested in consciousness
or there's something i say a lecture
that you just didn't get the first time
around
or you may be able to uh... clarify
things looking i saw electrical
in any event
uh... they're there for you to use
and there's also a link to the for the
text
that that nineteen ninety two text that
talked about a little bit
taught before
all my scan these
every once in awhile webpage turns out
to be
followed
fuzzy or tilted or whatever
that you discover something like that
i'll just write me and tell me or that
that's the case at all
all fix it
as soon as i can
all gears exam information
for one of the page the takes links to
all the previous exams in this class
home
pre exam reviews
arby e before each example doo-wop
face-to-face review here in classrooms
some room like this
but also prepare a written
narrative review of the material for you
to use and preparing for your two exams
and then all i have to reach its amol
pose
the uh... scoring guide
that we use in grading the exams
halt along so you could get get that
kind of feedback
called the will
so you don't actually have to join a
fraternity restore you get all the best
the package and
they're right here
we can save you that initiation fee
there the internet bugaboo vspace forums
alm
i tend to fill about fifteen minutes
with lecturer i like to stop and take
questions and comments i don't always
want to do that i don't always doug
can't always answer reporters' question
in class
if you have a comment or question about
anything that comes up in the readings
are lectures
and i don't get a chance to address it
cleft
just posted to the comments inquiries
forum on uh... dotted all of these days
i'd check that every day
paula and if i see a comment or question
that i was forced to respond to
all respond to it within a day or so
that way the exchanges available too
for the entire class
in addition
all for each of those six sections of
the chorus one oh one three one oh six
fault there is a separate all form
that contains a space for you to all put
in your own
your forum posting so that we can see
that you've done that
or people can read them
or maybe breedlove maybe somebody in
your discussion section below also
responded to all of them to what you
fault
what you've written
call it that way because graded
although if you're saying section one oh
three
not shown here
just scroll down till you get your
section
and uh... hero
and your four post
so that's that
forget that there is anybody here in
psych two twenty two the graduate
version of the course there is one of
these for you on as well will talk about
that next week
okay so this is what the forum posting
thing looks like
denham just showing five here
which can scroll down to your own
discussion section
you've got to know what discussion
section urine
all and then do you're wrong
the your postings the instructions or in
the soloists
and there also
there also
on the space as well
for those of you are coming in without
too much background in psychology we've
got some other resources
you'll see a link
ought to general psychology
that'll take you to the lecture
supplements are prepared for my
introductory psychology course
psychology one
give you a nice factory if you haven't
taken psychology course before
poem
uh... that will give you some
fillmore moralist useful along the
background about things like memory and
perception
all powell
palm
i've also dog of links to the booth
supplements are prepared for a core
support on memory for a while
and also to the other course for the
future of social cognition so if you're
interested in
those topics
and you're interested in what i think
about those topics
you'll find that information
wrong here
on his course has been podcast sould be
recorded right now
all of this is a the case you have to
miss a lecturer you want to go back over
something you'll be able to click on it
on the elbow webcasting
website
called berkeley
sold first thing you want to do with
get there
webcast dot berkeley dot e_d_u_
click on courses
that'll take you to a listing volvo aldo
courses are available for this semester
were listed as cognitive science one oh
two
dot in psychology one twenty nine
also just go to the cognitive science
one oh two
caldwell link
click on that
and you'll be taken
to calls on the list of all the lectures
beginning with
alone beginning with
saw that's where that goes
now palm the one thing i don't have on
here little don't tell you now
we are also called pleased to have a
problem
told yes you see lecture notes
available for this class
there is no substitute for your own
lecture notes
documents a class you didn't get
something you're you just want somebody
else's perspective
yeah yes you see election notes are
uh... org are generally pretty good
also like
undoubtedly do
i do recommend them
called paul send out some information
about how to subscribe to those
but they are available also listed under
cog side one oh two that's like one
twenty
will be confused about that
one of the reasons the scores have been
screened all the podcast it couldn't be
put up on the website for people outside
of berkeley
also with the uh... podcast will include
the slides
and whatever rhymes whatever i say in on
class about them so you can kind of fall
on
with the uh...
with the lectures
if you're seeing this class bid if your
ticket
byu in this course all as they are as a
web testing you're not enrolled
and you want to access to be space
website
you should
email me
all and all all of them
make those arrangements
send you back home
access information for the space
that typically goes into people's spam
folders
if you don't hear from me check your
spam folder
and they're a part of the out there
for that reason
people here in class if you've got
questions that he ask a question i call
on you
please
encourage me to repeat the question for
the benefit of at people and
who are on with the who were listening
to the scores
alm
that's something that
odd that that's a bit
very bad habit that i have a not
repeating questions when i'm asked
because i'd come at one of just
engage with the person who's uh...
and so on
although the talking to me
but for the benefit of the folks at home
useful for me to repeat the question
all motor christina bite
zara dinner she discovered that i have
uncovered
okay syllabus is pretty uh...
pretty straightforward and pretty oh
well organized any questions at all
about the organization format of the
course
will you be required to do work p_p_ not
for this class
all of the psychology department has a
research purchase a patient program
all up and the result
research for just a patient requirement
for some psychology classes
usually the higher almond classes
all but troubled
so far
not for this class
even though
there looks like a high drama class to
me
we just we don't quite
couple threshold
wrong
so anyway that's
stuff when it is
there are
one children bunches of experiments
however available on campus for people
to serve as say paid subjects
and i'd always encourage people to do
that
it's one it gets you
sign up money for a pizza sometimes
or happpy so
or a slice
but it's mostly forties
and uh... and interesting
anything else about
phil course itself
i've the policy on the waitlist assumes
that we will do our best to
got move people off the waitlist into
our
into the yard into the class
we have a couple of constraints
the first is that we need to give
priority to psychology and cognitive
science majors who are seniors and
juniors
and the reason we do that is that this
of course that fulfills
graduation requirements for those majors
every one of these people's way out of
what we want to have you here we'd keep
you here forever if we could
all but we know you want to get out of
here
we want to facilitate that process
folks yet
wiped off outside of that
will move people in again giving
preference to senior and junior non
majors this courses offered every other
year saw from the spring of odd numbered
years
also if you're a junior now you're not
going to get a chance to take it next
year
you really want to take at this
do juniors if we can move some
sophomores and freshman into uh... the
prerequisites that's fine
all will do everything we can to do that
into the courses through a discussion
section
so your weight lifter waitlisted for the
chorus waitlisted for a discussion
section
so for next week or so
you should go to the discussion section
for which you waitlisted
and see if there's room
now we've got to accommodate these
people who were
accidentally registered for the tuesday
discussion section we're gonna do that
first
all but there still should be some room
uh... in the course
especially after
i finished today's lecture or certainly
after monday's lecture half the people
will leave the room
so long to be plenty of room
i'm sure
palm we have a number of foreign
exchange students here called us those
specially in norwegian contingent
are welcome
to berkeley
arm
and uh... you guys should contact me
bartholet thought just kinda make
yourselves no not just the norwegians
but everybody
whose they are part of the foreign
exchange student
also world so we know who you are
anything else about of course
all right so nuggets working actually
you can actually hear
that's good because
if you couldn't hear this is where the
screencast of coming from
or you get is this and not by
not my voice
sol they'd spend some time talking about
what we're gonna talk about
consciousness basically has to do with
two things
it has to do first with
awareness
it has to do with monitoring ourselves
and our environment
by virtue of being conscious
world where
we're consciously aware of what's going
on all around us
what we're doing what events are
occurring in the world
by virtue of being conscious
word aware of the contents of our own
mines
but that's not all the wrist a
consciousness
consciousness has not to do with joss
monitoring but it also has to do with
controlling ourselves and our
environment
by virtue of consciousness we engage in
voluntary activities we deliberately we
consciously engage
in various kinds of behaviors better
intended to meet environmental demands
on and achieve our own or personal goals
monitoring and controlling or two
aspects of truth quite different aspects
of consciousness
but i think it can see how at least in
logical terms they're related to each
other if you're going to exercise
conscious control it's something they're
going to have to be consciously aware of
it first
you can't consciously control something
you're not consciously aware of
or insolvency in any event
alva but uh... still these are two
different aspects of consciousness we're
going to
going to pay attention to
in this course
the problem of consciousness was set for
us in the are guarded
seventeenth-century basically by floss
for renee descartes
all who took it upon himself to try to
figure out what could be known
simply by the application of logic the
adopted a stance to be called all of the
the political doubt
so i'm not going to believe anything
anybody tells me
on their start from first principles
and he discovered that there was one
thing he couldn't doubt
which was that
he was conscious
okay
but he was doubting
right so i'm doubting right so that's
one thing i can tell
called
and he came up with his famous old
all of the book but by virtue of the
fact that party the experience himself
as thinking
he understood you do you resent that
he at least
or exist that that's what could you tell
ever goes to means
i think
therefore i a m
a little bit later
he all of them change the formulation a
little bit to safely race project i was
alright i_t_n_ ma i think that thinks
and this idea
that human beings are characterized in
our humanity by conscious awareness
not just that we think perceive or
remember but that we're aware
of what we think and perceived remember
that were aware of what's going through
our minds
really
on shifted
the whole
alm
uh... list of rust before us a p
from problems of metaphysics and
problems of ethics to problems of a
pistol biology problems of knowledge
and to set the stage of for later a
scientific analyses of consciousness
trying to figure out what consciousness
is
where it comes from and what it's good
before
topics aboard try to assess uh... say
something about
in this class
in the beginning this historical
beginnings of psychology william james
great american
our psychologist
late nineteenth century
arthur tried to define the other
psychology in his textbook the
principles of psychology
psychology instance define psychology
has the science of mental like
first fact ross that for a psychologist
as for that matter it was for descartes
thinkin goes on
is trying to understand
how it is that were able to think and
proceed even remember and do all those
other things with our minds
wendy shortened the principles
to the briefer course he'd change his
definition a little bit all the way
that's very friendly to the goals of
this course
by saying that psychology
is the description and explanation of
states of consciousness as such
psychology
for james anyway tried to figure out
what consciousness is
where home
and where it comes from
now in fact there was consciousness in
psychology before james
psychology i'd thought that uh...
extracts itself from from philosophy
and becomes law and uh... an independent
science
on basically around problem solve all of
them
problems of consciousness
the very first psychologist for people
like that defied themselves as cycle
physicists
and they set for themselves a problem
art racine full links
tracing the correlations
between the physical properties are
various tamil aryan be environment and
the psychological properties of the
experiences to which those stimuli
gave rise so in a very real sense
the very first scientific psychology
or was
or an attempt
to figure out the nature of of conscious
experience
a little bit later in the nineteenth
century
although a pioneering psychologists like
of the building won't
in germany and off
uh... you'd be pitcher or here in united
states
developed a retarded technique which
they called introspection
in which their subjects the subjects in
their experiments would try to describe
their
conscious states
as they were experiencing various kinds
of of stimuli
so what wouldn't into cheer would do
would be too will
manipulate some aspect on some stimulus
situation
and then all i ask people to describe
how they're conscious experiences of
they've changed
home philosophers
ogle used introspection who want to
explore consciousness long between
before when temperature
although that came on the scene
but offer void intention or the
difference
their introspection as were experimental
in nature
or the expert matter
was all of the manipulating the stimuli
by various ways
and there was some kind of quantitative
analysis of the data
if you want
had begun as a philosophical on method
and tried to turn it into into a
scientific one
later on
paul good to consult
all the baby all the made conscious
experience the center called for a his
psychology
it began with this really interesting
distinction which will come up
all again and again in this class
trying to distinguish between so i could
members was a cycle physicist
between physics
and psychology
is the science of the world as it exists
independent of an experienced in
individual there's a world out there
that exists whether word here or not
pauline exists whether were aware of it
or not and that's what physics tries to
describe
but psychology
is the science of experience
as it's dependent upon me and that they
had to be experiencing individual
there's not there's ascension being
who was aware of what's going on in the
world
units those experiences
that vote tried to all understand
over in his psychology and in fact
large part
opens program of research
was to engage in what he called the kind
of mental chemistry
complex mental states
feeling you have when you
fallen loan for
univ dinner or a c_e_o_ a traffic
accident out on oxford avenue or
whatever
and analyze that complex conscious state
intuit's elementary sensations images
and feelings
on psychology
called the psychologist in the late
nineteenth century
completely focused on consciousness
it was very much overhaul of the new
york
a scientific
unconsciousness
all of that
went away of course for those viewers
psychology majors and know something
about the history of psychology
with what is known as the behaviorist
revolution
in psychology
people like john b walks in and later
olympiad scanner
argued that james was wrong to define
psychology as a science of mental life
because from their point of view
they're going to happen
a science fundamental life you can't
have it the bad thing
on to read a text book about
and they are going to be remembered
bug this way
science is objective
sciences salt that doesn't run tries to
describe the world independent of
people's kinds of experiences
but the method of introspection
that was used by the cycle fiza system
was used by
the awb dubbed by by by people like
blood
necessarily subject it
all or would the cold wind gust people
to do was to describe their experiences
and and and dot blots and you can't have
an objective science
if all you're doing is asking people to
describe
their experiences
science also
depends on public observation the whole
point of science
is reputed to be able to confirm each
other's observation i do experiment you
know i drop some all softly go leaning
tower of peas on may fall on a
particular way
and then if you will repeat that
experiment you can do the same thing
consciousness
on watson pointed out is unnecessarily
private i have no why do you know
what's going on through your mind right
now
on uh... died and uh...
man i've had no way
volvo above the of making that kind of
or that they do that kind of pop in
public
because
consciousness is necessarily subjective
in private
and science is necessarily objective and
public
yet have
a science of consciousness
on soul what watson and scatter
did was to abandon on any talk of
mentality the any talk of mental life
and to refer exclusively
to wipe you could have an objective
public science of
which was
behavior
walks in and skinner and others all of
this i was what
let's just set aside this mental stuff
deal with that
hong
and let's draw a build a new science all
inside the fine psychology of the
science of behavior
on a and set of the said about the
problem
of tracking
the functional relations between stimuli
in the environment
things that we can publicly observer
that are above that that can be
objectively described
behaviors
behavioral responses to them other
things that can be publicly observed
and objectively uh... described
so the behaviorist revolution which we
began about nineteen seventeen
all and dot continued well into the
nineteen fifties and sixties and
psychology
really dispensed with consciousness in
all discussion of mental white
on you can go back into the
psychological literature
called of the nineteen thirties and
forties and fifties
and find a very few references to things
like perception
or memory
or problem solving and the reason for
that was those are all aspects like bob
mental lights are all aspects of
consciousness
and they were ruled out
of scientific psychology
basically body alone
behaviorist revolution
nevertheless there was a persistent
interest in consciousness there is some
people were not
of those swept up in the behavior of
revolution
all and there were people who are built
into the certain for colleges who said
look you know there's some really
interesting problems here
are dished all psychology for those of
you had a course in perception
paula uh... thaw the did the idea that
you can't add a lawyer for perceptual
experience into did so the stimulus
elements
because for whole experience is greater
than the folders parts
gestalt psychology
essentially
kept in interest installed consciousness
alive
on one perception
people
i was mostly in europe
or didn't have much impact on american
psychology and phil
on over nineteen thirty's nineteen
forties
there were people like all of rest would
work
who are interested in problems like the
span of apprehension
span out the problem of the span of
apprehension is
how many things can you keep in mind at
one time
answerers roughly seven plus or minus
two
if you think about it for a second
how many things can you keep in your
mind at one time is a question about
consciousness that would never have
occurred
to what's the risk of her to ask a
question alike that but i think that
they did occur to work for it
on uh...
harvard psychologist for a vague tool
part of or that fought against the
behaviorist revolution of the what he
called the score mix psychology
and again which can be summarized by
this very nice phrase
which will see echoes of or in this
course
mental life begins with a cognition
continues with a culmination a motive
and ends with an abstraction
an abortion
cognition
motivation an emotion
thinking
feeling and desire those are the
essential features of conscious mental
life
and whereas the behaviors
wanted to rule in out
of barbara donna bounds of a scientific
psychology
these guys like mcdougal
on tried to put it that kim i'll skip
that
it took until the nineteen fifties
really into the nineteen sixties
four psychology to get over its
infatuation with behavior is that
and it didn't basically all it as a
result of what's come to be called the
cognitive revolution
in vivid in psychology
wholesale change in the way psychologist
thought
or about though
about their uh... about their business
which basically argued
yet can't understand behavior solely in
terms of stimulus and response
and the reason for that is
mental life
intervenes
between stimulus response it's not that
stimulus that controls behavior it's a
perception of the stimulus the controls
behavior it's not events in the world
that control behavior it's expectations
about events in the world for control
behavior
and what the congress what the cognitive
revolution dead
was to put
cognition
and then eventually the rest of mental
life back into psychology arguing that
you really couldn't understand
organisms did
whether they're human beings were rats
are dogs or cats or whatever
without having something to say about
the cognitive structures and processes
intervened
between stimulus
uh... response
and if you look back in the history of
psychology of notes thus the salient
events in the cognitive revolution
those landmarks of the condom revolution
or all all had to do with consciousness
the first cognitive psychologists were
interested in attention
and how it was the were able to pay
attention to some things and ignore
other things while we're paying
attention to them
think about that per second
that's a question about consciousness
by virtue of pain attention to something
you are bringing it into a conscious
awareness
and by deployment your your attention in
one direction
but not another you wore
bringing something into awareness
and excluding other things
uh... from where so
ons whole research literature on
attention
or brought consciousness back into the
picture
similarly it all the work on uh...
so-called short term memory the magical
number seven plus or minus two rate
the capacity of short term memory short
term memory isis photos
a sense with a staging area for
consciousness if what you're aware of
that that what your award ticket will go
in for your head
this second that's what consciousness is
all about
and then there was although the
wonderful light of research early in
kind of psychology about mental imagery
where people were actually trying to
study
the pictures and other images there
we're going through people's minds
if you think about that again
what you're trying to do there
is to study objectively something that's
necessarily private
close my eyes i come up with an image of
my cat with a beer
what you're going to do all the david
one mika signs of that is what well what
does it mean
to have an image of your chat with him
here is a real images of a picture do
you think it's an image
all you do you just talking
metaphorically or whatever
by answering those questions or were
actually ask asking questions about
consciousness
the cognitive revolution
lame duck foundation for the revival
within psychology and other sciences
psychology and cognitive science
four in interest in consciousness
but at the same time
on but beyond the content of revolution
had all the other certain
affects
on the study of consciousness
in part because first the alm
told the public or the revolution was
was predicated on on the notion that
the computer is a metaphor for the mind
that's fine
but if computers a metaphor for the mind
nobody thinks their computers conscious
i don't care how big your mac book is
park it's just not conscious that you
don't think it's conscious right
all relief we don't think it's we think
it's conscious
right because i had that debate sometime
god relieved we won't
but that computers can process
information
they are not conscious and we think the
mind of like a computer
well what does that say about
consciousness right maybe i don't really
need consciousness to have a mind okay
so on the computer metaphor tended to
undercut
home the are glad that this is this
interest in consciousness on some other
things did too
on chomsky in cycle linguistics
norm chomsky argued that will bar
language capacity was based on knowledge
that we had about language that was with
essentially inaccessible to
consciousness
so uh... raised by issues about
whether consciousness was necessary for
various aspects of human performance
and then there were some philosophers
and some girls like all of those some
neuroscientists who mortgaged
consciousness was basically just a
matter of folks like ology
that that's your grandmother who talks
about consciousness you know
all and i and other run sophisticated
people
but if you're really going to be a
scientist
youths consciousness and
and all that
has to go the way of largest on uh...
and easter
get
get away from it
kind of though that the condom
revolution kind of cuts both ways
all talk about this a little bit more
although later on trying to progressive
next time
because the u
what's happened as a result of the condo
cognitive revolution
lots of psychologists and cognitive
scientists or interested in
consciousness
but this interest unconsciousness
leaves them to be uneasy about what
they're doing
on there is first and foremost is
positive istic reserve that's basically
all holdover from behavior as well
consciousness is private
consciousness is subjective how could we
have a science about something that's
that's private and subjected
home
there are lots of psychologists and
cognitive scientists who think we should
kind of work for the bottom-up let's not
attack consciousness now
let's figure out how perception works of
memory works something cute work and
that will put it all together
and will get consciousness
are there are people who think that may
be consciousness
we have it
obviously we have a anybody here dot
your conscious
everybody knows your conscious
but maybe consciousness isn't essential
for mental function maybe
good old just go on the following in the
dark
and then there's finally
all what dog who all went flat again for
thr is called the apple for novelist
suspicion
is nagging feeling
that although were conscious of things
contest those plays no pausable role in
the world
that it doesn't matter
without but whether we're conscious or
not
because consciousness has no functional
significance is the kind of the
background
after the scores
so what we're going to do got forty
seconds to tell you
first thing we're going to is we're
going to talk about various aspects of
the mind-body problem
those of you have a philosophy course no
part of the mind-body problem
what's the relationship between body and
mind it turns out that there are four
different mind-body problems paula and
we'll talk about those in the beginning
of the courts
next problem of consciousness is the
problem of the knowledge of our own
mines
we are
to what extent can deal with a or b
aware of what were perceive even
remembering and thinking and feeling
maybe introspection isn't
valid after all
and then there's a problem of
knowledge about their minds how do we
know
when somebody else's conscious
on of the problem the comes up when we
try to describe arief altered states of
consciousness like
anesthesia or drug affects or whatever
but also when we get back to a good for
the the the problem trying to clear out
nonhuman animals
or conscious or whether our mac book
really is
squaw after all
and then finally
questions about the origins of
consciousness where it is consciousness
come from
where does that fit in
in both the evolutionary scheme of
things and in the development
all the palm
of the individual organist
that's what we're going to do
for the next fourteen weeks
try to address is much of it is possible
thank you very much remember discussion
sections me tomorrow and friday
we'll see you on monday
have a good weekend