okay let's begin
and let's begin just for the reminder
something you already know
which is that we've got a uh... midterm
exam
scheduled in this class for next
wednesday
maybe more details about the exam
day after tomorrow this wednesday
when with any luck i will finished
writing it
but here's the basics
our midterm next wednesday march
sixteenth right here in class
although i have an in-class review on
monday march fourteenth
that'll be done as a question-and-answer
session
are those of you will check your e-mail
today
if there's anybody who doesn't check his
email every five minutes
those who haven't checked your email
today i sent out
a link to the rome
narrative review for the midterm exam
sold devil
these we take care of that
and i'll just answer questions
palm
the exam itself is going to twenty five
short answer questions
and i don't know whether there's going
to be choice or not but just haven't
figured that out yet
on i don't like to have choice
sometimes i have to
and it'll cover everything since the
beginning of the class
right up and
right up through are wednesdays
all you don't have the i've done of the
via blue book for this will give you the
exam you're right right on the exam
hauled all you have to do is bring your
heads
and uh...
and your family
ok we'll talk more about that
okay last
last lecture we talked about evidence
for implicit perception including some
little perceptions so-called subliminal
perception
balm which is a construct
that we have by analogy to implicit
memory
in implicit memory we have
representations and past events
that influence people's behavior even
though they can't consciously remember
those events
in the implicit perception we have
representations of
current events
events in the current stimulus
environment
that influence people's behavior
in the absence of conscious perception
of those events
and this is an old problem it so
fascinated one on and it's one that
raises the question of just
how much
processing can you get subliminally
just how much processing can you get
outside of awareness
a question that was raised by vance
packard and others begin in the nineteen
fifties
armed with complaints about subliminal
advertising
like the
example from the two thousand
presidential campaign
only in a clinical context
you can often see advertisements for
so-called
subliminal self-help tapes
which are supposed to present messages
letters subliminal that start that get
around the barriers on consciousness all
and i help you to ons lose weight stop
smoking
flying dog
somebody loves you do all sorts of
wonderful things
and in the experimental domain lloyds
silverman a all applaud
the late lloyd silverman the saws
psychologist that though
new york university
all road in the sixties and seventies a
provocative series of papers
suggesting that the sub little
presentation of the phrase
mommy and all you are one
had profound effects on people's
behavior
pawanticku though they could impair
various kinds of aspects of
mental performance in through the
private people and others
and would also improve performance in
normals
silverman was a psychoanalyst
as you might guess
all but the berry idea
that a phrase like a mommy and all your
one what the hell does that mean to
begin with
all
or you could have all white seven
presented sublingual lee
all-new could analyze that for me no
doubt demeaning what affect your
behavior in various kinds of ways
these are reprieve different ways of
asking
the question about the scope of
subliminal perception just
how much processing and all how much
processing can you get
we can answer that question in part
palm
and unordered
show you how we've answered that
question or tried to
argued introduce you to one more
subliminal perception paradigm were
implicit perception paradigm
which is a halt
known as some little affect iv
the studies are showed you last time
were also subliminal semantic priming
the meaning of the prime dr
influences the processing ave
semantically related word alike vs
and then subliminal affect a priming
it's not the denote a div meaning of the
prime that influences the processing of
the target
it's the connotation meaning of the
prime
that influences processing of the target
whether the prime
represents
i think that's good or i think that's
bad it's a motion or on a balanced
and so when these kinds of experiments
is a paradigm devised by anthony
greenwald tony greenwald s university of
washington
you present subjects with an aspect of
lee balanced
a good thing
friend of
or a bad thing like enemy
you mask the primed for the subjects can
see it consciously
and then your present them with an
affect of lee balanced target
a good thing like wins or a bad thing
why closes
and the subjects task is simply to look
at the target
and make a judgment
about whether the target represents a
good or a bad thing
that's all you have to do with the
affect their judgment
and the general idea behind subliminal
affect depriving is that the affect of a
list of the prime or to influence affect
him
judgments about the target
so that if the prime is a good thing
that ought to facilitate judgments about
good things
vote impaired judgment about bad things
if the prime is a bad thing
it ought to facilitate judgments about
bad things
and uh... inhibit judgments about good
things
and so it does
here are three early experiments by hall
by greenwald
and his colleagues
in which we have
an affect a prime minister affective
target
and here we have
the relationships between them galen
green
we have a positive prime and a positive
target
in purple
or blue i guess it is
dark blue on negative prime in a
positive target
in white blue what positive private
invented target
and in of
a negative prime and uh... negative
target
and what you can see here
a nice priming effect
soldiers group prime in fact that could
be called how a double whammy
if you have martha what they are the
positive prime
that facilitates
all borrowed would be aspect of
evaluation of a positive target
compared to what caused the private
negative toward it
if you have a negative
prime emanated target
that the silicates
performance all of the final processing
compared to
a positive primal indicative target
now this is a case
where there's an eighty millisecond
almost all of the whole interracial
crime
driven its mast
in this case it's not mask so the
primers consciously perceptible
what you've got in the middle is
and eighty second any millisecond prime
that's messed so that the subject can't
see it and you can still see
significant
priming affects
and here
all you've got a forty millisecond prime
only half the direction for the prime
and then followed by the mask and you
don't get much of a primate effect of
the positive case
but you do get so still gets on prime
unitech turned the negative case
let's just focus on
this one's for a moment which is the
standard of of the very end here
you get it may be eighty milliseconds of
the prime at its best to still don't see
it because of the mask
palm and all
to get nice
the beasley subliminal
of the prime minister
here's another way to plot this data
like this is under another study by huda
what by greenwald
all here
we've all plotted be detected bility of
the prime basically the percentage of
trials on subjects
all can detect
trial
and all of them
here we have the magnitude of the prime
minister
and at the
calm but that the at the crossover point
where the prime sarraj's zero detect
ability
you're still getting
a significant primate affect so that's
just another way of showing
that this'll this psalm
called the factor prime minister
is in fact home
is in fact
unconscious priming effect
subjects or not conscious of the crimes
they don't consciously detect them
but you still get a significant affect a
priming effect
noticed by the way
then with the magnitude of the affect of
prime minister act is much smaller
when the prime is on conscious that when
the primers conscious
capsule kate that's not that's not a
problem
the point here is
that you do get some private affect even
when the prime itself
well that's that's the that's the first
of our limitations here okay
it's not that
consciousness makes no difference
to the prime minister act
consciousness makes a big difference to
the prime minister act but you can still
get priming even when subjects are
conscious of the prime
here is another limitation
what dog rewarded here
was look at the
the a synchrony between the presentation
of the prime and the presentation of the
mask
that is to say
basically hollow along the bu yacht the
prime is presented the subjects
seventeen milliseconds which is
pretty short that's about as short as
you can get on the standard computer
thirty three milliseconds four fifty
milliseconds
and what you can see is that you get out
nice priming effect
if the prime as presented for a third of
a second
unsorted done thirty three milliseconds
or fifty milliseconds
if you present the prime for all the
seventeen milliseconds
you don't get much more primary effect
at all so
you have to do these things called right
the prime has to stay on for a
reasonable period of time
okay before it's masked
or you don't get to know or you don't
get the affect
here is another all aspect of the legal
limitations on subliminal f active
priming in the previous correct what i
showed you
was the
through all of the amount of time that
the
prying
is presented
the all
the prime time interval between the
presentation of the prime the
presentation of the mass
here mogra looking at
is the interval between the presentation
of the prime
and the presentation of the target
okay
all whether the
the your private presented superwoman
away here and green
or sub liberally ought hear in blue
if the prime is on math
so that it's clearly bizarre bowl to the
subject
the prime targets stimulus onset they
say gritty doesn't make much difference
yeah there's a little bit of random
variation but it doesn't really make
much difference
but when the prime is subliminal
you will only get a primate effect
if the target is presented really
quickly
after the
all that after the time right after the
prime is presented
sixty-seven milliseconds which is not a
lot of time
you've got a nice priming effect
eighty three milliseconds just a little
bit more delay
prime infect goes down
a hundred or two hundred milliseconds
and the prime minister basically goes
away of goes away byerly
so again
there is semantic processing and there's
affect a processing of unconscious
primes
but only on dirt very of limited
circumstances the prime has to be on for
sufficient period of time
the prime dog target
can't be too long
this is all less than a second
yurman hapless second
palm gov goes between the presentation
of the prime of the presentation the
target
the prime infect disappears yet
yeah this is the prime
target stimulus onset it with a
simplistic
the devote the time
between the on some of the prime
and the onset
four hundred milliseconds that's less
than half a second
if there is a very very very short
duration
between beyond some of the prime in the
on some of the target
you can get
follow subliminal priming effect
but the longer that duration
experiments
the less priming you get
and it doesn't have to expend a report
this is less income for the second
levels like it
there are some temporal limitations to
these priming affects
on they don't last very long
uh... involved in
uh... implicit
uh... of perception
here's another really interesting
limitation
which has to do with the amal and of
processing you can perform
on a subliminal prime even under
fall optimum conditions
this is another experiment by greenwald
is very very very clever experimenter d
worked on this project for about a
ten years
didn't do anything else
uh... and uh... really did some nice
work
all the studies that i've shown you so
far involved
the single word prime
affecting processing of a single word
okay whether it's more cells experiments
doctor priming nurse
or greenwald's experiments
enemy priming
word like loses
what greenwald did law in this
particular experiment
was to construct
true word of crimes
from his original stimulus materials
and what's interesting
is that if you construct a true word
prime
from to negative words
you can get a phrase with a positive
connotation
hero wins
hero and wins for both positive words
positive positive
the implication is positive heroes are
supposed to win
enemy wins
here's a negative word
combined with a positive word
the implication of the phrases
negative
you know one your enemy to win
our hero loses
a positive word combined with a negative
word
you plication the phrase is negative
you know one heroes to lose any more
than you want enemies to win
enemy loses
a negative word combined with a negative
word
it's a good thing
okay
so if people get that
if people can process the arabic the
conduct a newbie villa two-word prime
a phrase like enemy loses or what up
crime affect of judgments about positive
targets
okay so that's what you want to look at
and the answer is
also here
we've got arm
to positive allahu phrase granola
considered too positive words
we've combined the two are conditions
where there's a positive and negative or
word and then you've got negative a
negative words
this is the process of the magnitude of
the prime minister act
and what you can see here is
palm
on negative negative fall
called
phrase
connotation really positive being affect
early positive
or a prime processing will positive
target and it doesn't
okay those are very long response
latencies
compared to these others
these two conditions positive positive
and positive negative
they do pride
positive or positive target but they
don't prime processing of a negative
target if anything
too negative words
facilitates a little bit
the processing of a negative target
so what that means is
people tend not to extract the meaning
at all but true words to a stimulus
what to word prime
when that crime is presented
subliminally you've gotta have super
liberal you've gotta have conscious
processing for that
justo
bug jitters just to kind of rome this
out a little bit
if people can't
figure out
that the word under prop up the phrase
like
enemy loses is a good thing
what could they possibly do with the
long
complicated cycle went over the queen
mumbo jumbo phrase
money and all you are one
much less
somebody repeating you will not smoke
smoking is bad for your body you need
your body to live and all those other
things
that allegedly appear on subliminal self
help tips
yeah i just can't do it
subliminal processing
is simply analytically all ltd
while you can only do so much
semantic processing or effort to
processing
all they subliminally presented
so just to summarize this little bit
limitations on subliminal perception
the limitations are brought the via fax
or relatively weak
all subliminal implicit perception
affects in the typical case are nearly
as strong as implicit memory of facts
for reasons altogether the second
second the effects of our time limited
the prime
the all interval between the
presentation of the prime of the
presentation a mask
can't be too short
it has to be short
because if it's too long you see the
prime
it can't be too short either or you
don't get to process the prime role
and the prime target as a way
can't be too long either
along with me
dull
because so terribly whatever process
union you do
is relatively rapidly for garden
semantic processing is possible with a
subliminal
of the stimulus
it's analytically limited you can only
do so much
you might be able to extract the meaning
of a single word
but you're not going to be able to
extract the meaning of the scope of two
word phrase
much less
an entire all
much less in the players and
lasting about subliminal perception
or it was a perception in general
is simply to all remind you of the
relations between implicit
perception of the one hand
and implicit memory on the other
both implicit memory and implicit
perception
or revealed by prime interfax
where one stimulus
facilitates the processing
another stimulus
but they differ in large part in terms
of
where that for stimulus occurs
in the implicit memory
the primers the stimulus in the past
environment have occurred alone
a long time ago
in psychological terms
more than thirty seconds hong
all though let's hope psychologist
did before and want to a memory
in amplicor perception the primacy in
the current stimulus environment that's
happening right now or it happened just
a moment ago
call him what
william james called the species present
james's point being
we're never really in the present
you know whatever we think of as the
president really wants
a couple of milliseconds
there's another distinction here that i
really want to promote boggled focus on
for a second and that is
the private in that when prime in occurs
in the implicit memory
the person was consciously aware of the
prime when it occurred
but just
isn't consciously aware of
that it occurred at is it's not that
there's no conscious awareness of the
republic god
of the event
in the past no conscious recollection
in implicit perception
the person is not consciously aware
of the memory when it occurs uh... to
begin
most of the research on unconscious
cognition focuses on the implicit
memory
and implicit perception of basketball
of research
but that's not all there is to cognition
leading us to wonder whether they are
evident and the evidence for unconscious
coffin
you know other domains of cognition
can you have something like implicit
thinking
can you have off
that affects your behavior
even though you're not conscious of that
thought
then you have implicit morning
can you learn something that affects
your behavior
even though you're not conscious of what
you've learned
let's take the first one first
this is classic work by oracle reimer a
psychologist a brooklyn college
on what he called implicit learning
then rebirth experiments
subjects were asked to study strings of
the letters
letters drawn from they are the alphabet
and these letters these these letters
strings
were all composed according to
all what we call when congress science
in cognos psychology
and artificial grammar
that is a set of rules that specifies
the order in which
all letters should appear in the strain
this is one such artificial grammar
that weaver all used
and the way you read this
all it is so hard to is as follows
use you go with you went to the grammar
this is a said the the firstgov and
it can be ida red t
for api
if the first item is to be
then the second item
can either be and ox
or in the ass
if the second item is an ass
that s can be repeated
that can be repeated forever if you want
it can be annex and so on
the first item can be a t
or a p
the first item is a p
then the second item
will be either a t
or abhi
if the first night of the p
and the second item fifteen you could
repeat that please
vide infra night up
okay that's the way
you read these artificial grammars
so that
spring-like
t access
is grammatical
here's the third string
that could be pure secularism acts the
sect but they're going to be a s
and so on and so forth
p
the second letter can be to be of the
rudy
in this case
it's a v
that's how
these artificial grammars generate these
strings
that's all the strings were generated
wad re-worded was to send his subjects
down
all up and say this is a test of memory
and what i want to do under presented
with a bunch of nonsense
strings there just lover strung together
palm
and all that i want you to memorize
so subjects studied these letters
strings in
and in anticipation
falguni later
memory test
poem and they did that
on uracil
this these are in fact
the letter strings to be reused in his
very first experiment and you can
imagine this is not an easy exper
this is one of those experiments where
afterwards you really want to kill
yourself for children experimenter
qualm
because that's just
completely mindboggling
uh... politics for a bit but subjects
will do it
palm and didn't get subjects do almost
anything you can motivate them
all well enough
and they did that
at that point alm of the rebirth and
tested their memory for the strings
and then he's surprised on the
all
i would request to make a grammatical d
judgment return of the subjects we said
what i didn't tell you before
was that the each of these strings was
each of the strings you memorize
was
are composed according to a particular
grammar a set of rules
now i'm going to present you with a new
of strains
and what i want you to do
is to tell me
not whether you remembered before cuz
they roll no
what i want to do is to tell me
whether string conformist
that part of herschel grammar
that's a grammatical adi judgment
uh... task
and so we present them with no strings
like these where grammatical springs
catherine redden on grammatical strings
are and uh... black
and what reversed finally was
wasn't subjects were able to identified
grammatical letter strings
had raised over better than chess
two alternate forced choice fifty
percent as chance bob sixty percent
sometimes a little bit better
compared chancery a base rate of fifty
percent
but he discovered
they could not tell him
through the grammatical rules
that they used to base these judgments
on
here is
data from
water rivers early experiments
he resolved
the big the condition of just described
or the subject for us to memorize the
letter strings and we've got performance
of people who
word asked
to try to figure out what the rule was
gorgeous test
what the rule was
the recess to memorize here or subjects
who were asked to both memorized and try
to figure out the rule and what we were
found is that
if your ass to memorize and not
as to figure out what the rule is
you're actually better at making
grammatical grammatical judgments
then if you're asking them arise and to
figure out
what the rule was that was both
demonstrate the power
called for
of implicit learning
parker
here's subjects are nesta memorizing
just were asked to look at the strings
here the strings are at in fact all
random they don't conformed any
grammatical rule
and so that's a very bad at the grand
isle
what the grammatical rule is which
that's a control condition
and hear the subject of just dog over
breck she told what the rule was affects
still had difficulty doing it
our performance was best
in these implicit conditions
where subjects
we're not pass to figure out what the
rule was
and they couldn't
so study like this
suggests
that there's something to the idea of
implicit learning that you can
acquire knowledge through experience
that's what learning is
and have that knowledge affect your
performance
even though you can't
consciously
retrieve the knowledge even though
you're not consciously aware of what the
knowledges
volitan rebirth story
subjects
then of course so memorizing urges
viewing these words
automatically abstracted the grammatical
rule
their knowledge of the grove of the
grammatical rules that influenced their
grammatical and judgments
but it was all done on consciously
and they couldn't
are consciously recollect any of the fit
any of the aisle nor any of what they've
learned
we now have evidence for implicit
worried in this sense
where subjects like water knowledge
through experience
knowledge that i
fax their behavior
in the absence of conscious awareness of
what that knowledges
and a whole number of different hong
uh... situations here is rivers
artificial grammar word in experiment
there's also lol orders for the number
of books for vince ustinov complex
systems paradigm
use up the subject of a save the manager
of a sugar mill
there's so much
sugar cane that comes into the mail and
so much
process sugar that goes out of the mill
and between the input in the output is
some kind of very complex system that of
that that uh... specifies relationships
between the two
and what those and the finding is that
subjects can learn to predict the output
of the system
given the endpoint
even though they can tell you what the
mediating
calls of sequence learning
you put subjects in front of a computer
you told me one of them to respond as
quickly as possible whatever they see a
point of light flashing up on the screen
the screen is divided into four
quadrants
like comes up and one of the quadrants
of the respond
but there is a sequence
the experiment
so that over trials
there's a particular pattern
fall quadrants that's repeated over and
over and over again
pick up on that pattern
because they're faster to respond on
later trial so they were on the earlier
trials
but if you ask him
was a ready pattern
they say no
okay they're not aware of the pattern
category learning something so very
similar and then finally although there
are demonstrations of both classical and
instrumental conditioning on that occur
even though the subject is not aware
of either the conditions stimulus
for the on conditions stimulus
my favorite experiment of the sort was
one done by a russian psychologist
gregory rads ran
back in the sixties
in which
he had subjects wall of fistula
which put a blue moon in there
stomachs
replayed atoned
slated the balloon
okay which pre which creates a little
bit of all
well a lot of little bit of discomfort
all that you do it to it'd be if you
would pleaded
two big try have some time you'll see
palm
but there's a lot there's a level which
is just don't feel anything at all
yet he was able to measure although
responses in the gastrointestinal system
to this even those subjects were not
aware
albee although i'll be on conditions
stimulus
it's the kind of experiment
i suppose you could only do with certain
laboratories buttons chords for
and
and i really like it
in each of these cases
subjects or clean water knowledge
use that knowledge in subsequent
behavior but they don't know what they
know
they don't know what they've learned
will call that
implicit learning or unconscious
learning
okay so now would look at the relation
between implicit memory an implicit
learning
let's look at the relation between
implicit
member amazon sorry before but look at
the relation between implicit memory an
implicit perception
now let's look at the relationship
between implicit memory an implicit
warning
a question that arises naturally because
memory learning or so closely related
when you learn something a dump it in
memory
if you don't have a memory
you really can't learn anything
right so they got to be related
implicit memory and implicit learning or
different at least in my view in a
couple of ways
in the first place
and implicit memory the priming effects
that we observe in and music haitians
for example
what we're looking at is the or
unconscious influenced bob stovall vent
that occurred in the past
okay but the subject cannot consciously
called not consciously remember
palm
and important so that at the sonic
memory
in implicit learning
over really looking at is the
unconscious influence of what you might
call semantic memory or procedural
memory
some piece of
abstract knowledge that you've acquired
or through uh...
through experience
palm
in the implicit learning
the subjects are clearly aware of the
learning experience all of rebirth
subjects of usa body of the doing for
the last forty five minutes to take
on the study in your damn listed
letter strings
they are aware of what they were doing
anticipations
park aware of what they've been doing
they can't consciously i'll remember it
palm
and in it was a learning as i say
there's nowhere else of the new
knowledge that they've acquired through
experience
there's a halfway case
armed
which is known in the trade as force
amnesia something we can see with
both emmys that patients and with
under a logically intact
uh... subject
where calm
subjects
learn something through experience
they're aware of what they've learned
but they're not aware alba learning
experience okay so they've acquired some
new piece of semantic or procedural
knowledge
but they're not aware of the episode
through which they acquire that
best example of this is off
is a uh... case study of by you know the
great swiss psychologist birds clapper
red
all who worked for a time in a clinic
volume switzerland
or benefit all of the dell with hetal
large
grupo form of of course the car patients
that is patients who by virtue of mostly
alcoholism
had suffered
bilateral damage to the diane cephlon
and were rendered and music much the
same way that agent was
well one day clapp a red came on the
ward
palm and on he walked up to a patient
and said uh... do you know me do you
know who i am she said no
called
and he held out his
hand to the introduced himself and
doctor clapp a red or you held out his
hand too
halted to show that you have to have my
call polite people do
and all that
all discovered that
clapp a redhead hidden a job of append
in his hand
that pricked
her hand and caused her
alarm some distress atrial injury she
was a bleeding all over the floor or
anything like that
she was pissed
palm
she was drawer and began the yelling at
him lol
all as salt was apologizes positions
wont clapp a red left
the ward and left it to the nurses to
calm the patient down
palm dubbed the best patient got popular
come down
at which point clapp a red came back
onto the ward
approach the patient said all do you
know who won
no
cost she's a music right she doesn't
remember anything that's happened to
work
on have we ever met before no
well i'm doctor clapper read it's nice
to meet you when he held out his hand
and she refused to take it
aman clapper red esther why she said
sometimes people highly depends in their
hands
she got the semantic knowledge okay
all inches consciously aware of this
move
facts that you learned about the world
that sometimes people hide pens in their
hands
but she was not aware of the learning
experience
leave me if i walked up to you introduce
myself to you and pricked your hand with
the pin
you'd remember that
and it would show up on my course
evaluations lakeview
it wouldn't be
sometimes people are people hide pins in
their hands idbi
kill stranded this horrible thing to be
on monday
you'd remember the episode
as well as uh... as well as the fact
sulfur semi just kind of a minute and
intermediate case
where subjects are aware of a new
knowledge but they're not aware of the
learning experience
on call that a barbarian dot implicit
memory because what's being for dot
is an experience
in implicit warning
consciously accessible
is something closer to semantic or
procedural
all home
procedural memory
paul cain now
last one
palm
and that is
unconscious thinking
is a possible took think
but not be conscious of thinking
convert it seems like a non couple
contradiction in terms and in fact
william james thought it might
ought be
but we've already made the case for
unconscious memory
rewarding made the case were unconscious
perception
reported that the case were unconscious
morning white-hot unconscious thinking
long ago altman portrait early cognitive
psychologist named wallace
all or the drug tried to make a case for
unconscious thinking
when he articulated what he called the
stages of thought
five stages
that he thought people went through
whenever they tried to solve a problem
or engage in some kind of reasoning
the first stage is one of preparation
which really just has to do with
learning your book burning the
background if you're an engineer in your
working on airplanes
prepare yourself
by org
uh...
mortensen whatever dynamics and
metallurgy and things like that
then you've got this problem
okay
and
precisely because edsall problem you
don't know what the answer is you don't
know what the solution is that's not
knowing what the solution is that makes
but what makes a problem radio a problem
wide some point
we solve the problem
that's what the poem
that's what art dot wallace called
illumination or you get some insight
into the problem
and then you verify yuor insight by
checking out making sure that all works
you've got a problem your prepare for it
and his soul that and you check it
inbetween however
wallace postulated their burden
two stages
involved
unconscious thought
and the first of these was one wallace
called incubation
and i wallace's idea here
even if you don't
even if you're not consciously thinking
about our problem you're not
fit your you're thinking about it
unconsciously or all along
this incubation process is kind of a fun
conscious problem solving activity
and then at some point you come to a
stage
that wallace called intimation
but which we might now prefer to call
intuition
you know the problem solve oval
kind of no andy's
i can tell you exactly what the solution
is yet but
hollings i would fall were born i'm
going to get it's own
the off
obvi upbeat get the our hikes periods
where all the sudden the solution comes
in onto memory
this is a little bit like liggett's is
pitied perceptions
alm
wallace had this idea that you got the
little germ this little flame of thought
and they gradually grows hodder
gradually grows more intense until you
can feel a calming and then you can see
it
incubation process
where a thought
gradually
alva gradually gained some strength
and there are a lot of examples of this
kind of incubation effect
in history problem solving their very
common in science
here's a famous one from the home
all from the article
french math mathematician point kar rae
all
i turn my attention the study is america
medical questions of currently without
much success in without a suspicion
of any connection with my preceding
researchers
disgusted with my failure
i want to spend a few days at the
seaside always a good help
for problem solving
and thought of something else
one morning walking on the block the
idea came to me
with just the same characteristics of
brevity suddenness of the media
certainty
that the arithmetic transformations of
indeterminate turner required braddock
forms were identical with those of the
non-u euclidean geometry
okay
all one parade claimed
this insight had to be a product of him
unconsciously working on these another
on this problem
all the time
and then
at some point the solution just kind of
got
got intense enough
and uh... and became accessible to
consciousness and there are lots of
examples of this
in the scientific literature
on here's another famous one key cooley
structure of the benzine ring
nike over his claim drug claimed
couldn't solve it
and then dalton
he had a dream hauled before snake by
dean its tail
and uh... he woke up from the dream
instead
that's the structure of the benzine
rings
closer to it when i want to reading
all
on again the idea greer is that he went
to sleep thinking about it
while he cut
prophecy that on consciously while he
was asleep he had this dream and then
you realize that are significant
lot of anecdotes
unfortunately they're mostly joyous
anecdotes
alm
uh... and
uh... there are problems with this
intuition it's entirely possible
for example
that all the time one parade was walking
on the bluff on the seaside
he was really thinking about this
problem
that's not a very good story
a really good story is
heedless of the song
the song
uh... inside emerged with a lot of
nowhere
ca cooley solid although
all that anecdote is really good
accepted cocco it was actually in a
priority debate with another campus
who also claimed to have discovered the
structure of benzine
and could cooley says well i did at
first does that occurred to me in a
dream on august eleventh eighteen sixty
five or something like that
home
and so you don't really know what to
make of that
foghorn either
and we know the people's intuitive
judgements can be misled
bio whole host of factors of
collectively known have judgment your
wrist
when you bring incubation into the
laboratory turns out to be very very
very difficult
together villains
uh...
almost until recently anyway
most evidence for incubation called poem
most experiments an incubation suggest
that
the solution than any other kind of
forget it
okay and then it babe ruth them every
member of parliament later
or maybe even incubation
what appears to be incubation isn't part
of the fact of
certain inappropriate problem-solving
strategies
more recently however
palm reduced dumaguete evidence for
incubation in the laboratory
and a number of paradigm
for example
using dog remote associates test
also ralph and martha uh... bed nick
devised this
loosing this on jeopardy a million times
saw those of you who played certain
board games at home
songs on how to see these kind of thing
so that task in the remote associates
test is to say
word to the following three words have
volvo
the share as a common associate
three stimulus words are democrat
and your job is to come up
what the common solicitors
don't say it
who knows what the answer is
okay let's just leave it at that maybe
somebody will have an incubation effect
arm
here's another example the so-called
nine dot problem
okay
and thus of the persons of problem is to
connect the dots
by drawing four straight continuous
lines
never lifting the pencil from the paper
who knows how to do this storm say how
to do is
think about that one
you know or don't think about it better
of a better yet
and see what happens there
well in any event there's now a
laboratory evidence for home
for something like incubation
insulting both these verbal and non
verbal problems here's a review
or by sight eleanor marauder couple of
years ago
ono funnel over a hundred
all two hundred studies
showing
they're actually does seem to be small
affected incubation
both on linguistic problem solving of
well-liked though
young remote associates fest
alva or creative problem solving
like the uh... like the nine dot
like the nine dollar problem
and all
you can reduce this by increasing
cognitive load by distracting subjects
which suggests that there really
thinking about it
here it is
i think i can do it
one maybe ill do too
here's a nice example
although something like an incubation
effect
in uh...
within the laboratory this is work by
the lake and the power is a professor at
university of waterloo in canada on a
very into all of the remote associates
test
known as the diet adds the triads test
what paul bowers david
was to take
route lou or eighty like
one of which the words really do have
a common associate
and the others
that the other trio
uh... they don't
have a common associates
so for example
white winds
there are they all have
as the common associate
still pages and music
i think bahrain psychotic levels of
of what was the so see asian of there's
no warm
no common associate
uh... they're not was ever discovered
one anyway
but this is all really hard one
all only about twenty percent
of subjects will solve this problem
when they are
when they first get it
and so what happens is
if something subjects can say which is
the soluble triad is close to say
one event
but if u can't say which is the soluble
triad
flowers that goes on and says
uh... double bed isn't can say what the
solution is
followers goes on and asks is subject
well okay
which triad
is soluble
has
a common associate
and bowers finding is
that subjects can distinguish between
soluble
and insoluble triads
at levels that are better than chance
you know they can tell you what the
solution is
that's likely wallis is intuition you
have an intuition about what the
solution is even though you're not
consciously aware
of exactly what it is
here are
five hours and his colleagues
all of which show
that subjects
intuitive troy cigs
in podiatry triads all of the situation
are correct
more than you'd expect by chance but
sixty percent of the time little douglas
compared to fifty percent base rate
even though the subjects can tell you
what the solution is
so here you have something like
anon conscious thought
the solution is clearly directing your
behavior
released pretty clearly directing your
even though you don't know what what the
solution is
victor shamas registered in my
laboratory palm cove
well what was actually able to show
solved triads
can actually
create semantic priming affects
even those subjects don't know what the
solution is here's an example
you have been subjects are prime
not subliminal primes these are
conscious prime sick
come up and you can see the clearly
died
and chair
all of which have
the word
party in common
high note climbed on a plane chair
for the again to bring a difficult one
all what shamas did was to
present the triad
if the subject new what the solution was
a response to say
if they didn't know what the solution
was
he then
presented them with
the target
for all lexical decision task just say
whether it's a word or not
and a fine he was
these three-word primes
prime
what i call the sessions
of the targets
even when the subjects didn't know the
solution to
clearly high was primed
with activated
in semantic memory
and influenced people's judgments about
whether a was a word or not
even those subjects were not aware that
height was the solution to the problem
here are three examples
from childless is on the doctoral
dissertation
in which
the controllers where there's no
semantic relation between
the three-word prime and the target
where they're is a semantic relationship
between the three were prime of target
and what you can see is a
very nice priming effect
so far faster response latencies
wherever there's a cement relation
and that primary effect occurs
even those subjects are not aware of
what the answer to the question is
they haven't achieved that solution
okay soul regatta
over this
and just get to the bottom line here
in the implicit thought
we have the effect of some idea
something that's in the head
and i've been a major fallout although
whatever
on on experience thought vaction
in the absence of conscious awareness of
what that idea is
sometimes
the idea is a perception based
representations some buckets of
representation of what something looks
like
in the shama send the borrowers
experiments
it's a meaning based representation
it has to do with the meaning of the
object
but it's not a percept
subjects never saw the word high as a
prime
it's not a memory
subjects never saw
the word high at any point in the
experiment
it's awful lot
it's something that they generated
internally and response to other kinds
of stimuli
it some thought that influences their
behavior
but it's a fourth it influences their
even though they are not conscious of
the fox
the fun conscious thought
it's implicit flawed
implicit murmured memory
perception
learning
fought there's even some evidence now
for implicit language i don't have time
to do it
next time will go beyond the domain of
cognition and look at evidence for
implicit
and implicit the emotion
that affect our behavior outside of
continuity obsessive conscious awareness
of what those motives and emotions are
thank you very much