okay let's finish up our discussion of
mind-body relations
in fact will continue in the next series
of lectures as well
just to
put the finishing touches on the
discussion last week
alm
it strikes me that
psychosomatic interactions of various
kinds where people's expectations and
believes that influence the function of
the body
are one way to approach the question of
whether the mind influences the body
and the point here is just to make clear
that
if we're going to
if we're going to talk about
psychosomatic interactions we have to
make distinctions among three
quite different kinds of all
relationships
the first of these
the affects of expectations and beliefs
on one's mental state
and a good example of this is the
placebo response in pain
pains a mental state expect bob placebos
involved expectations so if a policy
more reduces
pain reduces the experience of pain
that doesn't really count as a
psychosomatic attacked because
we haven't actually measured anything in
the body good called a psycho psycho
effect if you want
and similarly if we see have been we are
dwindling solve placebo or suggestion or
something like that
on psalm aspect of central nervous
system functioning
that's also belittle problematic as
evidence of psychosomatic while affects
because
if we believe as most of us do
that what goes on to the line goes on in
the brain
you could just have the central nervous
system affect
being a arm there being some kind of
represen
or biological substrates
bubble psycho psycho a fact
where you really want to see
psychosomatic affects where you really
want to see evidence
expectations beliefs and suggestions on
bottling process these
is when you look at this and physical
properties outside
the central nervous system
liken the skeletal system where the
cardiovascular system or something on
something like that
and last time i tried to show you a
couple of examples on the kind of thing
that we're talking about
and there's more of a civil lecture
supplement that i just don't have time
the discussion
all simply close that part of a lecture
by saying that
we now have two new scientific
disciplines
psycho and oh chronology and psycho
immunology
sometimes fought over psycho neuro
endocrinology
and psycho bureau immunology 'cause we
got to have no role in everything these
days
but the whole point here it is that
these are
although
recognize fields all aqua biology and
medicine
that are predicated on the idea
that psychological processes can have an
effect on endocrine function
and the psychological processes could
have an effect on immune function
the the existence of these subfields of
biology and medicine onto the sensor or
attribute to beyond
to the persistent interest in the home
in psychosomatic in elections
let's turn to
the next problem
which has a problem of whether there is
a nobody could have minds with our
bodies
mode bill question posed that way we
found a little strange
but in fact is the long history
ald paul did not know them discussions
even among still a big even within the
scientific community
of people who are both of the
possibility
that somehow
minds are independent
all volvo brings
and if you think about it for a second
you can see that the roots of this
go back at least as far as descartes
on diff not to religious doctrines of
both the soul
if big car was right
that mind and body or composed of two
different substances that in the
interact somehow
bennett ought to be the case
that mind somehow exists
only independent home
bodies
this question which is implied by
descartes archive god i came to light
headed in the late nineteenth century
with the rise in europe and america all
day movements known as spiritualism
which as it suggests that was study of
spirits
or though that or the spirit world
all the all
origins of this is unworkable or both of
you know
well the gun and a bad you whilst we
were questioned filed today
religious
ought to go over to san francisco
you'll see a sweden gorjan churches for
the finest examples of craftsman
architecture west of the mississippi
all that
and on but what what uh... what
spiritualism was all about what was it
that would be group of people who
believe
that dog but there were creatures beams
all spirits
which all of the word which functioned
as as they called them
this in cardiff he wins
that is
conquered creatures which were
affectively mines without bodies
and died in the united states there was
a a a a lot of our group interested
related argument in spiritualism
by these three women voted for fox
sisters
margaret
and we up
who are what around the made themselves
quite famous
all bubye all of the bod bike uh...
uh... present themselves as being able
to communicate with the dead
all one of their own goaded communica
tions
was a guide name mr split foot
which if you
with the word a little bit and see
that's supposed to be some kind of all
proxy for the devil
all but they spent on ralph a lot of
their time
art deco corresponding with a young
but the spirit named charles b roost mup
all who all they did they are
or you'd had died in the basement of
their host
and chuckle that they had actually had
lucrative careers as as well as mediums
they would go around doing sean's
seances and uh... and and other uh...
kinds performances
communicating with charles p_ rourk
smook
and abroad through charles b rosemont
helping all people to communicate with
their deceased relatives and other all
and on their loved ones and they were
very very very famous
all around the time of the you know
when the time the civil war
and in the home
the reconstruction period
arm so did was with the fox sisters that
we began a whole tradition
alba although among the medium ship or
clairvoyance people holding steady on
thursday
communicating with the dead by means of
a ouija ouija boards are automatic
writing
on the fox sisters themselves were very
although they're very good at table
wrapping
or where they would sit around a table
and everybody would hold hands and
all spirits would knock out messages in
something like morse code
on
wasn't worse code word was something
like that
hauled off on the other on the table
on thing that's so popular that in
england and in the united states
all grupo bald them people called funded
through society for cycle research
uh... to investigate these kinds of
things
these were not simply crackpots william
james was a founding member of the
society per cycle
all research
all
and lead to a gall bladder an actual
commission the saber commission
which investigated the fox sisters and
large numbers of other people
home who were presenting themselves as
mediums and who came to the conclusion
that
there had to be some kind of
fraud here but it was unclear exactly
off of the hull people we're doing it
our year after the cyber commission pole
vault of the made its report all
margaret
the along with it
over the world one of the park sisters
actually confessed to how they have done
it
the flock sisters had discovered
how they could
some of you never bought a lot of people
have the have a crack in your knuckles
although they have all of that they
developed a way of cracking buried me
use
without
actually touching them just by kind of
manipulating their legs
and so they were sending the what what
seemed like table wrapping it was
actually these three women
cracking their knees underneath the
table
all in this kind of code coming from
charles b realms book
margaret's confession destroyed the
armed the aldo leopold
the awb
economic value all vault of this whole
thing
so her sister's kinda get dub bonner
richie recanted in eighteen eighty nine
only to be here
called and then she looked a lot later
died and and and for full on the whole
thing too long
to her grade
all i had a boat margaret's confession
really pretty much put the kite basha
uh... on on this whole
nineteenth-century of the tradition of
spiritualism
and it died uh... until relatively
recently well when it got uh... revived
but again there are people here who were
quite dark on quite serious about this
william james himself towards the end of
his life
made arrangements with his elderly
friends
if they died and they remained in the
spirit and and then the bottom line
found themselves in the in the end of
the spirit world
but there were all of them what policy
goals baked that though i think your
rate with them to send back to him
so he'd know that they exist yet she
tried to do something slight
difficulties
odd james never heard a thing
palm
hoover but that's not the point the
point is that james that work
you know might be true
here's how we do experiments often this
right
all talk to all my dying friends
and ask them to send messages back
anyway nothing much came of that until
all below the
on the until more recently as we'll see
all bob white and protects what what
took the place of spiritualism
nineteenth-century spiritualism
wasn't interest among twentieth-century
psychologists in what probably know
called parapsychology
or the story of sod so-called saudi
phenomenal
which is defined that's the official
definition
on novelist prostheses of information or
energy transfer
that are currently export unexplained
in terms of known physical or biological
mechanisms
now if you read this literature which i
had to do ones
so that's one inflicting this on you
on there are two versions
all vault dot gov parapsychology
there's a soft version which says
there's so there are some processes of
information of energy transfer that are
currently on explained in terms of known
physical or biological mechanisms but
that just means that there are some
physical or biological mechanisms that
we don't know about yet
so the soft version of parapsychology
basically says
all there were some other sensory
modalities that we've got that we
haven't discovered in addition to a
vision and auditioned and custody
channel faction
all and all the rest
the harm version of parapsychology is
what we're really interested in in the
context of this course
because what the hard version of
parapsychology says is that
there are processes of the information
or energy transfer that do not involved
physical or biological mechanisms
and what that means is
minds
communicating with mines
without any physical medium
on at all
no sensation the language no nothing
just direct contact
and what that implies again
is that you can have mine without a body
you can have mine without
all without any kind of physical
what kinds of anomalous processing is
are we talking about
here's a list from charles part
or whose owners of the prominent
psychologist who's involved in this
literature
all basically come in altman these
phenomena come in three different
categories
alm most all of the mostly older or
probly all prophecies of extra sensory
perception
all telepathy the communication of the
contents of one mind to another
all without danielle dot without any
physical
all of them physical medium
clairvoyance is related to pull out the
fields also known as remote viewing
it and all the dan clairvoyance you've
seen what somebody else's c
okay so
i'm sitting here now and berkeley and i
and see what
mikhail gorbachev is seen in this
officer
dolphin moscow or something like that
that's remote viewing
all pre cognition
all has to do with all of the the
cognition baba bands that have not yet
occurred
because you can come to see the future
all band members post cognition
because that will geez pulls cognition
that's for investors memory
but noel post cognition is
experience in the past in the present
so i could sit here and i'm also a
veteran napoleon's army going abroad
that the attack in moscow or something
like that
and i'm seeing it as it happens right
now
all of that
or all of these phenomena
seem to involve the transmission of one
person's mental state onto another
now we have psycho cases
are moving objects simply by virtue of
the operation of the mind
and then all the tarred adds a third
category here goes our traditional
plus life phenomenon
tarred edsel any other third category
called medical spiritual healing
sometimes called energy medicine
where all part of the people he'll
diseases all basically by
the operations of ball although
coppermine
all right so those are but most of the
basic talked of the kinds of phenomena
that you have to
that we have to deal with
so the question is
how can you possibly make a science of
this
well famously j_b_ ryan a psychologist
who for it was first at harbor boulevard
person or burden of that uh... duke
university
all actually got interested this problem
we have got nineteen twenties and
nineteen thirties
and uh... developed aguilarg
experimental paradigm for the study of
or at least extra sensory perception
that has basically persisted odd to this
day
uh... he will not heal research
associated his name is either
invented
that water nao known as zener cards
these five cards with these kind of
quite distinct or the symbols on them
and you can see in this picture from
ryan's laboratory that's running
and that's his wife luisa
hall they work together in this is some
do sophomore
so all the there's a sender
who sees one of these cards
and there's a reason for
groups uses all morning
these steps
which one
the sender is seen under parsers this
barrier here that prevents communication
and uh... that and and and stuff like
that
there's a spoof of almost everything and
ghostbusters
odd yeah ghostbusters his
ghostbusters kind of our pub parody of
spiritualism
uh... but those guys just kind of
threw everything into the admitted into
the bathtub and seen that movie for a
long time
but uh...
i'm i'm sure there is
but you don't have to go to ghostbusters
to get the spook you can actually go to
solve department of psychology
so anyway tom what what what ryan nam
what what what ryan deborah these
experiments ok der the rye new what he
was doing was trained as a biologist
first as actually trained as a botanist
but they need retooled himself as a
psychology who don't know how to do
control sick
understood that you had to separate the
sender in the receiver in
and all that kind of business
all bandow he claimed on in his uh...
all that water rafting printers reminded
he had evidence for all
for home
the yard
what's on the mind of the sender
could go into the mind of the receiver
even though there was no what
opportunity for any kind of physical
uh... physical connection between them
all of these kinds of claims have lost
have long been problematic the national
research council all voting for the some
years ago i sat on this committee
all road reviewed all of the parable of
the parapsychology for the all of them
for the united states military which was
interested in this
poem
actually got you know what you are
interested in it
they were interested in the
nineteen eighty eight
they were interested in it because the
soviet union
had a big risk that the soviet military
had a big operation studying
parapsychology
and we figured
if there are starting at we gotta figure
this out to
so it wasn't just a missile gap between
the soviets and the united states unit
there was also a young mental
on so that some kind of some kind of
parapsychology gap
and the army commission the national
research council to word that the study
does
and the national research council quite
recently said
there's nothing there
okay
although a lot of all a lot of what
color claims to be plausible para
psychotic but it's for parapsychology is
just kind of outright
fraud
although there's a lot of expert better
by a slot of subtle subtle metal
methodological problems although it here
all a lot of capitalization on chance
that's the list of of issues but what
really bothers people most of all
parapsychology is not just that there's
no evidence for it
the whole idea of as did the from this
is a quote from the a_p_a_ dictionary of
psychology
admitted even one instance of paranormal
causation would overthrow virtually all
the established wars and principles of
science
sold you can see what's home
what's at stake
in response to these kinds of critiques
lot of people just kind of gave up
like i said yeah that's right
but other people have persisted
all and in particular aud trolls order
to and who was all leading figure in the
american society for technical research
all of the continued to
to perform studies all volun
twelve off
dubbo telepathy
on his email modify uh... basically
modification of rice procedure
which he calls the guns filled procedure
horner chen argued for being called the
noise reduction model
pole vault of all uh... slight
phenomenal
which basically says that whatever he
asked me is picking up
is a very weak signal that's why the
experimental results were so one
reliable and looked at me affects common
go
on so what what do you do if you want to
pick up a weak signal what you've got to
do is to get rid of all the noise so
that the signal comes out so we
developed what's known as the guns
filled procedure
paul dot hole
procedure
all of them to would kind of nasty
internal and external noise this is a
photograph of below what what happens
here
that the there's asunder
just like in the rhine experiments will
concentrates on an image not as either a
card anymore but in actual image
all up and the receiver has to choose
among of four test items for all part of
on or multiple choice
so there's a twenty five twelve percent
punch olympic rate
but while the receiver causes recvd
knees signals okay
while he or she does so in a restricted
sensory environment during a really nice
reclining chair that best or cologne
germany combined
these are actually ping-pong balls that
have been cut in half
bold and put over the audience so that
you don't get any visual stimulation
light comes through but the uh... but no
imagery
and you're wearing headphones that are
paldon sending white noise into your
room
into your rodney peers
to block out any kind of auditory on
distraction on as well
using this ganas filled all the
procedure
all hundred-ton paul and his colleagues
produced all the set of thirty nine
studies over a period of ball about ten
fifteen years
all all of which had the same quality
the sender focuses on a picture
the receiver picard and tries to guess
which old four alternatives the sender
is looking at
on dad what he found was
people could do this at
but doubt that breaks that are much
better calmed down now
than chance
alba dot at the
you don't agree about where that what
lee ellen's of publius patristic is
derived
but all the results that insane
psychology other aspects of social
science
we usually look at
all we would like to look at the size of
an experimental affect essentially the
difference between experimental and
control groups
and all he got across the thirty nine
studies as i mean effect size appointed
to the seven which is
statistically significant
bigger than you'd expect by chance
and jacob cohen a dead while you are
embraced dog
thought that uh... bob proposed a set of
some of the standards here
offer the evaluating these things if you
if you read met analyses in the uh...
from literature reviews and
psychological journals
you always see
of the reference to cohen standards
automate effect size of all
if we point to three is right in the
middle of the range that colin described
as a small effect
well any of the fact
right with what it would be uh... would
be interesting
almost social science effects are in
the small to medium
range
of the devil you get the facts eyes like
that
mostly by killing someone
uh... so that we kind of have to be
satisfied
uh... whitbread with these kinds of
things
so that's the old although that's the
old all that
so-called all gone still database so
name because there's a new guns fell
database
all subsequent we are at the heart and i
had a cornell psychologist beryl bhavan
that's dural bam right there
all-volunteer or the developer refined
into the gods filled procedure
dogged basically used a computer to
select
the home
the you know that the stimulus materials
just kind of get one more thing ha
uh... what what more opportunity
for all
for some kind of bias to enter
the enter into the situation out of the
picture
and in nineteen ninety four
on them in heart and reported a set of
eleven studies
if you look at just look at the present
if it's again
twenty-five print you'd expect twenty
five percent by chance across beyond
that the uh... across the studies
they achieved a thirty two percent
arbitrate which is against physically
uh... significant
on and the kind of thing that would give
evidence for
for rome
uh... telepathy
usual standards of
of psychological inference
fallen
ray hyman who's a psychologist at of the
university of washington now retired
longtime critic called para
psychological research
palm and uh... on he had actually worked
pizza these are interesting guy is a
quick but he says look i'm open
but if you're going to convince me i got
to do certain kinds of things
any i could have actually worked with
charles daughter kim
to develop guidelines for the proper
conduct of para psychological research
on that part of the basically enforce
all of them through this day
all blocked off of the all highland long
look at these things in symbolic burst
birthday you know
dabur aside from outright experimenter
fraud and
nobody thinks
that either darryl bam or charles
hundred-ton were deliberate gauged
outright fraud something
there are some
there is a lot of the serious problems
with these kinds of experiments
mostly
all because of some failures to
adequately randomized the stimuli
and also because of there was a lot of
opportunity
for all of the experimenter to prompt
subjects to respond
and therefore might contaminate uh...
their own their response
walked off of what high-minded in israel
ballusters
was to identify those experiments where
there were serious methodological
problems
and those experiments where their work
few or no i'm not of these were all
about the lobbies methodological
problems
and look at the hit rates in those two
categories of experiments
and it turns out in the problematic
experiments
you get hit rate of about
forty seven percent compared to what
baseline by chance of twenty five
percent
for those experiments that involved the
least problematic experimental
conditions that is the methodological e
titus
of orbited ordered experiments
you've got a hit rate that was actually
below chance
halt vote
point one eight
you put it all together
on his best estimate
of the hit rate in these experiments
was not home
tell the world war that was not thirty
two percent but something closer to
twenty seven twenty eight percent which
isn't
significantly different
problem
so again what see what what you're
seeing here is
but got the same problems over and over
and over again
now that's not at all
for people
all people kept doing these studies
all because they are fine and it's a
challenge
on joyce milner colleague at all but all
of the reviewed thirty new studies
thirty studies
don between nineteen eighty seven and
nineteen ninety four
just shows a how popular offices
all all of which
they presume to follow the uh... hyman
harder to guidelines because everybody
was doing that at the time
and when you look at those thirty new
studies
which are as methodological e good as
you can get
the overall effect size was point no one
as close to zero as you can
that wasn't enough
all stormin' airtel to european
investigators
examined the complete database of
seventy-nine gone spelled alguns film
studies
and got above the table overall effect
size roughly point pa warno
roughly point one four
which is significant statistically
significant
our in-store minner tells that
seemed there really is an affect here
you can't make this effect go away
what's tormentor tell didn't notice
if cardiac defects lies in the thirty
nine studies in the all the guns fell
database before the hyman hundred-ton
guidelines have been announced
not trivial
but if you look at the forty studies and
a new bonds fell database all of which
have been conducted after the hitman
hart and guidelines have been problem
gated
they got in effect size which was about
as close to zero all as though
killed as you can get
here is the overall trend
the year in which the study was produced
the magnitude of the affect
it's going straight down
to zero
also these early studies were quite
interesting they often are blueblood
produce the significant effects but the
war
gathered
for more
the affect
disappeared and that is pretty much a
story uh...
it's these all the guns filled studies
i'd the peace plan so much time of his
gun spilled studies of clairvoyance
precisely because this is where most of
the experimentation is
on this problem of whether you can have
a mind without a body
and uh...
this is where the actually where the the
standard surpassed
all and the land and uh... that and the
researchers are more careful
the bottom line is
there's no there there
on there just isn't on that there just
isn't any kind of detectable
any kind of detectable that
okay just all need to arm
of put the finishing touches on mind
without body we have seen the dalelro
relatively recently
a resurgence of interest in spiritualism
a revival of nineteenth-century
spiritualism
and the a_a_r_p_ they've been a movement
which gary schwartz psychologist at
university of arizona
calls the survival of consciousness and
by what by that he means
the survival of consciousness after
death
there's always been a lot of attic total
evidence for so-called survival of
consciousness
our people and often talked about of the
people who have had all life threatening
experiences
all often report had been out-of-body
where at their with it's it appears as
if they're mines have left their bodies
you can also get this
if u
ingest certain psychoactive drugs but
don't try this out
park and you can also get reports about
a body experiences uncertain
pathological conditions uh...
of the uh... dissociate disorders of d
realization and be personalization
again people who have all uh... laredo
confronted some kind of life threatening
challenge
have often reported called water nova's
near-death experiences
where first it appears as if their minds
have left their bodies and then they
experience themselves as passing through
what total let go ahead and towards the
light
all the company by a kind of life
are all of them life review
homebrew
remove the
has suggested
that what you're seeing here in these
new near-death experiences now how do we
know about this
well these people did die
game becomes
near today
maneuver group what revive somehow
raymond moody is suggested that what
what what uh... what dogle
with these people referring to
is there a mines leaving their bodies
and then
when they don't die
animal somehow the body snatchers them
right back
or something like that
now again there are some there's some
people take this kind of thing uh...
none of them seriously
all in labs at the famous british
medical journal all upon wobble in his
colleagues all report of a prospective
study of nerd near-death experiences
frittered forty-four patients who were
clinically dead following kartik cardiac
arrest
clinically dead mean they had no
electrical electrical activity in the
brain stem
okay but then they were resuscitated
all and they came back
and all of them for normal in his
colleagues actually involve the
interview these people
and reported in the lancet
that poem eighteen percent of them
experienced some kind of near-death
experience
there could be lots of things going on
in the near death experience your body's
going to a lot of physiological changes
you don't have any brainstem electrical
activity that's gotta have some kind of
consequence
all but uh...
i think it did it's not an offer the
filed for all of them for these local cs
two
to entertain a_d_r_ physical explanation
for something like that near-death
experience for the out-of-body
experience
although the for them this code this
comes as evidence of all those
supporting the idea that somehow mines
could exist independently of bodies
and off on wall mole and others have
done cheaper car palm
argued for an analogy between
all brains and radios
and say look what happened brains don't
generate consciousness
what brains do is received consciousness
okay
justices outside
also unconsciousness is independent of
the brain receiver
in the same way that or radio or
television signal is independent of the
radio or the television
uh... set
so if your brains turned on you can
receive consciousness if it's turned on
you can't
but the consciousness exists outside the
brain anyway
this is another example people taking
seriously
the prospect
on that we can have mine
without bodies
palm
one more trend if this is actually back
uh... there is a is a return to medium
shepherd uninterested mediums
gary schwartz mention him before
has actually gone tried to do of
experimental research on mediums
song
or he has a recruited
fifteen what he calls research mediums
or from around the country people who
advertise themselves in like the bay
area guardian or someplace as well
on as mediums
on and all uh... bleeds
i think is over fifty
all people now who are centers who are
people who have blood deceased loved
ones that they want to be in contact
with
and what the shorts has gone
tried to do or some experiments
in which poem
uh... in in which
of the mediums
try to contact the deceased loved ones
get messages from the deceased loved
ones
that are done presented to the sitters
to see if they recognize anything
meaningful envio
could be you know
in the messages
now schwartz is a trained experimental
psychologist
alm so he thought you have some sense of
how to do this
he's actually all of the not are limited
in these experiments
tried to uh... tried to will put some
controllers
if you've got a message from anybody
uh...
probably without too much trying
find something that's personally
relevant in it
so that's a problem with these
experiments
so much for its has done is to present
the setters
information at the medium got from the
troop from their own true target
and also unknown to the sitters
present them with information from
somebody else's loved one
okay control target
and watch words claims
is that palm
all applaud the of the sitters can
distinguish between messages have come
from the truth target and messages that
come from the polls target
and battles suggested schwartz of that
call that uh... that that medium ship is
possible that you can communicate with
the dead
and are raising you can communicate with
is because
minds exist independent of bodies
also what we are setback to the medium
here
while that's exactly what's happening
dot towards the and all of the twentieth
century
racine or revival
of an interesting involved you know that
you know uh... topics
there were very that that were very
impressed
albee interest
to uh...
that the end of the nineteenth century
whether it's some kind of ended century
thing
you know if i don't know
uh... the end of the scent of the end of
any century could have profound effects
on people
all but in any event
this camp possibly be true
okay must be just because about this can
possibly be true
are given everything we know about minds
and bodies and all of that
and i dont presented it to you with
something that
that i think actually is true i have a
lot of respect for gary schwartz up
when he left harvard for you know like
replaced them and we were colleagues at
the university result
as just
exhibit disinterested sample of a guy
who's had
heroes and terrible problem
if there are mines independent of bodies
we have the technology we ought to be
able to be that we know how to design
these experiments
and all
uh... when when you designed experiments
you get this
police say in passing
these are the initial results
these studies
and as
publishes
this work and it uh... and and the comes
under
than usual kind of wall
scientific strictures for publication
and replication uniform triple criticism
it'll be interesting to see what happens
to these kinds of affects
we know what happened
clairvoyance
early bigger fax
has ruled the research interests are at
the end of price proceeded and the
research became more carefully
controlled
effects disappeared
are more early in the in the stage of
experimental mediums studies or whatever
it is
all but you can predict
on the basis of past history
that that's what's going to happen
uh... as well here
the point of all of this is
the question of whether mines can exist
without bodies are perfectly legitimate
scientific question
william james
thought it was
as with the low budget but enough that
he would arrange with is dying
colleagues to sending signals from the
after world right
that was his that that that was his way
of doing slides
this is the kind of thing
that can be investigated
more carefully we investigate
the closer we get to that unanswered
that is
but time will tell
about the
last point
all of which will do very briefly
because we're going to spend the next
couple of days talking about this in
some detail
talked about
how about bodies produce mines
whether mines could affect bodies
but you could have mines without bodies
now let's
do the fourth one very briefly
can you have
bodies without minds
or put in psychological terms
is their behavior
that doesn't involve
the mind
at all
and the answer is
yes of course there is
we've known for a long time that there
are certain
here mate spent all of the detonate
behaviors that don't seem to involve the
mind at all
on spinal reflexes in cranial reflexes
paula dot that don't involve any hired
nervous system activity
on taxis and invertebrates
don't seem to involve any higher nervous
system activity
and be in staying sir fixed action
patterns that the following two studies
like carl
alarm calls and bird
and all uh... imprinting them aladdin
geese and all that
also seem to be built in the hard water
body evolution
and don't seem to involve any kind of
mental life role
when you get to
more complex organisms in human beings
there has long been an argument
there are certain
although aspects of behavior those
represented by classical and
instrumental conditioning
that also don't involved
mental processes for mine to simply
isn't involved in it
and the people who made this argument
here of course
the behaviorist
who argued for what's known as a
stimulus response theory
on a boat of conditioning
that basically says
perception memories thoughts
expectations police none of that makes
any difference to behavior
all all we have our
finally responses
to environmental stimuli and stimuli and
responses get connected by a principle
of trying to get woody
that buchanan connect any stimulus to
any response that's what the
arbitrariness assumption is all about
in order to wonder stand behavior
you don't have to look inside
on the the organism
you don't have to think about its
biology you don't have to think about
what's on its mind ripped expectations
are beliefs reports
and the organism
active
behavior
the behaviorist idea was that the
environment acts on organisms
organisms don't do anything independent
of environmental stimuli
in other words
that people
palm
on just like other animals
reflex machines
you see
we don't nobody
nobody acknowledges
that they're behaviorist any longer
i don't think
um... kinda like finding somebody who
voted for richard nixon nobody will
admit it
along
you can see this decide this question
about whether you can have a mind
without a body what he could have bodies
without wines and wines with our bodies
alm
in what's known in the fourth optical
trade as those on the argument against
materialism
snuggle wall in history a lot of
spalazzo for estimated on gonna david
chalmers
has made it most famously
he says what
we let's define as dom beat
as a creature
that is physiologically identical to
human beings
but lack conscious experience
this is a definition of what's known as
the full lhasa for resolving
a creature
that is physiologically identical to
humans
but lacks conscious experience
and childers argument
goes as follows
the actual argument
fall off of her
zombies are conceivable
whatever it is conceivable is possible
and therefore zombies are possible
an exam these are possible if it's
possible to have a creature that's
physiologically identical to humans but
lacked conscious experience
therefore
the materialist take on mind
unconsciousness
is wrong
because materialism leave something out
because zombies
who are physiologically identical to
humans but my conscious experience
have conscious experience therefore
there's something about physical
materialism that doesn't account for
consciousness
now what chalmers and other people argue
with that
perfectly
logical soldiers of
so long as you accept the major premise
leads on these are conceivable
and so long as you except the minor
premise
that whatever is conceivable as possible
must reach the conclusion
if you follow aristotle's rules
that zombies are possible
completely logical
solo her case if you accept the
pregnancy is right
okay but the best of
small problem with the argument right
now
and that's the minor promise bizarre
really true that whatever is conceivable
as possible
is it conceivable that the ratio of the
diameter toward the circle to would
start the woods radius is something less
than all your whatever it izak
conceivable i suppose it's conceivable
all of them
that maybe not but people like that
a lot of difficulty with this argument
in part
because it is
a perfectly logical argument
people just get
really wierd about it and doesn't
there's that's going to be something
wrong here
one response is that ok it's logical
okay
but there are some problems in the first
one is with the pts with the minor
premise right the conceivable would be
does not necessarily entail possibility
but the more though the better argument
i think against the zombie art
thugs on b contour argument it for if
you will
all the comes from den bennett
which is to say that if we believe
that the brain is the physical substrate
of the mine
then are being that is physiologically
identical to humans
would be conscious
perforce despite the fact that he's
physiologically
identical to humans
on you can say well materialism leave
something out
alm without dealing with
this problem if it hits the brains of
physical substrate of mine
that'd be that's physiologically
identical to humans
would have to be conscious you can't
have those kinds of something
my view of this is that the philosopher
zombie is the wrong argument to me
okay if you want to talk about this if
you want about the relationship between
body and mind
which you really want to do was
is the forget about philosopher is on
the
physiologically identical to humans but
lacking conscious experience
all ballad and then it at some point
talks about the simos
on as wonderful way of words and says
all winter but would would you might
have a zimbalist which is a zombie that
believes it's conscious
really conscious the implication
actually
debiting sw resembles
okay death really does think resembles
on new things that we just think we're
conscious
home
he's a darn he's one of those knew billy
j_c_s_ for example has got a whole
argument about religious belief is that
you don't believe in god you just think
you did
at the same kind of thing
anyway i think myself that we ought to
set aside the philosopher zombie
and instead take our scientific
inspiration
hollywood zombies
the kinds of people who are portrayed in
george romero is a night of the living
dead
palm
because so much more interesting zombies
they're really interesting zombie just
if you've never watch the row meryl
movies you should watch them and you
should watch them in order
because in the night of the living dead
ans oddly is just a creature
that has behavioral capacities
but lacks consciousness
okay
none of this physiologically identical
stuff zombies are defined in the movies
as creatures that my consciousness they
don't have free will decide to walk
around like that rate
they just walk around whatever they want
to do something to eat it
on and then when they're finished
feeding that they walk around until they
run into something else and then they
eat that that's all they do
out in the row meryl movies in fact
zombies evolve
which is really an interesting thing
deepened the that's why you have to
watch them in order
home
uh... until you can actually see of
romero zombies involve yuval
but underlying the hollywood zombie
is the so-called haitians on the polled
the uh... kind of
creature from the of the century old
beyond that
people who work stalls and lack
three wills okay
wire these interesting
buffalo through zombie just is
completely encoder
right just
dude u
get anywhere with the flow through
zombie
the hollywood zombie
asks really interesting philosophical
and psychological question by reversing
essentially the question about the
neural correlates of consciousness
will be asked about the neural
correlates of consciousness
what we really were asking his
what's the difference
between nervous systems that can produce
consciousness
and nervous systems that can produce
that's what we're looking for when we
look for the norrell correlates of
consciousness
what i think is much more interesting
is the automaton question that comes to
us from the hollywood zombies which is
zombies are behaving organisms
order any
behavioral functions
that require consciousness
or their functions that would be
impossible
have consciousness
by asking the question about kenya how
bodies without mines in that way by
looking at the hollywood somebody's
you begin to ask a question about
what consciousness is good for
being conscious
buys you as aid behaving organism
and it turns out this is an important
question
not least because in modern cognitive
and social psychology
love there's a lot of interest in a
distinction between automatic and
controlled processing
uh... argument that there is certain
mental function certain behavioral
functions that are automatic in that
they are inevitably a boat
by the occurrence of some stimulus
once evoked
runoff to exited that they're executed
in a ballistic fashion so that you can't
stop them
their execution consumes noel cognitive
capacity and it doesn't interfere
with other ongoing process he's okay
automatic processes are in some
important sense mindless process of the
processes
modern psychology makes a nice
distinction between of some processes
that are controlled
that is conscious
or other processes that are automatic
unconscious
all of the general assumption here is
that or dramatic processing used to the
extent that there are any automatic
processes they are all i'm conscious in
the strict sense of the word they are
performed
conscious effort andy conscious
intention anne conscious awareness
now as i said
psychology tries to all of the what was
to distinguish between two kinds of
process easy raising the question of
what's the next
how much of our behavior is
under conscious control
how much of our behavior is unconscious
an automatic
and some individuals like
john barge added gail university heb
argued that in fact
almost all of our behavior is automatic
and unconscious
most of a person's everyday life is
determined not by their conscious
intention to deliver choices
mental processes that are put into
motion
into motion
by features of the environment that
operate outside of conscious awareness
this world
consciousness by zee and often
mostar behavior
most of what we do
we do automatically and unconsciously
we are for all intents and purposes
without minds
world automatons after all
that's the argument we're going to for
the next series of lectures
beginning on monday
thank you very much have a good weekend