okay i'm assuming that clock is still
off by a minute
so what do i think you've all gotten
should what you what should have gotten
an email from you now about the all
midterm exam feedback
we identified a couple of items that
could have been better and restored them
and when we re scored them
they got my scores
all we also added two points everybody's
scored to compensate a little bit
further d
for the length of the exam
now that i can do about that
and
that's the distribution of course pretty
good distributions toward
median score forty four
use kore
forty-three
quite happy
so
if you have any questions we're going to
do arguably exams back in your
discussion section
so if you see something that seems
problematic
consulted yes i am willing going to be
give your restore
or remember to follow the rules first
donor threes go run
the chance that you might get an extra
pointer to
it's not worth it and you won't
palm and the reason you won't lose
just on chance
is at the g_s_ liza been instructed to
be very conservative every scoring
all but if you really think that's a
problem with how one of your questions
was evaluated
when a couple of senses
and present that to your g aside and
will take care of that as soon as
possible
assault let's talk about anesthesia and
komo
and today will talk about anesthesia on
wednesday we'll talk about karma
and the first thing to do is a little
bit of history here make the point that
anesthesia is a relatively recent
development in medical practice
introduced only in the mid middle of the
on making century
before that there wasn't anything like
anesthesia
people were simply ask to tolerate
surgical procedures whether was the
application of a leg gore part of the
word chest surgery or whatever
all sometimes they were given substances
to help them through that
alba alcohol
fall sometimes called the sometimes
opiates what warn them
all but mostly they were just acid
tolerated given a bite boarding clenched
thirty-five
and then restrained so they didn't
called start
fighting the surgeon
and the surgeon just went ahead and did
is uh...
and did his thing
towards the end of the eighteenth
century however people began getting
interested and the use of chemical
agents to relieve pain
and induce anesthesia
great british cameras humphry davy
all wasn't early experimenter with this
almost with a with nitrous oxide
argue from that dialog nitrous oxide
golden's headaches
why and also believe dental pain when he
had a uh...
infected through
but mostly humphrey davies onto humphry
davy found out the people really like to
take a nitrous oxide
all that it was not through him that the
home
georgian england
all develop this new social event komal
laughing gas party
where they'd ask humphry davy to concoct
some nitrous oxide for them and then all
these people would sit around and
home
michael faraday heartbreaking wish all
that physicist all began experimenting
with another substance of this error
discovered that it had analogies
occasioned
vodpod ideas friends were more
interested in theater parties
palm so let's is kind of never went
anywhere
all the even though out
brewed beer in the uh...
than the late
eighteenth early nineteenth centuries
people would be game to think that the
home
you could actually get rid of pain
all of this way
all of the problem
for the almost for most of the all
first part of the nineteenth century
the only all thing you could do besides
ask the patient to tolerate analgesia
was to hypnotize them
all and there were a couple of all
important scholarly monographs on the
use of hypnosis or as it was called them
asthma rhythm
are two while relieve pain and surgical
patients all talk about that a little
bit later in the semester when we talk
about the posters
all but all
florida gradually ether began to be
introduced first in dental practice
and then into medical practice home
uh... as they uh... as an anesthetic
agent
all and also people rediscovered the end
of static all of them qualities of
nitrous oxide
or was it raymond wells
volume eighteen forty four
all reported that nitrous oxide was
uh...
job was real good for or
does an anesthetic agent for dope for
dental extractions
all unfortunately dull after he was made
that initial report he was asked to
demonstrate the uh...
uh... thos technique publicly
and if the patient
all who was not under nitrous oxide but
still conscious
palm because that's what you are when
you're under nitrous oxide
fallen
of flinched
wind all buddha's tooth has been
extracted and all of the observer said
well he's not it's not a peep audits of
failure
he's not experiencing pain at all
and he is experiencing pain after all
and then finally in eighteen forty five
eighteen forty six
all you get the introduction of easter
him into surgery not dental
all of practice but actual medical
surgery
on first got to do this was actually a
southern all the of the position in
crawford long
after whom the emory university teaching
hospitals named in georgia could ever
been there
called base hospital unfortunately alm
while he never published his
observations and so credit for the
introduction of either as an anesthetic
agent in surgery goes to arm of the
world well you know another
actually a dentist
who introduced this
for medical surgery
hall at harvard
and this is a very famous painting if
you go to the hotel where library at
harvard medical school you see this
hanging on the wall
all of this is all of the introduction
of of of the surgery
here is the patient gilbert babbitt
who's having a big sis removed
uh... from his neck
and there's the surgeon uh... warren and
here is orbital
william morton
with his little speaker of either on
keeping on keeping gilbert ballot
added unconscious
during this whole procedure this of
course
as good as probably knows how surgery
was done though in those days
they call them operating theaters for a
reason the shift theater
ald where the uh... though that the
medical students were all crawled around
all to uh... to watch the procedure
and of course this was before antes
sepsis so
a lot of patients got infected
was not a good thing
you there was a very good thing
and in anesthesiology departments and
hospitals worldwide now
october sixteenth
is celebrated as either day you may have
parties
nadi for parties but they do have
alguna vez celebrating this thing
palm
mortenson headstone and mt auburn
cemetery in cambridge massachusetts
celebrates him as the man who abolished
pain forever
uh... really quite something
poem which had a picture of it
anybody ever goes to cambridge
if your jogging through mobile bird
cemetery watch out for the headstone
take a photograph and send it to me
anyway always be all that with the uh...
discover with with the documentation
at harvard of course
all qualities are analgesia of the
though you know that uh... the
anesthesia than no technique began to
take off
and there are a number of development
saw that neither substance chloroform
was introduced for anesthesia surgery
uh... just a couple years later
queen victoria famously had root eight
child the prince leopold
or with chloroform
liked it a lot recommended it to
everybody
coral colored austrian ophthalmologist
introduced cocaine as an anesthetic for
uh... ice surgery
all you need to maybe four sigmund freud
worked on this but mostly freud took
cocaine
bomb
then
all people got the idea that you've got
anesthesia would go better be more
reliable if you pre medicaid the patient
with morphine
ald
and then dot henri paul said called
introduce below of cocaine for the
purposes of local anesthesia
injecting cocaine right into a nerve
onto to delwip
same thing happened with corning
uh... with spinal out of the anesthesia
so why do you all of them by goldman mid
to late eighteen eighties
anesthesia chemical anesthesia was
everywhere
all but it wasn't always used
interestingly
on there were a lot of all of the on one
of our debates within the medical
community bellwether about when it was
appropriate to use on an anesthesia and
when it was inappropriate to use
anesthesia
home
a debate that's blood
summarize our wonderful book all by a
sociologist of historian of science
on call the calculus of suffering
bunch country road who should have their
pain relieved and who shouldn't they're
being relieved
and uh... to make a long story short
all of the mail positions of the
nineteenth century got the idea in their
heads that
it would be really good for women to
experienced pain during childbirth
all because that would uh... increase
their bonding with their infants
not sure exactly how that was supposed
to work but that's what that's what
that's anyway what they go
what they argued
okay in the twentieth century at all to
get new although for the further
developments are in anesthesia
on film people begin to use sedative are
drugs for the rapid induction of
anesthesia uterine chloroform take
awhile to put the patient under
with barbiturates like all the sodium
pentothal abetted by other things
newer drugs like propyl fault all you
can actually induce on the anesthesia
loss of consciousness very very very
quickly
alm and a bugaboo but though what one
problem remain
which wasn't even though the patient was
unconscious
still there were all of the reflexive
responses
almost all of the on the body
to what is used for mister quinn cold
surgical stimulation
and our people wanted to get rid of that
so they started introducing
archer rar redirect lives
all four muscle relaxation so the
patient as i said it is not just
unconscious
but also
of effectively paralyzed on the
operating alone
on the operating table
so it won't be any reflexive responses
wind on when the cutting
palm
then a whole bunch of new are inhalation
allegiance were introduced to supplant
the ether and chloroform which argues
very much anymore
substances like isoflurane and flooring
or people started using home or on
intravenous or opi lloyds for very rapid
called the analgesia
you'll see you know home
uh... references in the literature to
controlled substances like fennel and
some fat no
then regional anesthesia paralyzing
other than a surprising just one part of
the body of supposed to
or person
and a conscious sedation about which
i've talked
bangalore along
a couple weeks ago
where the patient is actually conscious
but sedated
feels no pain and has no memory
on personal memory afterwards
modern anesthetic and i dont technique
looks like this is what the positions
called balanced and have done that
although that anesthesia
and it doesn't involve just giving a
single drug to induce consciousness
but it involves giving the patient oval
cocktail of drugs that have all whole
host of different affects
so for example
patients will read all the bill while
routinely gava pre-operative dose of
laid off
all good
beds of as a team some kind of sedative
drug which is intended
are both to reduce the patient's
pre-operative anxiety
and also to facilitate the induction of
all
of anesthesia
then v all of the patients will be given
some anesthetic eight int
uh... and inhale a drug like home dot
like gold club
isoflow ring
or a dollar
all of the intravenous drug like san
fernando
to actually induce anesthesia
and cause laws orval
was awareness
patients are also given a muscle
relaxant again one of these uh... cure
rory
derived or the drugs
to alban calm the operative or area
because some of the patients effectively
paralyzed the patient that has to be
artificially breast berated
during the procedure so there's old
uh... you know
uh...
this good too
uh... it belongs
and then the boa patients will also get
towards the end of the procedure
on the day bobo list of some analgesic
on the agent that's intended to through
will ward off post-operative pain
because after recover from surgery of
course for those of you had surgery the
surgeries not over
on people the moderate pulling your ribs
apart to do it all sorts of things and
it hurts
uh... and it hurts while they're doing
it
anesthetized and it hurts
phone finished doing it as well
but in any event that's what we do now
all for apprentice the showed the hole
cocktail of drugs
and what will happen is that a typically
vienna the anesthesiologist would give
some will make a pre operative business
get informed consent for the procedure
administer all it was some kind of
sedative premeditation
palm song
of which i did it as i say again is
intended to
kind of help the anesthesia alcohol
along
and then there will be the induction of
anesthesia itself
that happens and wanted to basic ways
there's either what's known as rapid
sequence induction
which shall involves the intravenous
administration the obvious almost
synthetic or
synthetic opiates
or something like twelve the proper
fault
all four
on slower
all mass conduction with oprah dog
breathing mask
over the patients face
and administered things like nitrous
oxide you know at all the uh... in
oxygen or
so foreigner whatever
and it's at that point that they start
we are giving the muscle relaxant
to calm the operative roman coming up
with a area
and then once you've got the muscle
relaxant thing patient has to be
connected to a ventilator for artificial
respiration
then you maintain the general anesthesia
throughout the procedure
either by administering
albeit gun nitrous oxide and oxygen was
very common or solve all inhalants like
isoflurane
or by giving the home and intravenous
narcotics all-white complex internal
that goes on throughout the entire
opportu procedure as needed
and then at the end of the procedure
they give you all of the did you were
drug that'll reversal muscle relaxation
also that you could breathe on your own
again
all the
remove the ventilator
and then beyond
the anesthetic agents themselves either
the inhalants or the intravenous agent
they just wash out of the body
so you just recover from those naturally
they're not chemically weavers
and then as i say right at the end of
the procedure is very common
for a patient to receive some kind of
intravenous
on narcotic
that's intended to deal with
post-operative pain that's the procedure
all and it works pretty nicely
calm
and it will induces what the auger
positions now paul
at the very
nicest phrase of the world but uh...
what they call a controlled coma
as opposed to what uncontrolled komal
about which we'll talk on wednesday
that has these elements to it sedation
okay the patient is calm
all walks of consciousness
fault book talk about how we measure
loss of consciousness in a moment
and then immobility
that's uh... measured both by a lock of
voluntary motor behavior which actually
comes from the anesthetic agent
all four of reflexive responses
which our own
inhibited by diesel by these muscle
relaxant so that's what the procedure
looks like
and if you think about those combat
continue of consciousness that though
that we talked about all of our earlier
sorry can't get this done any further
wakefulness on one-dimensional awareness
on the other dimension
general anesthesia is commonly located
or were right about there
there's no wakefulness you or in some
sense and sleep you're not going for
your normal sleep cycles
or even up asians who are invested prize
for very long periods of time
don't go through anything like normal
sleep cycle and all the whole point of
this
is ought to run to the patient unaware
orble of what's going on
so we'll talk about komal
mark on them
on wednesday
now there are a whole bunch of
alternative procedures for general
anesthesia just wanted garb of the touch
base with those
we're not going to talk about those now
because they don't interested they don't
to all or that represent any kind of
loss or alteration of consciousness
as we usually uh... as you and as we
usually think about it the reason
anesthesia is of interest and of course
like this
is because
anesthesia is gottlieb is commonly used
by safe a la suffers
to artwork
what consciousness isn't
ka justices what you've got when you're
not anesthetized ka justices what you've
got when you're not asleep
also are what we want to do is talk
about
conscious although anesthesia as a laws
orval
the loss of consciousness
our couple although a point about
how it works
and the first thing to be said is
we don't have any clear idea
how anesthesia
homeworks
palm
when dad and that that anesthesia was
originally introduced in the all
mid-nineteenth century
or both of them
purely as what
the positions like to call an empirical
treatment
empirical treatments in medicine or
treatments that are known to work
what whose mechanism is not known
aspirin
is pretty much an empirical treatment we
know it gives pain relief but we don't
know
really know how aspirin works or
theories but
that's it
although
uh... but of course
they want to have some sense of what
uh... about of however seizure works
and there had the hub for a long time
been all some moralist informal theories
around
one of which is that
all of the analgesic agents alter the
dynamics of the are newer on membrane
so what's the interfere with the
polarization and all of that
there's another theory that says well b
l practice and that uh...
within is at the cell body it's on the
acts on a dog
that it interferes with the transmission
over what all the neural impulse down
the exxon
and then all of their theories of
anesthesia that hold that it interferes
with so that the transmission
either the release of neuro transmitters
into the syntax for the pre synoptic nor
on
or the uptake
barbara transmitter
all by the postsynaptic nora
now when you think about it
half a second
what else could it be
however dependencies or possibly work
something like that right
either you interfere with the
polarization or you oradour you
interfere with son after transmission
there isn't anything else that's going
on in the nervous system besides
people recession
and soon after transmission so it's
pretty obvious
that anesthesia interferes with one or
the other
what although above major topical
anesthesia research nowadays are lots of
people working on this
trying to figure out exactly are exactly
how it works
also
uh... they're a bunch of single pencil
called single process theories
one is that guardian helen battle geez x
like nitrous oxide and dong doens't fml
on dissolved in the fat cells all vet
that altman so that surround the uh...
the cell body of the door on
and basically of uh... screw up the ion
channel so that so you don't get the
polarization
and then there's another our civil
process period says not that's not right
has got nothing to do with fat cells
but rather that analgesic agents
all bind on to the proteins onto the nor
on
and in that way somehow interfere with
synaptic transmission
fairly standard theories now
but again on there's a lot of debate
about this in the literature and we
don't really have a good idea how these
things work
and then there are these are there is a
newer dual process period general
anesthesia
that says that
some analgesic agents
inhibit excitatory neurotransmitters
whereas
anna javel anesthetic agents
fault-tolerant
potentiated the activity of inhibitory
neurotransmitters
but again if you think about it for half
a second
got to be one of the dura transmitters
come in june for right
they come in
excitatory neurotransmitters an
inhibitory neurotransmitters
and if you're getting him hit in
addition of neural transmission
you're either going to get it by
inhibiting excitatory neuro transmitters
or buy
inhibiting
i don't bother all applaud the
potentiated vividly remember a
transmitter so
we have a very good idea of idea about
how the nervous system works the
mechanics of it the electrochemistry of
it
but exactly how
bill
exactly how org
analgesics work
is just something we don't yet no so
those of you were contemplating going on
the medical school
although palm
if you want to be famous
regardless
a really good
believed in the work on
alm
i'm gonna skip this this is just than
anybody is really interested in this
kind of uh... kendall
inflicted on yourself on your own time
hall but of roger penrose great barbara
british scientist has suggested on
uh... that though we can understand how
when assad anesthetics work in terms of
his quantum theory of consciousness
which is far as i can tell is just
basically a series of metaphors
for all
of unconsciousness
all but in any event
the idea here
worked out with
un-american anesthesiologists to work on
or off
is that
palm
there is
did this is a meron so there is your
cell body
here's your acts on
here's your dog terminal fiber
and there are called
uh... passageways applaud inside the
acts on
move chemical other chemicals up and
down
although the meron
and they suggested
that all of these micro tubules setter
inside the axe honor where the action is
for anesthesia but they don't have any
evidence for this either
ons just appalled this is an interesting
theory about about all this and what
makes it more interesting is that it's
couched in terms of quantum mechanics
home
leading of the church elan's of poland
patricia
to complain
what penrose and his friends are doing
is explaining one mystery the mystery of
consciousness with another mystery the
mystery of quantum mechanics
and that sounds about right to me
so okay
let's go back to consciousness here we
know who but don't think that uh... we
which bill discussed what amnesty at
adult the anesthesia does
how do you know
how do you know the truth
all of them that the patient is lying
out there upon the surgical table
really is on really is unconscious
for a long time all surgeons a land and
anesthesiologist really all the relied
on what you might call clinical or
behavioral assessment
of consciousness
one of which was a lack of response
deanna soup the end of the
anesthesiologist would say to the
patient
can you hear me
if you can hear me respond
which isn't easy to do when
you're paralyzed on the table
palm the but it
things are working well at least the
patient consent advice i can hear you
something's not working
or or they look at lack of response to
surgical stimulation went the first
incision if there's
some kind of movement from the patient
if they follow
not completely anesthetized
followed
then fog interestingly the other clinic
the other aspects of clinical assessment
of out of beneficial occur after the
surgeries over
it's very common either for the
anesthesiologist or for a l nurse in the
recovery room to ask patients
if they were aware of anything during
the procedure
did they feel any pain during the
procedure
paula and if the remembered anything
happening
during the procedure
so on
it's through this kind of
all posteriori lie order
uh... kind of barbara retrospective
of report
that they understand really bad things
on things are working
all recently however there have been of
annulled broke more faultless both
scientifically based all the way is a
monitoring surgical
or surgical awareness
but even so it's important to point out
that although we don't have a very good
idea about how
anesthesia o works in terms of his
on them terms of his neural mechanisms
it's very clear that it does work
almost everybody who goes above the
huard who has had a seizure
uh... for surgery
all reports
didn't hear anything didn't experience
anything don't remember anything more
laws and in pain or whatever
all far fewer than one percent of
surgical patients report
any awareness
of the procedure
are during surgery
all maybe point uh... look good
uh... point two percent of general
surgical cases
even if you look at medical malpractice
claims
fewer than two percent of all
all resolved medical malpractice claims
involved i think that any claim of
surgical where so
surgical overdoses
we could do very very very well
or in madison
alva
that that's probably as good a nap of
the there's good evidence that you can
imagine
there are some cases where you do get
some surgical workers
and that is when the positions have used
have deliberately employed
are very light
plane of surgical anesthesia for various
reasons
on softened on in obstetrics personal
caesarean section for example
because although that will put about
ascetic
drugs well they're their drugs right
and you want to keep them up away from
the broke from the uh... developing
fetus if you can
all
all of the white plains that the seizure
are often used in trauma surgery and
that's because
many
thoughts on that anesthetic agents
require that the patient have a song
minimum level of blood pressure
and if the person's bleeding profusely
from say a gunshot wound
nor or something like that
that's not going to happen
in the same outlook for the same reason
a lot of draws a cardiac surgery
wised up with a very white plate of
anesthesia because you just can't
deliver enough of the stuff
under those circumstances
and in rural surgery
very often neuro surgery that's done
with the patient wide awake
also that the uh... positions karen
kind of probe of the brain and
get the patient to talk about what's
going on
all of those uh... surgeons
use
general anesthesia
it seems to work on really really really
well
fall one or index and kind of indirect
index of consciousness
that all of that issue dot
anesthesiologists used quite a bit
is known as the p_r_ s cheese score
and that's based on our understanding of
how the order nomic nervous system
responds to stress
also
what's interesting here is that the
automatic nervous system
which we usually don't think of having
anything to do with consciousness
is actually being used as a indirect
measure
of consciousness
on positions will monitor the patient's
blood pressure that's the p
and heart rate that's the art
they'll look for signs of sweating
either on the brawl or of the in their
hands
or the secretion of cheers that's the
t_v_
all glad to have patient shows any of
those polled signs of auto nomic nervous
system response
surgical stimulation
then they'll jack up
the the the anesthesia
all but this again is very clear that
the very indirect measure
called for the help of consciousness
the basic idea being that
if the patient
was in pain if the patient were
distressed in any way
the sympathetic branch of the or a
number of nervous system would kick in
and create arby's r
these p_r_ resting
uh... sign
so if you look at their own doug if you
look at surgical records for example you
will often see a reference
to the patient's p_r_ rescue score from
time to time during the uh...
during the procedure
but of course it's an indirect measure
of consciousness right which would
really like to have is a direct measure
of consciousness
that at all
that uh... monitor something closer to
the central nervous system and we've got
a couple of those
all here is old one
based on the event related potential
sometimes known as the evoked potential
talked about this a little bit before
this is a bit of a system a signal
algunas or basically a reflexive
response
to any kind of any kind of stimulus they
can be an auditory stimulus
the sort of the anesthesiologist will
put your phones over the patient's head
and all
play yard
traynor beeps
uh... into uh... into the ear it can be
visual stimulus or not usually in
surgery because patient's eyes are
closed
are very good very commonly it's a
cement a sensory stimulus
attach a little cough
to the patient's wrist and deliver
very very very brief electrical shocks
and looking at the uh...
and theo
central nervous system response onto
these this is what uh... that related
potential looks like kind of a typical
dot related potential
we're out here's what the stimulus
is applied
i thought was a milliseconds just one
second later and you see this bunch of
positive and negative of the deflections
we basically all break-up we ought not
have been related potential of the three
components
there is a early component
all representing about
ten milliseconds first ten milliseconds
after
all of the after the stimulus
which reflects brainstem
responses
to the stimulus
and then there's a mid latency component
out to about a hundred milliseconds a
tenth of a second that represents all
the sub subcortical responses like
responsible for all of us
to the of
to the stimulus
and then bs
late components after about a hundred
milliseconds out to a thousand
uh... milliseconds represent god organ
cortical processing of the stimulus
and what cause surgeons will do is ma
continually maku what anesthesiologist
will do
is continually monitor the patients
they're related potential to
odd to this tenuous
and they'll try to apply
all of that
uh... and uh... anesthesia
the to adapt to a degree
that will abolish
entirely
the late components of the abed related
potential
so essentially abolishing cortical
processing of the stimulus
and also
delayed amid lakeview components of the
these waves
or displays way out here
that's a very very very common
lol all of them all the technique for
monitoring responsible anesthesia
the general ideas if you're not getting
these late cortical responses
the patient really is unconscious you
can see
uh... you can see the largest
uh... of that
here is another technique
that anesthesiologists used to
to monitor the success of our of
analgesia
based on
on of another
all reading from the g known as the jeep
power spectrum
beall
dot the person the electrical activity
of the brain can be broken up into a
number of different bands all talk about
this
next week at in more detail will be talk
about sleep
here is a so-called delta
which is just a couple of cycles per
second
and update a rhythm about five to seven
uh... of those cycles of them cycles per
second
here's an alpha rhythm
about eight to twelve cycles per second
and debate a rhythm
eighteen to thirty
cycles per second
called
alpha you've the wiki nije basically is
a mix all of the alpha and beta activity
as you fall asleep you begin to show
things like delta
and uh... and theta activity
so whatever physiologist will sometimes
do
is continually monitor the patient
c_j_d_
and don't administer aesthetic agents
so as to
the median
all frequency of the persons e_g_ five
down two oh two or three cycles per
second
something looks more like this
and a lot
less than this
and they'll never let
the patient to eugene
fallback creep up into
into the althorp
uh... the ban just endured
that's that's pretty clear the air kind
of
lapsing into
uh...
deal awake so basically what they do is
they monitor the g
randall
and keep it looking more like this
not flat
goes that's bad
very low level
on that very low level of activity and
again the idea here is
the closer you are diverse
the more unconscious
more unconscious you are
yeah i would be one of these
appear id
yes
in principle you could do that
whether you can actually do it in fact
or not is another question entirely
beginning and then late nineteen sixties
there was although a lot of interest in
all of the association between
alf activity in the g_m_ certain
meditative
although met meditative states will talk
about this when we talk about meditation
all you know
how do you know
embarrassing
of the pleasure of chasing a very famous
zen
across my college campus
trying to slap
electrodes on into
look at his e_g_
home
he kept saying you know with a very
charming way he had
but in any event yallop said the
principle you could do that
whether you can actually trained people
to increase the amount of alf activity
in the region
that's highly debatable
highly debatable
on whether you can actually trained
people to generate
just fade activity or or or or delta
activity
i don't know how good that literature is
either
to be really honest with you because we
think about per second your training
some way to do something deliberately
that they're supposed to show when
they're asleep
so that's not going to be easy
alms so all of the did there there to
set a separate things have to keep the
the
two things have to keep separate here
can people do it
to begin with
and the second uh... is home
if they can do it
we old
that pattern of the g
really induce an altered state of
consciousness as it's sometimes
expected
it was a rhetorical question
and they have not gotten
a lot of
actual systematic research
attention
there are claims out there
or you know if you would do so delta
state your be about
feel like you're now rafe type dance
party or something like that
candomble o
are just don't know
where the laboratory research is
but anyway that's the idea so what what
they will do is
bill monitor this they'll try to make
the with the patient c_j_ look more like
this
must like this
palm
here's another technique that bug dubbed
that we see a lot now even now in
medical use
this is a proprietary technique known as
by spectral analysis
all and what happens here is that
there's this little machine
that monitors a bunch of all volunteer
from parameters of the g and there's a
proprietary algorithm
that this format aspect medical systems
has generated through their all you've
done through their industrial research
that tells the that tells the
anesthesiologist
or whether the patient actually is on
conscious or not
because this is proprietary and based on
industrial research we don't know
exactly how the by spectral analysis
works rocket
here's how we think it works here's how
it advertising were the the board
there's this thing called the biggest
algorithm flights pectoral algorithm
tracks
how much high-frequency activity there
is in the g
say beta activity
it looks at
all low-frequency activity and
especially the synchronization of
low-frequency activity across
parts caldwell above the bottom parts of
the cortex
their tracks
how long and how often
the g appears to be
nearly suppressed again not flat line
but merely are suppressed
and the based on these kinds of
parameters calculates
what's known as a barista factor all
index
which goes all uh... basically a zero
to one hundred scale
one hundred means your as a way cuz you
are now
or maybe even more awake
on zero armies you are not awake and all
your brain dead
all
and what they want to do
is to basically
keep the persons by spectral index
however it's calculated based on these
parameters
down below around sixty
on old zero to one hundred scaling
gambar nih
old don't do that
also
dawes studies with almond with or
research volunteers
have shown that all of
if you can reduce a person's by spectral
index two eighty six
on this one hundred-point scale
all you get about fifty percent
reduction in recall yet
applied the anesthetic agent
get there by spectral index down to
about eighty six min chocolates the
words
get a fifty percent reduction of recall
ninety five percent reduction in recall
with radio on
uh...
by spectral index of sixty four
so the standard of care
is to keep the patients
all but all the by spectral index
below sixty
not too far below sixty
below sixty so again that's how
uh... anesthesia is monitored
and again
it makes sense
that uh... but that that this would work
the only problem with this and this is
used
all over the place i can tell you how
many surgeries are done using the by
spectral index
it so it is a proprietary algorithms and
dong do you know but research that's
based on it is also a largely
proprietary so you've got a trust your
equipment manufacturer
speaking of trusting your equipment
manufacturer group of anesthesiology
researchers at mcgill university have
now introduce that anesthesia robot
home which they call mix sleepy
nick for mcgill
and sleepy for
and what makes weepy does is
completely automate the delivery of
anesthesia
uh... this is done with all of the depth
typically with
phone
that intravenous on it
analgesics
but what will happen is this is the
machine this is one week sleepy looks
like
on and it's basically a computer program
that monitors various aspects of
although or that monitors the patient's
consciousness
based on the kinds of things that i've
just go on that
that i've just discussed
and if the patient's consciousness
begins to come up a little bit
it'll administer
so more anesthetic agent until the
patient goes back down
and when the patient comes up a little
bit it doesn't do the ministers were to
pick the patient backed out
and does the whole thing
automatically
so what does it do
are good measures consciousness of all
in terms of by spectral index
but i just discussed
it though looks of muscle relax ation by
monitoring a variant obviate g_m_ g the
electoral myo graph
on sexually photo not electro but it's
the same kind of thing
and then uses are two aspects of the
p_r_ rescue score
as proxies all four all for pain
and as i say the whole thing now
our business is done
with automation there's still an
anesthesiologist or nurse-anesthetist
there to monitor the whole thing
but the claim is that you don't really
need
abadi
in there anymore that the machine will
do it
automatically
sleepy was introduced in two thousand
eight at macdill
in two thousand ten
onto participated along with a surgical
robot known as the veggie
in a uh... article about the
transatlantic
of prostate surgery
like them case of love
as she was operated on in italy
for all the
montreal
completely
analyses are robot and the surgical
robot
well that's cool
what can you say it's kind of
interesting
soviet that the other guy
monitoring a good news in a couple of
joy sticks
montreal
to actually do the prospect of me
uh... all big sleepy also sitting in
montreal
was monitoring the patients
level of consciousness patient was in
italy
i'd was kind of a stone but it was kind
of interesting parting uh... for people
who do
also that's basically the story about
all of the bod anesthesia and how
consciousness is monitored i got one
more thing to say about all of this
but ordering questions about
monitoring of consciousness
of this whole thing would go a lot
better perhaps if we had neither had a
good neural correlates consciousness
which we don't
or if we had a really good theory about
how anesthesia worked
which we don't
palm
what people do
seems to make sense and we definitely no
okay so
adequately anaesthetized patients are
out of it they are not aware of what's
going on or around them
which raises all sorts of interesting
questions about well just hulond aware
or are they
palm my laboratory ulm
the estes question in terms of bulk
implicit memory
arrange some surgical events
of four patients
called what would they show the back of
a show explicit memory for those
surgical of ends
by definition
because we've got explicit memory you're
not adequately anesthetized
the question is
if the adequate anesthesia abolish is
explicit memory doesn't abolish implicit
memory as well
so of when i was a diverse array result
no
we got a hold of
once patients and all of the word
coming in for elective surgery are
getting isoflurane all further
anesthetic
and while they were in surgery
we put your phones on them
and played to a bunch of
or paris or suits of the former host of
water overnight and so on
we're just play them over and over and
over again for the duration of the
surgery
average of about of garbage about
fifteen minutes
and then although i have to they out
came out of surgery after they woke up
on the recovery room
we gave them a bunch of memory tests
and or first was a cube recall test
present them with all shins at what was
the word paired with
tell us that
palm
for recognition
we asked me to go to the performed
recognition tested before very poorly on
the recognition test as well
but what we give them a free association
test
while presenting them with the word like
oceana say what's the first were the
comes to mind
lo and behold
they were more likely to give
the word that that
q had been paired with
all of the during surgery
or that they were
on neutral paris it had not been
presented to them
so there's a prime in effect there it's
about ten percent prime minister act
which is about what you get on in the
use of uh...
in these circumstances
on suggesting that
anesthesia by definition abolish is
explicit memory for surgical of ends
calm or under some of the under some
circumstances of these
on seems not to had the same effect on
implicit memory
so something
can percolate
or even though the patient is all
is adequately uh... is adequately
anesthetized final clinical
and on and monitoring criteria
skip over this one
here is a review
of the slurs your group our laboratory
was the first
convincingly demonstrate spirited was
the memory of general anesthesia
they've been a lot of these studies
since then
alm
this is from a review by miracle and
damon showing that
on average you get out
small affect
on implicit memory
that you know general anesthesia it's
preserved but fully preserved a little
bit
so mason has preserved role
the patient is a mess supplies
of the affects our strongest if you test
within twelve hours of the surgery and
get progressively
and uh... and get progressively weaker
now this is all something that
uh... the raise some very interesting
questions here
but what we've got is argues that
implicit memory test
all what i'd prefer to think of this as
solve at that is an instance of implicit
perception
not of implicit
because you may remember although mir
talk about explicitly implicit memory
we'd thought
constrain the definition of explicit
above on implicit memory
to those cases where the event was
consciously perceived at the time it
occurred
and then subsequently lost the explicit
memory
but preserved in implicit memory
by all accounts
anaesthetized patients added adequately
anaesthetized patients are not aware of
what's going on at the time of at the
time the event occurred
are because there's no conscious
perception involved
i really think that what we've got in
anesthesia is case
uh... ball
of the implicit perception
but in any event
it appears to be the case that at least
under some circumstances
in anesthesia
something can percolate through
something can get through
on it's not enough to give rise to
conscious recollection it's not enough
to give rise to any kind of conscious
experience of all
bubbly conceived by subjects responses
to these priming tests
that's something did
did in fact get through
alm
which leaves
the question called
maybe subjects are aware of everything
that's going on
during surgery
and they're just bay just don't remember
it later on
this is a very common uh...
the question about its reminds me of the
harlan ellison
where it might actually be the case
that the events of that anaesthetized
patients are aware of what's going on
during surgery
but unable to respond by virtue of the
muscle relaxant
and what they experiences
a kind of
amnesia
for something that they were conscious
of
it turns out that's not the case
okay patients are not aware
during anesthesia
called we know that
alva through on some very interesting
experiments
that actually allow patients to respond
voluntarily
if they could if they would think that
they heard of the stimulus
why all their all boulder anesthetized
i can do this i think
pretty quickly
the isolated look at what's known as the
iceland fore arm technique
where the arm
the uh...
the a muscle relaxant spine two
receptors really really really fast
so if you put a blood pressure cough
on patients are
while the muscle relaxant or being
delivered
you can actually
faulty eliminate
the paralysis
so that you can then ask the patient if
you can hear me squeeze my hand
right cassia connection
make the response in the storm to
doesn't have the most we'll accept it
ald
and here's a very nice study are here
early on in the procedure bata
hundred-percent to patients respond
just one or two minutes after the
delivery of anesthesia there's no
responsible to the patient these
patients are not aware
during the procedure
nevertheless despite their lack of
awareness
somethings can percolate thru
to give rise to priming effects
uh... in the recovery room
okay that's controlled call mark on
surgical anesthesia
on wednesday will look at the
uncontrolled coma of karma and the
persistent vegetative state
thank you very much