okay let's turn our attention to
the thing you just woke up i would've
sleep injuries
let me just say that
costs we've got to
lots of material to cover in this course
and only a very limited time to do it
i can spend as much time on any of these
topics as i'd like to
all and that's the case for sleep and
dreams as much as it is for anything
else
fortunately we have lots of other
resources on the berkeley campus for
those of you who are interested in
learning more about various aspects of
sleep injuries
first we have a whole chorus on the
psychology of sleep psychology one
thirty three
which is talk alternately by professor
allison hardy and professor matt walker
are both of whom run
very gooood
sleep laboratories very interesting
sleep laboratories will talk a little
bit about mad walker's work
all later today
and then professor roller or wash draws
an ad altman operative asian chorus
devoted entirely to the psychology of
dreams
and on the history of dream
interpretation what the meaning of
dreams might be and all of that
so if you're interested in this
if i don't kill your interest in that
over the next couple of days
wanna learn more you should not talk to
these guys
forgetting sold
why should we be interested in sleep and
of course on now
and of course one consciousness
the first is that like anesthesia sleep
seems to represent all lapsing
unconsciousness
wet and philosophers for example tried
to talk about what consciousness is all
about
sometimes as i pointed out last week the
contrast
consciousness with
general anesthesia
other times probably more cobb were
wrong
commonly
they contrast or the consciousness with
the whole asleep and especially whipple
with what they like to refer to as green
was
uh... suite
so that's the first reason
that somehow
palm sleep
rep represents a contrast
with conscious mental life
the second dog point all take up all
club on wednesday
is that it turns out that they are all
sorts of things going on in our heads
while we are all the while we sleep
on there and all of while we sleep we
might very well be conscious at home
bit all over all the dreams and other
kinds of mental activities
so there is all
all of the the relationship to altered
states of consciousness
all of the third all reason is that
there's lots of stuff that goes on in
the environment
outside
palm dot outside the mind of the sweeper
palm and are what we want to know is
whether perhaps all of those sleepers
can engage in various kinds of
unconscious processing
we hear anecdotally about people being
able to
wake up at a preset time without benefit
of an alarm clock
that suggests that somehow the sleeper
is keeping track of the passage of time
all we also on here anecdotally about
parents awakening selectively to
the all across is a brother noises and
their children's bedrooms while but not
blow away coming too
hall louder more intense voices
on outlaw out on the streets so there's
all sorts of interesting
or questions about
is going on on during the hard during
sleep
and then finally all of the blob
cognitive scientists and psychologists
have been interested in sleep
for what it might tell us about the
mind-body problem
sleep injury misrepresent radical
changes unconsciousness
and those radical changes in
consciousness or associated with radical
changes in brain activity
then on studying the coral it's there
all my tell us something about tall
about some of the neural correlates of
consciousness so thats basically
why you were interested in that
uh... as far as the scores
well is concerned
so how do we know when somebody's asleep
if you ever had the opportunity to sleep
next to somebody
home or you can know you often tell
all that there is lead by virtue of
their
overthrow over behavior the changes and
relax ation
home usually sleeping
prone
people have been known to sleep in
shares
and people have been known to sleep
standing up
fell asleep standing up once in a row
museum in mexico
don't quite know how i did it but i did
it
are and you also lol
well are open to the sleepers oral off
usually characterized by very slow very
even breathing
not to say about the city's soaring
so that those are all over behaviors
that are used to diagnose sleep and were
used to diagnose sleep exclusively
often told all controlled relatively
recently
but there are also subjective
experiences
that enable us to diagnose so home you'd
be on the the onset of sleep
all first when people wake up
all from sleep they often experience
themselves as having
headed interruption in the stream of
consciousness
they find that they are not aware of
things that have been going on
for the last couple of minutes so work
for that matter for the last couple of
hours
so when he falls asleep in a movie or a
florio play or a quart of or or a
television program
the lawful makeup and say what just
happened
so there is some kind of blank their
that you have to uh... that you have to
fill in
alm
stars are similar legal
when people awaken especially if they
way kanata particular stages of sleeps
on panel talk about again in a second
our people seem to be disoriented
qualm
they've been not only don't know whether
they were asleep often well but they
sometimes don't know exactly alone
exactly where they are hot where what
time it is
there are a memory failures we diagnose
sleeps objectively but we can't remember
something that's been
we should be able to remember that's
been happening recently
and we also what are the diagnosis leaps
objectively
when we all but we remember that we've
just been dreaming and his bizarre
experience is about
dragons riding bicycles or whatever you
dream about
home and usage if you know i must've
been asleep cause
dragons dole ride bicycles
in the real world
okay so there are lots of ways
now my real world
alliance or what's a different ways in
which we can
of make-up to get it to the an
impression of somebody
were sold
we fallen asleep
there are of course better ways to do
list some old technical ways although it
though that sort of techniques that are
now known as police armed robber feet
polly many songs sleep haha griffey
writing or or were wrong but we're
graphing
so what happens here is we fasten
subjects
to are number of electrical devices the
record electrical at various forms of
electrical activity
on them they can observe changes in the
use of patterns of electrical activity
as people fall asleep
and wake up
part here's a typical setup
alm this is something called the e_m_
gene the electoral by a breath it
records all muscle activity
all
and i've been will record i'd movements
from the eyes
and also as will see you later
all was selected to be in the chimney is
usually used to diagnose the paralysis
that alum
that uh... occurs with the onset of
certain stages of sleep
then we record the g
are typically
in in that in uh... that most instances
just one electrode will do
though large seem set ups where there
are whole bonnets soap
two hundred fifty six electrodes
attached to
attached to the person
and then all the stuff goes into
all of a set of machines john sometimes
known as the polygraph
all because again it's recording lots
lots lots of different
our channels hall
at the time
and when you do that yes
well but there is just a reference point
so arb heroes
ulm you've got golf
that you've got
electrically you've got to have a ground
on
so you got to put it on something
michael had i'm here where there's not
supposed to be much electrical activity
down here
of people took off the rearrange so
they're not picking up radio signals
from morrison alone and other things
like that
but he could put it in you can put these
things anywhere
it's not good for anything else except
to hang in here
nearing or an electrode
so that's what that's why
soul called first thing we do
is always we observed are those people
fall a sleep and wake up and all that
are changes characteristic changes in
the electrical activity of the brain
this is all over
the newell find this in the lecture
supplements the one if you would really
want to go through it
but mostly we're looking at three
different bands of electrical activity
in the g_p_ electro insightful graham
elf activity which is very highly fall
baldridge rod activity body control
cycles per second
beta activity which is very low voltage
activity
home
homegrown eighteen to thirty
or cycles per second
and delta activity which is very very
high voltage activity
high-voltage
for the brain
about dove one before cycles per second
you can see
a little bit better business lie that
used to all of the less because well
what's on his waves look like
this is
so-called bade activities so you can see
the high amplitude
very fast
uh... activity
palm elf activities so what
lower amplitude but certainly all of the
certainly somewhat civil
somewhat slower
and delta activity here
one before one before cycles
the cycles per second
and what happens is you fall asleep
is that
all of these various patterns the
electoral ocular ground the electoral
himself would grab the electoral maya
grab
all go through characteristic guard
characteristic ships
all of which allow us to the following
this various stages
obsolete which comment
to or
for crimes
depending on how you count
here's what the halted typical waking
electrodes up a ground looks like a kind
of mixture of the alpha and beta
activity
are pretty decent provides pretty fast
homes and so on
and what happens first as you begin to
fall asleep
you move into a stage which is known as
descending
descending stage of stage one st
which is characterized by an absence of
alpha activity
remember the way kini g
is characterized by a mix about for and
beta activity
and as you fall asleep
alf activity gradually well gradually
disappears
and in most laboratories
the onset of sleep is marked by the
disappearance of alpha activity in the g
appoint it's important
will come back to a couple of different
on times
so stage one
are descended stage one d spending
'cause you're going down into sleep
marked by this disappearance of alpha
activity
then palm in stage two
you see the appearance although new
waveform
you can see one right here this is known
as the sleep spindle
because of what it looks like it looks
like oh
knitting spindle whirl oreo what we've
been spindle
all of these
begin to appear
in the g
and there is another called feature or
called on the g dot
that the begins
which is condone is a k complex
and this is one this biggs spike
in electrical activity that comes on
suddenly
and goes away the occurrence of sleep
spindles
and the k_ complexes in
the g
marks the transition into on into stage
two
and then what happens as the person
garden continues go they're not going to
sleep
on to begin to get these very large very
slow waves known as delta waves
appearing in
uh... in the g
allman and then as you get this and even
further into so-called stage four sweep
feed she is dominated
five distal
one of the by the stage for activity
here down here at the bottom
you can see really good representation
of a k complexes
paroxysmal
they call it spike
the comes out just comes out of nowhere
and then here's a very nice example all
the sleep spindle
where you can come to see that my civil
uh... the spindle of the spindle shape
so what happens is as you fall asleep
your heat that one way to think about it
is it that you really need you
progressively smaller style
you go from this mix of alpha and beta
activity
delta activity
as you go into into stage form so there
is as general slowing of the g
all which is why
all of this of the this activity is
called or that the tends to be cold
slowly
slow wave sleep
and then what happens is
young go back up
you get down to stage four
and then you move back up to three stage
three and stage two
into some people books like stage one
again i'll get in a second
stage one again except that now
in this eight sending stage one
you see two things
the energy is very relaxed through
record almost no muscle activity
all from me you know
on the from the chain and you begin to
see rapid eye movements in the g_p_ eyes
begin to dart back and forth
login and an awesome leading fashion
which is something they hadn't done in
stage two and stage three
those are cold wet but i'd move minced
and they give
this one stage its name
onstage ram in the older
uh... in the older sleep literature you
sometimes word
c refer to as is sending uh... stage one
down through these sleep stages
and then back up
in stage one
and as you'll see in a minute
as soon as it begins showing these
either of these read these rapid eye
movements
if you wake somebody up
and all what minister show in rapid eye
movements
and say what he did what do you do in
fills out all that was having a dream
so there's a there's an association here
between rapid eye movements him sleep
and really now you had a question
no they'd just come out of nowhere the
come out of nowhere on i'd misspoke
they come out of nowhere in terms of the
g ok they're just appear
you know you will see the war all over
the brain all of the dole depends on how
sophisticated and expensive in the g
monitoring setup
all you're going to have all you need to
see you all of this
is that
all you need is one crummy electrode
uh...
not that i'm aware rob you can see them
pretty much everywhere
hong again
it's not easy to look
you can do it
it's not
but it's not a completely
straightforward thing the localize
activity in the brain from the g because
what's happening in as the surface
electrodes are collecting
a lot of information about what's going
on you might think that when you're plop
of electrode under somebody's skoal
that what you're recording to see i'd
get to be the brain right underneath the
electrode
and you well you are
you're also getting a whole bunch of
other things
but on in general you can see these
things everywhere you look
anything else about this this is just
kind of giving you a sense of
what goes on here
alm so
what we've got here is all of the
appalled at the beginning is alright
already are summary
of the uh... kind of
nervous system activity in the city and
sleep so we won't first want to
distinguish
between slow wave sleepwear delta
activity is prominent
stage ram where palm where or verb rapid
eye movements are prominent
so what you get a slow wave sleep is
just kind of the body seems to be
shutting down and that's how was that's
how was generally photo
heart rate goes down respiration rate
goes down
brain temperature goes down three bo
blood flow goes down
on your tension or the attention goes
out of your body become begin beautiful
more rel
more relaxed and all that
five movements
are very very hard in a very very slow
your eyes might possibly back and forth
in their sockets
but there's nothing like the route that
i'd movements
that you see stage ram
then ram it looks like things are all
activated again
home
you get variable heart rate of
respiration novel global com back up and
be very variable
home
some of the post through blood flow
below
will go up and all that
what really happens though when stage
graham is that
the person is for all intents and
purposes paralyzed
there is a blocking
motors signals coming out of the brain
orbit this with the level of the or that
the level of the ponds
that effectively paralyzes the person
all from roughly the audience of roughly
the eyes down
you'll remember
from our discussion last time about
locked in the syndrome that in locked in
a syndrome there's damage to the ponds
which paralyzes the person renders a
person quadriplegic but because it's
barest those too
cranial nerves cranial nerves three and
four
the person is still able to under
generate i'd movements and blinking and
all that same thing is happening
uh... vote here
use paralysis of the body
basically goes from connect out of the
chin down
likens there is little
uh... spares the eyes of the eyelids
so that you can on record these rapid
broad but what it means is your name
yet look your body has got a couple of
different ways to thermal regulate ok
shivering and sweating and all of that
kind of stuff third also that's
just through
actions of the autonomic nervous system
and that doesn't work
the same way that doesn't work as well
on here
then poem
independent in stage round
or also
or the other ways we have for thermal
regulation is
throwing the covers off
were pulling the covers on
and they can't do that either
because you're paralyzed
in stage ram
also if you're a just in your covers if
you're sticking your leg of a book on
the part of the blankets and all that
stuff
that something you're doing in stage and
ram
when when your body is able to move yes
going to talk about that in a couple of
minutes i hope
on that's but what's known as sleep
paralysis
and what you're doing there is
you've awakened i would've around you've
waited on the stage ram
skeletal musculature hasn't come back
yet
okay
so you're still momentarily paralyzed
because print because you were paralyzed
or on a beloved move
while the muscle relaxation stage ram
and when you experience this sleep
paralysis which
is surprisingly common
palm
what's happened is your cortex is become
awake
what your ponds is not letting those
signals go back down to the alone
to be
uh... did to your skeletal musculature
yet
if you just wait a little bit
when that happens just wait it out
it'll come back
well the first time you experienced
something like that it can be quite
frightening
on that's that that uh... that that's
quite right
all but again
if you just kind of set there for ally
there for a minute because he can't do
anything else and try not to panic
home on
though the all of your
skeletal musculature will eventually
regain muscle tone
all on that subject to all of those
sleep paralysis dissolve as sometimes
thoughtful light behind
people's ideas that they've been in dot
blot abducted by aliens
wake up
i can't remember anything
they find themselves paralyzed and it
occurs to them that martians urban
museums or something have
captured the dot all sorts of terrible
things with them
but the back in bed and paralyze them
probably not the case
let's just put let's just put it that
way
so here it goes
let me see if i can turn these lights
off for a second so you can see this
better this is all of really nice figure
from
called from alan hobson
uh... showing exactly what happened saw
like here over a broad over an extended
period of time
here we're looking at higher movements
here is the needy
pattern for stage one two three and four
here's what's happening with blood
pressure low or highlight
of recording of
respiratory activity
here's a recording of pulse rate or her
trade activity
here is a recording all body movements
and what you can see
your urine
stage one stage two stage three stage
two
back up into what would ordinarily be
part of a stage one
but you're getting a lot survive
movements and then if you go back down
into stage two reside movements
disappear
when you're in this stage ram
your blood pressure
is going up
menace coming back down as you move out
of ram
respiration very regular here
then becomes irregular to reinstate
travel becomes regular again
heart rate
very regular in stage at around
very irregular
in stage where of
and then
fared are very of the regular again
and then body movements
you're not getting much body movement
here but you are getting some body
movement
all of the in this case ending phase
when you're coming out of staged for
your stage four
going into stage ram
they're not too much body movement and
then when the stage get so uh... stage
remnants over you're getting some body
movement again
that's what
full sleep cycle as light
and we now know thanks to of themselves
serendipitous discovery
that we have about five of these are
fluent in a regular nicely yet
not by cat account explain that i wish i
could
well but i could but it can
this is this is a sample record
what i suspect might have happened here
the pen went off the page
and comes back on which i think is
no book
actually you can do that if you suffer
from sleep apnea
you can stop reading
for a period of time
i don't think this record was selected
for displayed because i heard that
or in fact i know what some selected to
through one illustrate sleep apnea
what are people almost all of the
specially if they are overweight or they
have a certain
problems with their own that run
respiratory problems
our tenth stop reading for
substantial period of time
i have a feeling since it all for the
typically happens
as people or
falling asleep
i have a feeling that that occurs more
in stage and ram than in st ramp
though i'm not an expert on sleep
disorders i can find that out for it
also
the fight to have been posted something
to the website
put something up
whereas apne our current sleep cycle
arnold tried to uh...
while trying to do that
so here's what happens
okay
what we do what we do this is work from
home
from william dement part of the dawn at
stanford plotted this very nicely
if you plot
a typical eight hours of sleep which of
course is what your role supposed to be
getting
on who can see that
start off
you go down into stage four
then into the state of ren period
then that this appears to go back down
into stage three and stage for come back
up into a run period
go back down into add room
down uptown
typically people awaken odors stage ram
when you awaken in the morning to your
moral s bright-eyed and bushy tailed
all ready to go
hongkong that song
that's a special almost a sure sign that
people wake undoubted stage ram
if you away that you wake up in the
morning and you would rather be dead
almost a sure sign that you've awakened
out of stage and around
when you wake another stage amram your
very sluggish in new york disoriented
and it just
feel like
you feel terrible
yes
although that's true
although it has to be said that there is
a there's often transit awakenings after
any state run
this business about people waking up
with our own alarm clock we don't really
know what's going on there here's where
i have to sorbonne eyes for half a
second you've never seen you do this
before
almost every interesting question we
have about sleep has been completely
ignored by sleep researchers
palm raciest believable
all i have not
and i i i blame the discovery of rapid
eye movements all for this
home
powerful reasons all of the whole thing
to expand on later
but we don't actually know whether
people can do this or not
and if they can do it how they do it
one prominent hypothesis is when you
would have if you're the kind of
personal awakens called for the without
an alarm clock
it's because you're always wake up and
check on nine check on the clock
part of the somehow land and and and and
falling back to sleep
or you're just sleeping really lightly
to begin with
palm abut
to my knowledge nobody is ever
mail survey people take annual wickham
of alarm clock abroad for him in the
laboratory and see what they do when how
they do with how well they can do it
home
i wake up spontaneously about five
o'clock in the morning
po and by the probe that way so i don't
set some internal alarm clock to do that
just happens
phones
that that's what my sleep cycle looks
like and i suspect that's what
happens with a lot of people
if you go to bed at a decent hour you're
ready to wake up at six
yeah well if you wake up all of the en
route and that is definitely
disorienting palm as i said you'd rather
be dead
home of so
yes i mean your concert here or in part
for seven and a half hours but the grip
of about ninety minutes cycle of waking
and sleeping it's just kind of an
average
long and uh... turns out that
already period scuttled
the the uh... though you know interval
between ren periods get shorter
estimates sleep progresses
so you can't really play miss
as much as you might like
all you're not
here do you have your brains not kind of
on uk on a particular clockwork took in
ninety minutes going around now enough
that there is anything like that that
happens that's
approximately
ninety minutes
all go into these things
all all sorts of other things can
disrupt the sleep cycle if you drink
alcohol before you go to sleep that's
gonna screw up your sleep cycle if you
drink alcohol while your wrist leaf
that's going to disrupted sleep cycle
home sold are all sorts of things like
that pecan that can happen
phone
people who were on antidepressant drugs
that suppresses ram sweep
or all the antidepressant drugs along
food tri cyclic antidepressants and the
alarm
esis alright sales
they all suppress rem sleep
also almost anything you do to yourself
palm uh...
bio chemically
who's going to have
typically going to have some affect on
rem sleep and that includes taking
sleeping medications
sleeping applications articles we
compare revved sleep
on what you've got think they would make
a white that late
all but what somewhat sleeping pills do
was they catch it and uh... and ram
sleep pretty fast
but uh...
but they can uh... they can disrupt
video the floorplans
probably
that if you if you're having trouble
with insomnia
the best treatments republic behavioral
and nature
right rather than chemical
nature because the chemical ones have
all sorts of side effects
yet another question
yeah now again olympic i'm sure
this of course unconsciousness our
course on sleeping you really ought to
take one thirty three for that
but yes died professor david dangers at
the university of pennsylvania and and
and other people
have shown that
you can actually make up for a lot of
lost sleep if you just map
on and that nothing can be used to
replace weep all of the depth to replace
the standard
on eight hours of sleep the world
supposed to be getting
yeah yell i have to be if you think you
take a good nap a good serious nap
offer fifteen all of the fifteen minutes
or half an hour
you can get a lot of the benefits of of
sleeping kinda proably stave off the
equal
the uh... adverse effects of sleep
deprivation for example
injustice work all it is all good now
behind a new law federal aviation
administration policy
that allows airplane pilots to map in
the cockpit
not if they're the only pilot in the
cockpit right
palm bod carden for for example dot
trans oceanic planes usually have three
people in the cockpit to comply with the
plane
and the old rules
require all of them to stay awake for
all the time
new rules will while one of them to take
a nap uh... at a time
uh... so yeah you can do that but if you
remember that uh... episode of couple
weeks ago don that ronald reagan over of
ronald reagan airport where the air
traffic controller fell asleep
it's better to do that if you're not the
only air traffic controller in the
control tower
but if i got nothing
napping can be very good for you
so next time your teacher catches you
falling asleep in class just say that
this is very good for you
whatever they will go fine
okay now i don't want to get caught up
in all of the in london in a lot of
sleep stuff
did provide some person that
sleep is a real puzzle four psychology
because we have no idea was serious idea
what it's good for
it's clear we have a need for sleep we
have a by a lot of other and a dodgers
biological our biological rhythm
by which we go to sleep
warhol robo roughly one today and then
wake up one and then wake up
they are all sorts of theories about of
about why we sleep
but none of them had been particularly
well supported
uh... by young by the evidence
arm
welcomed what wild boar i'm interested
in the twelve more here on in the
in the course
art are kind of cognitive functions that
are associated
uh... with uh... with sleep
and here is a place for me to advertise
our professor map walker's work on
consolidation
although uh... sleep and consolidation
his laboratory has been one of the
leading laboratories in the world now on
making the case that sleep actually
promotes the consolidation of memories
so if you learn something if you go to
sleep pretty quickly there afterwards on
you're going to remember it better
of theirs
there are lots of details i'm leaving
out
take walkers chorus
psychology one thirty three
home but home
there are aspects of cognition during
sleep
dunno that are of interest here
so i want to skip over
the palm
uh... work by walker and his colleagues
and just all in
just to come
these are the guys
who put to sleep research on the map
michel jude's who was a psychiatrist and
a raledu stand friends
on eugene as a risky who discovered
rapid eye movements on the panel k-lite
men
all that all of the pioneering sleep
researcher at the uh... university of
chicago
in whose laboratory as a risky was
working and william demand
who was
called the claimants are second bogdan
second graduate student
has for years and years and years
run a big sleep laboratory down outcome
down at uh... that they've done at
stanford
art and without the work of these got
about one of these old their local put
four people
we wouldn't know anything half of what
we know about sleep right now
biar bu bu bu the story here about as a
risk is particularly interesting is the
guy who discovered
rapid eye movements falling asleep but
in fact discovered
than ninety minutes cycle of waking and
sleeping on inspiration to all those who
was a medical student at the time doing
a research rotation
on and off
in claimants laboratory
and up until that time
bugged all agreed and then sleep alone
and then sleep laboratories
our people had only reported
all of the the g
until people got down into so-called
stage forcefully
what looked like a dubuque what what
what looked like what was happening
the body in the brain were kinda
progressively slowing down going from
the mix of alpha and beta activity
characteristic of stage one
to the high levels of delta activity
there were characteristic hopeful
on stage four
and then i just assumed that that was
people fell asleep
and while there were asleep they stayed
down there doing a lot of delta activity
and then all
and then they came back up
all but they cost was a very good
because of the economic solve research
that using reams and reams and reams of
paper every night with these
abide by the police on the ground
people didn't want to people thought it
was no way stoked
to record
what's going on off
in the yard and in the brain and body or
mind
claim ended anyway he was alone one
ladies are wonder what's gonna happen to
read it
alleges waste this paper
and what he discovered was not only did
he discovered for a cycle but ninety
minutes cycle of waking and sleeping
all buddy also disco what discovered
rapid eye movements which nobody else
nobody had ever seen before
and he happened to hwang
songs that they just decided it was
going to wake the subject up and say
what do you know
and the persons are i've been having a
drink
and that was listed the discovery
completely serendipitous
our discovery of the association between
route that i'd movements dot com and
uh...
and dreaming
and at that point
all sleep research taco major turn
and all sorts of people started getting
interested in sleeping dreamy because at
last we had
we had an objective
publicly observable
index
or private subjective state
we had a way of determining whether
people were actually dreamy homes out
and uh... in a way that we never had
over that never had before
and this as soon as people started
recording
the e_e_g_ in the eulogy from
for mike's with
they began to discover that well we
don't just have one dream at night the
dream we often remember when we are
welcome
but we have four five of these trees
uh... every other
almost none of which we remember when we
awaken in the morning but all of this
basically happened because of these guys
jude's guarded some pioneering research
on sleep and cats
well which is pretty easy 'cause that's
pretty much all they do
palm
bucked although the clad men really was
a guided who will who discovered all of
this is just
fascinating
leslie's story
so ok that's what happened
uh... as a risk in play but this is
nineteen fifty three
they observed
these are tender twenty minute long
first
of rapid eye movement activity
that occurred in
okay sending stage one
alva boomer broccoli every of
every ninety minutes
and what as a risky dead one if when he
finally got permission to do a formal
study he awakened subject sonogram
and said were you dreaming
and he got an affirmative response filed
seventy four percent of the time
when he awakened the same subjects are
part of stage and ram when they finally
got their heads together
arm
he yard of the day he got an affirmative
response only about of them will be
about seven or the seventeen percent of
the time so from this one experiment
we discovered
that sleep is not unitary phenomenon
there are at least through different
kinds of sleep
so-called slow wave or and around this
week
arms of the role of the ram sleep
and also
that sleep isn't just a passive from one
of the bodies kind of shutting down
periodically but there are all sorts of
interesting things that are happening
happening inside
here's the original as a risky unclaimed
and study
belinda meant in a book you wrote in
nineteen seventy-six reviewed nine
although order of the subsequent studies
everybody gets pretty much the same
called the finding
if you awaken somebody out of state dram
you'll get a dream report about eighty
percent of the time
if you awaken somebody on a stage and
ran
they'll get a dream report
home of less than twenty percent of the
time so they're really does seem to be
very strong association
between being in the stage ram
and uh... and dreaming
so what else goes on lots of other
things go on
during our cognitively
during stage one most people will
experience what's known as a catholic
dodge ecr ever read
little fox and images will flow through
their called held on the flow through
their heads
all they're not exactly dreams
they're not organized there's no kind of
plot there's may not be a lot of
activity
all but two homes all of them
the good people will have
mostly visual imagery of various kinds
sometimes auditory on imagery
home
and this summer descending stage one
or often of sometimes
wyatt anderson what is known as a
mario quantic jerk
all which is above the variability
interested experience that people have
or where you're falling asleep
and all was said your
so although all the sudden your body
jolts
poland and uh... and and you'll wake and
that so the often accompanied by some
kind of imagery
or for me it's always song mole always
having to experience
falling off a motorcycle all the sudden
my body on wakes up
fall off a motorcycle
on food never had that experience
so about like remembering something what
i'm not afraid of that experience
cause i don't go on motorcycles
home
it just kind of comes out of nowhere
right
uh... and lots of people have been some
people have bother than associated
imagery of
falling off a wider or
falling out of bed or something like
that very very very common
and what's happening there
is that
your body is shutting down your muscles
are relaxing
but your
but all you had your muscles are
relaxing at
double dot all relax at the same rate so
one one before relaxes
and the corresponding pending
doesn't compensate
you'll get some kind of juror that's
what happens is purely physiological
struggle to do with anything
uh... if your waking people on a stage
and ram
you will all be you want that
you want to do we get a report of
dreaming
but you will get a report of some kind
of mental activity of the walking for
hours thinking about my exam tomorrow or
i was thinking about my boyfriend or
i was thinking about my cat or whatever
stayin stage adaran
that's where you also or will it will
all they've got all sorts of interesting
sleep phenomenal
like sleepwalking
sleepwalking occurs in stage
and ram
hong
we also reporting comes into a forums
but mostly talking actually occurs in
stage and ram
uh... as well
why would these people phenomenon stage
and ram
concert opera haha exactly exactly right
right
so if you're going to sleep walk it's
got to be in stage n around because so
if you're not in because if you're not
paralyzed your of
your you're on there that you are your
nodded stage will
sleepwalking is the same way
almost sleepwalking the old fear about
support was a people were
poor talking in their dreams
all of that does happen
palm abut uh... but it doesn't happen at
that as often as sleep argument stage
and ram
rather interesting phenomena mental
phenomena stage aramis what's known as
night terrors
user very frequently on observed in
children
on dr parents quite crazy
or where that they'll put the child
asleep the trouble sleep for awhile
bulldog sleeper little while
and then the child wake up at the school
read bloody murder
will be shivering and sweating and
frightened of all this kind of stuff
are will not be able to give any account
of what was going on
all and then the parents will
will build all common public on the kid
down
kiddle go back to sleep
sleep through the night no problem all
will have no memory of the order of the
episode the next day
the parents of course remember
everything that wonder if they're
kidder's
having some kind of
of uh... some kind of issue so the night
terrors scare the children
during the night but they scare the
parents alone during the day
arm
mainstage ram we have dreams
and we have nightmares
all and then
bowl last
is sending stage realm of the night
when you're when you're of doable often
experience what's known as a kitten
appuram pic
reverie
just like they have nagata gregory
except you're coming out of sleep
not going in
not going to sleep
also there are all sorts of volvo
all sorts of
cognitive activities decide sleep
that are going on
sleepwalking is particularly
we're going to do that
forget this
air sleepwalking quite interesting are
typically random
typically of doesn't seem to have any
kind of purpose to what sleep or cripple
get out of bed
all move around on maybe go into one
room and then come back into the bedroom
fiddle with the war knobs and things
like that
it's as if the person is kind of a on
automatic pilot
are not a lot of all the manual
dexterity on not a lot of affect
displayed we know this because we can
bring sleep walker is in the laboratory
and before there was radio telemetry
used to hook him up to really really
really long electrode leagues
so they could get out of bed
move from one part all above the law got
one for the laboratory are the to the
other now we just hope all the local
como twelve radio telemetry device that
they wear with her pajamas
arms and you can kind of see them doing
this all sleep walking is pretty common
in children on that it's also very
common on buffs are very common but when
you observe in adults it's often
observed when bob dole to rims a strange
locations
all army barracks are good place to
observe sleepwalking when new recruits
or or or sleeping in the new place for
the uh... for the first time
sleep talking or some know what weight
well person all of the gauges in speech
makes other kinds of meaningful sounds
during sleep
not have no memory for this all in the
offer
in the morning
again are probably more common in
children are banned in adults
but as i say it we now understand that
there are two different forms of
sleepwalking
when sleepwalking occurs during around
then that the person on will often be
talking about
the contents of his or her uh... his or
her dream
when sleepwalking occurs in stage and
round
there doesn't seem to be any apostle
association with mental contents at all
interestingly
ram sleep talking has syntax and
semantics it's kind of meaningful speech
you can kind of understand that
we're ready
and ram sleep already very closely
resembles the speech volvo phasic
of of the patients is cause gotten quite
interesting observation
although doesn't you can do this this is
kind of rare
by and pick the tickets for the show
infection control laboratory
sleep talking's complicated we now
understand that there are some some kind
of the well-read mistake sleepwalking
has some work always of a sleep disorder
part because what's happening a pop
the riddle whole reason you're not
supposed to be able to talking to
reinstate around
so if you're talking during stage realm
paula it's because the i'll
pros paralysis of the school musculature
is not
as complete
as it should be
so there's another all-news va the stage
ram behavior disorder
for people will actually act out their
dreams
and again that's a sleep disorder you're
not supposed to be able to act out your
dreams are skeletal musculature is
supposed to be paralyzed
all of these are conditions are broad
only recently been diagnosed and they're
not very well understood yet
all but the person on campus who wonder
stands the most is allison hardy
appreciate studies from
arches she studies them for a living
you will often get the farm
all ram august sleepwalking and this one
stage ram behavior disorder inpatients
song uh... with all of post-traumatic
stress disorder we'll see that often
called the military veteran what acts
out
a battle for example industries uh...
made me lash out of his bed partner
has nothing to do with
him or her
home but basically just acting out the
dream
not supposed to be able to do that
hooded sleepers disordered urine
completely paralyzed so you are acting
these uh...
that i couldn't stand self
all but
that's not to say that everybody you
shows this has post-traumatic stress
disorder
anything that screws up this played
home called
though correlation
between what the going on in your brain
and what's going on your skeletal
musculature
is going to produce these kinds of facts
and again what only just beginning to
understand the stop the stuff
the point of all of this is that there's
a lot more going on during sleep
mentally
and behaviorally then jurist
their sleep talking their sleepwalking
there is a nightmare is there's all
sorts of stuff going on
what happened is that the discovery of
sleep stages
and the discovery all rapid eye
movements
inadvertently distracted people who are
interested in what goes on during sleep
mentally in behaviorally into true dude
trying to put all look at what goes on
with sleep neurologically and
physiologically so sleep research took
this physiological turn which means that
a lot of these really interesting
cognitive and behavioral effects or only
dawn told me just now getting studied
fifty almost sixty years now
after the discovery or walden
the association between ramen dreamy
okay our border talked about some
research about sleep or they may be a
fit that in next time palm like the
eyeball fit that it next time
but next time we'll talk a little bit
more about dreams
memory for dreams ads where
thanks very much