okay let's pick up where we left off
last time
when we looked into our minds when we
entrust back we find various states of
consciousness that switching said that
there's no reason to think he's wrong
about that
hadn't
if you want to make a science out of
this what you want to try to do is to
trying to figure out
how to study these states of
consciousness in some way in the in some
way objectively
this was the gold all of the early
nineteenth century scientific psychology
which was oriented around the study of
sensation
and perception
and spent a lot of time
in guiding gazed in an enterprise called
cycle physics which i'm going to talk to
about today
what that's like a physicist tried to do
was to put
the kind of introspection bad jamison
fall suffers for centuries before him
had done
moral lesson
formally
on the some kind of firms scientific
basis
and what they don't know what what they
decided to do was to start of the very
beginning with the most elementary kinds
of
card conscious experiences you can have
which are sensations
and they decided that ok art
sensations are private
there'd their their states of mind if we
don't have any direct knowledge of them
but the way to make a science out of
conscious experience
so they thought
was to try to do
identify the relations between peoples
conscious experiences
and these
physical conditions
that gave rise to those conscious
experiences
so we get psycho physics which tries to
trace the relation between
physical properties and some stimulus
something that can be given a third
person objective description
and the psychological properties of the
experience to which that stimulus gives
rise something that has columbia sleeper
third purple first-person subjectivity
nyc amicus science out of the first
person subjectivity got tired to
something
and what the psychophysical is one of
the dough
height experience too
stimulation
so they came up with the basic
psychophysical principle
palm
which can be summarized basically this
way
every psychological quality alba sensory
experience is related to some physical
property of the cars
stimulus okay now that's it that's the
working assumption
all volvo cycle physics
and what they really are nineteen
century psychophysical is dead was to
develop a number of methods
that would allow them to trace those
relations
between the qualities of experience
and all
and the yard and and and the
characteristics of various kinds of
stimulation
and they did this by the simple
expedient of asking people to assign
numbers to their experiences
yet is that really bright light
or is it a very dim light is a very long
we're going through some very soft noise
and they simply ask people to
assign numbers
all representing the quality of
cigarettes experiences
and so you can measure mental state in
that
funny way
all glad you could also measure the
physical state of the stimulus in that
way that we always do
and then you could kind and see what the
relationship while relationships were
between them
a lot of the early cycle physics all was
fault was all focused on all of the ban
on the nature of what are known as
thresholds
and they're different thresholds for
conscious awareness
and the question above threshold is
what
cotton what amount of stimulus the
stimulation does it take
for someone to be consciously aware
called a stimulus
okay so
it's a dark tonight and i'm looking out
over the desert or i'm looking out over
the bay and there's a light out there
and how much later is required for me to
be conscious of that fit
there's certain white
that's not going up
fault of the make up their own through
into consciousness
you brighten the light a little bit it
does become
onto the conscious
so that's what what what's known as the
absolute threshold
the amount of although stimulus
in the audience tends to be
that is required for that stimulus to be
represented unconscious awareness
and there were also interested in what's
known as the relative threshold
exam idea
but the relative threshold is the amount
of change that's necessary to stimulus
for that changed to be consciously
represented
and if you think about it for a second
the absolute threshold is kind of a
special case of the relative threshold
when the good when we're talking about
the absolute threshold
we're talking about really the
difference between something
now the cycle physicians were very
serious about this they thought physics
was the great science
and that the closer they could come to
physics the bed the more scientific
there's psychology would be
all day and so they were very very
interested in
trying to devise
what we're going to psychophysical
parallels
that is parallels between the
fundamental although all of the
dimensions of physics
and the fundamental dimensions of
psychological experience to remember
this new tony in physics for talk of a
purely
nineteenth-century here
this is before writing stein and all of
his little friends
planned so classical did tony in physics
basically says that there are three
fundamental dimensions
mass
space
and time
the cycle physicist said well she you
know is an interesting
but there are also fruit our
corresponding three fundamental
dimensions of psychological experience
we can think about
intensity
how much light
how much sound how much smell
as being somehow analogous to mass
we can think about extensively distance
how much
mental space something takes up
as being part of the somehow an elegance
to to space
and pro tends to be hollow long the
experience last
as being analogous to the physical
dimension of time so right there
you've got these nice psychophysical
parallels are not just kind of kept the
psychophysical spelling
pretty quickly however
thus visa early psychologists notice
conscious experiences
had at least
dimensions attached to them
that didn't seem to have a
physical
counterpart
the first of these was called eight ten
city or we would call it vividness
fujian i have a burly vivid image of
something or other vivid perceptive
something
all world or a dim
vague fragmentary one
and there didn't seem to be any
corresponding physical dimensions loans
are there
and then there are qualities
of sensory experience which will also
talk about at length
on this lecture which didn't seem to
have
joanne the kind of uh... into any kind
of physical counterpart
but the idea that intensity extensively
in protest city
nap to write on to the are three dollar
dimensions abroad
the fundamental dimensions classical
physics
suggested to
the psychophysical said they were on
their on the right track
and trying to connect
the physical bulb and uh... and dislike
tickle
most of her lease like a physics was
concerned with a problem with intensity
the strength
of a sensory experience
invision vision science we have a
special name for this is called the
brightness
fom or of a_t_r_
of a white or or or a visual sensation
independent audition we have something
called loudness you never say that's a
lot of light
on you might say something to break told
but you don't you know same thing
alone as when you say there's a bright
light
and the psych appears asus argued
the intensity of a sensory experience
or to be related somehow to the amount
of of energy
physical energy
associated
the stimulus
and that the physical
intensity or that the physical energy of
the stimulus
was somehow coated in the nervous system
and gave rise to this continuous
dimension all-volunteer insti
now how that's done
they were completely sure about that we
now know
that into the intensity of the stimulus
is coated in the nervous system
by two principles
a principle of temporal summation of the
principal spatial summation
hi intensity stimuli
lied to
very fast neural firings
okay that's it
somehow the nervous system is able to
on keep track of how fast
under on
is for a ring
all wardrobe rather the frequency of of
liberal and falsehood
that gives rise to
one aspect of intensity
and then special summation
all high-intensity stimuli
palm lead to the firing of lots of ron's
not just one
so that's what special summation is
ordeal nervous system is able to keep
track of that
on angela as well
okay bob the first thing they noticed
was that there wasn't things that we are
not always so morphism
that is a wonder one relationship
between
changes in the physical intensity
although the physical energy associated
with the stimulus
and changes in the intensity of the
sensory experience
to which that stimulus or gave rise
the first i did notice this was of the
other guy named vapor
polo who home
looked looked at difference thresholds
that is how much
intensity has to be how much energy has
to be added to a stimulus
before a an observer will detect a
change in intensity
and what he discovered was what's now
come to us as they burst law system
doesn't work
delta are over i will see
the amount to all of
change required
to produce a
jost noticeable difference in the
intensity of the stimulus turns out to
be a constant fraction
of that intensity
so if you ritual stimulus is ten units
of or could be that there has been units
of of of energy associated with it
you'll notice a change if you increase
it by save one if
of the risk of a constant is uh... up
or one out one ten
if the original tends to be as one
hundred
then you require ten units
of change before the change will be nice
if the original
all of the intensity is two hundred
you might require on you would require
two hundred
called units of uh... of change and so
there's a lot here
these are these guys are remember
modeling psychology after physics
physics has all sorts of really cool
laws
and our end and they perform you
discovered this this was in fact the
first
of the psychological was that was
discovered and that again have suggested
to people
that they were on the right track
now neighbors fraction
palm
on delta are you over all right
varies from one load at would be to
another
and varies from one species to another
so that in fact you can use babe ruth
fraction as a kind of universal index of
of sensory acuity
that's good across modalities
and across alaska
and across species
here are selected palm vapor fractions
for various art aspects of human
sensation
albeit restrictions sociated with visual
brightness is one over sixty
for thermal pane that is
kane or resulting from he'd stimulus
applied to the skin
one over thirty cutaneous pressure
pressure on the skin
on one of seven
uh... feast of salt wonderfully and so
on
and what this means the smaller the
baber fraction no more sensitive
the sensory modality
so here for visual brightness
it only takes a one
what what one sixty f
of the original intensity to produce a
just noticeable difference
here for the taste of salted water
you've got a really dump a lot more
sultan
to produce a change uh... vietnam
in intensity so the nice thing about
their burst fraction
is that you could use something like
this uh... pump to
compare all sensory acuity across
sensory modalities and across all uh...
species
you can determined vapors fraction for
racks
were cats or dogs or anything like that
and you can show that wraps have more
visual acuity than humans do
with that as they have less visual cue
you've been humans do but they have
all more all all factory iqbal acuity
than humans too and so on that soon
that's the idea here
boost our faq nurse
although the following up on guard on
believers fraction called
or by the way
don't get caught up on these formulas
right this is a math class or anything
like that
repugnant using this is an illustration
of what these guys were trying to do to
try to make an objective science
unconscious experience
all the discovered a more general for
all of formulation alba of baber swap
in what's now known as factors walk
as equals k log alright
palm
film over what what factors what
basically says is for every aspect of
one of those sensory experience
there is some logarithm
that will all relate
uh... the physical intensity of the
stimulus
sensory intensity that is the
experienced intensity
of the signals
so here if we simply assume that
k is one
and we'd say don't talk about logs for
the base ten
okay here
we've got the stimulus
of no intensity
and there's going to be no sensation
because
the log zero zero
we get up here to and intensity
all all
dob ten
uh... sensory intensity of one
you get up here
all physical intensity of one hundred
units
you get the sensory intensity of
two units
you get up here too
called of the stimulus intensity of two
hundred units never mind what the units
or there
physical units
on who get a sense rian of intensity of
two point three oh it's it's a very nice
it's a very nice permitted and there's
all lawful relationship
between up this echo god
characteristic of the stimulus
and the psychological characteristics
all the experience
now what what
rockne really liked about this
was it a few plot of this relationship
on the cause of on on semi log paper
you've got a straight line
here we've got
logarithmic scale of stimulus intensity
anil ordinary scale of sensory intensity
and you get a sort of the uh... a
straight line like this
and the cycle physicist logged stuff
like this
and the reason i liked it is
there is nothing more beautiful in
science than a straight line
on we've got a straight line you really
think you know something
and here you've got something like
a wonder one
correspondence
that's one st one is
so inside the something like
an isomorphism
between all of the between physical
stimulation
and uh... and sensory experience
so we get factors law
and if you think about it for a second
you want most interesting aspect
effective flaw is that says
that sensation
grows more slowly than stimulation
a relatively large change in physical
stimulation produces a new relatively
small change in the hall
we've experienced sensation you can see
that here
where the stimulus
goes fall from
form of promo outpost of the ten units
of two hundred units
physical terms
only doubles
in on the in psychological terms
sensation grows worse wound stimulation
yes
now about this just an example companies
lager rhythm somewhere okay
all they've got got got a list rated
somehow so that's but that's what we do
all by that
lead again it's the shape of the curve
on that uh... that that really matters
here now this is fine fights are really
very nice general law that applies and
lotsa lotsa lotsa
of the places
the general ideas of sensation always
grows more slowly than simulation but
it's not always true
also for example the perceived length of
a line
there actually is a wonder one route gov
relationship
on there
you add ten units of actual length
opinion a change in perceived length
and they are really really interesting
exception
is for perceived
where you get a little bit of change in
intensity
can produce a massive
jolla change in experienced pain
and if you don't believe me the next
time you're at the dentist unease
grilling just ask him to press down all
little harder
just got these massive things
tucker's lawyers close
but it's not quite right if you're
really doing psycho physics
what you want to do with what i have a
general or that covers all the poor the
whole the possibilities
and we got that from a harvard
psychologist named s smith
stevens
all of those of you who ski
stevens brought these shorts dogged the
short downhill ski to america from your
so luxury
cool guy or outside of uh... outside of
psychology yep
they asked people to assign numbers
that's called the method of magnitude
estimation
so you'd give somebody say you know
wharton ten units scale
or all or or a one hundred unit scale
and u_s_ into assign numbers to their
experience
all all database and the thing is people
can do that
now sometimes on some time to give a
little anchors
so for example and in pain research we
will sometimes are subject to some to
give a fault they uh... value of zero
to absolutely no pain
and the value of tend to
all that as much pain as you can
possibly imagine
but the interesting thing is
yeah you'd think oh jeez that's
objective you know that's remote out
that's appointed subj active right
but what's interesting about it is that
people can do this reliably
and what's even more interesting about
it but gave the cycle physicists hope
whatever numbers people assigned
buried waffle leave with
something that they could keep track of
objectively
because we've got giving rise to things
like factors law unbelievers floor
and uh... and steven swap
this is stephen swap
okay palm
yes ok stevens what s equals chaotic at
the end
and what stephens' law basically says is
for every arcata other aspect of a
number of a sensation
there is some exponent
that will relate
the physical
quality of the stimulus too with the
psychological quality of the all out of
the corresponding sensation
here for factors law remember your high
school of high school mathematics
ology dot logs for the basement
you got something like an exponent of
one-half
so you're lookin faces square roots
and you get something although that
looks very much
like on like like doctors who are
here is
stephens on here is a case of ball
length
and there's the case of pain
where the exponent is actually greater
than one
meaning that
in the case of pain sensation grows more
rapidly
then stimulation
but in any case
derek installment exponent
somewhere that you can determine
incorrectly
double relate
the physical characteristic of a
stimulus
to the psychological characteristics
of the uh...
of the uh... uh... of the corresponding
experience
that's what these guys did not stevens
was working and in
said that as late as well
as late as the nineteen sixties and
seventies
uh... but it wasn't this was an
enterprise before that
stevens was the culmination of an
enterprise
that began in the early part of the
nineteenth century
with people trying to uh...
died trying to identify
these psychophysical principle
now why my telling of it
i'm telling you this because for my
money anyway
all thought classical cycle physics is
the very first
scientific approach the consciousness
that we have national discourse is
supposed to be all about
these guys were doing empirical studies
followed the rules of science as they
are
as the understood that we are getting
systematic observations not just some
guy sitting down and armchair somewhere
sybil what do i think about watch
you were getting controlled
experimentation
they're very carefully appalled above
the selected stimuli
are very under applied under very very
cool tightly controlled all of the
conditions
u_n_ quantitative data analyses you had
physical measurements of stimuli
you've got things like magnitude
estimations pole vault
of bald of of the people's experiences
you get out allies them statistically by
the time these guys really got going
palm of that we've got some mathematical
tools to work but what the correlation
coefficient of that we could use
and on the basis of their work
deride some mathematical function
whether it's expressed in terms of
ratios or a locker rooms or exponents
doesn't really matter for the purposes
of illustration here
got some mathematical function
that would relate
aspect of the stimulus environment
psalm aspect of conscious sensory
experience and to the extent that these
guys were able to discover these
psychophysical laws
they were able to show
that yes
there are lawyers
wonder why
conscious sensory experience
and we could discover them through the
typical methods of sites that's what's
like the physics was awful about
now as i said before psychophysical
early began with a study of intensity
and thresholds and all of that kind of
stuff
but pretty quickly
sab august of aside because it's moved
to all other aspects of unconscious
experience
your home beyond intensity
the idea was
intensity was that
was a characteristic that was coming to
all modalities
you've got a bright lights were dimmed
lights you could have wild selves are
soft sound to them strong taser strong
smells
were weak of that these smells and
that's fine
but there are also specific
over qualities
that palm that that are lucerne specific
t_e_c_ modality and um... i'll give you
one instance triton looking at
those psychophysical relationships as
well
so for example in vision
we have a quality that you find no place
else which is hugh essentially the
caller
of the texture of associated with
experts with its red or yellow or green
or blue or whatever
and you have saturation
all which basically is are the bad has
has to do with
hold much weight
latest mixed in
with the color
in audition you have a quality of pitch
though you own whether the sound is high
bridge or more woodbridge
and you have on camera
all which is kinda like the difference
between all
between eighty also flew to the clarinet
player of violin on
and an oval
and the general idea again
was that if your recycle bin systems
beer working assumption
each of these qualities sub sensation
is related to some physical
characteristic of the corresponding
stimulus
so for example
with respect to cuba
we all know
uh... thought the hw
is related to the wavelength
stimulation
so we've got relatively audit short
wavelengths
on giving rise to things like calm
uh... the experience of blue
and relatively long wavelength giving
rise to the experienced volvo of red and
green and yellow or somewhere in between
there
so again
there's eight psychophysical
relationship
something about
all of the someone there's some kind of
connection between wavelength and the
experience of q
and saturation i misspoke before it's
not exactly the amount of whites the
amount of great that's added to a
stimulus
this is
the same
allred to which i'd that'd a bunch all
a bunch of greater that gives you such a
rationing and again
all you can betrays the experience of
the saturation of a color
or and trace it to
various physical qualities like the
wavelength of stimulation of the amount
of great that's been added
same kind of thing happens with auditory
sensation of your recycle possesses
the pitch of the tone is given argued it
is
from from for their money given by its
frequency so if you think about the
musical scale
you've got caught in the bass clef
second stacey is associated with the
frequency of a hundred thirty one cycles
per second
middle c_ about two hundred sixty two
cycles per second
and third spacing of the trouble cleft
call upon the frequency of about five
hundred twenty three cycles per second
modern orchestras to into eighty four
forty
second space say in the trouble club
four hundred and forty cycles per second
so there's a nice psychophysical
relationship
is related to
of the two frequency
and a powder
is related to the shape
fall beyond all above the underwire wave
of church and see the story my sleep
but here is the characteristic
all the way the sociated with a violin
and a trumpet
a flute
at an old boat
very very very different courage
drug characteristics always really has
to do
with armed with with the number of
harmonics that are being added
but again
that quality of auditory sensation seems
to be related directly
to uh...
to some physical characteristic of the
corresponding part stimulus
which gave rise
palm
what's known as
the doc dot dot gov a set of physical
on the physiological principles
enshrined in
are what's known as the doctrine of
specific fiber energy
you'll remember for the last lecture
that johannes miller had argued that the
modality of sensation each different
modality of sensation vision hearing or
faction gah station
was associated with the different
neural systems
followed miller's student hermann von
helmholtz
although the basically articulated an
extension of miller's doctrine
that bit that said that that's true for
each quality of sensation
within
eight sensory modality
so are for example hw
home
you'd you'd assume that
to some extent or another
different hues are associated with
different rural
uh... amid different girls systems
uh... different pitches are associated
with different systems i mean fact we
know that something like that
uh... is on
is no troop
so that's basically where the
psychophysical scotus
they spent a great deal of time
trying to trace the the empirical
associations
between
these psychological qualities of various
sensory experiences
and the physical stimuli
that hong that gave rise
for those experiences and in that way
gave us our first scientific approach
to consciousness
the second tendency here onto the the
second trendy and get it in the in this
early work
is a job
discourse psychology that was known as
structural ism
which focused its attention mostly on
these different
modalities specific
qualities of sensation
and structural subsoil bill helped
villains who was the first one is
sometimes thought of as the father of
psychology
uh... and this is his american student
t_v_ preacher who founded the
psychological laboratory so
the idea that the structural aside
was to engage in a kind of
mental chemistry the cycle physicist
want to do a mental physics
they wanted to connect mental life too
thode to the physical world
and the structural us
were really more inspired by chemistry
than anything else and they are all of
the they've become work from a more or
less simple analogy
which was to say
let's think about conscious experiences
those complex things that we experience
for me
c_e_o_s
car running into a tree and telegraph
avenue or whatever it is worth watching
and i don't think i'll misconduct
analogous to molecules
and we now know
they knew them
harvest was made that member based on
nineteen th century home
uh... the chemistry dept
we can break molecules down into their
constituent or arvind adams
and in the same way
what the structure was one to try to do
was too
stark
complex
analyze complex conscious experiences
into
your reducible
elements sever somehow analogous to
vittu to adams
also of them
what these elements worker with a lot of
debate among the structure with the and
fistfights at their meetings about this
everybody agreed that
uh... there were these element that
there were some elementary sensations
follow but some people argued that there
were some elementary feelings that work
uh... that that you could detect in
these complex
our mental uh...
or the but with britain
and others argue that there were also
memory images so when you had a sensory
experience
cold certain
thoughts to mine uh... as well
both ways
the cycle possesses
focused and sensations and that's where
we're going to focus yes quick
i think that that's what this is right
the looks like a physics and structural
is on our intends to analyze quality of
scientifically that's why he introduced
his lectures with quality that they're
trying to correct
what the quali apart
i'm lookin out here about this whole
thing
complex visual although the heart of the
array and i want to analyze that
into various
quality up
can't be analyzed any further
one of the but what what are the basic
dimensions
so uh...
combat beyond the structural stability
whole bunch of techniques for doing this
so called known as experimental all
introspection
or which have a lot of rules
all uh... associated with it
but the basic rule was
make what they called the stimulus error
these though the stimulus error was the
error rome
describing the stimulus
instead of describing your experience
now that's not an easy distinction to
make
okay not really did think about it
but they tried really hard
hard to keep
inferences out of the process
and ask them to
uh... to uh... does a good to describe
what their direct on mediated
uh... experiences operates objects
ballpark
here's an example
so harm
here's what's known you know inundate
vision sciences color circle
on their whole bunch of callers on a
deep in their if i ask you to look up
say between
no twelve o'clock at one o'clock and i
ask you what do you see
or what republicans as well as trying to
see
you know by privacy some green and i
kind of cc yellow and if i ask you one
on off
what you see
down here around four or five o'clock
see some red nyc's yellow
over here
of around seven or eight o'clock what
you'll see why are our season read they
said that states that kind of analysis
into something else
that uh... that the structure was for
trying to well
we're trying to figure out
as a result of these kinds all booked
under of investigations
they identified what they believe to be
on the basic home the the basic adams
appalled
herzegovina visual experience of hw so
we get from young and helmholtz
or what's known as the try chromatic
pedal of the theory of color perception
which was basically the discovery
or so they thought
that all visible colors can be produced
by a mixture of just three colors
fall of the the red
green and blue
and as i described as ideal of
uh... when about people really were the
sweatshirt
those
on three primary colors
or or they'll reach associated with
different kinds of
of wavelength robert reich dramatically
returns ought to be wrong
and it's replaced by what's known as the
opponent process theory of color vision
were not going to get into that
that's for a sensory
uh... psychology recent three physiology
course
that the probe for the purposes of this
lecture
the point is
what young and helmholtz and for that
matter
hearing the part of the and others did
was to take
all the colors
that you could possibly experience
millions and millions of colors to be
don't believe you go into a paint store
sometime
and all of those colors can be produced
can be analyzed into
song mixture ald joyous three or so or
the primary of the primary colors
those three colors
green and blue
then become for the structural issues
the basic qualities
of the experience of color there the
quality
doubly bubble comport
on you can't get uh...
you can't get their own road really
really further on the further than that
are more recently altered the james
cutting who's a psychologist at the home
that uh... that at cornell
has argued that
the analysis of primary colors
or give them to a concert is on mult
for the determination of elementary
sensory quali a in the other modalities
part as well and he says if you can do
you think you've got
irreducible on analyze little
one of these qualities of experience
they're probably has to
behave
the primary colors do
uh... the so for example
you want to be able to have a situation
where
the physical mixture of your primary
quali a
can wield all the other qualities that
we know that we can get purple lot of
red and blue you can get orange out of
red and part of the yellow
and so on
are cut it also large is that these
quali o
once you've identified one
there ought to be what he calls
physiological atonement
there ought to be
following helmholtz is extension of the
doctrine of specific nerve energies
there ought to be on unique neural
pathway for each of these primary
qualities that we know that that's the
case for example
one of the reasons people like to try
chromatic theory of color vision isn't
it turned out that there were three
times a broads open three kinds of
problems with the rest of the aisle
one that's really sensitive to long
wavelengths
and wondered really sensitive to short
wave lengths and won this really
sensitive to medium wavelengths so you
get red green and blue
add up at the at the physiological level
it's about ought to be the case
for all for although quali a
then all the cutting or argues
that if you really got an elementary
quality of experience that is probably
expressed in language
in august eighth the descriptor for that
is probably
model like scenic that is that there's a
single word
okay like red
for green or blue
that the that expresses our quality
and if you look at frequency abusive
language
that word ought to be associated with
very high uh... frequency alvo
uh... abuse
moreover
cutting argues careers
really interesting psychologist whose is
interested in sociology and anthropology
of citizens psychology and uh... and
uh... and physiology
he argues that
alm part of the century quali a if you
really got one if you really identified
one it ought to constitute
a basic categories all four oh four or
perception
it ought to be applicable and called it
the most languages
and so for example we know
that all languages if they had any color
terms at all they've got
at the very least black and white
or dark
then fearful language has more than two
color terms the next caller terms turn
out to be some combination of red
quite interesting call a cultural
phenomena
and then doll later on after the
language adds other turns that vote that
they will add part of the terms like
gradient pain can orange and purple and
brown
but basically
red yellow green and blue
part for all of
of represent or or words of almost
everyone which that has home
have has a colorful february
there are some exceptions
almost everyone as that
and then all quietly auger cuttings
applicable let's look at the other bala
g these words
think about
and green
and blue
and yellow
and black
these words don't refer to any object
they just refer dot color
whereas
colour words that we have like orange
and violet
and uh... and uh... kind all over
our terms of our borrowed from objects
so one hard but what does doug collins
arguing is that we've got the basic
quality of sensation
it should be something that doesn't
refer to any object
okay so it's not
from the object itself it's a word that
has the day
that describes the experience
so here cutting is actually plane like a
structural uske isn't a structure was
all but he said why could if you want to
be used
colored vision
as you're a model for how would two on
covered the basic
quali are all that conscious experience
the basic elements of color conscious
experience
here's how you might go about own doing
it
now this enterprise has actually been
done in order ordered or dividends has
been no of
pursued
it all other sensor modalities as well
let me give you just a quick
uh... for
through world through this
so of a danish psychologist named
on identified of
four basic qualities of gospel tory or
experience
sweet so our
salty and better
all according to headings theory
all of the various things we can taste
difference between
justin and fish between oregano and our
time uh... between uh... oh
also opened up for whatever
all these appalled but with all these
different experiences
are composed of
four
trusted tori
all qualities
sweets are work salty
and better
i mean actually produce what's known as
hemmings
tetrahedron
all
in which he
locates
these are qualities at the apex is all
about three-dimensional of them figure
and the general idea is
every
discernible
taste
can be
geometrically located
as a point in this space
every
taste the weakened that that that we
could distinguish
some degree of sour to some degree of
salt in the some degree of bitterness in
some degree of sweetness
and if you just kind of why in those up
on you get a point and that's oregano
and there's going to be another point
time
and there's going to be another
that's savory
and that's what the differences are but
all those days
are composed of these
for elementary qualities
very nice
there are four elementary qualities
what you would what comes out of
introspection depends on what people
intro specter on
so what happened did was to have people
taste a lot of foods
with all due respect
he was danish they didn't have a lot of
japanese food there
when we come back
all be discovered that there is yet up
fifth
taste quality what's known known as a
mommy
all which is kind of the paystubs
voiceless hong
didn't
dead people just hadn't noticed
uh... before so what we need is
something new with pending spacecraft
tetrahedron
that's got
five pay taxes
uh... to it
somebody who's better if you have a tree
that neither are your hanging might be
able to figure out how to do that
palm
but that saw the ah... that that's the
general idea
all what happened was we discovered to
mommy as a basic case
precisely because we expanded
the numbers the the the the range of
stimuli that the observers were working
on
all and so what there's something here
that's
knots weaver not salty or not so we're
not bitter it's something else
savory
who bought me
called and
now we've now we've
understand that there were five basic
qualities augusta tory experience
you could do the same thing for all
factory experience henning did this
and identified
qualities of also mails everything we
can smell
can be boiled down to
some combination of
spicy those frequencies theory ality
of putrid and burned
and again we get pending the smell prism
each of these qualities located and the
home
video of the vertex
and you ought to be able to want to
locate
individual
smell leeches individual thing you but
you can smell at some point
inside poem
inside the space
all it just told me bong
mega will put note here
there are some smells we can't smell
there are all factory
stimuli
that lead to behavioral
changes
all of that don't give rise to conscious
experience came to bring no visas for
ramones
or a alright and we now have old list of
ceremonies that uh...
that better direct but so that's that's
not the case
get miss the footnote to stop it's not
the case of all
gospel tori
though lol factory stimuli give rise to
all factor experience
both we'd
usually can't all or not consciously
aware of these weaken
understand that they exist to try to
understand and try to identify them
physiologically
just by their effects
behavior
without a question
i have to know enough people are looking
for six taste and i haven't found one
yet
or you don't know that's where this came
from that's where the that that that's
where this came from his own hold whole
institutes of olfactory science
mostly supported by the perfume industry
this is true
alm and
on they spend a tremendous amount of
money trying to identify with the
specifics or cause i want to
rhythm x on new world new sense
we have lots and lots of different smell
receptors that and on
mapping these basic smells on tools
receptors is up
process that has not been completed
let's put it that way
on thinking what a sport
we met with we think
we know that there are
four five different
structurally different taste buds each
of which are sensitive to certain
common combinations of chemicals
so again if you think about
criterion for a quali a you ought to be
able to find physiological atonement
all but
disappointed all make again a couple
times in the scores
that psychology has to be right
four you can find me
before you can do the physiology
if there are
six
all voters
then you know to start looking for six
basic
pays clubs or something like that dot
over about avilable order receptors in
the nose
but until you've identified the basic
qualities
it's not at all clear
that uh... that you can do that
now yeah we may have three hundred
different kinds of
receptors in the nose
that's too many quality of
people would reject the idea that we
have three hundred different quali o
all depends investors too cumbersome
they all want to get things
to alum
as uh... few dimensions
as possible
i don't do this work i'm not going to
defend it pisses what
but this is an example
how people have tried to sab to study
conscious experience scientifically
that we start out with quality of
trying to figure out what the basic
dimensions are of various sensory
experiences
from a static experiences were quite
hard and would you boring
hong kong told also at harvard
who are identified job of
refunded
home roughly four different quality of
quality or in armed
tactile sensation
just whether there is of torture not
warrington cold is not a single formals
oracle quality
on turns out that
you can have warm warmth and cold are
very separately
and then there's some debate about
roughness on and all and wetness
uh... for that as well
maureen was a student to bb kitchener
and picture of self
tried to create a touch
pyramid
somehow analogous to hemmings taste
tetrahedron and smell prism
where you'd have
these basic qualities
of tactile sensation
or arrayed and any different kind of
proj
uh... could be located montana as a as a
point
in between
the idea behind
scientific investigation of quality a
to try to use psychophysical methods
varying
the physical qualities of stimuli
measuring process re experiences which
those stimuli we ordered give rise and
then trying to add a lawyer's called
that these things into
called for the into their basic cover
into their basic elements
okay can even do it about two minutes
here you can even do that with feeling
won't do this
fall the different emotional states that
we can have
home
solved when two argued
could be decomposed into just three
different dimensions
plasmids the persons on plasmids
excitement
versus com
and then what he called
strain versus relax ation
so the the difference between
disgusted
fear in anger enjoy in happiness n
various kinds of pleasures and uh... and
uh...
and on pleasures
you want to be able to locate each of
those experiences
as a point
three-dimensional space
according to blend
anyway these were the three
fundamental dimensions
all of our
emotional experiences
were arrayed
what structural is almost like a bizarre
cst dead
was they
tried to give us
or first scientific approach the
consciousness
are what's interesting to bs guys didn't
write a build-up of understanding of
consciousness from promo studies of
uh...
all volvo or the other kinds of uh...
psychological phenomena
they tried to
address consciousness directly
do you have to structure was what he was
interested in he'd say
i'm interested in consciousness
you would say i'm interested in
sensation her memory or something like
that so not because of consciousness
they tried to
to tie
subjective conscious experiences
to publicly observable aventis
and i'm in the process all form the
basis for what we now think of sensory
girl's life
structural ism had its problems these
guys got in debt
endless
fruitless debates about
you know how many
they're very different qualities there
might be
and our as i've gone suggested to my
very first lecture
pretty quickly the whole enterprise was
overthrown
by the behaviorist revolution when
people like john b watson said i can't
take it anymore
we're never going to get anywhere with
this science as long as we try to make
the science of something private
so now let's turn
psychology from the science of mental
life into a science volvo
of behavior
there was a start
picking up most of the nineteenth
century a little bit of the twentieth
century as well
the next scientific approach the
consciousness begins with
that we've got this begins again looked
a cart
and tries to understand the relationship
between the mind and the body
and that for meeting with
thank you very much weekend