okay let's start off of what you really
want to hear about which is the final
exams
final exam scheduled for tuesday may
eleven
um... for that's the first
that's the tuesday of exam week
from three to six p m
the exam itself is going to be a two
hour exam but you'll have three hours to
do it because that's what we do things
here
and it'll be up there are two thirty
seven percent
that's right next to the swimming pool
soul bring your suits
quality as peace through this
i haven't heard yet
d d_s_p_ offers
voucher arrangements bunch
still working on it
as soon as i phone
get the information from them all paid
for them to you
also tougher stalwart of the exam is
going to be a non culated exam will
cover all the material since the midterm
the second hour will be cumulative that
will give you a chance to apply
the whole thing together
uh... a little bit
and a bit dog
to a recession on the wednesday of the
reading period
or there are regular class time ten to
eleven
right here at our regular classroom
i'm not going to do a formal review at
that time they'll be you know
radio in order for you with into the
course website
but if you have any questions you'll be
able to bring them
to that session
so here's what the exams to look like
non-committal portion worth fifty points
will cover everything since the last
midterm
peculiar portion worth another fifty
points will cover
the offers pour the course
and so roles mystery of consciousness
and also collages
lots of resources for the exam he got
this to win a session no muchos gracias
fortress supplements for all the old
exams are posted
onto the of website
i'm working on the narrative review for
the final right now
that'll be posted by
friday
called and
on dads always there will be all set
special forum on these days for
questions of
lead up to the final exam
and if you have any questions of for
some reason don't get answered
post m_t_v_ of these days forum
by monday may ninth
and if you do that
for by the end of business
birthday
i don't bring blue books for the final
exam you do everything on the exam
itself
double supplied
anything quick about the final exam
sold very straightforward it's just
alm
i've often in the past had a couple of
questions that were a little bit longer
in the scope
but if you look at all
passed final exam
that looked like
the science of consciousness changes
from year to year but the questions
about consciousness dot
who's got it who doesn't have it how do
we know
that's what it's all about
okay
let's talk about
we've talked in this could be in this
class mostly about consciousness and
what it is and how we know
on now what we want to do talk about
on
where consciousness comes from
how we got it
and how we know about that
so these are questions about the
development of consciousness
and went psychologists another cognitive
scientist talk about all the talk about
development
usually talk about it
one of three ways
and we're going to had on all three of
these ways some of this week
orders of flight would genetic view of
development that basically tries to
trace the evolution
on song characteristic
or whether it's a physical
characteristic or a mental
characteristic
this is basically for the job over for
fuel donors comparative psychology
which tries to
compare
mental abilities and our various law
various species of animals
and the question there is we've got it
we know we've got consciousness
but to all who else has it
all in the animal kingdom
dot how would we know
the second which is more familiar to
most of you probably
is the odd road genetic view
or both of development
which basically six to trace the
dog deal
concours
of the development of psalm
characteristics on trait
with involved life span of the
individual
through the birth of death so again this
is they see the province of what's known
as life span developmental psychology
all of them will talk about their own
what would promote onto genetic use of
the development of consciousness
all this week
and then finally their resolve cultural
view of development
that basically it looks at via fax
solved
social and cultural development upon
the go all the characteristics of the
mind and behavior
all of the author of the individual
this is essentially the problem solved
sociology and anthropology and other
social sciences
but it's been imported into or
psychology or recently
with interest in cultural psychology
cultural of them cultural cognition
and so on
and towards the end of the lecture on
wednesday
all have a couple things to say about
the development of consciousness
in historical time
but for now let's look at
the of why would you like view of
consciousness
and a problem the really goes back to
our
by the back to descartes
you'll remember that
descartes argued that there was this
qualitative separation between
men between human beings
and bill
and other about no other animals
giving rise to his doctrine on substance
dualism
and four descartes battles were just
reflex machines
there was no stimulus in the environment
which was taken up into their nervous
system in the reflected back out into
the environment in behavior
that's where the concept of the reflex
of the comes from
all but they card argued that humans had
sort of cubans out all these animal
characteristics we are reflexes two but
we also had mines
and consciousness
free will
which all of the which settles apart
promo other animals
so all of them
you can say for what
former cartesian point-of-view that
humans are the highest stage of
development
home just look kind of just world will
build less than uh... guardian angels
all but that there is is qualitatively
or between
or or other animals and humans which is
that we've got consciousness
and they don't
so jake hard answers the question
the pilot genetic
phone of the development of
consciousness which basically says
there is a dead heat
file a genetic followed by development
small only or all the humans have it and
there's just no point
looking for a in order
well in other species
all idea of the all a good god dealt a
serious blow in the nineteenth century
by charles darwin on and his old man and
his own
some old paul
treatise on the origin of species by
natural selection
who argue that i'm not going to give you
a whole darwinian thing here but that
the essentially all the darwin argued
for the continuity
of species
that is that human beings
and all other rattles
shared in common on some kind of common
ancestor
all and uh... and that
with two countries
all of the the roots of any species back
all along
way of evolution
replied
now darwin himself
mostly applied
this doctrine called evolution by
natural selection and especially
this doctor and all of the evolutionary
continuity of species to body parts
morphological similarity
why do we have two arms into legacy is
for descended from fish that have
all but darwin was also interested in
in mental similarity
and suggested that you couldn't see
continuity as he could see traces of
koppel of dissent from a common ancestor
all valued in the fact
that older adults
shared sit with the shared some of the
mental traits
all with
well with those human spirit is
are very clearly in his late
treatise on the percent of man
the difference in mind between man and a
higher animals
great as it is
is certainly one of the greedy
not kind
quantitative difference we've got more
of something that someone around adults
perhaps
but there is no cartesian qualitative
difference
on that's the essential doctrine of
evolutionary continuity
let me just kind of goes on all of them
about this
that it could be proved that for quite
helpful powers such as consciousness for
absolutely for a man
which seems extremely doubtful
then that would be trouble
all for their own
darwin
call but he says that the home
all of that sort of aleutian
or not to be denied because we see it
all of
what all the time
in another round
thomas huxley sometimes known as
darwin's bulldog
or more vigorous
more vigorous in the defense of
darwinian theory then darwin himself was
on although the book up this problem
when it was only writing about
consciousness
headed back to you
laws and that he argued
that consciousness of blinks
would appear to be related to the
mechanism of their bodies
simply as a collateral
product of its working
and to be completely without any power
of modify networking
as the steam whistle which accompanies
the workable locomotive engine
is without influence opponents machinery
that's the classic statement
of apple phenomenal ism
but noticed what huxley site here
he's talking about
da consciousness or brutes
okay he's not talking about human
consciousness
uh... which suggests
that may be
human consciousness
is not up a phenomenal
even if nonhuman consciousness along
with it so there is a op
there's love
about the hypothesis about evolutionary
continuity there
all of that week and the c
significant if they can get translated
into into some kind of research
all beginning with the publication of
darwin's work
the on nineteen th century psychologist
a bunch of nineteenth century
psychologist
began to take up
feel though they are the implications of
darwin's doctrine or evolutionary
continuity with respect to
with respect to mine
and began talking about
animal intelligence
animal mind
animal consciousness
are based on the idea that
if humans have minds
than somebody else want to have mine too
especially those animals
uh... with which we share
approval nearby common ancestry
and so dogwood did begin actually with
this guy george rome honest that's what
it looks like
all of the romana so-called assembled
a whole bunch of anecdotal evidence
about or org
that seem to suggest that moves pad
intelligence
worksop reading just by reflex are
conditioned response
of course he didn't know anything about
conditioned response thought that this
is a teeny tubes long before pavlov
our budget
the hope that they'd instinct reflects
on
there's a wonderful story about a broad
bringing his food dish to his master
als
and there is little story for example
about all
baboons attacking humans in the home
in the jungle
and uh... they seem to be laxity
planning and coordinating their attacked
not just uh... rampaging as well
as individuals
agra labas even suggested that he saw
evidence of
fellow feeling and sympathy in ads
are where one at would help another one
already bowl ordering a picnic or
whatever
sources this observation seems if
unequivocal
as proving fellow feeling
and sympathy
so far as we can trace any analogy
between the emotions of the higher
raffles and those of insects so robot
has his taking darwin's doctrine of
evolutionary condo would be quite
quite seriously
and saying
i think we can see evidence
with things like consciousness
or you know
nonhuman animals
so there's role models as idea about
mental evolution of man who says look
it's just not
very likely
all of the body called is that the
show's evolutionary continuity
but that the mind doesn't
not least because
the mind of the body of related
in various ways
and he argued on the basis of his
anecdotal evidence
that poem that there's been
no interruption
in the developmental process that is no
qualitatively
quantum leap
all between all between or the raffles
laws
but that the mind of mad like the mind
of animals
has off
has evolved that was ramanrsood position
this book is still read
stillman though
uh... it fell to his organs don't
actually
policy void were going to say not so
fast
and he said look
love their guns out there a real
problems with attributing minds to
apples
not least because it seems to violate
the law
parcel moni
part of that
they corny and prescription that the
simplest explanation is always the best
exploration
and he said what you want to do big
there before you were started shooting
mind outils
you want to take care to make sure
that you could rule out
all of the hypothesis that their
behaviors the product of some kind of
instinct
for maybe a product of troy alone
trial and error learning
and so what morgan left us with what's
nao known as lloyd morgan's cabin
which is that
if you're looking at drug try to
understand behavior
you should always stop orton interpret
behavior
in terms of the lowest
possible psychological process again is
kind of they called me in
the korean parcel
on so that if you can if you can
attribute
a author of the some behavior toward
instinct or the trilateral learning
you should do that
and not start thinking
or have been conscious thoughts of
gauging conscious problem solved
there was one actually the interesting
corollary to avoid morgan's cannon
which set
all the stage for the behaviorist
revolution in new york
give your we twentieth century
which is his idea
and this is basically a quote here
by human process
is scientifically interesting
truly extent
that it can be studied in animals
also that just forget about that will
prevent much human research study that
animals instead
that won't talk about rather than talk
about a century for vote before world
people who say instead of us not quite
right
and in fact uh... jack your guard
probably check overdone at stanford
suggested that virtue actually reversed
void morgan's
and say that
animal research
is scientifically interesting
or lead to the extent
that it tells us something about human
mind of behavior
which is kind of an interesting
interesting proposition special point
here is
that powell or whereas rum on us was
quite happy to attribute mind
unconsciousness even tap dance
will barely have a nervous system
of along with his student word morgan
or was uh... what was sold some what
uh...
were more conservative
in this respect
as was john watson
or that the
famous founder of behavior isn't
all who who argued in his own
uni's revolutionary
that basically consciousness and
intelligence played no role in that will
be here who are at all
when we see animals they
they're behaving entirely hazchem
reflex and instinct
response
and if you pick darwin's fault of the
principle of evolutionary continuity
seriously
the implication of this is that
ip animals don't have consciousness
than humans don't either
right that be a bit the evolutionary
continuity goes the other way
oh and watson
a stab list behavior ism
of what the point of view
but you can understand
the all of the the behaviors of human
animals
the same way we understand the behaviors
nonhuman animals
in terms of instinct
and reflex
condition
conditioned response
all of this is to say
darwinian evolutionary continuity is
fine
but there is kind of a paradox tulip i
think that that's not good it's not
clear exactly what we on
for resposta make
out of this idea of evolutionary conway
everybody seems to agree
that there is evolutionary continuity
that applies to the mine
behavior
as well as to as well as the body
morphology
but the implications of that differ from
one person wannatter
romana said
but we want to do is to take human
intelligence unconsciousness
an extended down
to bother
nonhuman animals
whereas ford ikon walks in
wanted to say well look adult behavior
is just behavior there's no
consciousness there
and then they kind of extend this lack
of consciousness
or two
uh... cases
so it has to be said that lloydmorgan
himself
did say that there were some
mental capacities that seemed to be
exclusively human
and those people it was only supposed to
be
that had to do with language
followed
the next person here talk about business
world but very interesting person marble
floor in washington
or was the first woman during a p_h_d_
in psychology
hall and also lol
under lee president of the american
psychological association such a big
psychologist
all the very best very very prominent
and washburn took up this issue with
that romano sendawal and and and others
had done that
had been debating
and said look
if you think about it for a second
the problem called inferring
consciousness and all other animals
is really no different
the problem of inferring consciousness
in other human beings
we know were conscious as individuals
how do we know
somebody else
how do you know that i'm conscious y
know that your conscience dot
or whatever
that's the same problem
okay so the same
hines of data
that don't take as evidence of
consciousness
in all in another human being
you ought to accept
as evidence of consciousness
and other animals
as well and she says and just kind of
subsets that out here very nicely
or at my neighbors mine is a mystery to
me
how great is the mystery which works out
of the audience of a dog
very nice phrase sybil psychologist all
right with the same
which is really too bad
and how insoluble
the problems as entered by the mind of
an and
orifice fighter
still she thought the problem once all
your bowl
and it was so evil in the same way that
we part of the result
they'll be resolve this issue
with respect to
with respect which others
so washburn propose that we engage in a
mentalist a comparative psychology
not just comparing the behavioral
capacities of all learning abilities
of humans and other nonhuman creatures
but rather ordered are trying to
psychiatry uncover how the minds of all
other avenues work homework
oddly or some shit
the impact have money
that they're not just operating
on the basis of reflex
and conditioned response
and also shift all actually dot had a
critique
fall ball cobalt
uh... of the kind of evidence that we
use for this
suggested
though some some walpole nh
authors in fact robot has himself
had suggested that
whenever you see behavioral response to
stimulation
that indicates that there's a wind
workings of wombats
that person
all
all other are of nineteenth century
psychologist had to have been for mines
in animals
over the fact that they gave approach
avoidance behaviors so well that doesn't
necessarily mean that there's a lot
either
or the variability of the pages twelve
period only could come from lots of
places
in the end
what the farm
what washburn suggested
was that there were two criteria to
aspects of animals
for part of that uh... that that
that convinced her at least
that there was some evidence pole vault
or intelligence and consciousness
and first was what you called anatomical
resemblance to humans
fled the war of the brain all been
animal
looks like a human brain
the more likely it is
brain supports consciousness
so if you got loads of god
folds and they got all the stuff that
the all the features of human brain seem
to have
then you can start thinking about about
that adult having consciousness
but if the aval has already pleaded for
brain structure
for example
answers fighters who
really don't have brains they just got a
bunch of ganglia
know about
well then
though the maybe that's just too far
or too far down the evolutionary tree
and the other side the elder ralph idea
was this one of the rapid learning
on she wrote that she argued that
if a bit of a novel learns
really really quickly
kimba it must be learning
by virtue of some process or other then
simple choice whatever
and that maybe there is some kind of
all problem solving or insider
hypothesis testing
going on
and in fact the stories of psychology
now or that suggests
that it was more report washburn who was
the direct oregon
of watson's behaviorist
the old idea was that he was actually
read rebelling against
against thorndike
all but in fact
made very well have been
washburn zone
willingness to entertain
consciousness and animals
on that really septal
such a little
so how to make
well darwin himself had actually thought
about this
and proposed a test
all volvo or with which we now know and
show you what does the miracles but so
far
or darwin paul in his uh...
confirmed what the fed to them you could
tells the story
all bob watching around the kinds of who
are were held listed
house in the london zoo
and who had been are given a mirror
one of the put in the cage
and he uh... trays
all of these on stage is this a dot of a
ragtag cornstarch chimpanzee
on above the three stages of response
the animals were very surprised
or a at this object
or they were very curious about it
on then later on they began to get used
to it that weekend
remiss at it
and uh... actually sort of casino aborn
point almost as if we were or another
love
and other allele
on and then they or that eventually they
the the store
just ignored it
so dard was really interested in this
response all the chip abiyoyo above the
arrived at times
plugged into this matter
because that's the big because of
suggested to him that may be
uh... they were seen themselves there
recognize that the that the mirror
images were images of themselves but he
really didn't
the whole of look at this sort of
systematically
or so
you don't really know from darwin's
aliquot
whether these animals will reacting to
the mirror image as if it were another
eight cause harangues
spent a lot of time grimacing and
kissing each other
part
or
whether they were actually using the
mirror
onto our building to get information
about what they themselves uh... looked
like
but anyway there it is eighteen seventy
one just kinda sits there in the
literature
four all hundred years
untenable
farmville gordon gallup a professor at
the other state university of new york
at albany
decided that he was going to do darwin's
test and do it
director of the systematically
yeah but not gallup assault
climatologist he had access to a bunch
of chimpanzees
and what he did was to arm
but when they just kind of put a mirror
alive in their cages
of the same way that as had been done at
the london zoo
and he had to old
i'm going to be made observations that
were very similar to what uh... uh...
darwin had observed
i said of the michelly the chimpanzees
would explore the mirror and they seem
to react to the mirror image of zipper
were another animal
steady detriment reversing identical
and so on
but later although gallup observed
the animals would actually
use the mirror to explore themselves
volvo that they seem to react to the
mirror image
as if it were sold representation of
what they themselves looked like
they used america grew
bar body parts that they couldn't see
pork what that andy further
fall bay are used it to walk out the
pick their teeth
called they did all sorts of things are
there
big including
come characteristic chimpanzee behavior
of nose picking
chimpanzees do this
a great deal these chimpanzees weapons
winds have been made one of the pic
but that's that's a fact
is that significant
will see the second
of their yours your slightly ahead of me
and so here is actually barbuda gallup
psalm
twelve gallup stayed up
also
in in the blue you have
reactions of
to dubs and to build into the image in
the mirror
and in the green you have reactions to
the sell to the using the image
uh... using american room themselves
and you can see over
number of days of exposure
all reacting to the mirrors view mirror
image as if it's another animal
goes down
fairly quickly
and reacting to the mirror images if
it's an image of themselves
of point uh...
white progressively
but that of course
that's not
rooms could not completely clear what
lovable what what's going on there
on gallup then all invented would be
part of this
or that we now in use
known as the mirror recognition program
but the chimpanzees
anesthetized them
all
all of these are production pansies
would already had quite a bit of
experience with the mirror
ten days
bong over not surprisingly while they
were on conscious
applauded or color all other arnold
earlist although the paint
to their own for their farms
they were not surprised that they would
realize this is going on in this order
list so they couldn't smell distance
bill
visual dad
and then the animals were allowed to of
cause of come out of the anesthesia
onto the cage with the mir were present
and what the poem
delegated
was to again look at mirror directed
behaviors that his behaviors directed
towards the image as if it were another
chimpanzee
self-directed behaviors or as before
and then finally or whether the animals
or actually
looked in the mirror and touched a spot
and there's a control group of all of
the chimpanzees who had no prior
experience with the mirror and there are
the results
solo on the brawl
what you can see here
you can see that there is
buried at the very beginning to
experiment
walk home responses to the mirror very
few responses to themselves
at the end
no very few responses to the mirror
lots of responses for themselves
but what you can see here
mobile all most of these animals
were actually using american inspect
them selves when they saw this spot
state touch
the spot on their own
boren's
vara making it very clear
they understood
what would have never seen in the out in
the mirror was an image of themselves
and that they now look different
uh... dudley houston here's the behavior
for the animals with had no prior your
exposure
there was a things we know touching
of the morris all by uh... by those
animals
on the gallup includes
that chimpanzees show
uh... recognition of themselves and off
in a mirror and he went on to do some
other studies have all of the give other
investigators suggesting
that this is the behavior that is almost
unique
too
to look at the chimpanzees
mcc acts of various kinds don't do it
rhesus monkeys song
don't do it
they said look what you're seeing here
is evidence of self-awareness
self-consciousness
in chimpanzees
pressed their matching
sensory experience or perceptual
experience
with some internal representation
of themselves
fallen are gallup argued
implies both of you have a concept
itself
they have some idea about what they
looked like
and their their own
there where
of this concept
capable but would have to be around his
own
inference do this as well all of this is
were quite nielsen
and and and and his colleagues
and looking at mirror so the development
of marisol recognition onto a
genetically
inhuman infants
it's this crap right here
and somewhere between the ages eighteen
and and and twenty four months
the majority of human infants will show
behavior in the mirror
they were going to be here
just like the chimpanzee
so now we're looking at
some of the development of consciousness
onto a genetically
around
twelve months of age one year of age
not too much beer itself recognition
by about a year-and-a-half procedures
job of age
you're getting this village so pretty
experiment drove certain
animal behaviorist
we're just not prepared
to admit
artful
the any kind of consciousness or
awareness self-concept or anything like
that
and the revulsion critics of the sort of
a bit of these
of of these experience
basically said well you and that's the
ties the animals when you would not
surprise the apples and it's brought
their face budget behavior
fall bs ad-hoc criticism
but the actual responses
let's solve the let's see if this is
just a part of packed them for old balls
of kind of bob random face prachi
by looking at
marked the bond market areas on the
chimpanzee face
so will the market area
over one
on the
one-year and then look at
whether they are able
the two eyes
or the potential over the two wise
equally for the two leaders equally
that would suggest is just random
behavior
or whether they focus on
on the actual marked area
all this work was done by daniel paul
van elliott is that the louisiana state
university
who's probably doubling the
best work on god's green earth on
primate
cognition
on at the moment
fallen and you can see here
that poem
these are control animals
all who all who don't have any
exposure to the mirror
these are out of those who've had some
exposure to the mir and yes they push
their faces a lot
but they're cochin around the marcus a
specific
behavior
that has to do
or with the more
and that's true when you just count
touches
and it's true
when you look at the amount of time they
spend touching
various parts horrible of their body
so this seems now to be
discriminative behavior on the part of
these animals
that is directed
towards the mark portion
of their faces
which seems to really suggest
that they have some concept of what they
look like
you're aware of this concept
they're aware of the mismatch between
what they see
all and what
and what they expect
all here's some nice photographs from
over nellie
here's some the chimpanzees
who are
making contingent body movements
they'll approach the miller
from flight
until there
although appearing on the move around a
lot very interesting behavior
til seven for the mirrors bellowed make
smiles and grimaces and stick out their
problems and
do all sorts of things like that and
there's gauge of various kinds of
exploratory behaviors
comment only made an astounding
and uh... but uh... vishal discovery
which is that you don't see this
behavior and all chimpanzees
you seem very self recognition
every human infant as about abide by the
time it reaches about the age of
twenty four months
but in fact you always see mir were self
recognition in a minority
of chimpanzees
auto almost all of almost a hundred
chips that over that we tested the
status
that subject
proposal before down there
only about twenty one
or all the you know orval
more than
almost ninety all weird or so
dot chimpanzees
regularly show this song
brooding showed this behavior
in fact
the vast majority of chimpanzees
importantly such
study didn't show
this very self recognition so you can
get it in chimpanzees
you getting a lot more than just one
crummy
okay that's important
but it turns out that the evidence for
mera self recognition chimpanzees has
been somewhat overstated
tears
the impression they get in textbooks is
that jan pansy show this
all but the uh... were correct of the
statement would be
chimpanzees
shoulders
sonam let's get back to your question
who could we see this it
we see on yourself recognition and older
chimpanzees
chimpanzees have been raised in groups
and chimpanzees who have prior
experience with the mirror
you tend not to see it in younger
chimpanzees
or in a really old chimpanzees
you got to be a middle-aged chimpanzee
ice
you don't see any inch and panties were
raised in isolation
on it and you don't see it
in chimpanzees who have not had prior
experience
with the bear
if you do get some evidence on their
issac recognition interact attacks
now nobody's done the kind of extensive
study of a rang attends pullman ellie
did
nine-years-old chimpanzees
but it has been seen in around attacked
okay that's the answer
you can also see a bonobo such as well
sub species of
chimpanzees and you see it in human
infants
what you don't see it at all primates
interestingly
probably don't see although
yourself recognition in guerrilla ns
or a penny peterson the all foster balm
of the famous of gorilla koko
or suggested that or the anecdotally
that coco recognized
himself and further in the mirror
a lot of actually selling with me compro
but that's just an anecdote and was a
recorder that was in a formal experiment
on and uh... with the actually haven't
seen the date on this call
from anybody else
suarez and gallup tested
guerrillas
after eighty hours of exposure to
american got no evidence of mirrors so
recognition
ledbetter invasion
tested to alone agoura was after a four
hundred powers
four hundred hours of exposure
or to a bear
and got no evidence of mirror softly
soulful
we don't know about that one
shabbos don't show
of mirror so forgive recognition
monkeys don't show
under assault for a
and on
wilder non bogdan primate all of the
species
deleted
went on to the show it
either dole had something to say about
that
and second
okay so what's interesting about this
is that it looks like the capacity for
self recognition that they've got that
that's what you want to uses evidence
for consciousness
seems to have evolved
independently
because it turns out that chimpanzees
are our closest
although the primate ancestor
om havoc on prominent russian pansies
before we have a common ancestor with
uh... with guerrillas
somehow
or rag attends got it
chimpanzees got it
humans got it but apparently guerrillas
did
okay which is kind of interesting nobody
has any appreciably
explanation for this
it seems to at the seams of in the case
that this capacity for self recognition
hands on
has risen
at least whites and same atleast twice
about every year or so somebody will
publish followed by the blood that i i
know that the study
claiming to show
alot of mira self-regulation in psalm
nonhuman
or annable there are a couple of studies
out there uh... dolphins now
there's at least one study of elephants
wrong
letters i don't know cat has ever shown
marisol recognition
uh... dot i have a whole collection of
cats and probably it's about a week at
oppenheimer
who's now gone
bom
wiped out and he naked i don't know what
he was that we were moving that day and
he was just going to be there
he was also very soon
are but in any of that
there's one dolphin
widened often
that's shown yourself recognition
and one elephant
that is thought that that is shown
mirrors so recognition
but nobody has done
that kind of
comprehensive
widespread testing
of a representative sample of these
species has pulled the nellie answers to
a lesser extent gallup
or have done with god
a double chimpanzees
you cannot rule out
cats and dogs another out all of the
plug on primate animals might show on
there is hope recognition
but it's one thing to show it at one
animal
one but one instance of the species
it's another thing to make a claim
that dolphins as a species were
elephants as a species
had recognized
themselves
the question back your support
so anyway that seems to be in story of
there
all of that
mera self recognition
is your criterion for consciousness
if that's going to be used as your
behavioral tests
we know that humans have it by age to
view
some chimpanzees habit more than one
although some overall ragged tennis on
seem to have that by the end of their
this office
huge sample that's been tested
operated things like that has been or
for chimpanzees
but other species
it's not at all or it's not at all clear
for a long time
mirrors so recognition
always used as the criterion index
consciousness
and nine killed
nonhuman animals
more recently however
there's been a lot of interest paid
through another behavioral index
or which had the with which has more to
do with what our developmental
psychology or the colleagues call
theory of mine
consciousness the flying as a theory of
mine
this is an idea there was popularized by
developmental psychologist on stanford
john lovell
all based on work by loan
but ideas that came out of the work of
david prine back
hall and his
chimpanzees sarah
what sorry looks like
the idea behind the theory of mind
is that at some point
we understand it is not just that we
have mental state
not just that we have qualitative
states some redness and balloonists and
pain and smell and all of that
but that our mental states or
representations of other things
that our mental states are as james
would have put it
about
things bother
themselves
and that these representations
ordered that we have in our heads
of the world outside
may or may not
the accurate
so the first aspect of the theory of
mine comes with its recognition that are
phenomenal experience is about something
order that itself
that have represents all of them
something else
all the suck it out element of the
theory of mind
is this recognition
that part of our people have mental
states too
step other people have policeman fought
feelings and desires
or that are inside their heads
but they also may be true or false
and feelings and desires
may be different from a role
the idea that are mental states are
a kind of personal
consciousness
in developmental psychology
the palm
the acquisition of a theory of why it is
commonly measured with what's known as
the false belief
past uh... many of you would probly had
some
or the explosion there's no other
courses
onto this pretty briefly and let usable
lay the foundation for what we didn't
talk about
here we've got
an experimenter
and a child
fall and there's this
pop it here
okay this bit of this bear
and the experimental
takes a puppet
and makes a puppet tried on ball
all in the stalled middle compare
quicklinks
then after the boots for my child of
done this
all of them
barest put away in a cabinet
and the experimenter turns to the child
and say
let's move the ball
our called
or container into this box
okay so that they do that
and then they go get
the puppet again
and then say
the bear once the final hall
where do you think the bear will work
and the part of what happens is
three-year-olds
four-year-olds will say
the bear is going to look in the box
okay
and u_s_ to build us a child why the
bear is going to look at the box
even though the bear
the ball into the old mill container
and the child will say some words to the
effect of
'cause that's where it is
the three-year-old
seems to think
that the bearer who knows what you know
who has the same
five-year-olds
and some four-year-olds when they're
asked that question will say
the bearable look in the old mill
container
and when it passed one
they'll say words to the effect of
because that's where the bear thinks it
is
they had this idea
that the barrett has ideas and thoughts
that are different
from the child's
knowledge and believes and his lawyers
and that is
the criterion
padding a theory of mine
that is having an idea
of one mental states as representations
about
differ from one individual to
august just movement
those of you who are all bible readers
or or organs and
even as literature
the story of jacob these lawyers i think
the earliest
form or
hong broke representation or before
school the past
it's essentially a saint asked
elect read if you look at all
but here's work all by henry wellman
tracing the development of the theory of
mind
whether skids past forced most of the
forcefully expressed or not
alms
from oslo
age two and a half
most don't
too
age seven or so
almost everybody does and what you see
here is there's this period
where the child is
four
five years of age
where the majority of children and i'll
pass in the polls weakness
that had the idea that
there you know something
let somebody else does not know
had not everybody has the same part of
the the same knowledge in tomorrow
and you can think about that
as a criterion
for hall
for consciousness
are in fact simon baron cohen sasha
baron colin's
form
had suggested
that this fellow that that the false
belief task
is kind of the epitome of the
development
orble
of the morning you suggested that
when you've got a theory of the morning
you're able to engage in what he calls
minded really
understanding
the police
the feelings and the desires volvo
of another person
and he suggested there someone with a
whole bunch of elements
uh... here that were not we don't have
to talk about
the one that develops
last
theory of mind mechanism
the ability to impugn states of mind to
other people based on their behavior
knowledge recognition that other people
have
feelings and his lawyers just as we do
that they are thoughts feelings and
desires
well from ours
and baron cohen is carbon has suggested
that need to these elements all the
theory of mind
is mediated by the uh... cognitive
module that has been associated
brain module to it
where my dad brain module beat
taxicab wisher given adult tomorrow i
study in which they red subjects stories
while they were in the scatter some of
which were stories about true and false
police just like the false police task
orders just about mechanical inferences
and others just about human action but
not about police as such
and tried to identify and area of the
brain
was activated specifically when people
were trying to understand stories about
true and false beliefs
and they found it
here at the junction albee
and the parietal lobes doug briefly back
up okay
right about here
are back at the uh... at at at the tip
of the lateral fisher
on just where you see a particular or
part of the brain
activated whenever subjects are trying
to understand
home are stories that are based on true
and false beliefs
they've suggested that this is actually
the location of the theory of mind
module part in the brain
are module that is specifically
understanding mental states as such
in other words
atop a part of the brain at a specific
leave your towards
what are we going to do with this
on wednesday organising
we'd we know that consciousness
you'll find in terms of performance on
the theory of mine task-force police
past or burgess somewhere between age to
reach bondage flight
now we're going to look at on wednesday
we'll look at nonverbal versions of the
force please pass that attempt to
the origins of consciousness back in
infancy until genetically
and also
while a genetically
will do that on wednesday
thank you very much