volcano last time all introduced you to
the literature to some of the
experiments early experiments on
a phenomenon known as implicit memory
which i'm going to take as a model for
all of the experimental study of other
aspects of unconscious mental life
and if you
reading this literature even reading and
writing a swale for all of them
rosenthal's book
for example
you all along
noticed that
there are a number of different terms
that investigators use
palm
to refer to this phenomena
i follow schachter in home
distinguishing between explicit
conscious memory
and implicit unconscious memory does
that work for me
on the question him my task is
why don't you just say conscious purses
on conscious memory logistic use those
terms
well polished
dud i asked
schachter about this once and he said
two-term on conscious just has too much
all spare baggage associated with it too
much floridian baggage
too much psychoanalytic baggage
and he just wanted to stay away from it
for him and for me
explicit means conscious
and implicit means unconscious
now you will see in the literature from
time to time
references to
direct
and indirect tests of memory
direct tests like recall and recognition
and indirect s
mike priming pets or savings that
relearning or something like that
and that means pretty much the same
thing
home
i want to avoid at all
uh... the the the direct indirect
distinction however because
it's not just that prime innocent
indirect test of memory
that is
some kind of
varies so dole's sneaky test that
lol
and get somebody to reveal that he has a
memory that is not reporting
it's not just a non intrusive measure
memory we're really talking about on
conscious memories here
priming affects
that occur in the absence
of conscious recall a recognition
and then finally you will see some all
theorist referred to
this same distinction
as a distinction between declarative and
procedural memory
or sometimes as a distinction between
declarative and non declarative memory
and that's just really wrong
that's just the raw fun way to think
about this
the reason for that is
the declarant or procedural distinction
in cognitive science psychology in
cognos lives
refers to
format in which knowledge is represented
declarative knowledge is factual
knowledge that can be represented in
sentence like propositions
procedural knowledge and skill knowledge
that can be represented in
on
structures known as productions that
have a kind of
conditional
nature to them
you want to do with a then
be furs
and so
yeah it's true you could declare
explicit memories of a way that you
can't declare it implicit memories
but that's just a
that it confuses
the format in which knowledge is
represented
with the
way in which
memory can be expressed so
all for me
it's always an explicit horses implicit
distinction
all referring to
unconscious versus one conscious world
memories
one other thing i have to say is
all of the studies that i that i
described to you last time
involved the particular formal priming
donors repetition programming
and to remember be defined repetition
priming as a kind of priming
the prime and the target share physical
features in common
your primed with the word ash can and
then the target is a stem like a sage
that you're supposed to complete with
the new world with the legal english
word
repetition priming is the most commonly
studied
well called kind of prime news special
evil it in the literature on the
implicit memory
but it's not the only kind of prime in
you can get
and it's for that matter or not the most
interesting
are kind of crime you know it's amazing
how many studies have been performed on
repetition priming
a phenomenon that itself is
don't tell anybody
repetition priming can be mediated by
what we call a perception based
representation
alban event
all perception based representations
represent
thought that the whole or ordered
knowledge representations
the represent
the physical structure of an event what
it looks like what it sounds like
where it is in space are what its
relative location is with respect to all
other call don't bother robbed
butter perception based representations
dawson represent
the meaning
of the event
that is something that's represented by
army need-based representation
alm
all bought more like a propositional
representation
all deb represents both the meaning of
the event and it's so it's a magic
relations armenian relations based on no
m
on the among various kinds of objects
so what you really like to know
can the implicit memory which we know
includes all sorts of repetition priming
effects
can implicit memory extend to
also magic priming effects
that have to be mediated
by a meanie based representations
product of semantic analysis
that goes beyond
palm
just the physical analysis albee idm and
destruction
and there are calm as i say they're not
too much with all of them
or was torture on this
but there are all of the good examples
all of it
so for example what you'd like to see is
something like
category prime if a person studies the
word tree
is he or she faster to identify a
particular kind of tree
all of that that does the word so you
get
also magic relationship between three
and oak
and oak is a member of the category
three
or a solicitor priming
if the person studies
forward like table
can you get a priming effect
on a target mike chair
although the fact that has to be
mediated by
the associate of relationship
between
or and share
or you can construct autostart denture
actors dot a couple of times idiomatic
associates like sour grapes
sour grapes don't belong to the same
category they are not exactly associate
would prime
but the phrase so we're grapes isn't
idiom in the english so somebody's
studies so our
are they
now primed to deal with something like
of the the two was
idiomatic lee associated word
here is one of pearly study of category
priming and amnesia work by a gardener
is associates
where the calm
of those subjects did in fact study
category labels like tree and then they
were asked to make lexical decisions
about items like
or produce alm
or category associates
as old as free associates
and you've got a music patients and
controls
and you can see that the n_b_c_ patients
don't remember the items that they
studied very well on the test of
or kit would recall
but if you know ask them to generate
instances of the target i'll get out of
the category that they started
they show prime minister act
so on here are
on here the rest of the demonstrate
interest instances of targets they
didn't study can't be any priming
that's the baseline
and they show a nice priming effect when
there has to get very all instances of
targets of the cold front categories
that they did study
so this is a prime ineffective
that can't just be mediated by the
physical appearance all the work
it has to be mediated by something about
it's priming
and this is just a little demonstration
that shows you
on semantic priming can occur
independently or in the absence of
explicit memory
just like repetition priming
all i can occur
all a distinction between repetition
priming and semantic priming
becomes all but more important
when we get to the next topic
which is
implicit
or unconscious perception
descriptors okay
all implicit or unconscious perception
which is a phenomenon that's kind of
model dawan
implicit memory
in implicit memory we have
an effective a past event
study the word sometime in the past
the person's current experience for
direction like making a lexical decision
or generating a free associate
or generating a category instance
in the absence of conscious recollection
of that event
but in these could be in the case of
implicit memory
the prime univ and occurred sometime in
the past
now what we want to know is all i can
you get implicit perception by analogy
to implicit memory unconscious
perception where you can show the effect
of a current event
an event of the current stimulus
environment
on the person's experience water action
in the absence of conscious perception
that event
this of course is the classic question
about sub little perception
sold let's do a little bit of background
those of you who were all living in this
country and all two thousand
on me remember this famous alba
political advertisement that occurred
ald caught in the context of the bush
more
of the presidential on campaign
this was a arm
this was a alone
uh... advertisement mounted by the
republican allowed that national
committee where first
you see
pole vault with oval algo rithm
go that the vice president
all and then
a whole bunch of words come floating in
on the screen like democrats uh...
dollop of taxes and things like that
and four
one frame of the video
you get this piece of the word democrats
racks
flashed off on the screen
and that don't followed by
all of the gore prescription plan
bureaucrats will decide and just another
repetition of the word wraps
and there were some complaints that this
was the use of some little advertising
all over the time to influence people's
voting
all by means of this kind of
psychological called uh... treachery
and their bed there've been a lot of all
i have that there's been a lot of
interest over the years
and whether these kinds of things the
hard part all affective
or not they'll have something to say
about that
at the end of the lecture
the idea of sub little perception goes
back a long way
widen its writing onto beginning of the
eighteenth century
argued
that calm
in addition the conscious perception
we had an infinite number of what he
called petite perceptions little
perceptions
are governed that are unaccompanied by
awareness
and he argued that are conscious
perceptions
were built up all these called
of these smaller proof of the
perceptions road smaller percept
that were not aware of sewing
dropping pebbles into our commitment
when aquarium or something
all you don't see those pebbles but as
they fall on top of each other gradually
they come to the surface that was my
dances idea about how perception works
at the beginning of the nineteenth
century
all her bart called
or argued
that there was an actual threshold the
german word is lyman
that has to be crossed
all by a percept before it becomes
conscious
anne argued that our minds work
for would be
percept
and if one of them gain strength
it push the other ones out of the way
and cross the threshold into
consciousness
very nice spatial metaphor
all for consciousness
on it that's the one big we became aware
of
but her heart
also suggested
that even though these although the cell
belittle
percept
syllable little percept
didn't cross the front loop threshold
into consciousness
nevertheless
they could all exerted an influence on
our ralph
on our behavior so one of the questions
for the nineteen th century cycle
physicists
is there really such a threshold
all the that a that that out of stimulus
has to cross percept host across
before we can become consciously aware
of it
or before if you had any effect all on
us
again whiteness thought argued the
contras perceptions were built up from
unconscious
petite perceptions
by french is not very good so i'm not a
good gonna try
of herbert argued that on conscious
perceptions have an effect on
consciousness
and a philosopher
c_s_ first
and his
graduate student joseph just roll
all actually decided to do well and
experimented too deep too well good to
test out this idea of the wyman
published six that this experiment in
eighteen eighty four
just roll was the first american
to take the them for the first american
to take
a p_h_d_ in the united states in
psychology
although of this is the first
psychological experiment to be published
in the american scientific literature
really lovely experiment
and what percent just road ahead
was to ask their subjects was mostly
just road doing this
are to make us all of us there is a very
difficult comparative judgments
they'd put to weights
on aren't all of the uh... alone on the
subject skin
they were very close together
or did not do not need in weight
and simply ask him to what george which
one was the heavier
or they'd flash
to lights and ask
release of the the observer
to judge which of the two lights
all were wrong of
where the brighter
all up and
all the help that the observer will get
worse
typically just roll here
had to make eight
art had to rate how confident he was in
his judgment
now sometimes the discriminations were
really easy
the ought to stimulate were far apart in
terms of weight
brightness
or other times p discrimination was very
difficult or because they were very
close together
in weight or brightness
on it at some point
all the observers confidence rating went
zero
the observer would say i'm sorry i just
can't tell what the differences
so there is no conscious perception all
the difference
and at that point
or the observer was forced to choose
which white was the brighter
for which weight
or was the heavier
here are the basic results
all from the stall them from this study
is from the weight judgment
all portion of the experiment with the
collected more data
here you have the ratio of the weights
one point oh six to one
one point no three one point oh two
one point four one five one point
of hold
the whole farted and so on just kind of
goes way down
are here
and all
this is transfer form is is to
alternative force choice ordered a
judgment
and here it is so above the percentage
correct
when the observer was at zero accuracy
okay when the observer could not
consciously tel
which one
was of which weight was the heavier and
what you can see
at all of these ratios even down to this
teeny tiny ratio of one
about five and a thousand
all of the difference
the all moody observer
was right more often then you'd
that they need be by chance and in fact
person just roll had to work out new
statistics which hadn't been invented
yet
are in order to god convinced people all
of that uh... that this act this value
fifty nine percent accuracy
or was in fact significantly better
that you'd expect
five chips
so here we have the first
expert psychological experiment
published in the united states
all by the first p_h_d_ in the united
states
are ended fund subliminal perception
and its own awful portrayed of
experiments
especially in the early part of the
twentieth century
trying to
trying to determine
all-weather on whether
did something like subliminal perception
is possible
that is
cannot stimulus
that is below the threshold for
conscious awareness in this case
the difference between to wait
is the stimulus
can a stimulus that's below the
threshold for conscious awareness
nonverbal less be perceived
and we can track that perception
all by vide the influence of the
stimulus
on the observers ongoing behavior
now in fact experiments like this
generated a lot of criticism and are
some of these were interesting and some
of them were not interesting
all above bunch of criticisms had to do
with what i call the threshold bugaboo
a lot of complaints about
threshold setting procedures
also for example you could say well the
reason person just throw got these
results was better
they'd invite that they didn't correctly
identified the threshold for perception
and what it looked like all got them
subliminal ordered stimuli
really word subliminal stimulus
that's an argument that
completely circular but
palm
or they say what what
the way we are dental five the threshold
is
buffer in psychophysical threshold is
the point at which
a stimulus the presence of the stimulus
could be detected only fifty percent of
the time
that's how we define a stimulus
or that that's how we define of that
threshold
so if you've got a job you get your
below threshold where the stimulus is
being detected less than fifty percent
of the time
it's still being detected some of the
time
and that might be enough to push
uh... performance art
performance above chance
but the most important thing
on something a lot of foreshadowed
involved in the last what was uh... some
of lectures
was a kind of theoretical blinder
that people had on
which was the idea
that home
subliminal perception
really has to be confined to what we
would call pre attentive perceptual
analyses
so all yes you can get these kinds of
facts with calm with all
all with all pr
physical analyses like detecting the
presence of the absence of a deal of the
stimulus
but you can't get anything interesting
out of it you can't extract the meaning
of a stimulus
although subliminally
precisely because
if there is such a thing as subliminal
perception by definition it has to be
confined to pre attentive perceptual
analyses
and the prevailing theory of attention
at that time
was that
pre attentive analyses were themselves
confined to a dollop two
on extract information about the
perception of the of the physical
properties of the stimulus
generating a perception that he's calm
uh...
uh... but representation
what happens is there's our challenge
laid down
not to do studies like
what pure sva person just road did but
rather
to try to dead evidence for
processing of the meeting
of a subliminal stimulus can you add
allies the meaning of the stimulus
that's not
conscious awareness that's where that
debate i talked about about between
proponents of early versus late flexion
that's without all comes
another bella another criticism i think
with uh... it was even more revealing
and this is all criticism that
identifies consciousness
discriminative behavior
any argument went
this way
the evidence for subliminal perception
whether it's a person just roll
experimenter somebody else's
always takes the form of some
discriminative response to a subliminal
stimulus
notice the dates here
these guys were writing at the heyday of
behavior is and they didn't like
thousand-dollar don't terms by cult-like
consciousness
didn't even like using terms like
perception
the only way we can define consciousness
is behaviorally
and the behavioral definition of
consciousness is in terms of
discriminative response
europe aware in something
if you could respond to it
discredited privilege
so in fact
any discriminative response to
stimulation
counts as evidence of conscious
perception
that's how we know somebody's
consciously perceived something
so but uh... on when this criticism was
directed at the person just row study
the idea was
jest role in the other observers were
just warm when they said that they
couldn't i'll proceed
all of the uh... the uh... difference
consciously
the fact that they could perceive the
difference consciously
was
gammon by the fact that they could
respond to a discriminative lee so the
trick here is
all no discriminative response
on can count as evidence of one
conscious perception
and the effective this basically is to
rule
fall some liberal perception
palm
opry or
if you can't come to discriminative
response
to a stimulus that you're not aware of
it as evidence of subliminal perception
what are you going to count
and if there is no evidence that can
count
because dispirited responses taken as
indicated consciousness then you're
never going to be able to home
to test this hypothesis
the other thing that happened in this
literature
is that there was a shift in method that
is that that that turns out to be
important
in studies of the sort gone by person
just ro
all dawn subliminal stimulus was defined
as one that was very weak
very small difference between
the weight of two stimuli or the very a
very small difference
between the brightness orble of to uh...
of two lights
and what happened to end up with in in
the l
early twentieth century assist move
overture began to build
is that all people began to use first
the device called a to cast a scope
more recently art other computers
to control the amount of time that the
stimulus
is present
so a subliminal stimulus is now
fall defined as one that is thought that
that is
flashed very briefly not necessarily a
low-intensity stimulus
but one that's very brief
or that's fine
except that we have this kind of memory
cold iconic memory
devil hold
favorable representation of a visual
star realist
senior
visual system invision even after the
stimulus goes off
you'd be can't justify the subliminal
stimulus is one that's presented for
five milliseconds or something
the thought visual image of that
stimulus will persist for much longer
than that
for that reason
people developed a whole bunch of
masking procedures masking procedures
that effectively
all paul
you raised
this iconic memory
and on the phone
uh...
andrew render
visual stimulus
effectively or invisible
here's a little
figure that shows some of these mask and
procedures
here's up about two years old
technique called
phone energy basking we've got a prime
and a target
and the subject
fixate on this point
very bright light is flash
followed by the prime
followed by another very bright white
followed by the target
and what happens is these two energy
all of those stimuli
affectively vendors
evidence just bright light it's not of
did this not any kind of target
affectively all prevents the person
from home
from being conscious of the prime
so that's how that works
and we're talking about
this is called as a way stimulus on
cities agrees we're talking about
bug that acer craze of like less than a
second
here's a phenomenon called forward
masking
where you fixate
then that there is a fault that hash
mark hearsay rollbacks is new preview
warm
present the prime
followed by a blank
screen
a lot and the target
and lift the this stimulus
onset they synchrony is less than about
called the fifty fifty milliseconds
all of the forward mask will effectively
prevent you from the from consciously
perceiving the prime
here's the same mask and procedure
they're very popular one except it's
gone backwards
you fix it
the present the prime
you present the mask and then the target
and this mask affectively
all-new erases the prime from conscious
perception
if you're one of these belts and
suspenders kinds of guys
you can
do with the forward primer
then present the prime
that a backward mask
and present
the target so there are just lots of
these kinds of of them
procedures are better off that are being
used
and all of them have the effect
rendering the prime
essentially invisible
well not essentially invisible
invisible
the prime
tony marcel anthony marcela psychologist
at cambridge university maybe use of
masked priming
all-girl indictment classic study
reported in nineteen eighty three
that demonstrated for the first time
all water known as mast
priming affects
math semantic priming effects
his subjects were put in august that
would be use one of two on different
procedures electrical decision procedure
in which they are asked to
they could to decide whether a target is
a legal english word or not
or a perceptual identification procedure
immature simply ask to read the ordinary
the target why don't apply what the
target
uh... is
and then
this case
all of the targets were words like nurse
and dot masked prime
once they semantically related word like
doctor sold doctor comes up with the
prime
it's mask so you can see here
that nurse comes up as a target
and the subject is asked to make a
lexical decision about the word nurse
or to identify
of the legal
the word mirrors
and so that the target is always
presented super liberally you can see it
clearly
the primers presented sublet only in the
sense that its exposure
mast
so the subjects do not see
the prime
but the rest to do something with this
target burst
and the question is
can you see upright mean effect
the sailboat does the master
presentation i'll be associated warlike
dr
facilitate
performance all of the whatever task it
is
on the target
and of course the answer is yes
here are all
thaw what one of one of morsels
experiments doggedly expert five
and what we're seeing
ins on some trials the prime in the car
guitar not semantically related so you
wouldn't expect to see any semantic
priming
on other trials
all of the primary target are associate
lee related like doctor nurse cable
chair so on
also you would expect to see some of
semantic priming
alm
but brielle prime
is pres presented just once
to for twelve sixteen twenty times that
doesn't seem to make any difference
all but what you've got here is
responsibly missy
all of them but you can see here is
there's a nice primate affecting about a
ten percent priming effect
called when the prime in the target or
not related
our response latency
is about five hundred and seventy five
milliseconds
palm
when the private target are related
response leads his vote five hundred
twenty-five on milliseconds
temper sub-prime in fact that's a pretty
nice priming effect or in this
literature
all and so what martin what marcel was
able to claim was that
yes it's possible to extract something
about the meaning
all busted pollack of a subliminal
stimulus you're getting subliminal
semantic priming
where the priming
of the young the prime
has been rendered essentially
inaccessible
to conscious perception
by means of the mask
here's another experiment
followed
above the marcel did i want one
there's no called the subliminal strip
affect your number the stroop effect
from uga of from an earlier class
the subjects task is to identify
the color all big color patch
art that's presented all of the to a lot
of computer
and what marcel dared was to embed in
the caller
patch
a color word
but the color word itself was mast
so you can't actually see the color word
are sometimes the color word is congress
or other times
the caller word is
in congruent
or green or there's a very
paused ulm uh...
uh... short dog interval or hear and the
question is
will the mask presentation
i'll be in congruent color word
disrupt color naming performance
the answer
on is
here is where
the all of them color and the the color
patches presented simultaneously with
the last word
here is appalled by members of the
experiment where the color blue or the
color patches presented
a little bit after nor the presentation
called on of the word
and what you're seeing here
these are the income grew in trials
and you see the stroop effect
when the word in the pattern in
congruent
it takes longer to want to did to
identify the caller patch
when the word of the patch or conger
would
last time
all the way
across
all of this effect
so you can get a straw perfect
even when the word that suggesting this
drew perfect
not consciously perceptible
because or because it's been
all because it's been maps
here's another example of this message
from the canadian laboratory on she's
been americorps all that experiment
all be buried
v_r_ that the masking conditions
when there is no matter
you get a big stroup affect
or or the amount of interference had not
been color naming
follow you could detect the prime ninety
percent of time still pretty visible
you still get
austral perfect
all the subjects are detecting the video
of crime
all of the via the incongruity word
just barely above
and you're still getting that's the
significance drupal fact
and then when they can see the when
they're not the fact of the prime of all
poorly on twenty five percent of trials
the through perfect finally on finally
goes away
on the basis of this kind of finding
fallen
the magnitude of the strip affect
varies with the detective bility of the
problem
she's run an article
suggested that
we don't have just one threshold for
perception
in fact
thresholds
for perception which they called the
subject of threshold and the of
and beyond objective threshold hong
respectively
the subject of level
the subject of threshold
they defined as a detection level where
subjects claim not to be able to
discriminate perceptual information at
better than chance levels
when subjects a
i don't see it
the object differential
they hall identified as the level of the
detect ability
where perceptual information is actually
discriminated actions levels
remember the person just relax permit
where the the subjects that i can see it
anymore
by the response to choose
and he was able to choose
worrying
here somewhere if subliminal perception
occurs somewhere in this area of between
the subject of threshold
this is the threshold for conscious
awareness
this is the point where conscious
awareness goes to zero
and the object of threshold
this is the point where discrimination
subliminal perception explains or you
know
in roughly alone
in roughly the space
okay so there's number-one fresh old
their or in fact
now let's
see how you can call deb how you can see
this
we have
palm
the again its radio subliminal all the
screw perfect we're looking at response
latencies
between in congruent incongruous of
cellulite
here we have are clearly still
preliminary presentation
the uh...
i'll be all of the of the word you get a
big through perfect
you've got
mask that
takes the subject below the subject of
threshold
you still get a strip affect
when you
reduce
when when you increase the masking
ordered even further
taking the subject
closer to the object of threshold
the strip affect is home
is correspondingly weakened
and again the same thing here
super liberal presentation
big through perfect
below the subject of threshold you still
get a strip of fact
down at the object of pressure or
it's gone
and the same thing or here so that's
basically how duong road we would like
to distinguish between
the object of in subject of threshold
here's what i think
for anybody is interested
you're likely to get some magic priming
doctor nurse
kinda priming
when you were in this region
vera relatively close
for the subject of threshold
the further you get
to do toward the towards the object of
threshold it seems to me looking at the
literature
the likelihood of getting semantic
priming
correspondingly
all but you can still get repetition
priming priming based on a perception
based in dallas
even when you get
very close
to what used to an americorps cold
of the young the object of threshold
this is what the literature on
subliminal perception looks like these
days
the stimuli are not sublingual in the
sense that they used to be subliminal
and the classic subliminal perception
literature
subliminal stimuli were very weak
stimuli
in the modern
subliminal perception literature
subliminal stimuli are
stimuli that's not
exactly
um... that's not exactly the same thing
but beginning with this pioneer in excel
experiment
by uh... by marcel
we're taught
we now understand all of them
pretty clearly
subliminal of the perception can extend
to semantic priming effect
as well as repetition priming effect
i didn't show you repetition priming
texas
they're boring
the really interesting question is ken
you extract some magic information out
of a subliminal stimulus
and the answer peers to be yes
though it turns out
that there are limits
which i'll talk about on nanosecond
so now we have
it was a perception can occur when the
stimuli are
we we know that that occurs when they're
when they're super liberal
all and also when they're sab liberal
now there are also a bunch of
demonstrations all been plus a
perception effects
in brain-damaged patients
who were having some difficulty
conscious of perception
the famous example of this is the case
of blindside described by larry weiss
cranston a book length
organ study of a single patient patient
d_b_
all dv suffered brain damage
in his
visual primary visual cortex area
although the area b_-one in the yard in
in the occipital lobe
that call
of rendered him affectively blind
in his left visual field
left visual field a bullfrogs
you could see clearly in his right
visual field
couldn't see a thing
in his left visual field
all gradually
this this is called a skirt alma or
blind
alm
piled up eventually is blind field
receded a little bit so that it was the
lower left quadrant of his visual field
that he couldn't see anything
uh... couldn't see anything in but the
fact of the matter is that you presented
a stimulus
if this aerial of space the lower left
quadrant of his visual field
you couldn't see it
what why scratched discovered
was that despite the fact that d be
could not consciously c
stimuli presented in
a blind apportion of his visual field
nevertheless
you could make
although judgments about the stimuli
city quincy
judgments about their visual features
better than chance levels
so that he was able to
when just has to guess
so i know you can see a big just guess
is there a stimulus there or not
we could do that
better than chance
where is it
he could do that
better the chance
what it's four minutes he can do that
better than chance is that morning
is a moving faster slow is a papa right
is a horizontal or vertical
is a big recive small
in each of these cases
didi cad
judgments
guesses about the stimulus
better pensions
levels they're not great but they're
better than chance levels
all
even though
he cannot see the stimulus and we can
see the stimulus
he's blind
and that portion ald visual spaces
cortical blindness
here's a nice example
although this
so long
kal
indeed in this particular experiment
phoebe was simply ask appoint his finger
where the stimulus was
and if the stimulus is presented it is
intact
visual field
he's precisely accurate complete right
at the stimulus
if the stimulus is presented
uh... in his own sga thoma those blind
portion space
he's still pretty good
the screws up here
once in awhile
he's of
is pretty good
about uh...
about that
here is on the other example this is
perception of orientation
palm here is asked
judge whether this though whether a bar
is
horizontal or vertical
and he does that
very well be right
almost every time
parties asked to discriminate between a
vertical bar
and a diagonal bar
he's right
over ninety percent of the time
if he's asked to discriminate between
haldeman stimulus extra stimulus o
he's right
almost ninety percent of the time he
can't see the stimulus
but he can make
akbar though chance of guesses about the
physical properties of the stimulus
that or ralph
that are better than chance
palm
here's another one this is a very very
subtle test
onwards act i've been asked to detect
what's known as the grading
here we have
called bob examples of what or the what
grade he looks like
could barely see
like you don't want any broader goal
lines here
you can begin to see some vertical lines
here
easier to see them here very easy to see
them
uh... load here
graders
measured in terms of the with of these
bars
and evolving
baby is simply asked
is for that is the stimulus or the
graded or all of the great it or not
chance levels
and
is that the sales has presented in the
part in the impact portion
of his visual field
is pretty good
if the studios has presented in a script
alma
he's still pretty good
especially with
the wider stimulus
so he fails when there's very little
in the grading
but the fact that he can detect a great
enough all
when he can't see the stimulus
what account for something
so we've got to poland we've got this
there's one patient
i know where you're going to them
despite the next dog question
there's also a phenomenon of deaf
hearing
here is patient on a daily
who sustained a traumatic cause injury
to arm
to the oil primary auditory area anyone
in the temporal lobe has been called
kore dekh li death nothing wrong with
his ears
ald and it turns out
that home
by a can detect the presence of an
auditory stimulus
just as well as control subjects do
bacall soul localize the auditory
stimulus whether it's front or back or
uh... or the side
all pretty well
saving about the language of the
stimulus you can't distinguish between a
melody and just of the pure tone
all but he can make some judgments
about an auditory stimulus that he
simply cannot hear he has no conscious
experience appearing
and i don't have a slide for it but
there's also
one patient
actually there couple patients now
nonsense
they have
on damage to the primary somatosensory
cortex in the priore
followed a don't have the conscious
experience of tactile sensation
but yet they can make certain tactile
discriminations
outside all outside of awareness
on here's another phenomenon where you
can see implicit perception of work
this is a phenomenon known as pro so
peggy no joke
alm per person purposes will justify dog
ordered define problem for possible
nausea
as with the inability of a patient to
recognize right down to fly
faces
that car
faces a people who are objectively
familiar
um... too
he could describe the faces
it's a little purses got blue eyes
all persons got tall brown hair person's
got along those persons got this
person's got that
to describe all the features
are and then the classic case they can
recognize other objects
they just can't do faces
and all
this fella phenomenon
the syndrome is caused by brain damage
all here in the home
although lower portion of the uh... of
the temporal lobe
of the with rosa fuse a forum drivers
what's sometimes called the fuse that
face area
damage in this part of the brain
produces a selective
inability to recognize objectively
afternoon your faces now that's an
interesting phenomenon
on
russ bauer and his associates
did a really interesting all of the
study of course of a goes our patients
uh... new york a number of years ago
that showed that they were able to
palm make discriminate but they were
actually should ripple to show prime
interfax
from faces that they could recognize
what happens here
is that the subjects are
prime with the name
mark you go off
or the face
photograph
of all about the whole book a president
utah
and then have to make some judgment
about an associated content associated
target
and what you can see here where it is
where the name
fit or defend the the love the the
private part of the same
remains
you've got a very nice
although facilitation effect very nice
prime minister
compared compared to when
the names are on familiar
the same effect
we all go but when the prime is a face
so here and all the subjects or not
consciously recognizing the face
a face that should be familiar to them
fun consciously there is some perception
of the face as familiar there is some
unconscious recognition of the face
that produces these kinds of
these kinds of priming effects
one more example
and that's from another girl logical
phenomenon known as hemi spatial neglect
is one of my favorite clinical studies
on a very special neglect
alm is a gardeners are the neurological
syndrome
patients
pay no attention to something that in
one visual field or the other
on usually occurs
by virtue of damage in the right
hemisphere
part in this area basically where the
off quite old and the trouble will be of
from two uh... come together
all
and what time we now know that dumping
these patients have a lot of difficulty
of pending
damages on the right or the business in
the right side of the brain
they have a lot of difficulty attending
to the left portion
so for example
here in some clinical tests
if you ask such a patient
to draw a flower
still draw a flower but they'll leave
off the left side of the flower
the left leaf isn't here
hard here
if you give them a bunch of of wines and
ask them simply too
all of them
put a yacht
or they'll put a line through each of
them
you know they would find for the lines
that are in the right side of the paper
the lines that are on
are left side of the paper
if your present them with along the
horizontal line
and u_s_ withdrawal vertical line right
in the middle of it
they'll put their burka line
a quarter third of the way across it's
as if they don't see
this part of space
if you present the word like this
cowboy
rape in the center of their visual field
and ask them to read the word
they'll tell you the word is boring
we'll miss
they won't read
cowboy
they are inattentive
of wall of space
marshall and how we're going to british
alguna duda ro psychologist performed a
really interesting study
palm or the though dot on couple of
years ago
in which they asked patients
to all
to examine
almost identical line drawings of
something
for example like of like a house
the first test will go on for the
subjects was to ask if there was any
difference between them
neglect patients
don't pay any attention to the left part
of space
they say now they're the same
even though this one's got
smoke coming out of it for something
like that
but then what marcia lamb elegant did
was to ask
well which one would you rather live in
let me ask which one would you rather
live in is the neglect patients
are almost always chose
siong the that the impact house
and that doesn't happen
you reverse the image
so that the fire in the smoke is in the
right
albums of space
if you were asked subjects
a good usc seeing patients
but there's a difference between the two
houses there they'll say yes
and if you go on and stable which one
would you rather live in they look at
you like you're a moron
polum principle of course would rather
live in uh... live in this one
the subjects are not consciously aware
of this feature of the visual stimulus
yet they seem to be responding to what
they seem to be
of
they seem to be at all
uh... taking that information in and it
seems to be influencing their behavior
outside of awareness
okay
all
no i won't do that either
yall do this one this is cool
this is an auditory example in normal
neurologically intact subjects doesn't
work by eric wright who's a psychologist
at the university of british columbia
use a dichotomous named procedure in
which subjects were asked a shadow a
complicated pros passage that was
presented to one of their here's and
ignore what was presented to the other
on here
already on attended channel in the dike
article are same procedure say heard
paris socio consisting appalled a
have a phone
a word that it has two different
meanings but
the same sound
all along with a descend biggie waiting
word like taxi
and peace
later on after they finish the shadow in
procedure they were asked if they
remembered anything
all of what had come over the audit
ended channel
and because it was a complicated shadow
we cut their recognition test was of the
recognition performance was very bad
and then
all what i did was do what they say okay
now less than we're going to a spelling
test i want to spell the following words
for me
and he presented them with these
powerful
how do you spell the word fair you can
spell it that they are really as in taxi
fare or you can split so that they are
yaar as unfair plays
you could spell at p_ a c_ is that
warranties
or you can spell it p r_u_c_ as in piece
of pie
and what you see here is recognition is
very poor no better recognizing targets
that morris
faith showed dot strong tendency to
spell the hama phones in their direction
implied by the paris owes his presented
over the unattended channel
no conscious awareness of this
it prime their performance on the
spelling test a bunch of examples of
implicit perception
okay have a good weekend next week will
gobble gobble move on
to a couple other domains of implicit
cognition
and then we'll talk about implicit or
unconscious
thank you very much