let's continue our discussion palm
various psychological approaches the
consciousness
by picking up the topic called
attention
and we do this in a large part because
of tension there has been one of the
primary ways in which psychologists
have interpreted the notion of
consciousness fall all these many years
so that
you can think about
attention for the process of attending
as the process of bringing something
into consciousness if you pay attention
to something you become aware of it
if you're not paying attention to
something
palm related construct in psychology is
what's known as primary memory
sometimes known as short term memory
sometimes known as working memory
these are three different terms of
psychologists now used to refer to
roughly the same thing
which is the idea of the world which is
the place in the mind if you will
information resides while we're working
on it
if i you know i ask you to
are performed poster mathematical
computation like adb two plus seven
true and seven you're holding them in
working memory what you bring to bear
ear knowledge of rules of addition
retrieved from long-term memory
and then the answer appears and work in
memory of leads you to do
to too well could it
so working memory is that there is the
the place and work in the in the mind if
you will where we maintain
an object
in awareness while were working on it
cognitively
and these two a psychological constructs
attention and short term are working
memory relent
because the general idea is that
attention is the pathway
artist the gateway
too short term memory
we bring things
we were we bring information into
on where artists
by virtue paying attention to it
while were aware of it
it resides in working memory
when we stopped paying attention to it
it drops out of work in memory
and it drops out malval of consciousness
so we want to do for the next couple of
days is to talk about some of them this
is the tunes
of attention
all as if there is on the question of
all
about consciousness
and as you'll see it
duds as we get to the end of this
gone we're going to there with the
moment make a transition
into the next module the chorus which
has to do with the concept of
unconscious mental life
also tend to start early in the
courtroom footnote
we start our discussion of attention
early in the course because as william
james that everybody knows what it
engenders
famous james ian stabler rhinos what
attention is it is that taking
possession by the mine in clearing vivid
form
of one out of what seems several
simultaneously
possible
objects or trains of thought
sonya part here is kind of a under the
hood like capturing
all the nineteenth century
uh... introspective analysis of
attention which form the basis for
tremendous amount of work
twentieth-century psychology
and a continuing of control
the president ah...
up until the present moment
this was an older james had to say about
attention
all he made it clear on the basis of his
introspection this
that there were a lot that that
attention came in various forms that
there were several different varieties
of attention
found for example he distinguish between
what he called sense so really tension
and intellectual attention
whereas
the sense or ill attention as its name
implies is directed towards sense
objects the things we're seeing or
hearing or smelly norte stinger feeling
or touching or whatever
and intellectual attention
attention was directed inwards
towards our former
or ideas or images
home as opposed to something that's out
there
volume medial in the world
and james further distinguish between
what he called immediate attention and
ap receptive attention
bulb
here noted that you did what he called
the media that the tension
well it's back up for a second we pay
attention objects because they're
interested
okay that's why we do it
alm
and in the media detention the object is
intrinsically interesting to talk or
relevance jumping out at you or a car
that's coming toward you were asylum
that
that appears all
unexpectedly
and then when he told appa receptive
attention using the old term a
perception that you don't see in the
literature very much anymore
or where
your the attention that you pay to an
object
they're not interested in the object but
your there at your attention the objects
dot object is derived from
that your interest in some other thing
that it's related to
and then finally james make some of the
distinction between passive attention on
the one hand
and active attention on the other hand
whereas passive attention is
reflex of the nature it's involuntary in
nature you can't help
but pay attention to some object
all of that would be passive attention
whereas active attention
has more of the nature of a voluntary
on cognitive cognitive activity
you could do it
or uh...
you can do it or not
so that's not that's that particular
uh... distinctions
now market doesn't marvin chun who is
one of the one of our psychologies job
but paul
all most interesting oklahoma modern
contemporary attention
uh... theorists
in a recent review he bob what kind of
put these aspects of attention
in a somewhat different form he pointed
out first
or the major property of account all of
attention
or one that will come back to over and
over and over again in this lecture and
uh...
is one of limited capacity
the environment is very complicated what
james referred to as a blue mean buzzing
confusion
although
and that presents
for all the uh... we'll go to our own
food sensory receptors
or whole lot more information
then we could prosecute lee although god
the possibly
keep track of
arms so that
lots of things going on in the world
but only very few of them will be a very
limited subset of those things
ten-week a any attention to
at any particular time
because some of the limited capacity
nature of attention
we have to select
among the available objects and events
homes on the death of uh... present
themselves in the world
punch on the home
as this image of multiple stimuli
multiple events objects and events
competing for attention
and we have to pick some
all and uh... and ignore alone and
ignore all others
third
altman of the process of attention on
here is what
latrone calls modulation
whereas
playing up the pain attention to
something
facilitates processing of that thing
facilitates
our cognitive analysis of that thing
whereas
not paying attention to something
inhibits
processing of these kinds of things so
if you want to make sense of something
to one interpret something if you want
to add a y_ sued for
you've really got to pay attention to it
because if you don't pay attention to it
processing is somehow going to be
inhibited
now these the first three aspects of
attention
all alba pertained to what you might
call momentary attention somebody comes
in the room you look
pay attention for a minute
palm
or the fire alarm goes off you listen to
pay attention for a minute
but then
all attention also involves which one
calls vigilance
by which he means
or ability to sustain attention
over a fairly long period of time
attention is unjust grabbed by an object
and then grabbed by another rocket
despite what's going on outside in the
in the world
we can focus our attention we can pay
attention
to something and ignore allot of other
things that are going on
these kinds of considerations lead
trying to propose a particular
architectural attention
that makes a distinction between what he
calls external attention
and uh...
and internal attention
palm
and uh... various
sub components are both of these
external attention
again has to do with paying attention to
things that are out there in the world
whereas internal attention
has to do with paying attention to
things that are
on inside the mind
so charm proposes that
it's important to put to wildman or make
a distinction between sensory modalities
or attend a visual stimuli she attend
auditory stimuli
and the mechanisms by which we attended
these things
may be different
uh... depending upon the sensory
modality uh... in which they occur
almost
or were caught attention
are ever since the beginning of
scientific psychology
has been devoted to visual attention
of some work to toward rory attention
but the other or the other center
mentalities really haven't had worked on
or all that much are at all
another aspect of our interest in the
home
you know
visual attention
is all of the big is of wealth of
research
on spatial attention of the of ribble to
pay attention to some
location in space
and ignore what's going on in other
locations
uh... in space
are similarly that's been studied a lot
much less studied is the idea that we
can selectively attended things of the
current particular temporal locations
particular points uh... in time
follow join points out that we also
would tend not just to the objects that
occur
followed that the present themselves and
the environment
but also to the features
so you've got to be able to focus your
attention down
on elementary holland
up aspects of objects
turning attention
turning our attention to internal
attention
so what what kinds of things that we
have time to that are going on inside
certain inside our heads
palm
first what he called
task selection
we've got a bit www
have goals
well for processing
on you want to get his walk by as much
as you can out of a lecturer or you want
to
focus on
the tweak that you're sending or
although the world or the one that
you're getting or whatever it is that
you're doing
you've got some task that you're trying
to fulfill
and that's not something that's out here
in the world
that's something that you've got
that is more or less all moralists
internal
also relieve your pain attention to the
tune to information from long-term
memory
are defy askew some kind of wild
that's a trivia question jeopardy
question whatever
you've got to search through long-term
memory for all of them for the answer
and it run
like james
simply points out that searching through
dot vast mental storehouse of long-term
memory to find an answer to a question
it's really not all that different
from searching through the environment
to find something that you're going to
focus on
and then finally although there is
working memory on concept that i on that
that delay introduced earlier
basically is this become mental staging
area
where reaper
the various processes
that are
that are necessary for cognition
so that's one passed through what we
might call the architecture of attention
how attention israel
is structured
all another has psalm done through the
architectural attention is provided by
berkeley's own bill prince metal uh...
working club where she was a graduate
student barbara landau
all who made a distinction between
voluntary
blending involuntary attention again
another day yelled
of the the distinction that was ritually
proposed by william james
voluntary attention or what
uh... some authors
cold and dodge innocent pension
is attention that we pay to that we
actually paid to
some kind of oval
of external q
home
i decide
i'd choose i select what i'm going to
pay attention to in the outside world
what it is i'm going to ignore
palm and um...
told the principal points out that
voluntary attention is always goal
directed you have a reason for
turning your attention
from one thing
and to another
and god that's quite different from what
he calls involuntary attention on what
some walkers call exogenous attention
where attention is just capture by
something
you don't have some goal in mind you
don't intend
part two of them to pay attention to
something
but you just capture nice example very
familiar example
or logo's on t-shirts and things like
that
you've got this nice plain background
and you've got this thing here which
happens to be at u_c_ berkeley
cognitive science all the logo
if the somebody's coming toward you when
you're where they're needed just not
look at anything
object is going to stand out and it's
going to capture your attention your
eyes can't help
but be drawn
uh... to this song
to the subject
stimulus driven
all up and up rings metal alarm bell
make the point
whereas
you can
attention voluntarily
to both
external upload all of the matter is and
internal matters
involuntary attention
is something that is really just
captured
by above them
by objects that are
that are external
i'm not sure whether that's really true
to be honest with you they are not that
i think that's
usually true
but in or in the psychology of memory
for example we have a concept now called
involuntary memories
where you just kind of
sitting there and all the sudden this
memory occurs to you all of nowhere for
no good reason
on at all
and it seems to me that those kinds of
involuntary on the memories
capture our attention it but in exactly
the same way that external cues capture
our attention
that's a debate
uh... sometime
and up until one bundle simply point out
these two hundred attention really are
different
they have different behavioral effects
pain voluntary attention to something
affects both the accuracy of processing
and response latency
reaction time
whereas involuntary processing palm the
heart xlr response latency and doesn't
really have any effects on the accuracy
hopeful processing
frens melamine bell also have very good
evidence now that voluntary and
involuntary attention
or mediated by different brain systems
different parts of the brain light up
when your attention is being captured
by external q
as opposed to when you're
actively deployed attention
okay so it's just kind of background
all of the denoted picture of some of
the vocabulary of attention
let's see what people of done with this
palm
in the yard fifty some years austin's
song
people started
really working on the problem
alm first actually is stuck just dot
just the four of them
well first of the blast fifty years was
the first fifty years through to some
extent
all robert s woodward flown as i
mentioned in my very first lecture
did a bunch of studies on what's known
as the span of apprehension
which really isn't the question of
how many things can we pay attention to
on at once
the in world war two when there's not
for the first time certainly lots of
airplanes flying over
uh... ltd dot blog apart in space
palm
this problem was uh... became of the
important applied issue the polar bear
traffic control you've got an air
traffic controller
trying to keep track of airplanes
how many can he or she keep track of on
at once
and i think i mentioned this also before
bill fell laboratories on wendell
i mean stuff started dull producing dial
telephones and people started getting a
sign telephone numbers which they didn't
always have
home
had to figure out
or what the maximum
where the were the optimum length of a
telephone number one the answer is
always something like
seven plus or minus two
the magical number seven plus or minus
two and uh... those george miller put it
we seem to be able to keep up seven
things that our heads
uh... at once
uh... and that's uh... that's all of
that
and these early studies of span of
apprehension
gave us
all what dogwood worth called the first
facts about uh...
about attention
first is that is limited
as i said
the warning so many things you can keep
all of the focus of attention
uh... at any time
and the second power point
is that are tension can be controlled
than a week and deliberately
shift our attention from one thing to
another
attention isn't just captured
faisal unexpected or highly salient
tough
stimulus input
we could also
pay attention
you can also deploy attention
and again this general idea
that attention is somehow hong somehow
the path
sold what happens
when people first started talking about
attention
followed that
taught in the yard
in the in the fifties
a lot of or work was so dry did by
what's not what's now known as the
filter model of attention proposed by
donald broadbent in english
they were psychologist
and this is interesting this is
basically a version of broadband
so-called although the famous director
this is the first time that offload
chart was ever used to represent the cog
yellowstone of psychological theory
so of broadband argued that there is
there are a benz in the environment
and all the allowed these events
impinged on our sensory receptors
and information from the sensor
receptors is copied into what broad band
called a short-term or store
and from for broad term for broadband
solved noble purposes
the short term store
have held a copy of everything that was
going on all the whole blooming bosnian
confusion
was represented in short term island in
the short term store
and then all broadbent argued
that there is a selective filter applied
let's
poorly a very small subset
aldous sensory information
into
what he called a limited capacity
processor
which would then
processes information somehow and
restore it long-term memory or use it to
generate some kind of uh...
although some kind of response output
but the general idea here
was that
there was this
filter
that took the whole blooming buzzing
confusion
filtered almost all but i would
alltheweb
a little bit off will be a little bit in
the evidence for this came from studies
of auditory attention
by abroad ben's colleague donald cherry
all using a paradigm known as bush
hardik listening
all of the month of cherry was much
taken by what he called the cocktail
party phenomenon
go to a party in there lots of
conversations going on the lots of
people and you're having a conversation
and all
somehow you're able to focus on the
of the conversation you're having with
your conversation partner and somehow
ignore or almost all of those of the
rest was gone
and it really
are developed the laboratory analog of
the cocktail party phenomenon
homework home with it
with in terms of what he called i caught
up listening
you put your phones
and presented too
different messages
to different here
left it here is getting one message
and the right here is getting
a completely different
on message
and the instructed the yells at me
the subjects are instructed to shadow
one mc ear or the other
that is to repeat the message that's
coming over say the left your phone and
ignore the one
that's coming all over or over the right
to phone
and subjects who could do this pretty
well
auger cherry discovered well later on
after the trial was over
he'd test subjects
for their memory
for what had been presented over the on
attended
and found out that it was pretty that
are for example of subjects didn't
notice when
the message on the unattended channel
switched
from one language to another
switched from english to french or
we're go for the spanish or whatever
phone
he also discovered that subject didn't
notice
when the message of being played over
the unattended channel was generation
because was being played backwards
if it didn't notice off
didn't notice that what they didn't
notice however
or was when beyond the message on the
unintended channels switched between
uh... along
vocal genders which was a male boys
was switched to a female voice or old
that vice versa
but they didn't notice
switches and language
they didn't know that they didn't know
sila switches between forward speech and
uh... and uh... and backward speech
which led all good cherry and all
broadbent
to suggest
filter
interposed between the blue mean bosnian
confusion of the world and a limited
capacity are that we have four o_ for
information processing
was a filter
that filter dot out things based on
their physical
all the physical properties
so that's where the filtered through the
tension comes from this conception of
attention of the bottleneck or a filter
through which all the a very limited
amount of stuff
all can get through
there was a uh... one of the uh... an
interest in the nature of these sensory
stores
on you'll see
if you read in this literature
on uh... references to i'd konica memory
on that's the short term visual store
or act collect memory short term
auditorium for or whatever
and all broadbent argued that
all that stuff that's going on
people can really attend all lead to a
single communication channel
wrong and reaction introduced on the the
notion of
uh... surreal information processing
basically cut will be processed one
thing
or at the time but most important for
our purposes
broadband argued that attentional
selection was based on perceptual
features
you could
attend to some point in space
you could attend a some object
in space
all
bought you've got bought
that selection
was based on the physical features of of
the object
and analysis
of the meaning of the stimulus
what you might call semantic analysis
occurred
after
the attentional bottleneck
so just to come back here for a second
if you're going to see if there's going
to be a selective feature
the selected feature the selected filter
is applied on the basis of physical
features
where the object is in space
uh... what it looks like what it sounds
like whatever
and then only after
the material gets through this limited
capacity processor
is it analyzed com is about the lights
for me
communication channel of the time
attentional selection based on
perceptual features
semantic analysis is
post attentive
that is you can only do it after you
paid attention to something
not before you paid attention to
something
and then the filter theory also argued
that this
filter could be deployed in lots of
different directions
that attention is flexible
you can turn your attention from one
thing to another
once
you turn your attention
from one thing to a second thing
your ability to process
first thing
is now going to be severely restricted
onto only after you bug turn your
attention from wanting to another
that you've been begin to process it
on the basis of uh... on the basis of me
those are discarded that's where we get
some implications of this filter theory
of attention all four o_ consciousness
the first of these is that
perceptual analysis
has to be
thought all go
or unconscious
or if you will
conscious
that is
all uh... perceptual analysis has to
occur before attention
uh... this is paid to something
and that is just a logical e
true it logically follows
of the from the theory
because if you are going to pay
attention to something based on its
physical features
yeah i have to have already analyzed a
physical features of that
but if i'd
if by virtue of paying attention you
become aware of something that enters
into your consciousness for further
processing
then that that had blood priya tend to
has to be
oliphant has to be essentially
unconscious
perceptual analysis can occur
unconsciously or at least
pre consciously
is guys didn't like to use the term
unconscious
in large part because it was all it
would have been
co-opted by freudian people get really
we're around freud
home
uh... sold able to hold pre consciously
or unconsciously so what do you mean by
precourt while i'm iran contra federal
on his word
uh...
audit that also follows from the filter
theory that's semantic analysis
on the identification of the stimulus
the undoubtedly the analysis of its
implications its meaning no of all that
semantic stuff
has to occur
all has to occur post attentively
so what we got in broad bands filter
theory of consciousness articulated in
the late nineteen fifties
is a whole bunch of assumptions that
have continued
of ought to uh...
onto world of the played out in the hall
of the in the literature attention
the first thing
again is the identification of attention
with consciousness so that
people will use terms like pre attentive
processing
palm
basically meaning pre conscious
processing
and the filter theory limited pre
conscious processing to perceptual
analyses
analyses of the
wall location
hauled the movement
haldol of an object
whereas
attempt a processing
was identified with conscious processing
and conscious processing although the
permitted semantic analysis
as well himself as well as perceptual
analysis
so been prediction all the filter theory
is
analyzing the physical features at all
an object or event
can occur
before you paid attention to it
pre consciously
unconsciously if you will pre
attentively
analysis of the semantic
features
of an object what it means how it's
connected up to other things
that requires consciousness and has to
come only be done after he had begun to
pay attention
on too
the object
okay
now just as well footnote on this yes
i'm getting there
and getting their there's a story
ed turner they'd that you can't make too
much of buggered too big a deal of discs
that turns out to go back to that
that that's true that the best for the
study people mobile cygnus thoreau names
as well
but of course
that's part of the cocktail party
phenomena
you're talking to somebody at a cocktail
party then all of the suddenly here's a
meticulous from
your attention is captured
by that where your ex-wife comes in or
something like that your attention gets
captured by that
and it's not just on the basis of
physical features of on the basis of
something like me
song the semantic analysis has to be
able to be performed pre attentively
but broadband theory didn't permit
all denver's was so let me just give you
another example of how boggled howled
did the absence of broadband filter
three
worked its way of through
and all moved in another domain of
cognitive psychology so-called multi
store models of memory
all proposed offer spider-man seawall
and on norman are working the homes of
the basically at stanford
dawn norman's novel
visionary with apple
home and also by young richard atkinson
and avert schifrin's
all who were at that
point at stanford
rich your friend
on drugs or richard atkinson so
you see president
the same president atkinson
that though
recently retired and was replaced by
uh...
by president hugo
you'll see
then rb atkinson this is a really be
active since your friend version of the
theory
stimulus information
that's processed by a bunch of sensory
registers
and then attention is paid to tucson a
subset of what's in the sun three
registers and then held in short term
memory while it's being worked on
maintain it in short term memory by
means of a process of rehearsal
and then you can encode the some of this
information long-term memory
retrieved from long-term memory and all
that kind of business
but it's a sexually of variant on the
broadband
attention occurs relatively early
processing
uh... occurred so
occurs relatively late
now let's get to your point
because it turns out that there are some
problems with this filter model
and one of them
actually been known for a long time
noble mourey are cut all another english
psychologist
colleague oklahoma college cherries
all had discovered that
at least on some subset of trials
people would our pay attention to their
own name when it came over the
unattended channel
home they would necessarily
retention anybody just anybody's name
but it was their full name
and that suggested that there was
all that that uh... pretend to
processing could occur all with respect
to
also magic features as well as episodic
creatures
now in fact if you go back to the moret
experiment
you see that this actually only occurred
relatively small minority of trials
but it did occur
and the broadband theory suggested
shouldn't occur
so that was uh... so that was trouble
all day
moreover entries one
johnson's all who was actually broadband
saugov broadbent graduate student
although did some di ka dicuss mainulmh
uh...
that experiments
in which
she did did something quite clever she'd
have subjects
try to shadow a message that was
presented to the left ear
and ignore the message being presented
to the right here
but then somewhere in the middle of the
trial
should switch
the message
from muneer to another
and what you discovered was that
subjects would continue shadowing the
message in the wrong here
okay
and it would be the most of notice that
they were doing those volvo but the but
the point is
you could all lee keep track called
the above the shifted message
if you're making something like cement
the connections for the for the fact
that people could shift
this in the shadow message between all
yours
suggested again
the analysis paul vault a stimulus
import
on pre attentive analysis
most simply limited to physical things
all you had to be able to pick up cell
that based on armenian so that lead
vault gold patrice min and others
to suggest that
there was some possibility for pre
attentive
semantic analysis
as well as pre attentive
physical analysis if you're going to
pick up your own name when somebody
mentions it not been paid
if you're going to
follow-up message from one spot to
another
hard then haldeman priya ted you have to
be a while
notice about shift occurred
that saddam noticing that
that shift occurs requires somethin like
semantic analysis
and so
all pre attentive
semantic analysis has to be possible
put another way priya type of analysis
has to
go beyond physical structure so now what
do we do
our treatment
on an important paper off the hook
published uh... they see as a result of
her doctoral dissertation this issue she
has to be here
she retired from or berkeley in the
darwin to went to princeton
which wonderful place to recorder
thoughts cold
slowly
um...
rob produced facing a modification or
broadbent filter three which is known
not surprisingly as the modified filter
theory
and the first thing she says is
at smu it's wrong to think about
attention sa
what it really is is about ten u waiter
turns the turns some things down but not
also that the reason why
people could pick up there all the their
own names coming over the young
unattended channel
is not that the other tended channel is
blocked completely
tomb down
turndown all like the volume dane va
stereo or something like that
and she also argued
that the though that the toning
all this on ten u waiter
could be modified depending on context
and goals and all that kind of stuff so
that wasn't the physical structure of
attention that was creating a limit was
something more gold directly
although the point of major point here
however is attention does not determine
by the physical attributes of a stimulus
alone
what you pay attention to can be
determined by your goals
and what you probably attention to
compete deterrent body of the home
by the significance
of the uh... of the stimulus and that's
basically congress whipple
a new tradition and
uh... no sensory psychology
known as signal detection theory
on didn't get to talk about this when we
talked about quali a
but be released like a physicist
basically argued
or whether you detected the presence or
a change in the stimulus or not that was
determined
solely by the properties of the stimulus
how intense the stimulus was or how big
the change was that's what lies behind
things like neighbor's lawn factors lawn
stephens' law and stuff like that
and the signal detection theorist came
in and said well that's not quite right
it turns out
that whether you detect a stimulus is
also going to be determined by your
expectations
about whether a stimulus is going to
occur
and whether you detective stimulus is
going to be determined by
motives where your goals
part that is
what the consequences are protecting the
stimulus as opposed to missing a
stimulus or whatever
those are computers or b
observer of the perceived or not
features of the stimulus
all and all of the of
trees would simply
principal auto signal detection theory
and applied it to attention as well what
you're going to tend to spend depend on
your goals in your expectations
and all that
the result of which is that patrice been
proposed
the really the first cognitive you
called
of attention
home
in the first of all of the clothing vote
theory of attention
that took into account something that
seriously ka
people's beliefs expectations desires
goals
motives
whatever
nachos
not just the characteristics of the
stimulus itself
and that was she who all don't put into
place
of this very familiar distinction now in
psychology cognitive science
between bottom-up processing which is
driven by the stimulus
and top-down processing which is driven
by the goals and expectations of the
uh... of the procedure
bottom-up
although the driven
top-down more or less of morris meaning
so that's the first vote that that's the
first kind of step away from broadband
social on the filter theory
but it wasn't and apparently it was
it was a kind of step
that a lot of people to take account of
the fact that yes you know people's
names will leak through and things like
that
on you can see how that
could happen in a system like this
so if i'm in a cocktail party when
talking to people
i've just got a little piece of my
attentional system
looking for
my ex-wife for
won't listening for my name or whatever
it is
that uh... that i'm doing
that was enough for some people
on diana deutsch with her husband jay
alfredo richmond don norman again
all propose an entirely different way of
thinking about
this i pensionable filter or this
attentional bottleneck
and especially in terms of its placement
in the information processing system
these late selection theories withdrawal
plan all proposed around the same time
in the mid
in the mid nineteen sixties
were motivated by
basically anomalies a bike honestly that
these things kept proud cropping up
that before our crew dial process evolve
more semantic information
they've even tree simmons of a modified
filter fury uh... seem to prevent
sold what are the deutsch is that what
don norman possible let's just get rid
of the filter
let's not
debate whether it's a
filter or of attenuator anything let's
just forget about any notion of filter
and instead let's assume that all input
channels boho lb
you mean by the end confusion of the
world
his all process
and it's all
fully processed
processed
in parallel that is appalled at the same
time
and that once it's all process
processed with respect to its
physical features
but also
fully processed with respect to with
semantic features then
we pay attention
and we pay attention to it are based on
what thrown what doug norman called
prints
that is
permanence called
of the uh... the information for our
offer our processing goals
so attention that is required for
response to a stimulus
it's not required for processing or
proceeding
uh... yup
the stimulus
now these paul late selection theories
are quite interesting or show you with
an example of one in a second
but i don't want to uh... that i don't
want to admit
the implications of these late selection
theories for home
for the for consciousness
early selection theories of the
broadband type again just to repeat
you can process
physical attributes of the stimulus
unconsciously
but you can't process semantic features
unconscious you have to pay attention to
have to be represented consciousness
but these wade selection filters
because
the all the input channels are processed
fully beef
for attention is paid to them
suggested
pre attentive analysis is complete
including an analysis of the semantic
features alva stimulus
as well as the uh...
as well as the physical features
including the meeting
as well as the structure
one of these things looks like
this is art
br presentation of a bomb
don norman's view again we've got
stimuli impinging on the sensory system
we've got a bunch of analyzing
mechanisms here
analyzed both the physical and the
semantic
features of the stimulus
and on the base of these analyses
the basically why it up
volvo relevant information in memory
creating
various
represent debating various
representations
and i'm not done on the side we have the
perceived all the cognitive stuff we
have the perceive urs expectations
knowledge of language
and their goals
which make
certain
into a deluge of it which makes certain
information in memory permanent to
current processing goals
what happens is
we pay attention
where there is an overlap between
what's been activated in memory
through these analyzing mechanisms
and what's been activated in memory
palm on unit and a top-down fashion
by virtual perkins
so it's admits collate selection jury
after all the analysis has been done
we pay attention
to just to what's for dinner
lineal a straight this one other way
just by a clear
comparison of late and early selection
theories
old form
malcolm attention
here we've got a whole bunch of stimuli
impinging on the organism
in early selection
there is of
physical analysis analysis of the
perceptual properties the physical
properties of a part of an object
based on that
some
subset of information
is selected for awareness of response
and after
were aware of the thing then we perform
semantic analyses that's the frost of
all early selection theories
oh of attention
by contrast
the late selection theories say gather
all these stimuli
and you do this physical analysis but
you also do
a semantic analysis
although everything
then you become aware
one thing or another based on pertinent
sir goals or whatever
and you can respond to it
sojourn the selection explains very late
in the information processing
impression processing system
now why am i doing this
i'm doing this because
in psychology in cognitive science
there is a
jen are that general identification of
consciousness
attention
raising the question of
how much processing can go on
before you paid attention to something
oregon or terms
how much process you can go on
in the absence
conscious
awareness
all the the the problem here is
what can you do without conscious
attention
is
priya tentative
pre conscious processing ltd
simply to the analysis of perceptual
structures
whether where something is in space and
what it's moving in what its physical
features or
ken
pre conscious or pre account of analysis
something like semantics
that turns out to be
a serious problem
and
four on number of years all day
proponents of early selection theories
and proponents of wet swatch of the
reasons to do a good out in the yard
in the in the meetings
and basically that literature did not
gold very
home
and
daniel condom
who was also
at berkeley
alone
before he
to princeton
this is a daniel common who won the
nobel prize in economics couple years
ago
for his work on judgment and decision
making
before he worked on judgment and
decision making he was an attention
theorist
and he wrote all very important all of
the monograph on attention
attempted that that uh... with
was an attempt to get psychology out of
this
endless debate
between early selection theorists and
late selection through some attention
basically by calling through of the
debate
and redefining
uh... various kinds of terms
what kind of ended first
was to identify attention
with mental effort
that is
when we pay attention to something
we are engaged in effort for
cognitive
processing
that day
also that paying attention to something
requires all minimum level volvo
of cortical arousal
second he agrees with everybody going
all the way back to would worth and for
that matter james
that cognitive resources are limited
we can all agree
you can only
or devote so much effort to certain
kinds of tasks
there are limits to the amount of effort
that you can alone that you can deploy
that come unraveled
did gave the example one disposal i
could take a simple arithmetic problem
like two plus two
now pay for a lot of attention to that
we can pick up a lot of attention to
that
it doesn't deserve a lot of attention
right
all
so that they are the does their assigned
tasks that you just can't pay a lot of
attention to you can't devote a lot of
effort to
but then there are other tasks like
redeemed for example work
making various kinds of judgments
that really require that you pay a total
to pay a lot of attention to what's
going on
is that ok
what we have to do because our cognitive
resources are limited
because there is always so much
cognitive effort that we have to deploy
what we have to but what we have to have
is what he called an allocation policy
you have to have some sense of what
you're going to pay attention to and
what you're not going to pay attention
to and he says the
art the individuals allocation policy
is determined by home
via a number of different things
we have or set of what he called in
doreen cognitive dispositions
palm
that process information more less
automatically
and then we have
all more transient momentary intentions
that process information
more consciously and the amount of
attention we're going to pay daunted by
the to something
is going to depend upon the the man's of
the task
therefore poor performing our bunch of
tasks that are
cognitively on demanding
breed that dog consume
relatively few cognitive resources
we can do a lot of them at once
weakened perform brigham actually
engaged
parallel processing
but therefore performing
i'm very demanding task
very glad that very demanding past may
have to be performed one of the time
series
and you can think of all the number of
examples of this with them
talked about this a little bit last time
drivin
driving a car
uh... and carrying on a conversation
if you're driving a car on a familiar
street and it's a familiar car
home and
you're basically making mindless
conversation with the person
home for the next few
you can do both of those things at once
but the moment to get into heavy traffic
the talk stops
or the morning to get into any
conversation yell pullover right oreo
slow down or you take a different wrote
or something like that
also that you conducted do these two
things that's the that's the but basic
analogy here
so the general idea here is
which i will get to right at the
beginning of next class
for him to talk about
the extent
of conscious and unconscious processing
the implications all condiments capacity
three of attention
is that
so long that as the processing is
does not require a lot called
mental activity allot of cognitive
effort
we can do it preoperatively it into a
pre consciously
but once the task requires a lot of
cognitive activity
that task
has to be form
has to be performed
consciously
so the implications for unconscious
processing are these
the filter theory
basically said
you can perform physical analyses
unconsciously but you have to perform
semantic analyses consciously
the late selection theories basically
said
you can perform both physical and
semantic processing unconsciously before
you pay attention to things
the capacity theory basically argues
that
the important distinction is not whether
the processing this physical or semantic
perceptual or in terms of meaning
the important determinant
howell much
the task requires
physical task
if its physical processing and it
requires a lot of cognitive effort it
has to be done consciously it can't be
done
pre attentively
if it's a semantic analysis
but it doesn't require much cognitive
effort it can be done pre attentively
it doesn't have to be done uh...
conscious
so will pick up from next time
and explore the ideal
automatic automatic processing
as unconscious processes
thank you very much deal on wednesday