appl
okay
palm let's finish up our discussion of
the explicit implicit distinction
fight turning our attention from
explicit
cognitions watchful so the motion
but first
alm
a word about the uh... about the exam
remember regatta
our midterm exam is next wednesday
so you can go off for spring break and
not be thinking about it
will do well i think let's review on
monday the fourteenth
alm i've received over
about half dozen d_s_p_ accommodations
homeowners
and just yesterday i got called
information about the d_s_p_
accommodation
for the exam
those who have d_s_p_ accommodations
also into that stuff in the email
probably today
also the exams going to cover everything
that we've done
called the since the since the beginning
it's going to have twenty-five short
answer questions on it
and i really mean short answer
now one word necessarily but each one of
the questions can be completely
perfectly answer in just three sentences
or perhaps less
also
got a couple other material
don't want to give you a multiple-choice
exam
you probably don't want a
multiple-choice exam either
all bob we want to make sure that these
exams can be
fairly objectively scored
on the reliably scored so that's what
we're doing short answer
and ulm there's a lot of the jury also
there have to be after a number of
questions
lots of resources for the exam on board
is sent to all gordy posted to the
website the narrative review that kind
of
covers the high points or if you will
beable points
on something so far
will do all follow-ups u_n_ a session on
monday
i'm not good at
lecturer or draw recover that narrative
review on monday i'm just going to be
here
how to uh... to take any questions you
have
there are a lot of materials on the
course website
all the old lecturer was trations
although all the electoral stringent
drop there
their electricity elements that go into
things in more detail
all of the exam information page on the
website the hotels you
poet constructed grade
on exams and courses like this
all also
of on his you went to war the
prestigious
use in this course along with the story
of the scoring guide that i've developed
for the
for the geo spies
and finally if you don't get your
questions answered on monday
home
you should uh... post any questions
about the exam to be space or
and uh... if you do that by noon on
tuesday
began with the
to get a response from me
by five o'clock by the close of business
so that's left
and
well that's right
on any quick questions about
format of the exam the coverage of the
exam
i think it's all pretty clear
if you look at the past exams you'll see
what kinds of things i'm looking for
that's one of
so far in the series of lectures we've
talked about unconscious cognitive
fall
part or the formal unconscious kardasian
the autumn of two city of thought
process these are the prospects for
unconscious memory and perception and
thinking and so on
and that raises the question
what else is there
when we talk about unconscious on the
mental states
all it's a good question because
remember that
homes as well manual contras all over
the argued
all there's more
to what goes on in the mind of ben
cognition
there are three absolutely irreducible
faculties of mine
knowledge viewing the desire
the last three letters we've talked
mostly about unconscious knowledge
now what we won't want to talk about
qualities the motion and motivation when
you have plug consciously motion
and on conscious motivation
in the same way that it but it appears
to be the case
that we got a unconscious on cognition
okay sult now were treading into
psychoanalytic territory
all here
all there was freud of who owned that
made the strongest case for unconscious
feelings that affects
flight as i pointed out before freud
himself did not use the iceberg metaphor
but it's or somethin
the metaphor there always comes up in
the alone
in discussions of psychoanalytic theory
the general idea of behind all of the
freudian psychoanalysis
is that our conscious mental states
all var dark conscious behaviors
or the product of one conscious
determines
and freud characterize these unconscious
determinants in as
primitive affects all proponent of
sexual and aggressive drives
all or calm
of defenses that are on the phone but
better deployed against
against these drives
in order to avoid
and in order to avoid home
anxiety
and
dried invented psychoanalysis which he
told it is a technique
that that allows people to
become aware of their true feelings
ordered they're they're they're true
drives
the real reasons why they do the things
they do
on getting gain insight into their own
their true feelings and desires
that white at
lawyer consciously
all of the iceberg
well-lit unconsciously at the root of
our homes of our conscious experiences
and behaviors
now that's really all i won't say about
psychoanalysis just a kind of
all pick knowledge that there is that
what you see
will skip over this
analysis of the freudian defense
mechanisms
forgot time all connected with later
all what i want to do in this watchers
having
debian
are you turn live in boulder freudian
ism which is what mostly
but we do
all or even the serious uh... for unisom
and the reason for that is
in my view anyway home
when you talk about the unconscious
offered in theory just doesn't get you
anywhere at all
it turns out that after a hundred years
all volvo vault
of clinical experimental research
there just isn't any evidence for any
specific proposition
in classic psychoanalytic theory
and in fact some floss is a science
argue the psychoanalytic theory is
completely on testable
on because of the way that simply
because of the way itself it's framed
and for that matter there is no evidence
of psychoanalysis is a particularly
effective form of psychotherapy you
think of
psychedelic period of the mind was right
that psychoanalytic theory
bogdan psychoanalytic therapy would work
all but there's no evidence of
psychoanalysis
works any better than any other
or form
volvo of psychotherapy
instead what i want to do is to talk
about
the idea of on conscious emotion and
unconscious motivation
all
within the context of
something we got we know that's actually
true all of the establish psychological
theory
and dog
that that at that has really two aspects
to it
all first
it turns out that sold more emotional
and motivational states
are reflections
contradicts all of our consciously
motion
emotional
and motivational states are reflections
of unconscious cognition i'll give you a
good example of that
on you know the in a second
but then further and more interestingly
although there are some theorists out
there all of these days researchers on
not just their risk
who are met on making claims that
well there are actually
on conscious motivational and emotional
states
that guide
or experience for and action
all first
all with doubly gotta say just to kind
of touch base here
there are certainly some
the emotional states and so on the home
taught us all motivational states
that are automatically activated and
we've known this call for a long time
clearest example i think there are the
processes involved in home you'll static
regulation wonder why in things like
longer
and first those are
mental state star of the bulls are
motivational states
and we know that hunger is related to of
the body's attempt to regulate job
problem levels hopeful blood sugars
and we know that thirst israel is
related to the body's attempt to
regulate undersell fluids
and all
jerry didn't see a show in town
argued that there was a whole category
of sensation that he called intro
ception
all which
is sensitive to
levels the blood sugars and all that all
of the cell fluids and body temperature
and things like that
are and then instigate behaviors all the
various kinds of
all bottle lee and all that and
behavioral responses better intended to
restore
all blood sugar levels are so fluid
levels further
for their own
today were wrong
appropriate levels
the or the person to be said about this
is that all of that goes on
automatically
you don't have any conscious accidental
meter in their head that reads out your
blood sugar level you don't save
yourself
on as noon is approaching
all my blood sugar level is dropping
are you know i i gotta go
need to go and get a hamburger and our
something like that they don't do
anything like that at all
you're just feel hungry
brea feel thirsty and uh... old the
whole
breast with this kind of generated
automatically
the other volvo aspect of all that early
aspect of autumn it is to be
has to do with
armed thug
will be cannons classic
flight or flight response to threats
stimuli
and again what cargo cabin argued was
that
on one of our parker kind of in a tree
flecks of response to stimulation wanted
to uh... pregunta threat
was either an emotional state of
fear
or an emotional state
called anger
so here you have nice basic sample even
as early as nineteen fifteen when cannon
wrote his book
all on somebody talking about automatic
unconscious all activation all conscious
so of conscious mental states
art harris or something more recent it
has to do with the effect of paul paul
all peoples salt a bit exposure on under
on preferences
this is work that's caught in every
social psychology class so those who've
taken psychology one sixty will know
something about this
this is work by robert zion so-called
late robertson
mostly of michigan all prevented
whiskers at stanford
and science conducted all the following
experiment he brought subjects into the
laboratory
palm end of the ford experiment on
language learning
already said word what we're going to do
is we're going to teach at a pronounce
all all the words of a foreign language
and either so words were presented as
turkish words
or they were presented in the form of
jonah chinese idia grass not a word to
actually turkish words and they weren't
actually chinese idia graphs
but the stub subjects in the south study
didn't know any different because they
didn't know anything about turkish o or
chinese
all but what those lines did was to
arrange subjects that have
home with a big big see that the turkish
word of his see the chinese to be a
graph
and then they'd go board to pronounce it
in there
you'd don't do the word reviewed a graph
would be repeated
all for a number of trials up to
twenty-five on trial
that's all that it
in the expert except at the end
when dolls i instead of well it turns
out
that all of these words in easily graphs
were all artwork world padgett kids
and we don't just like you to guess
all-weather all of the adjective is a
positive thing a positive property palm
oh or a negative
property of
of the uh...
of the stimulus
and the results of the experiment
you're just so you can see
these are the pseudo chinese idia graphs
they're not real chuck venue
read chinese
you won't be able to read these
poems and these are the arm
wants to go traditional words
they kinda look like turkish if you
don't know anything about turkish
poem
and one half what what happened here
was that
on science presented some of these
stimuli
or a large number of times
and other stimuli just a few times and
it turned out
that when the when the stimulus
had been presented for a large
relatively large number of times
what relatively large number twelve
subjects were more likely to
uh... say that it implied a good
birthday
statewide the stimulus
all more than they did all if it'd been
we've been presented for only
hello
frequency presentations
here is ok lee nice example of this
whether you're looking at pseudo turkish
ur pseudo chinese
this is their home
evaluation zero two six k love goodness
the uh... word was entirely unfamiliar
tended to be
rated as a bad word
if the word was very familiar
it tended to be rated as a good word
and that's a significant defect
and that is what's known as the mere
exposure affect
merely exposing somebody's something
tends to
get them to like it
to preferring we don't like unfamiliar
things we tend to like
familiar things
and
uh...
part
the opinion social psychology the
importance of this
is that this exposure is what we've hold
up your situational effect
on
that is there's just something about the
situation
whether you've been exposed to something
or not that leads to the like of that
thing
or not and the general of the general
explanation here
is that repeated exposure
ought to a stimulus increases are
familiarity with the stimulus
familiarity increases likability
ald
and uh... that just shows you that your
grandmother was wrong
familie ready doesn't breed contempt
familiarity all breeds liking
uh... we prefer that
kcal with which we're familiar
now while i talk about this i'm talking
about this
welcome cape
it's not just turkish in chinese at a
press
although mir exposure effect has now
been demonstrated lots and lots and lots
of different kinds of stimuli
words song
real words saw i'll pick jurors all
sorts of all all sorts of stuff like
that
the place where does the work is
painting
if you don't like kandinsky it doesn't
matter how many times you see a
kandinsky
you're not gonna like kandinsky
and idon't know why that is
all-new targeted shouldn't be that way
but it is
farm
what's up what's interesting y_-twelve
why introduce this is
it turns out you can get the mere
exposure affect
even with so little exposures to the
stimuli
exposures work yeah i don't see
the stimulus at all
on either because it's masked or because
its been presented for a relative a vote
for a very short period of time
this is work by zion send one of his
graduate students on the way in queens
or wilson
all who presented subjects with nonsense
polygons just
shapes
mean anything don't refer to when you
think
all quality custer scope
one of the screen
well for only a single millisecond
gave one thousand of a second
falsehoods just two brief
or for anybody to to see that
and all but some of these all good some
of these polygons were presented
the subliminally for large numbers of
trials
orders were presented subliminally for
only a lot of the relatively of the few
number of trials
and i like the end of these exposures
phones lyon france wilson's lyons
presented although the stimuli again
along with some lowers
and as subjects
to recognize them as having been
presented
to alter the force choice all
recognition performance was exactly
at chance cust they had never seen
the words consciously
though that the stimuli consciously yet
when they presented pairs old and new
parents
onto two subjects at some which one they
white
there was an effective exposure on
preference
people preferred the old
hondo the signal light which they've
been subliminally exposed
over the new stimuli that they have
never
scene and then he sends before
so the idea here is that you can get
this mere exposure affect
you can get
all light enough of something you can
induce
for someone to like something
even if web by virtue of exposures but
they're unconscious exposures exposures
that the person is not consciously
process
home i'm gonna
and almost all stick with us
so the general idea here is
mask presentation
still was perceived that sub exit
similar it's another example of implicit
perception or unconscious perception
unconscious perception unconscious
percept is sitting in the old in memory
and when you see these are the stimulus
again
the to connect up
all you get a feeling a familiarity and
that leads you to
uh... but like the stimulus so there's a
kind of unconscious priming effect
which in the which inflates all of the
the general from the we are in effect
so here we have an example
all conscious or motion the cut the
subjects are consciously aware that
they'd prefer
one stimulus over another
but the conscious emotion is created by
or unconscious perception
palm and there are some other exhibits
permits for the same thing is done with
lately
in the memory domain
alm dot the peace of the emotional
unconscious if you will
sometimes
conscious palm uh... emotion
on can be created by all
well perception memories of which were
not aware
there's an old roman appa graham
freely translated goes like this
all you do not love the doctor
foul why that is all i cannot tell
all you only know i do not love the
calm
of and assault
purses quite conscious
but you not
all but doesn't know what
your you have
laboratory example
of the same kind of thing
this close wilson and zion six permit is
actually considered important in the
history of psychology
because it several off what i had no
called the affect of counterrevolution
in psychology
in the fifties and sixties we have a
hong cognitive revolution against
behavior is on
in the eighties
all we began to experience that affect
of counterrevolution
all which is really kind of a penalized
by debate between robert science
on who is the right there and berkeley's
ullrich all richard lazarus verbally
richard what lazarus
all who debated the role of cognition
you know in a motion
and science was really really really
clear
that experiments likely like the ones on
the subliminal mere exposure affect
showed very clearly that in some sense
emotion was independent of cognition
that is of the the the prevailing
dot psychological theory at the time
was that emotional states
where the product of cognitive
constructions
that it was our own valuation of some
object or so our beliefs about some
object
that led us
react emotionally to that object
and lyon says
that can't be true
because we can have a motion or
reactions to things that we didn't
percy at least we didn't consciously all
perceive them the subtitle of sciences
all non nineteen eighty paper was
preferences need no inferences
you don't need any cognition
uh... in order to have affect
all your further went on to say that
emotional states were activated
automatically in our reflex like matter
in response to certain kinds of stimuli
all
he further argued that's the title of
another one of the sciences papers on
the privacy of affect
that in fact
the an emotional response to a stimulus
comes first
before there's any cognitive
uh... evaluation of the stimulus
cognition is in some sense of
afterthought
and then most radically that emotion
emotion is more powerful
then cognition on that software our
feelings or emotional reaction to
something that drives our reasoning
about it
on and you can see all of the this idea
in a lot of
work on human judgment and decision
making
uh... recently
so for example
ralph david brooks of thunder columnist
for the new york times
or has written a new book called the
social addl
all item which he argues that
previous social science made that made a
mistake in thinking that we are
conscious
an irrational about kind of about
various kinds of things
and brooks in this so in in this book
the social animal
argues it's quite to the contrary first
beyond conscious parts of the mind or
most of the morning
where many of the most impressive feats
of thinking take place
and then second
you motion is not opposed to reason but
in some sense he motioned comes first
a motion assigns value to things and
found out
and uh... and and is the the basis for
reason
called this is a really interesting
aspect of the affect of
counterrevolution
which is the identification of
unconscious processes with emotional
processes
now that's clearly not the case because
i've just spent three lectures talking
about unconscious cognition
but you can see
brooks and others
all brooks' into my mind one of the too
public interpreters of social sciences
specially psychology writing today
the other ones malcolm gladwell
fallen and and he's just capturing the
property per is like rights within the
field on now when he saw when he talks
about this
so palm we can have some emotional and
motivational states are activated alva
automatically
all
i'll remind you just on barge on barges
auto motive
all model for behavior
weary argued that motives and goals to
be aroused automatically
through these automatic unconscious
processes in response to various kinds
of stimuli
all by the men barges automotive model
the implication is were conscious of our
motive
the motive may be generated
automatically on on consciously
but once it's generated
fall more conscious of it were aware of
what our all motives are
so that raises the question of whether
it's possible
of unconscious
motivational states
that nonetheless
palm dr direct and sand and select or
behavior
our case for a good for unconscious a
motion was made by the late david
mcclelland
ferret almost clearly
on
when i taught at harvard i talked with
him is a really good guy
on and on
of the troops from him that we all do
you
uh... to him that we go with this
constant distension
between two forms of a more of
motivation to me
express your expressions of uh...
motivation
explicit and implicit
mcclelland identified explicit
motivation as our
we with our conscious drives then needs
and goals the things we want i want to
hamburg er i want to snickers bar i want
to get out of here all all those
conscious mental states that lead us to
do all boldly of what we do
all that he'd spent his entire career
studying these in the form of
the need for achievement
on say silent and academic settings
the need for power and political
settings
and the need for affiliation or intimacy
and uh... in interpersonal relations
but mcclelland it was also very clear
all of that there were some of the that
some of these well motives could all
parade on consciously part as well
on and all of them
in the in parallel with our earlier
definition of the implicit memory
we can define implicit motivation
as any effective a driver a goal on the
persons all behavior
in the absence of conscious awareness of
that goal the question is
if they're not aware of their goal
hadi i know they've got that goal
mclellan favored all about the the use
of a particular kind of assessment
procedure
originally invented by henry murray
hurry marie another of harvard
psychologist
known as the fanatic our perception test
and what you do in the fanatic a
perception test as you present all
subject
clinic patient or old
or a laboratory subject
with the picture
and just ask him to tell a story
although what's going on the picture a
real story a story that has a beginning
and a middle
and an end
all of them so for example here's this
guy here
and you consume tell me what's going on
this picture and vic
well all this person is just a lot of
the pope copy palace and not you know
that they became istanbul
and he's climbing down a rope from the
wall to a state with
so you know what with the jewel dagger
if you've ever seen the movie if you
haven't
rented this week and it's a terrific
movie
calm
oh or you can say
this is all although no member of the
fly-in while lenders greatest trekkies
artists in europe is climbing up to the
high taught
ordered i don't have a higher opens
performing before the crowned heads of
europe
and he's going to do work
triple double
flip and be clogged by his wife another
flight and will end up
and he's going to astound everybody
that's a story with a lot of achievement
imagery in it
all outperforming somebody else mediator
suppressing some standard of excellence
that unique accomplishment
here's another one
wilted looking at a violent
one story might be this little boy who
has two practices violin
all up and he really reba rather be out
films on the plane uh... played football
with his friends but his mother and
father making and do this
not too much achievement imagery
or the story might be
this is the young yahoo demanded when
who's about to play a mostar concerto
for queen elizabeth or something like
that
all and he's thinking about how he's
going to handle the contends that enough
first movement
unkempt tremendous amount of achievement
imagery and that
well what mcclelland did was to do was
to arm developers go away or coding the
stories the people pulled about these
kinds of pictures
so that he could almost all the
determine
off how much of a
achievement imagery or how much
affiliation imagery or how much of power
in the jury was in all of the rome
was it was a what what was representing
the story
and the assumption is
that people are projecting that they are
all unconscious goals and needs and
drives and motives
into the story automatic a perception
test
is a classic example of a projective
technique
now we have a questionnaire measures
of measuring of the questionnaire
measures of things like unfortunate
motivation as well
you can just ask people
how much do you enjoy doing things that
challenge you
how often do you set goals that are very
difficult to reach or whatever
that would be a measure of conscious
achievement motivation
mcclelland argues
responses to the fanatic a perception
test are measures up on conscious that
you can't motivation
and the finding is
scores on the thumb at ikea perception
test don't correlate very highly with
stark our correspondents floors palmer a
young questionnaire measure like
jackson's personality research form
here are some met met analyses reviews
of the literature
of the chairman motivation the need for
achievement
power motivation the need for power or
affiliation uh... on the motivation a
need for affiliation and these
correlations are really really really
low
you can't get correlations lower the
price
are and the that the other the moral of
this kind of study is
well in some sense
achievement motivation
one conscious achievement motivation can
be desilva ciated from consciously
treatment motivation
and we know that that's the case
we'd be because the t_-eighty measure
of achievement motivation
doesn't correlate
the spca bill yard questionnaire or
self-report measure that's that that's
basically the logic
and it's good logic so far as it goes
but the fact of the matter is
that showing all lack of correlation
between two measures
is only the first step
in convincing people
that one is a measure of unconscious
emotion
all of the motivation and the other is a
measure of conscious motivation
kinda prima fascia villains
first glance and say okay
dissociation between conscious and
unconscious motivation you'd expect low
correlations
but you've gotta have something more
all than that
and the problem is
but truly methods of assessment
are stolen different
that the by catalog correlation
just by virtue of something that the
psychometric shins called method
variance
though don't do ya
further apart to methods of measured
defer the board distinct who methods of
measure
to methods of measurement
are
on the lower the correlations could be
between even if they're both conscious
of psychometric track
find that might actually don't turn out
achievement motivation
measured by a questionnaire an
measured by early on something like
thirty eighty whether different kinds of
achievement motivation
and if they're actually different kinds
of achievement motivation
then you wouldn't necessarily expected
from correlation between them
so the finding that there's although
correlation between a questionnaire
measure
of social motives
all it was uh... t_-eighty measure
is kind of necessary
but not sufficient to get to demonstrate
at the one who really is unconscious
unfortunately bohot implicit motivation
literature doesn't much
doesn't usually go much beyond
the arm a finding of all low correlation
so we just don't know
what's going on
let's turn of the briefly to alm
uh... too
the iaaf that the question of
unconscious emotion
can you have unconscious emotional state
feeling state and affect in st
that drives your behavior
even though you're not aware of what
those of what those feelings or
arm
again
although
that there are direct theoretical
reasons to think that's that this might
be possible
peter wagon
of although long-time a motion
researcher all told of has proposed a
new what he calls a multiple systems
theory of a motion
which basically says that there are
three components to every emotional
response you walked down the aisle
when you walked on the campus in a
guerilla jumps out at you from behind
the bushes on you have an emotional
response three things happen
there's what he calls the cognitive
component the refers to the subjective
experience
of emotion
you feel scared
second
there's a physiological component or a
covert
also matic response to your heart starts
pounding wildly
for example
and then there is
the behavioral or overt behavioral
response
all which is the star running away or
whatever it is you do when you're
frightened by the gorilla
fault
lines point was that usually we think of
these three components of an emotional
response is going to go there
when you're afraid your heart starts
pounding a star running away
the coupling between these are three
components on the line proposed was
actually in perfect
and that could lead to state
uh... rachman and harmsen called
desegregate
adi synchrony along the components of a
motion
so that for example
show the physiological and behavioral
components of a motion
but you might not show
the cognitive
component of a motion
and that's the situation
that were really interested in here
so we've got an emotional state
usually we think of these things is
coupled
so they all run off together
in a state of desegregate
you might have an emotional state
and have over
motor expression of that at the home
state
might have a covert physiological
expression that state
for per barriers reasons
you might not have the subjective
experience
of the emotion
sold lang's theory is interesting
because it actually lays a foundation
the person for suggesting
the subjective experience of a motion
conscious experience of an emotion might
be dissociated from motor
farm uh... or or physiological
manifestations
of that emotion
and there's some evidence for this song
but it's not very good evidence on them
uh... admit that i'm just it's just a
plausibility argument i'm gonna skip
those
but still
because of the because these three
systems might be arthur might be good to
so simple and principal
weekend
joist as schachter did for implicit
memory
just as mcclellan bid for implicit
motivation
we can
our proposed at least in principle
a distinction between
to expressions of a motion explicit
emotion having to do with your
conscious mood or
feeling stater affect in st
and implicit emotion which we can define
as
any of fact
of an emotional response
on a person's behavior
in the absence
subjective awareness
of that allotment of that emotional
response
and those behavior was perfect
might take the formal
facial expressions or other both other
overt motor-voter behavior
smile
because someone consciously happy even
though i feel miserable
palm
or of covert physiological response
my heart's racine meddling
on even though uh... don't
on any kind of
fear or langer at least in principle
you want to be able to
where are you seeing the most attention
paid
the idea of unconscious emotion
is in the social psychological
literature all martin relatively large
social psychological literature now
that is god claiming to have evidence
for the dissociation between to deferred
expressions
of a social attitude
farm
on explicit attitude conscious attitude
or implicit attitude
unconscious
on attitude
and all
on that this is all relevant to the idea
of one conscious a motion because
attitudes are fundamentally
emotional
on in nature
part of the attitude was originally
defined by are l_l_ for stone in the
nineteen twenties
as a after active disposition
disposition
favor something
or to opposed
or something
soul our attitudes always take the form
of
some kind of pro were empty like or
dislike home uh...
positive or negative
uh... statement
and ever since they were stoned we've
assessed harder our attitudes
basically by sold by self-report scales
all the political pollster will call you
up at the dinner roll over and say
well do you like browner deal like
whitman
okay would you favor in the election
and you're supposed to be able to say
who your favor and an eighth it in the
election
because you're supposed to be
consciously aware of what your attitudes
are
arial unfavorably clear power plants or
not or you would favor of drilling and
ad war or not
does uh... these were all
paula assessments of conscious attitudes
what what gramm golden but largely this
is the same greenwald who did that those
subliminal affect the prime minister
haris
well greenwald and balaji balaji was at
one time
his graduate student
all proposed
was that we also carry around in our
heads
implicit attitudes
on conscious attitudes which also affect
our behavior
all behavior that's attributable to an
altitude that we're not aware that we
have
unconscious attitude
that drives our behavior just like
conscious attitudes to
the difference being
we're aware
of our conscious
or explicit attitudes
were not aware
of our unconsciously implicit added
so i would you know
david mcclelland
propose diplomatic our perception test
as a measure called unconscious motives
how we're going to measure
unconscious attitudes and other aspects
of the unconscious
greenwald unbutton archie have proposed
that the that unconscious attitudes can
be measured by
something they call the implicit added
to the press
anybody done this on the web
couple of people
some really good at really others really
interesting exercise
here's how the implicit attitudes test
works
first in the implicit attitudes test
people arrested make a series of di ka
doesn't know that all of the dichotomous
judgments i've made made this off here
for example in phrase one
they're presented with a bunch of names
and all the subject has to do
is to make a judgment about whether it's
a swedish name
or a finishing
okay that
presumes that you know the difference
swedes and fins know the difference
so i'll turn and as finishes erickson
this leadership
uh... and and and and so on and so forth
sold out all the subject of
press one key at the name is swim
swedish
press in other key if the name is finish
bang bang bang all the way through a
whole long list of names
in phase two
the subject is asked is presented with a
number all the words referring to
objects or activities or whatever
and is simply ask the press one key
if the if the word refers to a good
thing
and another key if the word refers to a
bad thing
admiration is good aggression is bad
caresses good abuses bad freedom is good
then what grade woman but i should do
is they just kind of superimpose the
tasks so that the swedish finished
judgment
is alternating with the good and bad
judgment sometimes this we don't
sometimes and they will come up neck to
make a judgment but whether it's swedish
you'll finish
sometimes a word will come up they have
to make a judgment about whether it's a
good or a bad thing
and in phase three of the experiment for
example
yugoslav swedish and goodwill sherry
teach you press the same t_v_ if the
name is swedish
as you would get the word refers to a
good thing
and then there's a control condition
which i don't want to get into and then
in phase five
uh... there is a look at the finish
share is a key
with org with a with wit with bed
the home
uh... you use the same to you today
to identify whether a word of the name
is finish
as opposed to and uh... and to determine
whether or the word refers to a good
thing
now why do you do this
the rationale for the implicit of the
associations test
is based on the rock pool principle in
human factors called stimulus response
compatibility
and the idea here is
that you have off
faster response
when the response is compatible with the
stimulus
and this was originally discovered by
some early human factors guides
all who worked with had their subjects
simply make of dish or judgment
about whether
an object was on the left
for the right of another robbed
and it turns out
stiff the stimulus is on the left your
faster to respond
with your left hand
and if the stimulus is on your right
your faster respond with your right hand
that stimulus response compatibility
in the context of the implicit emotions
test
the applicable to all of the implication
is yes
that if you're making
using the same key
to respond to swedish name is and to
positive words
and that's
you do that faster
that if you have to use a different each
respond the swedish names
and all
and uh... uh... uh... good words
that means that yours
down deep down in your head someplace
there's a common conscious association
between
swedish
and good
and
suppose you're making the same response
to finish names and negative
of words
faster response latencies
when you're using the same key to say
the name is finish
as you
boggled who had the same key did you use
to say that a word is bad
that is supposed to reveal hey on or
unconscious all association
between
being finish
and being
okay that's the logic of the implicit
association yes
on here's an early study by greenwald
and his colleagues
on this is all implicit stall racial
stereotyping and white subjects
palm
white college students were presented
with wooden bad words
but there were also presented with
stereotypically black and white
names
palm
and it turned out
that palm
here is that secures the most important
thing
farm
when white names
were associated with a positive response
keen about us are faster response
latency
the blackness
were associated
a positive response on wednesday
com and that's so that
that person suggest
the people have
and implicit association
between
whites and good
and black
here is another example this is not
a large uninteresting study
on implicit stereotyping in japanese and
korean subjects
they had our korean subjects judge
whether name was japanese or korean
they had japanese subjects associate
with judge whether a name with japanese
or korean then they made a good bad
judgment
as well
and what you can see here
is that
if the subjects were korean
they responded faster when mccurry okie
was paired with a good ki
wendy japanese ke was pure with the
griffey
and when the subject for japanese
the japanese subjects responded faster
when the japanese ke was paired with the
good ki and the korean ke abdomen the
currently was paired with a good ki and
this is supposed to reveal
phone dot idea uh... kind of
prejudice against or of that uh...
negative attitudes about koreans
on the part of japanese uh... those
students
and about japanese on the part of
koreans do
there are now in the literature
honduras
thousands
of studies using this methodology
to look at home
to look at the pump power
uh... did to assess peoples
implicit unconscious attitudes towards
various kinds of things
and the important thing here is
it turns out
the albeit bb attitude measured
by the i_a_e_a_ t_v_ implicit
association coast
is essentially
independent
of people's attitudes when they are
asked in this case
all of the white subjects rest how do
you feel about black people
okay what's your attitude towards black
people
the correlation between
prejudice as measured by the i_a_e_a_ t
and explicit prejudice as wrote as
measured by a spill simple rating scale
very well
in dahil
britain in in the in the teens which is
a pretty low correlation
when you do the japanese study
you look at the correlation between
or ethnic prejudice as measured by the
are yuki
and ethnic prejudice as measured by
archaeologist simple rating scale
it's again
relatively low
of closer to zero
band called into one
and this is taken as evidence
that people's unconscious ethnic and
racial attitudes
are not the same as their conscience
racial an ethic
attitudes that there's a unconscious
attitude that's different
the conscious
brian no seconds part of this research
group understood give you a flavor for
what this is
on has
ald of thought constructed all you need
to use the measure all sorts of
attitudes
here's one about job
your attitude towards pants versus
courts
paul your attitude of the poor jocks
versus verbs
all your attitude towards all tom cruise
versus denzel washington
chawla cats vs dogs
palm jazz versus teen pop music and so
on and so i missed you
if there's a whole industry now are
devising these tests
and that um... and again but the point
of this for tougher or exercises that
there's all relatively low correlation
between
on attitude as measured by the i_a_e_a_
t
and that same added to it as measured by
self-report
and that poem that evidence that lack of
correlation
is used to suggest
that we really do have or unconscious
attitudes
influence or behavior that are different
from or conscious attitudes
that's the argument behind the i-eighty
on and again
this is although certainly the most
substantial body of literature
suggestion
that we actually do have
on conscious emotional states
in the form of various kinds of
attitudes
that are different
from our conscious
emotional states
that's fine as far as it goes
there are some serious problems with the
i_a_e_a_ t
problems that are so serious there when
you run home tonight and take the
identity
and it feeds you back
all the information that your prejudiced
against some group
you should take it with a grain of salt
there are all sorts of con from noon
factors
one of the prom perhaps the most all of
or the uh... the most important in this
context is target familiarity
white subjects
than on valuating
stereotypically
african-american
first names
may
what like they don't like them
but that may be completely apart a fact
of the fact that they're just not
familiar
moreover
beyond haiti makes no distinction
between active prejudice where u
dislikes somebody or something
and simply being
less favorably inclined
if u like white people but
don't like black people your that's
going to show up on the i_a_e_a_ to use
a reaction time difference
but if you white white people and you
like black people just up as much as you
like white people that's also going to
show up as racial prejudice
on the i_a_e_a_ t
and that doesn't seem right
plus this is not believable e difficult
task
okay as you'll find out when you tried
to do it
also there are all sorts of
methodological problems but the big
problem that i want to talk about here
it's not actually clearer
prejudice or attitude as measured by the
i_a_e_a_ t
is actually
dissociated
prejudice or attitude as measured by
part of the self-report scale
to make that point let's just go back
to no sex crap
the median correlation
between self reports of attitudes
and attitudes is revealed by the
i_a_e_a_ t
is a whopping point four eight
big correlation
in personality and social psychology
kill for a correlation that day
okayed so your mother
alone
if if the correlation between the
ostensible e unconscious attitude
and yes ten sibley conscious attitude is
about as big as we can get in social
science research a croatian point four
eight
there's really no reason to think
that whatever the i_e_ eighty is
measuring
is measuring
conscious added to
it's measuring something
arguably
but it's not necessarily measuring and
unconscious
so you got to take this with a grain of
salt
so there's a problem with the i_a_e_a_ t
all that it's not clear that unconscious
attitudes really had been dissociated
from conscious attitudes
on one from home from my point of view
the i_a_e_a_ t
hole really kind of illustrates what
william james called the psychologists
fallacy
which comes into forms
the first out element of the
psychologist alessi
is the idea that every event has a
psychological cause
well they don't
okay sometimes things just aren't did
come out the way they do because of the
mechanics of the response
the more important part of a
psychologist fallacy
the psychology idea that the
psychologists explanation of behavior is
the correct one
and this brings us back to freud
troy's biggest mistake
heat told people what was on their run
conscious mind
you know one of weep with your mother
and you want to kill your father
rightly said no i don't want to do that
will hold yes you do yes you want to do
that
the r_u_ eighty
does exactly the same thing
it's just super dot dad more mechanical
and
more automated
it tells you
your prejudiced against japanese you
don't like pants armed
arrived here is a year on favorably
disposed to home ordered to return to
black people and we know that's true
because were psychologists and we have
this fast
it ain't necessarily so
have a good weekend on monday will be
working with a review