okay well let me begin
what i want to do today is to show you a
couple of experiments
that paul
gives some idea about how we could study
various aspects of cognition
unconsciousness
vault
during and surrounding sleep
home most of the research on
consciousness and sleep is had to do
with dreams
and most of the research on dreams has
been physiological in nature not really
cognitive in nature
and most of that has been guided by
what's known as well
v_r_ hobson a mammography aryan model
from sleeping dreaming
and i'll have some things to say about
that
on later in the uh...
in the you know that
in the lecture
but for someone to show you a couple of
things about
poem
how we can use
the kinds of experimental methods that
i've talked about
in this song in in this class so far
to find out what's going on whether
somebody's asleep world were not
just as the most artists off
here's our cold early study by will see
web at the university of florida
in which he simply what people up
between these are subject to risk within
the laboratory
walk mobile come up during the whole
different the home
stages of sleep
and simply ask them
simple question
have you been asleep
and
alm went
when he asked a question of people who
are awake they said no
typically anyway
all
in our stage one
all again
these are people who are actually asleep
there's no elf activity in the region
either in descending spit dat
marin of the stage one of sleep
and on
they'll often so i was a hug i was awake
palm
ins more slowing sleep stages to three
and four
when you wake people up for them they
say yeah i was asleep
but there's a lot of confusion
then this so
in this uh... the stage one whether it's
uh...
you descend in stage one as you're
falling asleep or or what we now call
will be no call stage ram
palm james wyatt the gradual than a
graduate student are displayed who
wanted to use all memory technique
student too well
cloud of dust to explore this process of
falling asleep
and what he did was to bring subjects
into the laboratory
for all the
for uh... for them for the person sleep
and while they were
that after they got squabbled in they
got their bottom of electrodes and all
that kind of stuff up
to turn the lights out
and then presented to them over a
speaker
a set of paradiso suits of the forum hot
cold you've seen this before
and all
that the subjects were simply instructed
if they heard
a pair of of of of words
simply to repeat it back in there was a
microphone placed on in the bedroom
holland as well
and he did this are the result that with
the word presented
altman and repeated every odd that every
minute
until the subject no longer responded
j presumably the subject is fall asleep
although at that point
all of the way up to the subject failed
to respond through the ode to the word
pair
all he made sure that there was at least
fifteen seconds of alpha pre
home uh... do you think
over free g these subjects role in stage
one just because they're
falling asleep
and then he allowed them to sleeping
either four thirty seconds
or for another ten minutes
before awakening them
pauline at that point
what he did was to give recall and
recognition toes
and he did this ten time so there's
something which is a particularly cruel
to experiment
you bring the subjects and you tell me
going to sleep in a laboratory in her
wake up every thirty seconds
all world or aural reverie ten minutes
but the plan was to see
all-weather this
item that they've failed through all
failed to repeat so impreza we did not
go that did not hear it they were asleep
would somehow world
would somehow persist in memory
on these all of them on these recall
recognition
now why applauded his data in a very
strange way so don't don't don't be put
off by this he like
he discovered a three-d_
three-dimensional graphics program
just wanted to do you think is that
correct
i would not dot at this is way ahead
alm
but in any about what you're reading
here
these are beyond minutes prior to sleep
onset
also appears sleep onset one minute two
minutes and so on
and this is all percent correct
and what we're seeing here all subjects
who
slept were allowed to sleep for thirty
seconds
were allowed to sit for ten minutes
after the presentation of the last word
and here
there's a control group that but mobile
that was tested after thirty seconds
being awake
or ten minutes on the being awake
and what you can see here is if you were
exiled jigsaw up
immediately after the presentation of
this word
they're actually able to report it
a fair amount all the time that's about
fifty or sixty percent
or all of the art
of the time
it's not as much as if the move-up items
have been presented
when uh... one when they were awake but
it's still pretty good
but if you will also objects to sleep
for ten minutes
after that
non reported
onward pair
then you wake them up
they've got essentially no memory portal
here it is all of the results from
recognition
if you present these items when subjects
were actually awake they've recognized
him perfectly well
if you'll be allow them to sleep for ten
minutes
above the courier wildness within thirty
seconds you'll recognize it pretty well
not quite as welll as when they're open
it but still pretty well
but if you allow them to sleep for ten
minutes
than they just don't have any memory for
this to all
what what what paul why its conclusion
about this was
that palm
what happens is that does this material
is actually getting them despite the
fact that the subject is asleep is
unhelpful free stage one on descending
stage one sleep
and it's kind of
city mayor in what you might call short
term were working memory
for at least a little while on the
little while
one up so that
if you're awake and within thirty
seconds
you can recall it
recognized the pretty well but that did
some of them
the just disappears after a little while
decays or something like that
so that if you're awake and ten minutes
after the presentation
all you recall that were recognized with
recognized very poorly
so what's what what what you can see
here is that despite the fact that the
subject does not seem to be
aware
of this material as it's happening
otherwise disposed to respond to it
still the travels around eric working
memory arm
a little bit
for a while so it is possible
for something to get the end
during sleep
falling even if you're not necessarilly
even if you're not necessarilly aware of
it at the time
uh... skip over the was a versace
explosive memory test
and that brings us to the subject of
sleep learning
is it possible for people to actually
learn something during sleep
this is something students of all sorts
of would love
would like to know
not that you guys get any sleep
poem but still
the art of the possibility of sleep
learned something that's been around for
a long time
and in fact there were a couple of early
studies
all of that suggested that it would be
possible for people to all the time to
learn
called during sleep
put up tape recorder on
but some earphones all under your pillow
or whatever
place something that response to
remember the backstage
and you'll actually lorna the firstly
studies was done by all the pioneering
warning psychologist on could delivered
four indyk
or during world war one in which
military recruits were trying to learn
more skoda
and what all the
for thorndike did was to record
called of what letter morse code
palm or or the paris
eight years
dot offshore long
be used on to do it if i remember
correctly
called but in any event that's what he
recorded on a record
and then play that basically done that
in the barracks
all of the heart of what while these
guys will while these guys were asleep
and all but he dint of find was that
there was a nipple monitors sleep they
didn't know anything about how the
monitors
in nineteen sixteen
but what if i was sort of over twenty
pound anyway with some evidence of all
for all of them for learning
all but it turned out calm i thought
whatever was evidence for working there
was
boat soldiers were also very fatigued in
the morning
also on led him to suggested either
sleep learning to upload along consumed
a mental energy
or that the subjects that but that the
other the soldiers had actually been
awake
on during this time there is also some
hint about surreptitious practice
on the part of these guys but that's the
kind of that's the kind of study people
tried to do
here's little later studied by
fox and robbins again in their young
kind of wartime context
on the cold war of the island of the
nineteen fifties
here it goes thought that subject solo
over trying to learn about
correspondences between chinese and
uh... english words
and they studied these during the day
and then evolve
that though
on that night they they got more
practice with these up here is being
presented to them
onto the during sleep
and then the next morning
all-day tried to relearn these pairs and
the idea was
that if they could sleep learning is
actually possible then that you want to
show more savings in a real learning the
next morning
all four material that was presented
called direct bite
and all
to look at the turns out that there was
a little bit of evidence in the fox and
robin study
all for this here is subjects who didn't
sleep they got music as a control
but as you can see
the subjects who
called they've got the presentations and
sleeping morning onto a calm waltham
fewer trials to relearn correct
chinese english errors
called dog prabhu there was one of the
actually interference when they were
morning holland incorrect trying to set
a record of chinese which workers
so these are two studies have suggested
that maybe there was something part
interesting going on here
all simon evans all brass to look at
this although the four the army and by
this point
our people it discovered sleep stages
they had discovered a bball rapid eye
movements and dreaming and all that kind
of business
but they had discovered sleep stages and
they had all other stab wish this
criterion that you're not really asleep
unless there is
ono alf activity
five in your region that's the standard
physiological
on criterium ralph
firstly
and what's line-item instead was to alba
rug runner study
in which they
basically presented words for subject so
hard to uh... thorne
and while they were awake
in stage one sleep
all with
all hari
medium or low amounts of alpha activity
in the g
and then stages to three and four where
there's no wealth activity in the
contingent by definition
and what you can see here
is that all of them
there is pretty good recall and
recognition when subjects or awake
naturally
there is pretty good recall a
recognition when there's a high amount
of alpha activity in the g
costs they're still awake
but as alf activity disappears from the
g
the amount of sleep learning home
you limit the amount of sleep learning
progressively uh... diminishes
flows so here is a deal
chargers basically
all of the vote the summary of this
if there is
atleast ten seconds of elf activity
after the item is presented
you've got a pretty good
palm uh... all about
uh... likelihood of remembering
if there is no welfare activities
you've got called burberry
very bad very poor likelihood of
learning now remember
alpha activity is the criteria have been
asleep
and the finding of the simon aman study
is
that'd be the amount of learning during
sleep is correlated with the amount of
alf activity in the g
leading to their famous conclusion
sleep learning as possible to the extent
that the subject remains awake
palm
sleepless justices support
if you're really asleep that there's no
elf activity allies in europe
in a region
and that was nineteen fifty five and
that's pretty much
although you know that the builders of
the status of the literature uh... today
all
uh...
which apparently does not prevent people
from advertising sleep learning programs
and selling sleep learning tapes and
drugstores and in the back pages of
on magazines like psychology today but
it turns out this is one of the great
home
uh...
uh... requests of all time for a bit of
evidence of sleep learning and there
just isn't anything marital
yes all of that actually there is
something to that
almost all of the again this is work
done by professor of old walker kiran
did your berkeley
and when it was a postdoc taught at
harvard working with political
and it turns out that
if you've already if you go to sleep
right after you study something you're
likely to remember a better in the
morning
orthologs street seems to facilitate the
consolidation of memories
now i don't go into that much defined by
the
fought about though talking about that i
just don't have time to do it
snuggle really relevant to the question
of consciousness during sleep
flown homework over the land or or
consciousness at all but it's a very
important finding
fall having to do with
the on rural science of ball
of all of the form of warning the memory
and walker alan has done the best work
on this
showing that both for declarative memory
like factual memory and for procedural
on memories of the skill learning and
things like that
that various stages of sleep on do seem
to
uh... that
do seem to ah... improve
memory the next day
the and the ideas that
somehow sleeper most of consolidation
process
now there are some puzzles in this
and walker would be the first to
recognize that there are puzzles of the
whole in this
there are debates for example about what
stage of sleep is really important
for consolidation
onstage ram seems to be good for
consolidating some kinds of memories and
stage and read seems to be good for
consolidating other kinds of memories
and up the package doesn't completely
hang together
but the fact that sleep promotes
memory consolidation that is promotes
memory
for things that are learn
when you're awake
is pretty well established now
all but what
slime minuteman diamonds of pointed out
is that sleep doesn't promote
consolidation of material
memory for material for itself is
presented during sleep there just
doesn't seem to be anything
on the anything there
and that as i say that's basically ball
will be what what that literature is
light except that palm they're all good
but there were subsequently though
subsequently a couple of times
all about something and all of you do
more interesting might be going on
all here for example assault with a
little sleep study by called fred
evidence and off
that bill work shirt
in which they presented subjects
with kurt associates of the form
eight is for apple
beers four than an hour or whatever
instrument but now
all of that the paris so it's it's
while subjects were asleep
this was an palm pilot alpha free on of
alone
phage rem sleep
and i know what the subjects up august
the next day
but instead i was doing a standard
explicit memory test
all insane what were the paris
okay that we presented unto you the the
night before
what evans at orchard did was to say i'm
thinking of the letter or a what's the
word that what's the first word that
comes to mind
i'm thinking of the letter be what's the
first word that comes to mind and lo and
behold
subjects work much more likely
to all of the bed to give the word that
that letter had been paired with
the night before
now you'll recognize this as i kinda
priming test
art that somehow i've been presented
without
witham the paris those details for apple
subjects are even more likely than they
would be under base rate conditions
to generate apple
as a uh... that
as a free associate
to uh...
hable literary note the date was
nineteen sixty nine
evans in orchard had no idea about the
distinction between explicit and
implicit memory
buddy retrospect we can say
well you know maybe some all maybe all
of that this week when it is impossible
with respect to explicit
memory
for the material presented during sleep
but maybe there's something going on
with respect to implicit memory
for material present during sleep
leslie coburn hearing pasqua batch
alguna duda dot they've been a very
similar study level with what
with russian english word paris
all band again
there have been their test all of that
had some of this implicit
fall flavor to it was more like a almost
more like a free association task
than anything else and they got some on
interesting results as well
so those are those results so for
example
of all do that
do the oven tortured one paul first
when these items were presented in stage
rather
you actually got
of notes on the some evidence of memory
but at the other representative stage
tourist age for tourist just nothing
there
holding role both days three
and here's the cooper across garage
arm you present these items and waking
you get pretty good memory
all but if you present them in sleep
the jet better recognition
then you do recall this is or better
recognition than you'd expect by chance
and again recognition can be mediated by
priming effects can be mediated by
familiar respects other at least ends
all in the literature
called that maybe also clinton was
possible
even though the subjects are asleep
as long as you look at implicit memory
which led james one
ought to actually do a formal starting
of explicit and implicit memory for
material presented
on during ordering suite
all he took a l
locally
of that
vote for a while
the ike study on dicom listening that i
talked about a couple of weeks ago
the subjects were presented on the first
night of sleep or with hama phone errors
that is an ambiguous word like peace
all ball paired with a descended you
waiting awards like warren peace
work toward us and hair
and then the next morning
they were simply preserve read these
words
piece
hair or whatever
and were asked to spell them and the
test was
whether of subjects would spell peace
dac as opposed to p_r_ you see
whether they'd the hospital care
h_ a_ r_ d_ as opposed to age
they high are
the next night although hogwood did
something similar
he presented subject for parody
associates consisting of a metal on
metal and a category that is tube the
word metal or animal horse or whatever
and the next morning
allman palm
call it the would would test memory
simply by asking subjects one think of a
metal what's the first metal comes to
mind
i'm thinking about animal what's the
first animal that uh...
that comes to mind
this was an extremely carefully done
starting
all would really pulled out although
stops you read this one minute and study
he knew not to make
uh... the usual kinds of of mistakes and
he threw out of the study
any item presented
while the subject was this fence of
leona mostly
that was associated with any body
movement
or any other signs of the part of alpha
activity in the g
so would new
precisely
that the subjects were asleep by all
physiological criteria
all what when the all when the items
home with them
were presented to them
soul again
like yours to recall results from hubble
phone priming when these wanna holla
phones were presented war peace
uh... dog taurus fair
when those low hollow phones were
presented in to some pics of the waking
state you've got a nice priming effect
they spelled the hubble phones in line
with the descent biggie waiting word
the idaho phones were presented when
subjects were sleep you've got nothing
there's absolutely no priming effect
uh... there
all at all
here is where we are comparable data for
category instance priming
when you present at the yacht club
her associates two subjects when they
were awake
and so i don't think of a metal what's
the first word that what's the first
metal the comes to mind also gold
what i'm thinking about of all what's
the first walked out of all the comes to
mind allstate worse
but when they're asleep
nothing whatsoever
so there's just no
that's for the of this might have
qualified different results might've
qualified the simon
and admins result
all but they don't
on it turns out that there's just no
evidence role
for anything getting in
when subjects or actually asleep
it might be true that sleep warning as
possible
oh window
thought want to stay awake
but it so it's not true that sleeper as
possible so long as you rely on implicit
as late as opposed to expose of memories
just there's just nothing
and i have to say
but this is a tremendous disappointment
for everybody involved in this study all
above because it really thought it would
be cool
right it would've been very cool
of the the show that there was an
implicit memory for material presented
during sleep
home home via phone it just didn't
happen that way
on think
would have effectively killed off this
inquire line of inquiry
there is a paradox here
last week
by showed you some studies that show
that you can get the implicit memory for
material presented during general
anesthesia
this week punched telling you that you
can't get that memory
for material presented while you're
asleep
why any standard
subjects who were asleep i've got to be
in a better active alert state of mind
and people run to replace general
anesthesia
how could we have gotten
priming
for mature presented during jut during
general anesthesia
all wed would couldn't get of the
priming for material presented on during
sleep
well the first thing to say as they are
different states you're not just asleep
when you're in s the times of our song
i dare not just enough supplies when
you're when you're asleep
but there are also important differences
between the
the the between the effects
all of that
that uh... we got that with anesthesia
and that would go out on what was sleep
that has to do with the kind of priming
in the anesthesia studies all the
studies showing priming during
anesthesia
had made use of repetition priming
repetition priming which can be mediated
by a
perceptual representation
of the physical properties of the
stimulus
everyone
of the successful studies of of
prominent anesthesia
have used a repetition priming
no one has ever
succeeded in showing semantic priming
during general anesthesia there's one
case but it's
uh... its fifth
it's not
it's not really
one studies
used by all tell you why it's not right
cuz he use very highly although that
does a very high yard the associates all
four colored names and
what what what seems to be in prime and
i think was really
really above base rate adjusted has
pastry
but then the one studies
war is not looking at
repetition priming
he's looking at some magic priming
you can't get priming and humble phone
spelling
or incategory instances unless you
process the semantic relationship
between the two words
unless you recognize that warren peace
or opposite for the title of the polls
boyd novel all of us who recognize that
toward us and hair or animals and that
so that's that's the name of it he saw
fable
all you can't get semantic priming
unless you recognize the gold is in fact
the metal in animal is in fact the horse
that just doesn't happen
so what you would really like to see if
you really want to nail this down
is a study of repetition priming
it might
actually be possible
to get a repetition priming
in helpful freeze sleep but we don't
know
nobody's ever done that study
would went on the other things he never
did that study
palm the heart that any of you ever get
a hold of a sleep laboratory that would
be a very interesting study to do
and it would just kind of all that they
were just kind of
of the make the case
so you can get
private in anesthesia if its repetition
priming but not semantic priming
you can't get priming semantic priming
and sleep
group called the remaining question is
can you get repetition priming and sleep
we just don't know
and that's really all to be said
about that yes
yellow i personally would want to call
it implicit perception
all up and the reason i do that is that
there's no reason to think that the
subject is consciously aware of the
presentation at the time it occurred
and i think the best evidence for this
is the
is that it is that study of people
falling asleep
all by james wyatt
on bed just not there comes a point to
just don't respond to the word
sold for all intents and purposes
they're not consciously aware of it
you know it's kind of reverberated
around at least for about thirty seconds
and it might be possible
for all for it to be alone
to be at all
subject to some consolidation be encoded
to some extent
and be available for an implicit memory
if not an explicit memory but we just
we just don't know
so yeah for the same reason that i think
the peas priming effects during general
anesthesia
reflect
implicit perception
these attacks if you could get them
would also
reflect implicit perception
member right
it's just me
bus not just me
allah but
we'd like to think of exported implicit
memory
as referring to cases where something
was consciously perceived and then
subsequently lost a conscious
recollection
there's no explicit memory for something
that was explicitly proceed
and for our friends the show and
if you could get it
in the case of sleep
as far as we know subjects are just
not consciously aware of what's going on
in the
in the outside world
anther at that point on
what what what unconscious perception
anything else about any of this
there are things that people can do
there're still some mysteries to be
solved in some questions to be answered
on both though
about some of these phenomenal
let's spend a little bit of time talking
about
dreaming is clearly something that
occurs while were asleep
all but the real interesting thing about
dot what one of the really interesting
things about dot that uh... about
dreaming
is that we know from studies of the
sleep cycle
that we have four or five dreams night
on average because we go through four or
five cycles of sleep you know
average eight-hour audited it hours of
sleep
and we know that when you awaken
somebody out of stage where and you're
very likely to get
on dream reports so that shit
run-up percentages
and you can see the people have please
for five dreams and a good night's sleep
we remember at does
only one of those remembers a dream from
last night
carried out of gay not believe that they
are not to remember is more than one
dream from last night
there you go very web that very smooth
very seldom
so what is it that could that dalton
that determines palm
all of the bevery on memory for creams
off
we don't know that
but what we know is that there is at
least one
on
when people waken
or go to our awakened out around the
question usually is
what was going on with you you know
where you do in anything door you having
a dream their various ways of asking the
question
and they say yesterday described their
dream or whatever
people rarely described to a dreams
in these
program awakening studies
now would maybe for reasons or show you
in a second that people rarely described
through dreams
because the active describing the first
three box the second one out of memory
all but uh...
as far as we know
the one of the general
ruled from here as you get one dream for
rent period
and there are studies that
correlate
the length of a person's dream report
with the length of time they spend of
around
and there's a positive correlation
so if you allow somebody to spend a lot
of time
in rent before you awaken them you get a
much longer much more extensive
all of the laws of the dream report
that if you waited owned immediately
the basically are the pace with the
default their but the point is if you
have more than one dream for around
the situation for memories even worse
because you've got lots of things that
are
brulee available for uh... for
recollection and you're still
remembering at best
only one
or of
we want to die
called how it is upto how does that
happen
okay so here's the problem
there's a high frequency of dreams on
stage ram go through four or five epics
of ramen night's sleep why do we
remember only of low want no
one dream
although
the general idea here is that we can
think about the dream as occurring
is something like
short term more primary or working
memory
and at that that's kind of the stage on
which the dream is up
is played out in
and if you awaken some or did the if you
awaken somebody
during rabah
well the dream isn't working memory
then they can just readout
for u does in the same way that if i
gave you a telephone number and you
won't bulb rehearsed at her work or
whatever
you could repeated back to me
and then what happens is that
all i have to do a good after the
reading period causes all
is over
the drillers over
so now what we want to know is
on what happens on the consolidation
or holders of the how does that
dream which is occurring
if you will on the stage of working
memory what happens to it permanently
do we get any kind of uh... would get
any kind of permanent and coding
one of these theories basically says
that
there's a lot of them a prominent they
re basically says that
there is no consolidation
of the dream
either your awakened up out of the dream
and do you remember
that dream
all for a while
or nothing happened
nothing happens at all
and of course of the dreams not
palm stored in consolidated long-term
memory you're not going to be able to
remember in new york in the morning
the key here is
most people when they wake up
they wake up on her brother
when you're when you're in stage ram
you're dreaming
you'll wake up on your dream and that's
the dream you remember basically you
remember the the up
the last dream
video
of the night
alm
but there are a difficult one studies of
this the film
may seem held few studies have been done
on memory
for dreams
all
though if you think about it for a
second it's listed so i think the kind
of difficult thing to study
what's the
bait what's the from one thing you've
got a
if you're going to study memory for
anything
yeah i got i know what the person skills
to remember right
and we have no way of knowing what
another person drains that give pat
absolutely no way of knowing
whether a dream record is correct or not
if somebody wakes me up and said more
but what were you thinking about it
there's
dragons riding bicycles argues that no
position to say no we weren't
or that's wrong
or or or or the or or or anything like
that
soul really all we can do
is palm but they did a study what people
remembering take that'd face value
and frankly that makes a lot of memory
psychologists on
memory psychologist uh... nervous
but here's a very nice study by david
cohen at the university of texas
in which he although
uh... in which he ought to applaud the
surveyed college students
and dog uh... identified uh... college
students
who remember to dream in the morning the
spontaneous memory for a dream
and those who did not remember
law young dream
brought them into a blood sample of each
of these into the laboratory
and uh... just let them sleep for a
night
and they discovered that subjects to
remember dream of the morning are much
more likely to awaken i would have stage
ram
subjects who do not remember dream in
the morning
are much more likely to awakened out of
stage
so again this is consistent with this
idea
the that that that dreams are kind of
played out in something like working
memory or short term memory
and all that you will make them up it
would be beaten
if you awaken
while they're in short term memory
you can recall of just like you can
recall anything else that's in short
term memory
but they have fallen
he thought
the the dream is kind of got off that
stage
called
here's all
rome
here's another of uh... but very very
very similar study the cul winded
on he asked subjects when they woke up
in the morning
on to do one of two things either when
you wake up
don't do anything
just why they're in bed and think about
rather though that i think about your
dreams
all or he instructed subjects
as soon as they woke up
to all of them read the telephone and
dialed the phone dial the weather
service for a weather report
this is supposed to be at the
distracting test grade and we know
that any kind of distraction is going to
basically empty the contents of working
for all
for short term memory
and are what you've whether when he
showed very nicely
wasn't subjects were instructed to just
when they wake up just why they're in
think about your dream for a couple of
minutes don't do anything else told
make coffee don't watch television
whatever
they were much more likely
to recall a dream
palm
and all
the subjects
who won't be nearly got up distracted
themselves by alum
all built by the body are calling for
the weather report before writing down
their dream report are basically were
much more like this that you know i'm
sorry i don't remember a dream
on vol
this is a kind of finding that's
consistent
with the idea
that part of the dreams kind or played
out in short term memory
reason we don't remember our dreams
better than we do is that they're not
consolidated their not encoded into hall
into long-term memory now and then there
are a bunch of studies out like that
here is a very similar study done by
donald gooden often his colleagues they
had thought
customers state university of new york
downstate medical center melvin in
brooklyn
are here
what are the good enough did was to
awaken subjects during stage
all and then home
on asked them or the at best and whether
they had to do it one hundred report or
not
palm
and uh... this is what he called online
called online recalled his immediately
after awakening
but what he did he had a couple of
different conditions here
in one art that you've been in one
condition
the subjects were just allowed to uh...
to uh... don't go to sleep
bound to go back to sleep and another
condition
they were on gauged in some kind of task
that kept them awake
all for a little while
and what he found was
if you are all kipah i'd with so if you
are kept awake for a little while after
you gave your dream report
you were much more likely to remember it
in the morning
than if you went right back to sleep
so this so-called i'd actually thought
that the presumably date subject kind of
think about their dreams
and consciously encode them in long-term
memory
before they went back to sleep
the idea here is the reason we don't
remember dreams in the morning
better than we do
is that were not able to engage in the
effort full
conscious
deliberately activity
that's required in order to encode
dreams in long-term memory
the reason why we remember the one read
dreamer remember if we remember that
remodel
home because we want to do would be
wrong have to depend on long-term memory
dog just read it right out of short term
were all we're working memory so that's
the general idea
are behind that
i would not be doing my job
uncomfortable the suggestion stuff
on here
all i would not be doing my job if i did
not say a couple of things about
the focal pack division synthesis theory
of dreams which is the prevailing theory
why we dream
what the nature of dreaming is and why
redial wat wat why we don't all over
remember alone
dreams any better than we do
beyond the dat theory of dreams began as
what's known as the activation synthesis
of theory of dreams proposed by uh...
alan hobson
and robert carly
who were working at the moment at
harvard
and the general idea behind the
activation synthesis theory was that
to remain as a product isn't incidental
byproduct ald cortical activation
that occurs regularly
during tonight
as a consequence
of the sleep cycle
remember that when you're in stage one
stage one or stage rem sleep
the g_ is showing signs of twelve quite
a bit of god cortical activity
and if you're in stages and ram
there's less cortical activity
and the idea here is
dreams of her home of that as a product
of this quarter collectivity
but what happens is
that this cortical activation just
activates random memory structures
palm the whatever what what whatever it
happens ticket
that's for the that becomes a dream
image
and that what happens is that there is
that in some sense the sister of this
imagery
into something like a coherent
also song
form of the debate activations happens
to activated network corresponding to a
dragon
and a network corresponding to a bicycle
you had this dream about drive-ins
riding bicycles down the shahms it was a
or whatever
pad that's your brain
uh... that space with the idea and the
panda though that the point of the art
activation synthesis on along with that
theory
be classified these dreams just wrap
with represent the active the accidental
activation ald plug dural networks got a
corresponding to various mental contents
these dreams are essentially law are
essentially means
be hobson mcaro we all
no activation synthesis model has been
refined more recently by hobson himself
into what's known as the aim of model
and again if you're going to see you see
a lot of references to this
all in the literature
which basically says
that there are all
three different kinds of prophecies
that go on and consciousness
these are implemented both at the
psychological level of analysis and the
physiological all level of law
of analysis
first is
what hobson calls cortical activation
which is a product of activity in the
rita killer activating system
or and can be measured by the of the the
rate of which neurons require reading in
the best in the in the uh... brainstem
and the psychological consequence of
this or the psychological carload of
this
is some kind of increased
or mortonest
then
the second part of the physiological
level
has to do with what he calls input
output dating agencies activation gives
you the ending a model
input-output dating
gives you
the find
all part of the model who has to do with
has been with input
it said look what happens in sleep
is that these ponting structures in the
brain stem basically shot down
and by virtue of shutting down
the cerebral cortex doesn't get any
input from the external world
because all those afferent neurons are
passing through the ponds
moreover whatever's going on in your
head
doesn't get translated into overt
behavior
because all those more signals have to
pass through the pollens in order to
in order
get out of the skeletal o musculature
so what happens now is that
walden that women would be sensory motor
channels or blocked off
you're just kind of left with your
internal world whatever your cerebral
cortex is generating
as above at the product by product of
the souls of those cortical activation
and then the bien part would be a model
all reflects on modulation or what
hobson calls girl modular to rebalance
he says again there these two
biggs systems in the brain there's not
the whole system of m interject neurons
to work on nor epitaph brennan serotonin
and then there is a system of
colin urgent neurons to work basically
on uh... on
uh... about under seal choline
and they modulate
all your you word your levels called for
although of attentiveness
and so what happens during the night
tough position of the brain with respect
to these three dimensions of
consciousness
physiological dimensions as well as
psychological dimensions
progressively ships
you've got what hobson calls
the jama state-space
of the portrays consciousness
all the represents consciousness in
basically a three-dimensional model
where you've got activation
going from low to high
and you've got
the source of inputs
the internal just from your
brain
or external from the world outside
and then
modulation where there's good got high
levels so i'll bomb nor up annapurna
serotonin
or high levels
volvo
of the civil court
high levels of co of colin urging or an
energetic
all of the modulation
and so he argues
in the wake in st
you've got higher levels of activation
you've got
high levels of attentiveness because
they've got high levels of twelve go the
co liturgical a activity and your
processing information
inputs and outputs with respect to the
external environment
so waking life is
apa nak order
okay that's that that's what we can
consciousness all
is supposed to be all about
and then as you fall asleep
what happens is that all of this
systematically changes
when you're in stage and around
diminished cortical activation
more of a balance between colin their
gic
and aman urge ic activity
and for that matter more of a balanced
between
external and and and internal or old
sources of input
stage and rent he considered he construe
zones
degrade the middle
and then when you cycle into stage ravin
you end up down in this corner of the q
higher levels of activation
all give shifted from high levels of co
undertook activity at the high levels of
an allergic activity you've cut out
external sources have been put your
rewind just on what's whatever's going
through all your head and that's where
you dream
but the reason you don't remember the
dream in the morning
is because
you've got these that this imbalance
that favors
all the diameter gic activity as opposed
to corner gic activity meaning
you're not paying attention to the dream
okay if you're not paying attention to
the dream
then you're not going to process that
you're not going to win coded
on you know
in memory
so what uh... what god loves a hobson's
dot of the suggests here
if you think about what the bob what the
nervous system is doing
during the course of the night sleep
you can explain both why did we dream
we dream because
harbury high st
cortical activation
but we're not getting any information
from the environment
and why we don't remember the morning
because all this but this neurological
asian basically has prevent has impaired
our
attentional processing
our ability to are to intentionally
uh... in code information and long-term
memory
so the dream is taking place if you will
and short term memory
but no further processing
all is going on that would that would
put it
long-term memory
very very provocative model
very although they're very very popular
with over with people
in part
because
it seems to achieve
what a lot of people have been looking
for in studies halt to all of the new
vivid stories of consciousness
which is a way to relate
what goes on in people's minds
with what goes on in people's brains
arm
this is essentially a neural scientific
model of consciousness
hobson promotes that on though
as such
and he argues that
during the night we just cycle
around
various kinds of states
palm
heavy dreams
when ran this position not having dreams
when or in this position and being
awakened able to remember that the dog
to attend to
and remember the things that go on in
the external world
or where no
when of
but were in this position
so again the a model ald
hard to do this something that you're
going to see a lot of attention because
of the warm water bro princes to in the
consciousness literature
hobson himself as has argued that it's
essentially a solution to the mind-body
problem
all because it shows correlations
between
going on in the body and what's going on
the line
i think that's probably or reach too far
to be honest with you
i think the mind-body problem probably
is going to be more complicated
them not to solve
but in any event it provides a very nice
way of understanding
what goes on all
what goes on and dreams
why we dream what we do
dreams mean
socially
no i think they're just
random accidental activations
all and why we don't remember them
better on
before
there are some issues
with the a model i don't want to pick
those up
uh... but i do want to pick those up at
this point
although i do want you to have some
some exposure to what this model
okay next week we'll turn our attention
from physiological alterations
consciousness
the psychological alterations of
and we'll look at
bloody dog
nature also hysteria
and hypnosis
thanks very much
have a good weekend