okay let's take up a couple in new
topics this week
last week
introduced a couple of
altered states of consciousness that
seem to be induced
psychologically that is by virtue of
suggestions or ideas or whatever
as opposed to being induced
physiologically by the administration of
one or another kind of uh...
controlled
one of continued that theme today
by talking about a bunch of states that
are related to
ships in the deployment of attention
as i indicated at the very beginning of
the class one of the
easiest ways fifteen percent colleges to
think about
consciousness this difficult out
consciousness in terms of attention
we've become conscious of something by
paying attention to it
when we pay attention to something
we become conscious while that if we're
not conscious of something we're engaged
in pre conscious or pre attentive
processing
equation
between consciousness and attention is
something the runs
very all strongly through
the entire a scientific literature
on unconsciousness
so what i want to talk about this week
are some states of altered consciousness
that seem to be that seem to come about
by virtue of one or another
or alteration unlocking the deployment
of attention
today i'm going to talk about a number
of everyday states
that is
states that are encountered it in the
ordinary course of everyday living
everyone of us in this room
experienced these kinds of states
also lists more than others
some of us right now
and then on wednesday i will talk about
and i don't like the term but had to
have some contrast between everyday with
with everyday what you might call exotic
states of consciousness their associated
with various meditative
traditions and uh... and disciplines
our scientific work
that has its origins in the home
he hugged eastern
or the religions
or hinduism
giving rise to the practice of yoga and
buddhism giving rise to the practice
exam
farm or not there yet
first let's talk about some of these
everyday states states that ordinary
people in the ordinary course of
everyday living
all have experienced
uh... from time to time
one of these has been most of commonly
study does the state known as absorption
all work doesn't work mostly by alcatel
again a psychologist at the university
of of uh...
of minnesota
who gave
absorption
kula state that the has a kind of weird
definition
cognitive restructuring of self and ego
boundaries by which he means you
perceive yourself you proceed
the distinction between yourself and
other raj x
that's what it needs or boundary is that
barrier
difference between me and u
or between you
and the rest of us
which takes place in a all under
circumstances a very narrowly focused
attention
on you've kind of
taken a spotlight and honed in on just
one aspect
all of the stimulus uh... obstacles
warming
and leading to
some kind of a departure from everyday
modes of thought
uh... that was
they didn't have to be there i'd suppose
all but uh... all adobe what what
elegant tried to do is to develop a
questionnaire
known as the absorption scale or the
telegram absorption scale
which would kind of which would assess
the degree to which people had these
kinds of experiences
in the ordinary course of everyday
living and he just sat down with one of
his evolved into graduate students
covert at consent
and they just had a party writing items
all dog the dog tried to goad trying to
capture these kinds of experiences
also
this is kind of a informal content
analysis will give you a better
idea of the contents of the scale off in
a moment
if you want to take the absorption skill
for yourself if you haven't done it
already
if you go to the lecture supplements
click on absorption
and just scroll down a little bit you'll
find a link to the absorption scale
on which you can print out in
fill in for yourself
all that and then there's another link
to page that'll tell you how to score it
and find out whether your high remedial
more loyal
in absorption
based on the normative all-new
for the study of the absorption scale
on telugu and all the discovered
that the thirty four items of the
absorption scale
all kind of
while parceled themselves out into six
major factors
fine you can see with these novel or
likable right here
responsiveness to engage in stimuli
that is something really kind of
picks you up then
puts you in a different place all like
you can be deeply moved by us on the set
some of us would go off and we look at
the songs that we all serve all the ads
could be dark soon
home
and uh...
and other people just get fascinated by
the sunset of the changes of color of
the song and what what it does to the
clouds and
and all that kind of business use kept
kind of got wrapped up in it
and there are lots of items on the
absorption scale like this
cause that has to do with being absorbed
in this sense three are sensory
experience
painting
callers
almost anything
all
so just the usual is another common
aspect of absorption where there's a
kind of a what's known as a cross modal
experience you have
visual experiences that are stimulated
by auditory stimuli
or you have all
all factory experiences that are
stimulated by visual stimuli or whatever
here's our kind of
that an example of this soul music
reminds me of pictures or changing color
patterns
and of course musics of auditory
stimulus a doesn't have any changing
color patterns that at all
all of the most serious in his speech
paula alexander screen album
the great russian romantic
neil romantic composer
was himself this in a state
he had the idea that problem
that uh... different pitches
on the scale were associated with
different colors and in fact he invented
of color oregon
which when you press the key would play
a c
but i would also flawed although show
radio
know that uh... a swatch of the color
that per screen arbonne
was associated with each of these things
most people don't have that experience
but some people do
scrabb inhabited spades
all third factor enhance cognition
aiken somehow sense the president's
of another person before i actually see
or hear
on him or her
all bball had that kind of experience at
that one time or another you've got your
back to the door
nobody's said hello yet but all the
sudden it kind of sense that there's
somebody there
all some people have that allot more
than others
but it generally this enhance cognition
factor has to do
now what whether cognition is really
enhanced
like you get twenty extra points on your
right to test or something like that
but rather it's the experience
of enhanced cognition
the feeling or the belief
that you're seeing things that you that
in a way that you didn't see them before
that you also somehow
are having experiences that are
different from other people
on here's another one
oblivious mysore what all of the pelican
calls dissociated involvement
when watching a movie i may become so
involved
but i forget all about myself and my
surrounding in and experienced movie
physical real when i was taking part in
it
it's a disposed of experience because
your routine awareness of your immediate
surroundings
while you're engaged in this so-called
in this sort of the in this activity
lot of people have the support of the
kind of experience
alone when they're
what where they re gauged with media
the scale the absorption scare was
written in nineteen seventy four
i think the only video game around at
that point was pacman
alms and all of these days you can just
imagine
that there are people who get wrapped up
in video games of various kinds
hard on the plane on for hours and hours
and hours on end
nobody in this room of course
small blood
it can happen
then vivid reminiscences
sometimes i feel experience things as i
did when i was a child
kind of regressive experience where
your your past comes flooding back to
you
all in various ways and then finally
enhanced awareness things the might seem
meaningless to others
often makes sense to me
again
this idea that somehow your cognition
has been
uh... has been altered
uh... you know in various ways
we now know based on various kinds of
psychometric studies
absorption as a trade a personality that
is is that characteristic weight that
some people are pink
that's different
quantitatively from the way other people
kind of thing has its place in what's
known as the big five structural
personality
for those of you who have taken a
personality course or maybe some
versions of
of intro you know the personalities
psychologists have now taken all the dot
down now argue with her
thanks we come to a consensus
that the major individual differences in
personality can be summarized
five principal dimensions
barrada schism extra version agreeable
miss conscientious
and what's called openness to experience
murata schism is just what it sounds
like a high degrees of anxiety worry
depression all sorts of other kind of
dysphoric or experiences
extra version has to do with the
outgoing an adventuresome
agreeable this has to do with being a
nice person
on conscientious this has to do with the
reliable
and openness has to do with
opened its that has to be other ed has
to do with a person's
willingness to entertain new fox
willingness to try new things
willingness to have various kinds of
experiences
and on something like the any you know
eroticism extra virgin openness
all of the n_ deal personality of a jury
which is the standard
instrument for off for measuring the use
of the these traits
openness to experience is measured in
terms of six different facets
what many of which
look like the kinds of items that are on
the absorption scale your richness of
your fantasy life you have the same old
tennessee wilbur and over and over again
the same way
or do you have these really great
fantasies where they're at the
characters change of the times change
and all of that
aesthetic sensitivity
pretty but pretty self-explanatory
awareness a bitter feelings or u_n_
touch with your with uh... with uh...
with your interior wife
alm people who are audience openers have
all
seem to have a need for a high degrees
of variety and actions
they're very curious
on intellectually that want to know
about lots of things whether it's
old quantum mechanics or just collier
tv remote works
and also interestingly
on these individuals tend to have a
liberal value systems
which doesn't mean that they always vote
democratic or something like that
on what it means is that you need to
spend that kind of be hauled to have
more of all live about live attitude on
towards uh...
towards other people and uh... and other
ideas
although absorption
dont takes its place in the big five
structure personality
by virtue of its oil
of its relationship to this
fifth dimension
this dimension global of openness
here's a little study for my laboratory
long ago
in which we looked at the correlation
between absorption and hypnotize ability
telegram was actually hypnosis
researcher although you know the low but
it wasn't uh... developing personality
questionnaires
and donald
he'd old the original idea behind the
absorption questionnaire
was a one thing we know is that people
who are highly responsive to hip
youngsters are also prone to have
hypnotic like experiences
outside
we have not a context
they tend to get
their leaders states for their
attentions
focused on one thing to the exclusion of
other things on
imaginative experiences to become real
for them
and art elegant was actually trying to
write our personality questionnaire
paper and pencil questionnaire
that would help predict people's alone
um... level of hypnotized only
and it does
kind up stored up
that's a significant correlation
but it's not the kind of correlation
that allows you to predict in advance
whether somebody's going to be kept the
price of oil or not
the only way to find out whether
somebody's hypnotize ipl
is to try to get no's'
and c at about that it works
scores on the telus absorption scale
correlate
high teens low twenty's
with hypnotize ability
and so do scales all although openness
but it turns out there is some big
differences
there are these three facets of openness
fantasy of fantasy is statics and
feelings
that are
reasonably modestly correlated with the
advisability but there are other facets
of it all go out on both of those palm
all floodwall
on me for a variety of actions on
openness to other ideas and liberal
valuable
they're not related to the prize ability
uh...
really very much at all
which suggests
that in fact
there are two
different waives all be open again this
is work for my laboratory
we distinguish between
on three different kinds of openness won
the recall absorption which is all about
absorption
and this fantasy anesthetic sensitivity
and feelings facets
or or both of us would for instance if
measured
uh... traditionally
and then there is so see a political
liberalism
and there is what you might call
intellect ins
intellect in this is an old termined
personality psychology
and it has to do with
appearing this march
being smart
just looking smart
and the hall of the holdout uh...
getting other people the impression
that you're smart
ald
these absorption
socio political liberalism and intellect
ads are all part of this open this
package but they're really quite
different kinds of things
an absorption is really all the
correlated with the hubble
windfall fantasy ascetic sensitivity
and uh... and feelings
mean you can be a right wing person and
still be hired absorption you can be not
all that curious and still be absorbed
by
what it is that you're curious about
palm and uh... and so on
now absorption is often measured by this
absorption questionnaire that's how we
do it but at the pinnacle isn't whether
context as well
and this is the kind of experience for
all of you of or at least many of you or
will
the love had
this is work buyer i'm sure
on wave run short of the university of
new hampshire
on what he called the book reading
fantasy
and shore observed
that's fun people when they were a
dangerous read for the content of the
book you know and they could re warren
peace or something like that they could
tell you
it's about war
it's about russia
uh... which is what tolstoy said it was
about
palm uh...
or they will really get wrapped up in
their reading their turning pages madly
trying to get to the end of the chapter
they don't stop at the end of the
chapter that go onto the next tractor
pretty soon they've lost the whole day
the book is overall band and all that
wonderful experience when you have it
all
on and also these are people get deeply
involved in the imaginative experiences
stimulated by the book
so that what they're reading in the book
becomes real to them as realistic they
were actually have been the of the um...
know that uh... the experience itself
paul
jason boren's being chased down the
streets of paris and you feel like
you're jason bourne being chased down
on the streets of paris
the fantasy elicited by the book reading
the active book reading is very
compelling
visual experiences you are not just
reading words on the page
all you have a novel all sorts of the
old experiences and caller in three
dimensions in europe
smelling things that we're hearing
things that all of that
all at the same time
all going to be you get so involved in
the book
that you've become oblivious to what's
going on outside your roommate may come
in and star rummaging through
on spirit or per day
para socks or
letter yet rummaging through your bureau
drawer for a pair of socks
already just don't
pick up on this on at all
alm
moreover
people are
within the book reading fantasy
people already aware that they are
actively constructing this experience
for themselves aren't so i'm reading all
of the board identity and i'm going up
that never pretend i'm jason bourne
running down the streets of paris
they just do it
happens to them
on you get wrapped up in this thing
now that doesn't mean that
you know when the fire alarm goes off
they're not going to respond they do
though they might respond kind of slowly
like a little
what's going on
that's the kind of bog of of experience
that is really kind of captures
the essential phenomenology
of these absorption states that poem
that uh...
how it was trying to we're trying to
talk about and this is an experience a
lots of people have i dare say everybody
in this room has had this experience one
time or another
but unfortunately it's one that's not
been studied very much
and equally unfortunately it's one
that's not been studied very much by
i'll buy you know uh...
investigators
who study reedy
they're interested how people decode
words and how they understand text and
all of that
but there's been a very very little
uh... attention given
the subjective experience of reading
all and to
i'll be you know that the way in which
people get involved
all one person whose job it was a bit
counter example of this is
rabbi arabic turn alle south african
psychologist
who has actually argued
that certain forms of reading
what he calls the utica reading
playful
reading
archived and can it can actually involve
consciousness changes of various of our
times
and his wrote written wonderful book
called lost in a book
hog in which you details on these up
these experiences
where people are reading for pleasure
alva and they become absorbed in what
they're reading
and what they're reading creates a
subjective world for the person
that he or she law
that she uh... that he or she enters
and again
the idea here is
that'd liu dick reading playful reading
the reader becomes very very very
absorbed
and what's going on
what's going on
bulb
and bill
uh... it's it's not a
cycler criteria but one way to identify
buddha graders is to find people who
read a lot
especially real lot of fiction
it's very hard to do would agree dude
with an intro psych textbook
long photo
a little bit readers all the time to
read
very very very along
abundantly
you know a book a week uh...
now just because you read a book weight
doesn't mean you're alluded reader
book reviewers for newspapers and
magazines read a book a weak some of the
read a book and a
but they're reading for work they're not
reading for play
they're not getting absorbed necessarily
getting absorbed in the book
they're trying to figure out
what the books but what the book sold
out
so they can report on it
to their own readers
and you don't all of the josephine hell
guard delay josephine bogard on at
stanford
although also did some work on this and
suggested that there were uh... black
shoes several different types of what
schorr called the book reading fantasy
one where you are going to fight with
the characters
in the story
the other one where you don't know that
if i with the characters you don't think
you're scarlett o'hara something like
that
all but you are identified with the
with the emotions
that are being boldly presented
and dog and a very nice set of loan kind
of sending clinical studies
on hill guard who was both a
psychologist and a psychiatrist
home
who tried to identify some of the
characters characteristics of these
involved or breeders
and she made the point
that involved readers really have to
actively get into the reading
they don't they don't just get swept
away automatically
by reading
uh... it's it's it's kind of it
intentional activity
that takes on of life or a life of its
own
though
why canal
she pointed out
that this kind of
book reading fantasy is very time
limited
sometimes of the tube very often see
all of them people put in a book down
you know but they're very involved in at
the beverly come to a logical stopping
point that could put the book from side
and turn it unturned their attention of
whether tasks
if u bombs are ever watched a parent to
read a book to a child
you will often see this kind of thing
happening
where boat
the the proverbial redo the child in bed
at night
and the you'd be doing a chapter book
annulled get involved in the book to be
reading although all the way through
get to the end of a chapter
and then the parent says
okay that's the end of the chapter time
to turn out the lightened go to bed
on what that does is interestingly
that gives the child practicing going
into this state involvement and then
coming back out of it and then going
back to do it the next day and coming
back out of it
on that kind of experience
lays the foundation for a very very
active
imaginative involvements
all later in new york unit in the
child's life it's very good alum
very good people
child-rearing experience
here's another place where you can see
absorption
the so-called
method acting
on has logged on made famous by the
great russian of the theater director
constantine stanislawski
i will read this quote to you except a
highlight absorption
are the actors completely absorbed by
some profoundly moving objective so deep
rose is holding passionately into are
into effect into its execution
fallen
when a good example of method acting
got watch any marlon brando movie
especially it really marlon brando
movies streetcar named desire
on the waterfront something like that
brando was trained in this method
uh...
dot he was probly america's foremost
them
practitioner
okay and then returning to hell guard
for a second hilbert pointed simply
pointed out that there are lots of other
places ways in which people can be
actively involved in a magic of
experiences
totally absorbed
in these kinds of
non radical imagine experiences not just
reading but also draw baat
alone she made a distinction between
method acting and technical acting
difference between
marlon brando and dustin hoffman for
example
hoffman's a great actor actor but he's
not a method actor he's a technical
actor he knows how to turn the stuff on
and off
all
getting involved in various kinds of
sensory stimulation
all people get wrapped up in the sun
sets or bolna ranges or snow for or
whatever org
and basically
what the hell guard pointed out was that
there are these people
will get highly absorbent whatever it is
they're doing
and engage in what she called
by their mental
or hall or physical
physical space travel
one last speech or alba sorption that
gets a lot of attention these days
though not as much research as it does
talked
it is possible
is flow
this is work by argue carly chicks and
maja aali
that's how you pronounce that
all of the made what
for teachers
enormously more complicated by
publishing with his wife
right i got to say that word twice
arctic semi
okay odds vaguely variant
section is pretty
clearly area
alm and i think though that has been dug
up a lot of the paid a lot of attention
to a state that he calls
flow
a state in which people are so involved
in an activity that nothing else seems
to matter
where the experience itself was
enjoyable
people actually paid to do with the to
engage in this
or do it just for their shoes
just for sheer pleasure
of it
flow is that there is an experience a
gets a lot of attention these days
from so-called positive psychologists
we're always looking for people who are
that kind of get into the
flow of things
altered some of my has not
in of particularly
uh...
uh... active in trying to relate
flow to
cognitive psychology of attention
but it's very clear from his
descriptions
that what he means by
this is same
experience of
focused attention all of them complete
involvement in a task
to be exclusion
global oval
of everything else
alm
oh so here we go
focused in ordered stuff dot focused on
ordered state of conscious also and
focused on this end this is our number
one priority
all from my mind
fault the checks at mile high suggested
that
floor workers
all went to task calm
is all good didn't dissolve
appropriate
to whatever a person could do you can't
get into the
flow of the task if you find it really
difficult
by the same token he argues that you
can't really get it get into a test to
get find it too easy either
that there there is some kind of
optimum point there
that that balances the ease of
difficulty
or where for flow is more likely to
happen
so the argument would be
you might be able
how boat experience of
flow if you're a pretty good tetris
player
but maybe no matter how good you worried
checkers it's just not going to happen
although i'd known people who can really
get involved in checkers
really amazing
amazing experience
and the contents of conta consciousness
or conger with your goals
your goal is to play the game
your goal is to play the instrument or
to improvise or or whatever and you're
not thinking about other things and i
think it about
uh... hungry or how tired you are or off
what you have to do tomorrow
palm
and
again the idea here is that
what you what i want to called mental
energy or cognitive capacity or whatever
seems to
flow
that's where the experts can't sustain
effortlessly
whether it's truly effortless or not
is another matter
okay
in fact if you're focusing all your
attention on the task is probably not
effortless
in terms of not consuming cognitive
capacity but it's experienced as
effortless the consciousness
you don't have this awareness that
you're working uh... very hard
palm
and again
on the up the heart of the check some of
my argues that law
if you think about something else you
just can't get into the
flow of this activity you've got to be
able to devote forward your cognitive
resources
we saw on this thing
gypsum are high was himself a student to
all day perhaps man slow one of the
great paul dot the forerunners of the
modern positive all of the psychology of
movement
and in fact the cardiology concept of
flow
all comes out of matters most concept of
a preacher experience
again many of you had uh... introductory
psychology course
know that matt slow postulated a
hierarchy
motives
physiological needs like longer in first
down at the bottom
safety needs
home
warning this needs the need for other
people that fr
nism lovers and all of that
the steam needs up here at the idea that
you're competent in perceive yourself as
competent and
loans of the need to be perceived as
confident
and then ballclub appalled
basil argued that once again all those
needs met
and not until you get all those needs
met then you've got these distinctly
human on needs the argued
on what he called self actual is a
stands
for which he
kind of captured in those kind of uh...
oh
rock dramatic language
all whiteness richness that need for
truth and need for
of those for book for playfulness and
our
and for all the proper wholeness
and firm are slow
the attainment of all of these self
actual is a sudanese was marked by what
he called a peak experience
the experience or the object tends to be
seen as a whole
of complete unit
on detached from everything else
detached from possible usefulness uh...
and all of that
of the percept that's fully intended to
your absorbent at it's yugo transcending
you kind of
dissolve
the boundary between of
between self
and other on he become disoriented in
time and space on and there is kind of a
unity unconsciousness
by which maz lament
you perceive yourself as one
at the world
that's not easy to do
okay giving these cheap thud experiences
but matt slow argued that
what that
cheating
these kinds of people experience is
was a uh... was goal that we all had
but again there was a gold at all they
could be bad with the more blood being
safety and uh... and all that ten b
than the intended
how would you know what he had one or
not
basil had no idea
all public trying to do is to on id info
on the studies
was to try to thought that get an
assessment
of whether people in that it had never
had this or not
and he would simply ask people this
question
i'd like you to think of the most
wonderful experience or experiences in
your life
the happiest moments moments of ecstasy
rapture
algunas the maybe be in the world but
not
just being in long beach
qualms or been something hit by a book
or a painting or whatever
what he did was he asked people list
these
most people
relatively short list
and then on he tried to just get them to
describe
what that what that experience
old was like
and what he did what when he did that
he got
all reports that he characterized as
follows
in some reports the whole of the world
is seen as a unity
as a single rich white bent to the
so there's no baba re between self and
others
there's no separation between one object
in the environment and the other
called yet have to have been there
i guess uh... is part of the point here
alm
in other pic experiences
one small part of the world as if it
were for the moment all of the world
on so we get that goes on and talks
about the the cognitions that kinds of
perception experience is that
that occur
occurred during self actual inflation
that these are all various
facets of all the portion
this absurd that this the state
we're your attention is focused on
one thing
to the exclusion of everything else
that one thing
fills your consciousness fills your
awareness
and for called
for all of that had at least for the
time when you're absorbed
that's all you know
that's all you're experiencing
the rest of the world
is kind of
now let's look at the other side
for a moment
where your attention drifts off
from watcher supposed to be doing
you're not paying attention to the
things that are supposed to be of the
run right in front of you
budge or all of the book but uh... but
is the moved elsewhere
which we called a drink
all which is also gotten some study but
not
nearly a swatch into maisie medals
something that everybody experiences
everyday
okay maybe somebody would give right
here right now
hong and all the just don't throw we
just don't know very much about
uh... is kind of experiences
jerome singer then at the city
university of new york now would be a
real
i got interested in this is a clinical
psychologist
and worked on daydreaming with org
registered because john m traverses now
will levy
researcher
in the area of uh... of sleep cognition
and again watch like tell again and i
consume
they're just sat down one day mother sat
down for a couple of days
and tried to formulate
a questionnaire that was first
every album
magical aspect of daydreaming
that you could think of
how frequently you dream how frequently
daydream compared to make dreaming
how often you have problem solving
daydreams
how often you have guilty daydreams or
who were elected dreams or sexual d
dreams are any kinda daydream you can
imagine
on big od that they don't the plugged
into the song
that this questionnaire
so hugely long questionnaire
also long that
it's very difficult to get people
actually
birthday
are there's a short version
solve all cigarette that produces
daydreaming questionnaire colby
po imaginable proc
imaginable
imaginable across the seas inventory
uh... which is also available in the
lecture supplements on uh...
funds or chin
and if you want to fill that out and
kind of reflect on your daydreaming
on you can do that
as well
in the same way that tell again used
factor analytic techniques to try to
understand the basic dimensions on
daydreaming
singer adventure beside their colleagues
home http the same thing with their very
very very long imaginable
magical prophecies inventory
and they basically all found
after all of that work
all you could measure people's
daydreaming
part of the activity
on a scale that had basically three
dimensions
the degree of positive ur constructive
daydreaming
if you say on had a really good idea
once in a day dream more almighty
bookman my fantasies provide me with
with with
pleasant thoughts
second a dimension of guilt
and fear of failure
on daydreams
where
in my fantasies of friend discovered
five lauded
or imagine myself
those log
so some people have a lot of those they
dreams
all up and then finally
there was a dimension
poor attentional control
you're not necessarily have been
positive daydreams are not destroyed
negative david here just having a lot of
difficulty focusing your attention on
whatever it is you're supposed to be
paying attention to
i'm the kind of person who fought for
wonder
and i find that i huh
lose more all that was interesting
things that i'm trying to work on
sorry for that
of
in any event
these of course art more
clinical personality aspects of
daydreaming
what's happened in the more recent
literature
is that people have
they'll have begun to focus on
daydreaming as an infant from
poor attentional control
in absorption
fixed your attention on one object
still consciousness without
with poor attentional control
and in daydreaming
your thoughts are moving off
or what you're supposed to be doing
again it is in that sense
an altered state
of consciousness
alm
and just kind of show you that the big
removes or if you're a somewhat
different
here are some correlation to fit the
puja billy
better correlation between hypnotized
glued absorption in this particular
study
but the correlations whipsawed
daydreaming
not so great
bulb sold reserve these are different
kinds of scales
how can you study this experimentally
well john enter busted and early study
which is kind of served as a model for
subsequent research on the hot day
dreaming
he put subjects in a uh... an evangelist
task
extended over a very long period of time
two hours
the subjects only task was to press a
button
or whenever
while he or she heard a particular tone
atone all of a particular
pitch
and just to kind of keep everybody awake
for two hours and make the cuts will
build more interesting
he gave them a monetary incentive every
time they were right
home every time there was a hit
that is not a false alarm
on they got uh...
they got four months of money
and in the experiment what activist did
was to very
the information though that is a very
that the the difficulty of the past
on on some conditions dog very the rate
of presentation one tone every five
seconds one point everyone second one
went on every half a second
as you can imagine when those tones are
coming at you with every
drug twice a second
that's very difficult
and then palm
in another fault within another
manipulation
he buried the number of tones that were
presented to people
single tone
three tone two tones are three tones as
you can imagine
if somebody's presenting you
three tones very quickly
okay very rapid rate
that's very hard to detect it's harder
to detect of the uh...
the target drone
at the same time
every fifteen seconds to this expert
brief if
dean seconds for two
hours
on d_-day subplots and point
and what you prob is that what do you
think about right now
and of course the correct answer s i'm
talking about your damn tones
all but in fact what would happen
is this what is one thing about my
girlfriend or a headless terrible
telephone conversation with my mother
last night or
i didn't think about
vacation in aruba or whatever it is
what are not
psychologists have a wonderful
pension for this
for coming up with little acronyms
task unrelated intrusive
plots
uh... that's what did they dream is that
that task on a related intrusive all
thought
and he tried to measure the occurrence
of these two words
all as a function almost as a function
of information load
and you can get it here's the load
one three or five
stimuli being presented
add a low medium or high rate
of uh... of presentation
and what you can see here is that
when you increase the load
on the subject
the frequency of daydreams
tends to
when you've got
excess
cognitive capacity
one tone coming at you every five
seconds that's all a lot of time to
think about a rule in your girlfriend
and your mother
all and that's what people do
they tend to drift off to get abs on
uh... and spend time
talking about
that thinking about other kinds of
things
more recently called part of the uh...
set of investigators
have bought them expanded this concept
of tulips
past for related intrusive of fort
uh... into a kind of a home
to buy two of the home of the four-fold
table here where they classify people's
thoughts in terms of their task
relatedness
and if there's stimulus dependency
and they find here
that there are
two different this lead to different
kinds of tulips
they're ones that are stimulated by the
stimulus itself but kinda takes you
offer another direction
and then there is mine won't mind
wondering uh... we're daydreams of uh...
uh... come the classic example
of the past unrelated
intrusive intrusive floor
plone
donald broadband this is the same
broadbent too is that attention their
many many many weeks ago
for first cognitive model
osvaldo dot short term memory has gotten
involved in this all by developing a
cognitive failures questionnaire
so olympian kind of assess
occurrences of daydreaming and want mine
one million people give forget people's
names
you find yourself only wondered whether
you've used the word correctly
defined did you find your project
on why you went from one part of a host
of the other
the search for answers a
some people have more often than others
home
and all again are kind of
uh... intended to measure kind of
disposition all
disposition aligned one
again we can bring these kinds of
experiences into wild
into the laboratory
jonathan schooler now with the
university of california santa barbara
has done a number of studies of what he
calls the zoning out
what technical term
zoning out are during the during reading
bring subjects in the laboratory
and ask them to read and attention
demanding tax
hold
textbook passage or some kind of heavy
uh... pros prose fiction
and then are using variance of ad
reverses although aldo
will probe technique
tries to pick up all instances all vo of
mind wandering
in this particular experiment
paws could quite interesting because he
asked subjects
to keep track
ob instances where their minds wandered
off the task
they're supposed to be redeemed reading
this tasks though that this text
silently
on their thinking about their
girlfriends of their mothers in aruba
on instead
all those are
self
instances of mind wandering the subject
is disposed to click off
key when they
that their minds wondering
all and then
there were older
probe caught
uh... instances where poem
preschooler would
uh...
bring a balance eight what do you think
about right now we are paying attention
to text me thinking about something else
and what he discovered here
uh... interestingly
was that subjects were often on aware
that their minds had wandered away from
the tax
uh... when the when the probe came
through was only at that point that they
realized
i've been thinking about my mother on a
rumor
or something like that
instead of thinking about the tax
palm
so what dole what job
what the scoreboard
one to put one of the park to point out
here was that
even when we're daydreaming
were not always aware
that we're daydreaming
unless our intention is brought to it
which is if you think about it for a
second kinda paradoxical yet
yeah well what what's course trying to
get out here think
is that there's a difference between
blanking out
which is kind of the implication of zoe
knows
beneath it
uh... lol
on power and the kind of letting your
mind wander onto something else
and interestingly i mean here's what he
compares what defines defines as over
and over and over again said it's it's
really
that's not what you'd expect
december's probe and say what it comes
from a think about
i was thinking about my mother on a roof
and this is that
and these are the actually ask the
question
were you aware that you were thinking
this before right
sent the probit
and subjects would blow very frequently
say
geez you know i wasn't
and just once in the wherein he contest
their memory for the tax they can see
that there's been a lapse in attention
to the text we know that there
wind was
was directed elsewhere
they just don't seem to realize what was
going to the flight in a couple of
minutes funnel
do it here instead
it's on the basis of that kind of
finding
that all of the bed schooler blasted the
distinguished between two kinds the
consciousness
one which you called basic consciousness
which is
kind of what's goin for your mind at the
moment
and that the other what he what he wants
to call
met up
consciousness
this is going to be tricky
your awareness of what's going on
through through your mind at the moment
and so there's a difference between
you having thoughts about
your mother on a rule book
realizing
where your awareness that those thoughts
of what our what was going through your
mind
so i can track the fall
schooler s
recently proposed uh... kind of
three-level
classification of conscious experience
where there's what he called basic
consciousness
and for him
basic are just as simply as mental
activity of any kind
also whatever your per cbm whatever
you're feeling or or or whatever
and then there's what he calls me
meta consciousness
which but by which he means
a person's reflective awareness the
person's work fault
i'm thinking about
or i'm thinking about my mother runner
ruble run thinking about my mother with
my girlfriend or cold war
whatever
which is this is not the same thing as
thinking these thoughts
it's being aware that you're thinking of
them you're thinking about thinking
which is why you calls it
medic consciousness
and then this third level
which he thinks is essentially
unconscious
withered he says there's a kind of
tacit monitoring that goes on
there's the system
that checks consciousness
palm and uh... uh... and uh...
identifies when you're kind of gone off
task
in any event will go back to the swot
path of for a second on what's
interesting i think about schoolers work
missus other guide the so-called uh...
british psychologist jonathan smallwood
is doing the same kind of work
daydreaming is not just a matter of
zoning out it's not
then the technical term
it's not just a matter of your attention
lapsing then you're not paying attention
onto anything
he says what's happening in
daydreaming
or what he prefers to call mind
wandering
your attention
is being paid to something
being bitten
decoupled or dissociated all from
appropriate whatever it is you're
supposed to have
it's not that you're not paying
attention
you are paying attention
you're just paying attention to
something you're not supposed to be
paying attention to at the time
fourth-year your
donna attentional control
has shifted
from the primary task
to what he calls personal goals
and what's interesting about this is
palm wherein you daydream
you can show that they dreaming consumes
cognitive capacity because the berry act
of danger imeem
on interfere
with ongoing cognitive processing
you'll make errors you'll have slower
reaction times they'll have all sorts of
things
so daydreaming itself is although it is
something that will consume attentional
resources
on and another fighting all of them from
this literature that's quite interesting
dub better you'll get
at the primary task
though more likely you are to daydream
during that primary task
why is that
because
if you get better at task it's becoming
more automata you are not devote you're
not you don't have to devote your full
attention resources to
plane tetris or playing checkers
whatever that you're doing
you're just working on automatic pilot
that frees up a lot of cognitive
resources those cognitive resources they
don't just sit there empty
you know like a bullet wound that hasn't
been inflated or something like that
their devoted to dogwood two-year-old
pure daydreams
daydreaming can be
from go from schoolers point of view
anyway
daydreaming ten b
unconscious
in the sense
people often don't realize
that they're daydreaming
that their attention
has shifted
the ongoing task
for their personal goals
bulb
on there's no conscious awareness of the
daydream itself
those i think are pretty provocative
ideas the idea that you're
conduct not be aware of what you're
thinking about
all but we've seen him so that in the
past
or when we've looked at things like
implicit perception of implicit memory
implicit flawed
so it's not pearly
beyond that
bones possibility
also use
only go okay
he argues because again he observes that
when he sense in this probe
and for those
what do you think you are right now so i
was thinking about my mother
that next question is
what were you aware at the time the
probe occurred that you were thinking
about your mother
and subjects will sometimes answered no
quite interesting
in any event
the point of this is that here in the
ordinary course of everyday living
or experiences that everybody has
experiences of absorption experiences or
flow
experiences of getting swept away by
books and movies are all sorts of things
one good getting swept away by our
daydreams
and we have
almost no experimental literature
on any of its
that's a shame
all and so on that next time i'm going
to talk about some of these exotic
experiences
on mats
that there'd be very sexy studies about
his end monks meditating mood electrodes
on their heads and all of that
but there's a lot
of the same kind of
shift unconsciousness that occurs in the
ordinary course of everyday living
and that deserves experimental
exploration
thanks we'll see you on wednesday