okay let's pick up where we left off
last time
just to review from
last
from last lecture
general anesthesia looks like a loss of
consciousness and it is a loss of
consciousness
adequately anaesthetized patients is not
aware of what's going on with the
surgery or anyplace else
on not aware of this home
forty five
operating team is saying or any of that
nevertheless it turns out that at least
under some circumstances adequately
anaesthetized patients can display
implicit memory forum vents that
occurred during the
during the surgery
and we know that for experiments in
which
also addicts are played things like
words or music or whatever
and then they're given the implicit
memory tests mitterrand
and all
more often than you'd expect
all they do show home
they do show to show some spirit priming
despite the fact that body definition
adequately anaesthetized patients
explosive memory
for all further medical procedures
and this is now been confirmed on board
and a bunch of different ways i don't
want to go back to that home today
except to say that
from my point of view
what we've seen our tests of implicit
memory for surgical of ends
but seems to me that what we're really
seeing here is implicit memory as
evidence for implicit perception
remember hide distinguish between
implicit memory where the person has
conscious awareness of the event that
that at the time it occurred
but memory for that event has been lost
the conscious recollection
so priming affects custard evidence for
implicit memory
but in this case
you've got
ald no conscious perception of the
events at the time that they occurred at
least as far as we can tell but you've
still got psalm are spared priming and
so what we're really looking at here
is evidence of implicit
perception
now why wont to shift now to arm
went to work on the bone problems of
karma
physicians often refer to general
anesthesia as a controlled coma
put the patient into a coma you do the
procedure you bring the patient out of
on
all of the coma and that's not a bad
analogy
what would really like to do though
is to see
what kind of all the more what happens
to consciousness
in cases of
uncontrolled coma that is the medical
syndrome where by virtue of some sort of
brain damage
the person loses
palm of them loses consciousness
either for an extended period of time
days weeks
ones years hall or
for that matter on the permanently
let's first a little medical terminology
to distinguish between all three quite
different to poland and urological
syndromes
first concussion
all which solid
refers in the medical terminology simply
to a temporary disturbance of
consciousness
it's the kind of thing the results
typically from what's known as a closed
head injury
if u samak your called near
your head on the out of the wind chill
of your car during automobile accident
or you get that long to get from
clustering football or soccer practice
or whatever
that's what happens
there's a temporary disturbance of
consciousness
not necessarily a loss of consciousness
fall but though the condoms sentencing
law
into a young
we're in st
in carmel you have a chronic loss of
consciousness that is that's what's it
say they are
wass of consciousness from which the
person does not read carver
all in a over relatively quick period of
time
you know if you can lose consciousness
completely if you sustain
uh... serious enough welcome closed head
injury
but you will spontaneously come out of
it
called after a relatively brief period
of time
but in carmel abut which a lot more to
say in a minute
we've got a loss of consciousness
that extends for a long period of time
and the person can't be all rollins
doesn't respond at all
even ald when subjected to vigorous so
we're all very painful
on the stimuli
and all color is
then distinguished from afar third
category of neurological all the best
known as stupor
where again you've got a chronic loss of
consciousness
but despite this quantic loss of
the person will respond
to are vigorous or in pencil holder
regan painful stimuli
you can squeeze your arms squeezed her
hand this over that very very very hard
and they'll come out of a little bit as
soon as you let go they go back in
that would be that would be stupor
in coma you don't see anything like that
all at all
no it's not
it has some id has sold more all of the
similarities to but
christopher we're talking about
something that's very
transitory okay
will go on for minutes or maybe hours
but the vegetative status on that goes
on for days weeks months
years amid talk about that for a lot
in this lecture
just stood to let you know it's actually
possible to do experiments on these
things one of my favorite experiments
call in the uh...
neuropsychological literature
i'll buy yarnell and when she long time
ago
on the daily that expected that was
experienced by college football players
they manage to
get themselves seated on the bench
or with old
with various college football teams
and whenever one of the album
players would get gained on the field
that is
get rid of the head and scroll out lose
consciousness their ran out there
and as soon as the medical team had
taken a look at the uh... but that the
person
bait and the person to be going to arm
won't come out of oil
commodity xo home concussion
they did minister
little memory tests they'd save what was
the number of the guy who hit you
on what was a number of the play you
were running the power and and and all
of that the kind of track
all peoples long wallis and recovery
global of of memory
and in this case
uh... in uh... in in this particular
study there was really no loss of
consciousness of all
there was that some kind of a media
disorientation of something closer to
to stupor but what they did discover was
that within minutes on the concussion
all within minutes and kind of walking
off the field have been carried off the
field
these old these players tended to lose
memory
so the effects of a concussion are not
necessarilly
belong
visible home all of the immediately so
when your head on the head
okay
get up and start trying to think that
there's something right
are you really believe the they get
somebody to take a look at you
on many of your recovery of the famous
case of the tasha richardson
the uh... that the actress who was could
cost today
i skiing accident hit a tree or
something like remember exactly what it
was
and she was fine she walked away that
ought to provide thought she was fine
and the next day she was dead
pollen because structure had closed head
injury and all of the blood had built up
all got phone calls and pressure on the
brain
so whenever there is any kind of head
injury even if it's a closed head injury
know what
or no bleeding or whatever
you're really need to see somebody
along and get them get a value-added yet
well be entered for one thing
sometimes people don't even ask
and she wasn't disoriented what happened
when the tasha richardson case was that
there was there was a came a drama club
called of audio completing all inside
the door of of the brain
and that just kinda build the build-up
and created pressure on the brain from
the blood
if they had climate
they couldn't believe that and she'd be
alive today
all but uh... it just built up
too long too much
olwen and uh... uh...
the that the extra pressure on the brain
killed all the brain tissue and
it's it's serious business
okay let's look at look at called light
itself now
alm
here's the medical definition all the
medical diagnosis of caramel
loss of consciousness
indicated by you
failure of the patient to communicate
the lack of patient response to
stimulation
these are ordered to review say
something visual job shoulder something
or
on you make bob prick their skin with a
uh... for the pad or something but with
the pin
on no signs of a motion in common
vegetative functions are ok the patient
is breathing on his own
small and although the heart rate does
they did is doing what it's supposed to
be doing
you know i start closed permanently
closed
or and there is no evidence of the
patients can't do anything like
on normal sleep cycles
on that the way you know
the way we would that's a contrast with
the vegetative state which i'm going to
talk about on you know in a second
so that's what goes on in coma
clinically we evaluate all of the coal
according to our yard that the test
known as the glass gold colour scale
all which on who you evaluate the
person's best response to a command to
open your eyes
they open arise spontaneously that's
really good thing if they don't open
arise at all that's a bad thing
best verbal response u_s_ from a
question
if they can't answer that's a bad thing
all
if they can you estimate who they are
where they think they are what day it is
a thorough re-entered the time place in
person
that's a very good thing
and then there's the best motor response
not at all
which is classic case in coma
or that able to obey commands so they
won't burn valuation of person state of
consciousness clinically all of the goes
by this glasgow coma scale which is used
pretty much universally on now
and if you score alone
if you score all the less than eight on
the salt that on the scale
that's considered to be a severe
uh... severe komal
if you score higher
automat that's all that's relatively
bulge of the good thing
okay now we get to your vegetative state
all which is something that
when it happens typically follows the
cold war
person goes into a coma first
then begins to recover from the cold war
palm
usually within about a month or so
and what distinguishes though though
vegetative state from although from a
color
is that
the person appears to be awake
but still doesn't appear to have
consciousness
so what we mean is that
the persons are used
are open
palm and they open and close
o'connor diary all go according to
something that looks like the normal
sleep cycle
nevertheless despite the fact that the
patient's eyes are open
all
there's no communication
there may be some response to conclude
that the stimulation
if there's a very loud
very loud noise in the room the person
my shop startle reflex
or if it's a very very noxious cost plus
another sensory stimulus the person my
show a response to that but not very
much dot
you know that there hasn't been that
much work on the exactly what the sleep
cycles or like in you know
you know
vegetative state and i don't know why
that is 'cause that's an ideas thing to
do
all but the behaviorally what happens is
the person's eyes will be open for a
long time and then they'll
close
and then they'll open again for a long
time and then they'll close just kind of
like you would not eat or in class or
something like that just
on the bore the person seems to be going
all through some kind of regular
rhythmic
uh... cycle
all i'm sure there is such a study out
there cuz i can't imagine somebody
hasn't done it
but i'm not aware of it so i'm not going
to look that up
okay that's that that's a very very good
very very good question
alm
here is just a little grass
from uh... epidemiological study dawn
auto them some time ago that's
purvi represented what what what goes on
now
what we've got here it is on two-time
since
a severe head injury
and the percentage of patients who are
in the uh... uh...
uh... perks persistent vegetative state
all the if it's one month
ten percent
then there is some recovery
so that
for year after the head injury
all fewer than two percent all doll
headed your patients or renault more
persistent vegetative state
but if you think about how many such
people there are actually quite a bit
there
and fifteen twenty thousand
cause of such patients all around in a
medium in any given year
what goes on in the brain in colour and
persistent vegetative state
i think the best way to think about the
is that it's
a less severe komal
the damage the brain damage seized seems
to be pretty much the same
in phnom while
you know to be either case
well primary damages in the reticular
formation the sort of part of the brain
stem
projecting up into walk into the palace
on especially implicating these two
alba regions of the uh... within the
reticular formation
the curry ecuador pple gray right about
there
and the para break you'll
nucleus right about there
it's also possible to get called off
from diane c palak damage
damage to the fallacy for example
all but
one way or the other
on what's happening is
communication with the cerebral cortex
is basically on disrupted cause all such
communication
runs through the reticular formation
on and uh... and the foul so that's
basically what happens
bear
alm
and it's this kind of evidence that gave
rise to of the the idea of a reticular
activating system
that is with that one of the functions
of the reticular formation is to send a
message is off into the cortex that
keeps the cortex all white and alert
and sleep cycles
well-regulated
palm out here
all of the that this was first
discovered by a are two italian
investigators neurophysiology groups in
the group
on you know in nineteen forty nine
they dropped microelectrode stone into
the particular formation of caps
and what they discovered
all was that if u barbecue lesion the
reticular formation
you've got to palm belgium the cat space
we went to sleep
they've off the lobster into a comatose
state
home
and if you still a good
that same region
told barbour cats would stay awake
permanently that as soon as it turned
off the stimulation
the cats would go back to their normal
all sleep cycle
we now know again for work by a group c
in the boom
that all if you region
this area of the particular formation
so-called rostral area towards the front
towards the peace
on you guessed dog the animal falls
asleep
briefly lapses into a coma
if u lesion
rear area of the coral
haldol
ordered area towards betrayal
all what what you get is insomnia
instead
can dalton
it's this
there's a particular pattern in the g
that will talk about a little bit next
week
uh... that's a good sign of cortical
activation
but it all seems to come from here so if
you damage the reticular formation
what's going to happen is
that the cortex
fog doll that becomes inactive and
that's
essentially what you get
birthday ya
with a coma
i'm going to skip to main zero
all of members of a syndrome but we want
to talk about here a little bit going to
be relevant on later on
is a syndrome made famous by oliver
sacks in the movie or wake innings
wall and also by of them dot by some
other hong films and uh...
and books known as the locked in
syndrome
in cold blood and the persistent
vegetative state
it looks like the patient is unconscious
but in the lockton syndrome it's quite
clear
that the person is conscious
it's just that the person has lost the
ability to
all communicate
either vocally
or or through our motion
also there's quadriplegic problem
parapro what's this all before all of
the four limbs
orders walsons speech global more so
than the ability to filled vocalize of
all
but it's pretty clear
that these patients
compulsive into thin contrast to the
patient's uncoma and be vegetative state
all i have preserved oratorio plugs for
example the preserved auditory and
visual flight
you can play employees of the rule no
show a startle reflex
all you can
moved an object
in front of their eyes and and and and
they'll follow it
and they can communicate
or not vocally
all but they can communicate through i'd
movements you can say blink once for yes
and linked waits for no
and all that you do actually get them to
without answered questions
and there's also evidence for preserved
emotion
in these are these patients multiple on
the you know
on the face
something that you also don't see
in comatose patients
or in the persistent vegetative state
the damage and a locked in syndrome is
in a quite different area
on here
palm it so that they screen in the uk
anterior
on the portion of the of the brain stem
the ponds and so on
excluding
the reticular formation
the reticular formation is doing its job
to keep the cortex alert
there is damage audited elsewhere in the
alone
in the brain stem
the prevents the person from movie nor
communicating or anything cardinals like
that
except
by movements
now how does that work
here are the barometer twelve cranial
nerves almost all of the most and coming
out called beyond of of the brain stem
and what happens is you're getting
damage
here in the all the movies and stuff
along or the violent stuff along
events bearing
on the diane cephlon or the or or or the
cerebral cortex itself
and notice
that palm
if you didn't murder getting all the
soda damage right there
on that basically spares
rb ocular motor nerve so the person
couldn't move reserve arise
and also the truck clear
uh... nerve
on so
there's the damage right there
palm and
all of that damage
basically prevents or the person from
are moving or viewable world or
communicating
in the usual way
alm
there are some other terms about the
vegetative state that uh... that uh...
that go wonders why the debate about
this right now
palm about whether we should talk about
uh... persistent vegetative states of
all or just talk about vegetative states
because you
if you call something a persistent
vegetative state and people might not
try hard for
all three of the with haitian
but there is now quite a bit of interest
in the home not trying to
on set the stage for people to actually
be calmer instead of
vegetative out
on a uh...
on a hospital bed someplace
log home impatience with a vegetative
state get
acts of actual physical therapy to try
to
maintain some muscle tone
or there might be electrical stimulation
of the brain stem to see if you can get
them alert all sorts of things like that
on you can actually paid people to read
the newspaper
part the people in a vegetative state
just a kind of maintained uh... maintain
some kind of
and it does happen from time to time
that there are that there is recovering
all from oil from this condition here's
a famous case
on hearing on northern california
couple of years ago
where a woman had lapsed into a coma
appalled by what what one day of that
you gave birth she had a brain tumor she
gave birth
that you have brain tumor surgery lapsed
lot left into a coma
are in stating that cooperating here
all and then all of the basically agreed
on a year or so later
or began to show signs of of of recovery
on she ought could in iraq for their
child she could communicate by rolling
their eyes and so on
i don't know what happened to hurt there
hasn't been anything more in the news
uh... about over lately but you do see
these cases once in awhile
and all
there are limits
if the person has been in the persistent
vegetative state
the prospects for recovery or roughly
fifty fifty
uh... fifty fifty
but the longer the vegetative state is
gone on
six months to a year
one to three years
on the less likely any kind of recovery
is going to occur
snot zero
still about five percent
depending on what you mean by recovery
but at least they don't meet clinical
criteria
for the uh...
for the vegetative state
but again onto if you're in a coma
tonight's to refute nice of you come out
of it
fault of
within a month
otherwise you're very likely the lapse
into into the vegetative state
if you're in the vegetative state
it's really nice to get out of it
within about six months otherwise
the prospects for recovery are
relatively
relatively slim
famous case from a couple years ago most
of your probably remember this sub terri
shaw evolve all who in nineteen ninety
on had dot gov they've experienced
cardiac arrest when into a you know
went into a uh...
uh... komal and then into a vegetative
state
on eight years later her husband tried
to that ask the court to allow
url
like supports
uh... to be removed
or her parents said no no all that
lab that that would be albright
they thought that
behavior like this suggested that you
might be conscious she was in a
vegetative state
for eyes would open or once a while she
blog appeared to do something like smile
all four or or get a little bit weepy
alm there was out of the c_t_ scan or
performed in two thousand two that
suggests that there was really no
cortical tissue there at all that have
all atrophy
on
all fucked up all
all benchley although the husband
prevailed and although the wildlife
supports removed shy bulldog
and when the home and when she was
autopsied in two thousand five there was
a sensual you know on phone
no uh... them cortical tissue
there
miracle
this is a serious serious
problem for health policy
on what to do with these people how to
manage them how long to continue life
supports and all that there are no weezy
answers at all
all but called
as unpalatable trying to show your by
the end of the songs of them were by the
end of this lecture
new technologies suggests that
volvo fault
there's new technology the mike that i
should be helpful in resolving these
kinds of cases
or they might make
so uncertain
questions easier to have to answer
but they also might make certain
questions
to answer
people in comox and in the vegetarian
state appear to be on conscious whether
they're going through the normal
sleep-wake cycle is one thing
but they just don't seem to be
responsive to their own
to their environment at all
the question that that their rights as
naturally as
maybe there are some kind of unconscious
processing maybe there's something going
on there
but we've got the audits that that's
simply not too old not manifest in terms
of uh... in terms of conscious
processing
and over the last several years people
have tried various techniques to try to
figure out whether that's the case or
not
here's a pioneering study by a winter
extra who was that a graduate student of
the speech and hearing
all program i had a bunch of patients
who were in either an acute vegetative
state that is a bit of a vegetative
state for less than three months
or a persistent vegetative state have
been in it for more than a year
and some patients would actually been in
a vegetative state and recovered
and she did something very sad that very
simple really
which was to put them up to a little
psychophysiology kal monitoring device
monitoring what's known as the galvanic
skin potential
changes in the electrical properties of
the skin
and then present them with all
sound
to try to induce startle response
continue presenting that sounds to see a
phone there be an oriented responsible
bitch away shin
or she would when the patient eyes were
open she'd or hold up on pictures on
familiar and unfamiliar faces
to see if there be a differential
response onto those
and she'd also lol holed up on messages
are worth the risk has written command
finkel sad thought were thinkin angry
thought or whatever
i want to see hall what would uh...
what would happen
although this was a pioneering study she
really didn't get that much
palm
uh... here you've got of of the good
probably the simplest test of
consciousness
all of the magical
of on startle response these are control
patients who are not
argument and a vegetative state courts
they all gave the the startle response
our patients who were recovered
did give a startle response that's
almost definitional
budget all about sixty percent of the
patients in the acute
fall below that phase of the pledge it
it is they didn't give
or an acoustic startle response
will be about forty percent of the
chronicle phase so there was some kind
of
prob processing there
but remember that the acoustic startle
response is a reflex
okay and i don't have to have a lot of
consciousness
in order to argument in order to give
that is kind of the bare minimum
for diagnosis of any kind of information
processing
here is also what rick your test
our response to famous faces
control subjects
all the hard though the tend to give a
differential response to famous faces
picture world reagan or or or or
whatever
the acute and the chronic
uh... patience not too much
nor for that matter did the recovered
p_b_s_ stations
which suggests something about the
nature of this recovery
it's possible to come out of the
persistent vegetative state to be able
to interact with your world
it's not that does not mean that you've
returned to full function
these are patients who did not recognize
the picture of the president or pictures
of uh... of family members or or
whatever sold they worked
conscious
but they were by no means song
no means fully functioning
all what doctor extra did find however
was that
response to her test during the
persistent vegetative state didn't
predict
recovery
from the persistent vegetated state that
is
dot blot you go to the patient did show
the store response
they were much more likely to come
through to recover that if they didn't
if they didn't show
differential response to famous faces
they were much more likely to recover
than they did
so there are some implications here for
rehabilitation
you might think about doing some testing
like this with the patient
vegetative state
to try to are the figure out what kind
of off
what kind of treatment they should do
all of them that they should get
wilder in
that state
okay now just a complicate things
further
are just so you know what his car that
their colleagues all at in the uh...
the vivid in two thousand two
argued that
for some patients in the persistent
vegetative state
there is another evidence of conscious
mental activity
that we'd need a new label
for these patients we shouldn't call
them vegetative state patients
all instead
although they proposed
a new category
minimally conscious patience patience in
the minimally conscious state
where the patient's ought to be you get
this label
if you had
some partial response
or even inconsistent response
to the kinds of tests that i talked
about ulm before
all
all but
consistent and not a full response
necessarily custom you fully responded
consistently on these tests
there be no question about whether you
have a vegetative state are not newbies
are going to be classified as as
conscious
but these will attest that jesse no ald
all
law and the federal proposed
all for diagnosing this off
the state leading to real debate in the
medical literature
weather
patients who meet the criterion for the
minimally conscious state
should be
treated differently
in rehabilitation then patients volume
media in the dedicated state this is a
question basically a medical ethics and
social question of
all of of of how much money
but at least
onto c l_ began to all
began to argue
all that
by virtual gifts just kind of standard
clinical criteria we ought to be able to
distinguish
between patients who are clearly not
conscious of all like ever
even though they seem to be going to the
sleep-wake cycle and their vegetative
since we're okay
and patients who do seem to have a psalm
degree of consciousness
sometimes
the obvious thing to do
in these guarded in these cases
used to
look at brain
function
home more on more or less directly
church to remember looked at order nomic
nervous system activity
the a galvanic skin potential or
galvanic skin response as well
peripheral measure
palm of blood called
we now have the ability
on using things like
cat scans and all that related
potentials and even off
on m_r_i_ scans
to be able to look at the brain function
in these patients
pioneering study by ship of his
colleagues to patients
diagnosed with all of the the minimally
conscious state
okay
although and what they did was to
although called record the subjects of
brain responses various kinds of
the various kinds of stimuli
touching the hands
although telling them stories about
family all of the family events
all worried even laudatory or the
passages
and in one of these conditions have read
your gpa repetitive straight
and the other condition read 'em
backwards
okay played the tape backwards
of reverse speeches
speech
but it's all but it's on intelligible
and did they looked at all of the brain
responses that various areas
and one of the things they discovered
was that all when you stroked
the person is all about the cause of the
the these patients have to member was
just to patients
what you almost see is
activation
in what they call the anatomic hand area
that part aldy sonata sensory area
parietal lobe
of of the brain
that alone
is uh...
did who specialized for
smile tactile sensations the rights of
the brain
you can see these
and so that lights up
so at least there is some kind of
cortical processing
all of this particular part of this
particular stimulus
fault
they did the same kind of analysis
with verbal stimulation
and they found on that when they played
for these patients
you get activation and very few seria
all at least in one patient
one patient hard-fought unfortunetly
a lot of damage in the left temporal
lobe so
no question about
bradley's area working there
but the other patient didn't have left
uh... what atmosphere damage
and you can see
you can see it here
activation
in the uh... in the left temporal lobe
in response
speech quist
well once you start them once you get
the person this can you please real
basically can't control that
caller id
any longer
in the in this particular starting
what they did was to ardham the patients
were or wake
by the definition of having their eyes
open
all and they said well look this is all
we can do
at least they're awake not asleep
on and although they put them in
michigan this is pat scanning uh...
remember correctly
that's all you can do
really is just hope that you're going to
catch these people when they're at their
best and
these trials take a little while
counseling and some of their drifting in
and out they're gonna drifting
group
i'll show you all uh... all of them
for one more convincing study
in a moment but at least
all bob what was interesting about this
was that you could actually see
rain there is
responding
more or less differentially it wasn't
just that the whole brain became active
but when you touch the handy anatomic
head area became active when you read
people's speech
although you know about the cause speech
all of the speaker of the missionaries
karnicki seria
com contacted
here's a nice demonstration of that
all brain activity
in response to speech stimulation
an will be cut here are the two patients
palm and uh...
and controls
and what you can see of course is that
when you place
all of the speech forward
of course the controls or brain damage
there
showing a lot of activation and burn
ickies area
patients who
didn't have
did the damage in the left
for the hemispheric also showing quite a
bit of activity
patient one who did have a lot of damage
in the left hemispheres not showing much
activity
can do anything about that
all
fall and there's more activity in the
left
hemisphere
then in the right hemisphere
palm
and on
and when you do
when you are doing first speech
what's interesting
is that the control subjects are trying
to figure out what that's all about
right so they're speech centers are
getting off
forgetting activated
all but
not so much
with the you know
with the yield on that with the patient
so again
this is really more of an example of how
people tried to use brain damaging
two-track what's really going on into
they had to get evidence
offer patients
who can't communicate
through the usual kinds of channels some
idea about what's going on
uh... what's going on inside their heads
on here's another one paul that same
sort this is by parent and his
colleagues using about related
potentials
i talked about it dot new york he's a
little bit a little bit last time
remember that there are three components
to be your p
the first time milliseconds after a
stimulus reflecting brainstem activity
the next hundred milliseconds reflecting
subcortical activity and at all involved
not the for the route reflecting uh...
reflecting quarter collectivity
so what they did was they recorded
all of this issue force vpn these days
late
although the cortical all bad
performance reports to reflect
cognitive processing
of the stimulus on in various ways
and so what they did was i cooked up all
subjects to org
would it would be jerry
and recorded the ventilated potentials
when the subjects were presented with
their own the first name
as opposed to
somebody else's first name
all four groups of patients this is a
very substantial study
some patients and uh... persistent
vegetative state
some patients who have been diagnosed in
the minimally conscious state
a group of patients
we're clearly conscious
but had blocked in syndrome and a bunch
of neurologically intact on age-matched
controls and again what we're looking
for
is the fate of these
consul called cognitive event related
potentials
that occur in new york ny
out here passed about a hundred
milliseconds
there is the uh...
there's the ah...
data for that we've got controls
stations of the vegetative state
patients in the middle in conscious
state and patients in the walked in
central
and what you can see here's the first
negative component about a hundred
milliseconds of out
and the controls are giving you advice
are done by strong response or response
diminished they have been
vegetative
patience and
interestingly less so
the mentally conscious state patients
all
patients who were walked in argentina
and actually the least
glad to be at all
that's crazy
right and it's just a really wierd on
novelist solvable finding
because bio all accounts patience in the
walked in syndrome or conscience
so they should be showing
patterns volvo
above the brain activity that are
comparable
to those in the yard
salvage the controls
and they're just really not doing that
place where you see something really
nice is in this
this love focal p_-three component
p_-three
is a positive deflection occurring about
three hundred milliseconds out in the
event related potential
that's a response to
a distinctive or unexpected stimulus
so if you're trained to do play a true
dot patient or train of high pitch
stimuli and stick in a low pitch
stimulus
p p p p p movie
you're going to get a big peacefully
the controls
give me a big p_-three
the patients who are locked in on the
patients who are in the minimally
conscious state
give you are fairly substantial p_-three
the patients in the vegetative state
not so much
perrine yet all that the parents of the
colleagues focus mostly on this finding
to suggest that
yeah there is some differential
all of that there is some cognitive
activity in these patients
fall especially
the patients who are in the minimally
conscious state
as opposed to
uh... as opposed to the vegetative state
all but again
kind of an anomalous result
what's going on with these locked in
patients because they should have been
showing
all of p_-three response
comparable to that
of the controls
alright are same thing here here's
evidence of semantic processing
lots of evidence in the controls here in
the here the the data actually works out
the way it's supposed to work out
controls showing
lots of
p_-three evidence in the in new york ny
walked in patients
this bold
this is the magnitude of the people who
responds
this is just what it is shown
change in the future in response
all the controls did
all the locked in
all of the patients in the minimally
conscious state show the putri response
just was smaller
only about half of the patients in the
vegetative state
this uh... chill dispute response
so again what we're doing here is using
direct measures a brain activity federal
arguably related to the person's
consciously
they resolved to see whether the person
is conscious
uh... countries will
now param
add up and and and his colleagues
themselves admitted
that the best evidence for consciousness
in their study in patients with no about
that minimally conscious patients
came from the p three response
but even that is kind of end big u_s_
because it turns out
that you can get the p pre responsive
lots of other circumstances where the
persons not conscious of what's going on
for example
you can get the p three on even in
response to a subliminal
stimulus
okay so that's a stimulus by that by
definition the persons not aware of
if you get a piece three
to a subliminal stimulus
than the fact that you get a p three
in a patient
uh... in the minimally conscious state
necessarilly mean that they're conscious
of that stimulus
you can have apparently
psalm auditory processing some even
relatively complex processing
it being actually
without the person actually being
consciously aware
of what's going on
here it is all but burgers where this
art area on the part of the research is
going now
this is all of them
pioneering study by or one of his
colleagues out of bob dole journalism
big hole more research carpet on the
project on dot university of new van
and what this is a case study
twenty three-year-old woman who had
uh...
uh... serious serious brain injury
following automobile accident
she lapsed into the vegetative state she
was completely unresponsive
tour external stimuli
of for for five months
she got a diagnosis of vegetative state
precisely because
onto her sleep cycles seem to have been
preserved
and what though what all of his
colleagues dad was two wheel this woman
into laos f_m_ are alright
uh... did doable into a magnet
and look at her responses to various
kinds of stimuli
uh... sometimes all the dividend one
case all played over here phones on
either meaningful speech sounds like
words
of various kinds
song
or just
noise
and in another case
they actually asked her to engage in
certain kinds of imagery
here part of the all the results of the
scans performed
during home
torino the speech processing
and what you can see is that
for the patient
all good
speech
not noise
the all of the bed
roughly not all of the auditory cortex
but also some of their orders from a
very few seria is responding
differentially
not as much as in the controls
but you are getting a response and
you're getting it in the same area as
the controls
which suggests
that this patient was able to make a
distinction
between actual speech sounds
uh...
non speech on goings
there is a very interesting thing but
that yesterday do
was to but while she was in the magnet
they actually aster to imagine
that she was playing tennis
not watching a tennis game
aster to a magid that she was playing
tennis
of like hitting the ball swing in the
racket and on the and and and so on
when u_s_ controls to do that
you get a lot of activation in the
supplementary border area
this is the next gyrus over from the
motor cortex
all of them towards the frontal lobe
that this week preparers
motion
and so that's exactly where you'd expect
to see activation if you were a magic in
yourself swinging a tennis racket
control show
very nice activation there
but so did this patient
moreover
they then the estes patient to imagine
walking through her house
moving from one room
to another
your house or some other familiar area
when u_s_ controls to do that
activation the primary motor cortex but
you also get
activation all
of the hearing in the poem portions of
the temporal lobe
and you see
activations and pretty much the same
area on in this uh... in this patient
what's interesting about this
on magic yourself playing tennis
magid in yourself walking through rome
or walking through a familiar location
that's a conscious
voluntary action that's a deliberately
conscious
voluntary response to instruction
and this patient
seem to be doing that
even though she couldn't communicate
for consciousness she wasn't able to
engage in overt behaviors if you looked
just at the brain called brain activity
by any standard argue would say that she
was engaged in conscious uh...
conscious behavior
now very recently this same group this
belgium group
palm
did a very extensive study using the
same methodology reported that just last
year
fifty-four patients there must have
every comatose patient and
thought that the other fifty-four
patients
half of whom had upper-level diagnosis
of persistent vegetative state
about half of whom had uh... diagnosis
of mentally conscious state comparing
two sixty nine called healthy controls
and they did exactly the same thing
for each of these patients iran trial's
in which they asked him to a magic
swinging a tennis racket
or to imagine
all walking through a familiar heart of
the street or or or or house
and they looked at activity
in these regions of interest first for
the motor task hitting a ball in tennis
court
the supplemental all border area
and second
for the special task volvo
aerial in the medial temporal lobe
noticed a parrot hippocampus drivers
all of which we know is that bill
clinton's office involved in
all spatial processing
of various kinds
here are there you know the although the
results of the stands
it turned out they tested fifty-four
patients
or only five of the fifty-four patients
showed any differential response to the
instructions
the other forty-nine patients showed
no differential responsible
for what you've got here are these five
patients
compared
orthodox compared to healthy controls
for the motor imagery the healthy
controls you're seeing called activation
inbio
in the motor cortex
and for the special imagery
your scenes of activation on in the uk
the part of the temple
area of media temple solvable
and for these five patients
you're seeing the same kind of thing
here it's hard to see
skoal injury there
as you can see
all but
at least on the other side
you've got are gap
where your helmet
palm
all but at least you can see some
activation here in the supplementary
public workers
part and you can also in the special
task see some activation
in nam
revealed temporal lobe
on here's another one
for the motor task seen activations
and paula little bit
don't hear in the office
for the spatial tests
palm
here's another patient
seem lost the top of the head here
all but you're also seeing these same
activations so again
five out of the fifty-four patients
tested
so that's a minority that's
on basically
nine percent
all of these patients
so it's not everyone
interestingly
four of these five patients for patients
who are diagnosed in the persistent
vegetative state
poorly one of them
had a diagnosis of minimally conscious
state
even expected to be back underway around
right
the whole point of the dubbed the
diagnosis of middle way conscious state
is if you want to be more conscious
that a person who's in the persistent
vegetative state
but it's not working out that way i
think this whole
diagnosis of middle econ two stages
very very very problematic and
as they say
more research needs to be done
palm
these guys were ordered put those who
are the purpose one step further
to see if they could actually use these
differential brain responses to
instruction
as a way of establishing communication
with the person
archive inspired by all that all of the
diving bell the butterfly purebred the
booker seen the movie
the patient with a locked in
syndrome who is able to communicate by
palm halt
why you're using identified i'd
movements
to lower pick out letters
on a l
primal letter board
and what they did all with these
patients
although those
five patients who responded
differentially to the motor imagery or
the spatial imagery instruction
they'd say something like
okay
if the younger brass has some questions
if the answer is yes
imagine that you're playing tennis
if the answer is no
imagine that you're walking through the
house
okay sing look at them
differential
all involve them
brain wave there
they did this completely correctly the
interrogator was blind to the correct
answers were all sorts of
on all the holes for the methodological
by cities
one patient
of the five
of the fifty four
five patients showed differential brain
response one of those five patients was
actually able to use
the all
does that these imagery instructions
to answer questions on yes or no
so that's not a lot that's one other
fifty-four patients being able to use
this for communication
but daughters open up some possibilities
here
for on weatherford offer diagnosis as
well all as well as for management
what we've got here
here
the persistent vegetative state
and the minimally conscious state there
is some evidence of conscious activity
there's some evidence that these
patients are actually able to
voluntarily respond ought to command
you just can't see it in their overt
behavior you've got a look at something
like brain activity they were to see it
kada qualify this
this occurs only in a very small
minority of patients the basque majority
of patients
in these conditions
don't show this differential
response
and it might be possible to use this is
a technique for communication watson's
only a very small minority of patience
show this
different responding to begin with
it's not something that weekend all rely
on
yacht
dubbed the published paper doesn't talk
about that
so we actually don't know whether this
predicts recovery or not i'm sure
they're doing that study
generalizing from the turks trust wrote
study you'd say
the people at the best chance of
recovery the people or showing some
differential brain activity
but in this paper this is published in
february two thousand ten
there is no such as no such follow-up
so anyway
here it is a way in which we can take
people who are apparently unconscious
all going to try to figure out or
whether there is any kind of conscious
mental life called their there at all
it turns out
sometimes there is
most times
these studies especially the the the
studies of the belgian groups
of or open up a whole new direction for
research
on these very very very difficult to
problematic
neurological conditions
okay next week's sleep injuries thank
you very much