pooh-pooh
okay last time we talked about
alterations of consciousness that occur
in the ordinary course of everyday
living
flavor truong phong shift in
attentional functioning
in absorption your attention has focused
intense leon one particular object
in daydreaming
your attention drifts away from the task
is supposed to be working on
and instead
on is occupied by
on material that's relevant to
of various kinds of barbarous kinds of
goals
what i want to do today is too hard pick
up on all of those things
and talk about mall
the similar kinds of states or allegedly
similar kinds of states
that occur in haldeman association would
want one or other kind of
formal meditative disciplines
now the true meditative disciplines that
i've gotten the most attention in the
scientific literature
and for that matter have got the most
attention in the popular of literature
our yoga
then nor some or all other writing of
buddhist meditation
and that's where might talk a scandal
focus on today
but i just want to make the point that
yeah i don't have to be
your going to be a hindu were a buddhist
in order to engage in all of the in
uh... they did in meditation
there are strong
vibrant meditative traditions in the
three great monotheistic
all-girl all religions
christianity judaism and hindu i hand up
and islam
and there are lots of other ordered the
kinds of meditation
but for reasons that i think are more
cultural cultural and historical than
anything else
all the footer truce focused on one
variant or the other
of yoga or home
road resent
so just to take a very long story very
short
all yoga discipline is based on
knowledge about the various aspects of
hindu philosophy
and the whole idea behind yoga as a
meditative practice
is to achieve some body
the total self collected this
which basically abolish is the
distinction between self and others of
blurs the boundary between the ego
on and off
and object
walton's oz then part of the city
meditation is based on uh... various
buddhist art of traditions
it's cool is to achieve nirvana horror
what you meant
and we you know you're in lightened
when you've got rid of all your desires
and your consciousness global
consciousness himself
as i say
one-story
it turns out that
all all of these meditative traditions
carmine one dob three basic forms
all the one-third or the younger and
then
arvo most people thought of as would
so-called one point meditations
where you take some object
some point of reference
and focus your attention on it all you
do you focus your attention upon that
object
or you engage in
bogdan variant on one point meditation
on which a budget
in which you not focused on anything at
all so that's the point you're focused
on
at all
all of them and there's a star forum
which is coming to prominence recently
with increased interest in tibetan
all forms of buddhism
known as compassion meditation
where you're not contemplating
you're not focusing your attention on
your breathing or some object in space
or whatever
what you're contemplating
thus offering all of the world in
so much for religion
though very first of all moved on to the
psychologist to take an active interest
in these meditative disciplines was a
guy named hartford aikman who did a lot
of writing in the nineteen sixties note
the date
first-grade consciousness revolution in
american culture people dropping drugs
and trying then they're doing all sorts
of things all right there in the middle
of the sixties
and also was also was altered like a man
who actually did so wonderful
called kind of analytic work not so much
experimental work
what really tried to
connect
especially zen
meditation up
the interests of blow modern uh...
uh... cognitive behavioral sciences
any argued that all these meditative
practices especially zen meditation
involved a of the uh... you know that
an element that he called contemplation
by which he meant non analytic
apprehension of an object
so the general idea just post the focus
your attention on in object
but not to think too much about it
don't don't don't engage in a lot of
elaborate of thought
are don't think about what it might mean
for you or that you're hungry and you
want to go up go to lunch or whatever it
is you want to do
which is supposed to do was kind of and
through your mind of everything but the
percept
including all the thoughts that you
might have about the percept
this is a really good percept alittle
like this percept whatever just get rid
of it
because in these in these traditions of
especially in the seven
all thought is or construed as
interference
and what you want to do is get all of
the again ins and with them
filled with the knowledge that really
matters
is obtained through perception not
through thinking
also you're supposed to be experiencing
all of the stuff
without thinking too much
thinking too much about it
like went further distinguish between
two kinds of contemplation
active contemplation word you're really
working out of your trying really hard
distant to keep your mind focused
on on on the object
you're doing kind of breathing exercises
and do it all sorts of other things the
kind of distract yourself
from things that would distract you from
on contemplation
all-party point you pointed out that
after you do this while gigi had really
good at it
and so when you went to the spiral basil
full contemplation
contemplation itself has been automatons
on just come to do it it's your time to
meditate this with the new meditation
you don't have to work very
along the way for that
beyond
the implication of this is that
contemplative meditation is a skill
it's a skill that has to be practiced
it's a skill that you get that a rat
with time
that's why they call it a meditative
discipline
and that's why you go and spend time in
a monastery to learn how to do this
long and dot
play video games
whatever else
did you want to do
om and so what did i could also argue
against just kind of uk conceptual
analysis of what's supposed to be going
on on your dad meditation
that what happens is that
by virtue of meditation
we shipped from what i couldn't called
the action mode
called experience
one that is based on
all understanding objects
for the purpose of manipulating and
changing them
ought to
what he called the receptivity road of
experience in which we simply experience
the environment
experience the object
for what artnet is all i think i was
like men but it was somebody along those
lines who argued that the essential
shifted takes place in of
in these kinds of meditative disciplines
is a shift from doing things
onto
letting things be
for what's the old zen joke don't trust
do something stand there
all of that's the general idea
home behind us
albany argued that
as you get better at this as you engage
in this kind of full contemplation that
practice meditate hers or the experience
then disheartened start to experience
all sorts of interesting phenomena
which he called
all done with which he drove group
called the the mystical experience
so first with what he called all the
reality transfer
in which your thoughts and images are
experienced
not as fought send images but as real
lob jerks in the external of above the
world
similar to that is what he called
sensory translation
where you're meant both process easy
although they get experience
nod as thoughts or ideas or as images
but as physical sensations who can
actually
ordered doesn't feel various kinds of
changes lonely in uh...
in your body
you also yet
on what log what we call the unity
between self and object
that is you
pursued you experience herself as one
with the object that you're trying to
contemplate
fluorine
breaking down dismantling those ego
boundaries
uh... between the self and others
and then he said
you know
it's really hard to describe this kind
of thing
because this experience that you have is
in some sense of ineffable
in much the same way that the quality of
or perceptual experience or a duffel
bore hoti describe read this old body
all along
also he argued
that home that these old
the these experiences were very very
very difficult to describe
they described as somebody else
finally here i think diaper and made his
most important contribution to the
psychology
for the science
all of all of this
is it he characterized the results of
contemplative meditation
as what he called
deal for comment is they should
of mental one
hauled
we argued that
by virtue of alone
carvel haldeman meditation
we know what we abandon our
habits of mind
we abandon those automatic process to
use that we used to apprehend the world
and think about the world the plan
of with with the world
automatics commodity actually useful
that term and that by virtue of
three in ourselves
from our habitual automata eyes process
these
we're able to look at ourselves
and the world
fresh ways
automata version
that's something we can talk about right
we don't quite know what out what some
body means we don't quite know what
nirvana means
when somebody says you do your comment
i'd
your mental process these
we know what that means because we've
got na we didn't in nineteen sixty six
we've got technical definition of what
part comet is asian means automatic
process these are inevitably a vote by
the appearance of some stimulus
they run incorrigible ego completion
they don't consume cognitive uh...
resources
and they don't interfere with other
kinds of things that are going on
so what's going on here it is is the
general ideas
that the in the ordinary course of
everyday living
or or of the reports
experiences
are actions
are overwhelmingly guided by these
habitual
processed sees that are engaged in
automatically and that by virtue of one
form or another of these meditative
disciplines whether vendor he'll go or
whatever
free ourselves from that
deal automata lies
experience
and action
so that we can approach
every new object every new event every
new experience and something that his
new
we know what automata zation means
date we have some idea about how to
measure it
let's see
what we can pardue
the question here really and it's a very
interesting one
once some
feature a mental life has been
automatons whether it's a vaguely
automatons like a reflex
or art or or onto automata eyes through
some kind of
or extensive mourning process
kenya unring the bell
can you order them somehow
i'll break that off
and return to what bug to appoint where
you were where your not
necessarily responding to these kinds of
mobile of habits
and again just to point out
with the government of the date of this
dichotomy
or all of this interest has its roots in
the nineteen sixties counterculture
movement
along and there was alone
well for the for example
a great deal of interest in the sixties
i'm sure there is a boost interest today
and the use of psychedelic drugs of
various kinds
like l_s_d_
order resposta break off these habitual
patterns
and leave people
to have uh... have mystical mls
experiences
on various
veristrat
so nazi
exactly how we could figure out
what to do with this
first is
we got a couple of methodological
problems that have to be solved
yoga ends then are essentially religious
practices
okay
their they're prepared contemplative
practices ever embedded in our body of
religious belief
or at least some kind of deep
or that people are sitting
and if you want to study what what's
goin what what goes on these you really
auto find practitioners find real you
know he's working and subhash from
someplace
or real buddhist monks are working the
insolvable
insolvable monastery someplace
as soon as you start doing that
you've got all sorts of
well above all sorts of methanol
buffalo article problems
for example people select themselves for
entrance into these disciplines you
can't randomly assigned somebody to be a
yogi
on so you gotta worry about what these
people were white
before
they entered the are strong or the
monastery
all you don't know what they were like
before they get driv ers from where the
monastery typically
so you don't have any premeditated pays
for it
if you've if you want
uh... dept sons ambassador in new
testimony somehow when you find these do
you want alma prices fought
you don't really know where there is
always that way for him
or whether the actual meditative
tradition
produced some kind of change
and then finally public not not finally
there are problems though
volvo a kind of conflicting vocabularies
and uh... at that time that the other
things here
when duckman says
that the result of printed contemplation
is the deal automata zation of fought he
means one thing
when we talk about it in this class
what we mean is
bus trip test
or something very much like that
and the question is
is performance on something like the
strip test
uh... pan adequate
of the law about of the arc de or
compensation our hypothesis
you've got to deal with all the problems
of
at what stage the oppressed people do
expect novices who are meditating to
show the same effect says about weapons
experts
probably not
and then finally whenever we bring these
things into the laboratory
if we are going to kind of take people
off the street or take people out of the
college classroom in teach them to
meditate
all there's going to be a very broad
very alone
profound change
in the
sore rounding the socio cultural context
in which that takes
it's one thing
to doing yoga on a mountain top it off
her meds cottage
okay
it's another thing entirely to do yoga
forward maybe another thing entirely to
do yoga on your seventy five dollar
abercrombie unfit she'll go back in an
air-conditioned gymnasium
that's just
not necessarily
all of the same thing
on and you gotta make
you've gotten we've got to be clear
that there are going to be differences
here
palm
in any event
there is a trumka truce virtual that so
i have to tell you
i'm going to show you the high points
but there is a very much research on
those and i'll tell ya why
the reason why is
until very recently cognitive scientists
have been interested
right that the more interested in the
letter perception
palm
and the second thing is that
when these
when these meditative disciplines were
imported into the united states they
were imported largely as stress
reduction techniques
and because they were imported largely a
stress reduction techniques
the most scientific analyses are vara
fax
have focused on
physiology
the stress-free pa response order nomic
nervous system activity apart rate blood
pressure muscle tension stuff like that
all the indices which are interesting as
indices of relax ation and stress
reduction
but are not necessarily the best indices
around four
changes and consciousness
and attention so
so on that so that that's a real problem
that the research
that's been done signed some cases very
extensive research
hasn't focused on the kinds of cognitive
changes
federer of interest to us
or hear or escorts
you know their problem is
that or with one exception that's the
stroup house
government spend a lot of time of the
strippers
there has been
on general failure vault for people to
use consist of assessments for one
laboratory to another
or one laboratory will use the d_-two
test of attentional deployment
onto to look at the effects of
meditation
another one will use a all haha object
perception test or off
counting tester something like that
there's a lot active standardization
that prevents
pause from comparing results from one
study to another even within a
laboratory
much less from one study to another
or across laboratories
we do the best we can
what god all of this interest going
were two studies in the nineteen sixties
that were extremely provocative
all of that and made use
on measures of dvd nosers although
attention
are specially twelve with respect to the
alpha rhythm null and reduce the
operative before the context of uh...
in the context of that is the show and
uh...
and sleep
palm
and we know that all as you will fall
asleep
first alf activity increases as you're
relaxing and then it goes away
uh... we know that elf activity has
increased when your eyes are closed when
over as opposed when your eyes are open
we know that when your eyes are open alf
activity has increased to be just going
to be focus your eyes and you're not
looking to do anything in particular as
opposed to looking at
uh... its own particular old object
on
the very earliest
scientific studies of meditation
made use of augie j measurements to try
to figure out what's going on in their
heads of people who were meditating
and they looked basically ad
three different of phenomenal
what is known as alpha density
which as its name implies
simply represents
this year amount of elf activity in the
g
as opposed to
beta activity or delta activity or or
whatever
the second
phenomenon is what's known as el for
blocking
which occurs as a or e_m_t_ response to
a novel stimulus
if you've got somebody sitting in a rule
when you've got the eleven the g
electrodes on their heads and their gov
got their eyes open and they're really
not focused on too much to generate a
fair amount of alpha activities
but as soon as you play some kind of
sharp lawyers are introduced any kind of
novel stimulus
what will happen
this alf activity nice sinusoidal elf
activity will quickly be blocked
fuck and replaced by on the by beta
activity this much bastardy synchronized
activity
that's known as powerful blocking that
sale or e into response to a novel
stimulus
but character you play
that stimulus over and over again
what happens is you get habituation i'll
be alpha block in response
with repeated
stimulation over trials you wronged you
don't uh... you don't see the awful
blocking anymore
the awful blockages
that the elf activity just remains more
or less constant
is very increased alf activity during
meditation yes
unfortunately a lot of that is an
artifact
but the fact that many meditate urs
medicaid with arise caucus
which just naturally increases alf
activity just can't help but you're a
warrior
that have a lot of alpha activity
well your eyes are closed
and even if their eyes are open
or they're often engaged in this
behavior of the kind of not looking
or or d focusing
uh... we used to think that at the high
levels of alf activity in the g work
characteristic of the meditative state
we now know that's not
that you can see high levels of elf
activity all in all sorts hopeful
it all sorts of mental state
so it's the justices so ciation there
you do see high levels of elf activity
in meditation
it's just not unique
premeditation
so what else
can you look at
here is a very early study note the date
nineteen sixty one by unarmed and his
associates psychologists and on in india
on of the practitioners of raggio growth
these were very very very dept
practitioners they've been added for a
long time
and the really interesting thing
of apostle awesome trainees
the really interesting thing about raj
yoga
is that the goal of the meditative
disciplines
is to be called the whole bolivia still
the world
oblivious both too
external stimuli like voices and and
uh... and events in the environment and
also what would be a state internal
stimuli
like your stoma grumbling as it
approaches uh... at that as it
approaches
sold one another's colleagues did was
kawaii drop a couple of all in all of
the experience the oldies
all and and also some yogi said training
and all
and lenin look at their e_e_g_ elf
activity
they discovered
yes there was an increase in the density
of elf activity while these guys were
engaged in their yoga on uh...
meditation
the second a much more interesting thing
is that these yogi is especially the
experienced you know he's
did not show the powerful block in
response to a novel stimulants
brothers of the interesting for two
reasons
alpha blocking is and
innate response you don't have to learn
it it just happens the same way that
the patellar reflex just happens
but these guys
palm uh... show ante up
anne blocking for the stimulus
it appeared that
in fact they were
achieving
the state
that is the point of raja yoga which is
a state of all bolivia's snows to
external stimulation it's as if
those novel sounds
just didn't get in or at all
they didn't have bitch way to the
blocking because they didn't block
are there just wasn't anything uh...
their role
very early paper very primitive data
presentation would be really have to
take their word for it they kind of
showed some of their grabs
all but that's basically what the report
home okay
alf activity
behaved as it should be hehe
given what these guides were trying to
do
they're trying to become oblivious to
the external world
and they or oblivious to the external
world as measured by
fail your of the alpha blocking
responsible for
right about the same time
to japanese psychologist casa matsu
emicare right did a centrally the same
experiment with zen practitioners
users and masters and disciples
undoing their sitting order that the
city meditation
and again they measured apology health
activity in the gene here's a look
actually photograph of the guy sitting
in the yard
well it would be no
meditation room with their electrodes
attached
and first thing they found
was that there was
on again
a large amount of elf activity generated
while these guys medicated
even though they were medicating but
their eyes open activity that usually
diminishes the amount of althorp
these zen meditate or is
in contrast to the yogi uses embedded
peters didn't show blocking to the
stimulus
which is interesting
what's even more interesting
was at the zen meditate or as showed no
habituation
yell for flocking
and again
the whole point exam meditation
is to experience each new event c_n_n_
obv itself without relating it to
anything else without seeing all that's
the same old hand clap that's the same
old bill that's the same or whatever
appear
to be doing that
or they're not showing
all automatic alpha blocking
called for
uh... the they're showing the awful
blocking stimulus
other thoughtful block into the stimulus
that's automatic
but this habit uation processes also
automatic
the bowl of their medication
is to experience each event
new for itself
and that appears to be doing what
they're doing
uh... physiologically as well
and then finally casa matsu in her right
ought not observed
with very experienced meditate urs
you got even though slower alpha
activity
like data activity
on especially towards the end of the at
st
but it's a difference between zen and
yoga
of uh... practitioners
with respect to alpha blocking
and the habituation of alpha blocking
that's really interesting
you cannot imagine the amount of
interest or closer to his phenomenon
uh... in the nineteen sixties
are young
i chased a very famous that master all
over my college campus
so the several months trying to get him
to let me put electrodes on his head
and he was very nice about it
very nicely
but he was very nice
uh... he kept saying that would
what would it be
buffeted name
and i actually think
crashing think if you have got the
invite them masters something that was
what we will call when
you know what would it mean
palm total or what
one day at one day he could turn to be
said
if the pope or hear would you put
electrodes on and wiley said mass i said
now is that why not
i don't have a good answer for that and
because i didn't have a good answer for
that party eventually went away
the interesting thing about all of this
this is just more of their date again
very primitive data presentation on here
is that ok
dorgan's and if you come param
differences between you know guns n of
uh... that are that are reflected in
this song path
in this performance in yoga you get no
blocking to the stimulus
exam the blocking dawson habitually
only one problem
never been replicated
or herbert benson and all our item
dollars arthur shapiro abdullah at
harvard very taken with the study
basic repeated this study with a large
number of practitioners of zen
meditation
standard raggio got and also
transcendental meditation which is off
of derivative
although they just got nothing
they got no shall we call 'em doc
triangle
no doctrinal differences
all all these guys
or showed alpa blockade as expected
and all of them showed
habituation
of the alpha blocking
as a as expected so that's just one of
these
brings that kind of seats in the
literature that bags that you
a new route would really like to see it
again
but the reason i talk about the unarmed
experiment and the casa months when her
rights for women
even though
that becca ringe other shapiro palm
of were were thrown unable to log
replicated
is it a gives you the idea
of how you might go about scene
meditation really has the kinds of facts
it's supposed to have
all yours a more recent serve it does
work well ya rolling david presley a
lecturer at the uh... blog
department
with all booboo with buddhist or the
medicator zazzle
much more extensive study
uh... that the other one was these are
seventy-six that monks with lots of
training
calm
and all of the actually compared
of that
practitioners of two different forms of
meditation
compassion meditation which is
characteristic of buddhist
or that the baton
that buddhism
of the
the traditional one point meditation
which is characteristic
of zen meditation
and what they did was to employ a
phenomenon known as binoculars rivalry
and what happened
you probably don't know about this when
i was very cool
all prominent visual all of the visual
cognition
what you do is to present to different
images one do you try
so for example
all stimulus with a horizontal grady
like this
and a stimulus with a all vertical
gradient all like this
and when you do that to ordinary people
people like ours
what the person experiences
binoculars rivalry
the proof that you want to get one
percent right because what's happened
what's supposed to happen
images cast on the revenues of the two
wiser
all later on in the off
individual system
but it turns out that for uh... that
though
do that
called sold out
when you present
horizontal grateful left aryan the home
vertical grade to the right i what you
see is a alternation
between the two stimuli
but not it turns out if you're an
experienced tibetan buddhist meditate or
okay very nice
all here is the amount
all vault
of the the number of subjects
experiencing binoculars
all rivalry
and what you see here is that
especially
while the subjects are meditating
it's very reduced
and even after the subjects of finished
meditating
on itself
it's very reduced sort of the rate of
thought but the rape of rivalry the rate
which
with which the images
shift back and forth
very much slowdown
and that suggests that
they really are cable to pay attention
to one
as opposed to the other they're not
subject to this kind of
almost reflex like
all rivalry phenomenon
fascinated experiment
all that i know on uh... doctor prestige
is uh...
that has been following up
over the last
last year
a great deal of the research on the
effects of meditation
all have laws that have flowed
not from studies of you know he's like
don't wanna like the anon the study that
i just showed you
of people who are practitioner you what
you might call
secularized and become modified version
of yoga meditation
either the transit double meditation
promoted worldwide
by called such figures as the maharishi
on mahesh yogi
still got a partial dot on
uh... telegraph avenue
or all we within our power the medical
context by
all of the so-called relax ation
response that was sold
pioneered by herbert benson
like harvard university
basically what bentsen did was to take
maharishi scores
dog
uh... what whereas in t_m_ you get your
own mantra to focus on
during your yoga exercises during a
previous exercises
fence and gives everybody the same
mantra
the word one
called and odos span in the basement of
the same thing
but the idea is
but resin double meditation is
essentially a translation
techniques
kind of strip double law called the
religious harder than context
on not entirely
ulm and all the time to relax ation
responses completely secularized it's go
that
it sold for two people
halt who have cardiovascular problems
for example
as a stress reduction
here are the martin
see this for yourself
later on
basically fences
instructions
for the real excision response
and the question is what kinds of faxes
do this kind of meditation
or have
and again
here it is where
within the transit double meditation
community for example the t_m_ community
has been
very very very good about doing research
the document the effects of
transcendental meditation
they published several volumes
all volvo research
almost all of it
for has focused on
you autonomic nervous system
and other indices of relax ation
hardly any of it
has some
of the pope has focused on
one example what one counter example
home here
is a pioneering study by art
patrols alexander skit alexander
or who was the uh...
after he got his
the hood doctor bri from harvard became
the chairman of the psychology
department at maharishi international
university
on and uh... alexander of wagar inside
their colleagues
on basically
on forty m to the residence elderly
retin residents of a deal
of a retirement home
called and then called and tried to
measure the effects of the practice of
transcendental meditation
on a wide variety
of cognitive tasks
unit one i want to talk about
stroop interference because
strength interference is the gold
standard of automata city
of where the whole idea of automata city
came from
you can't help
but read the word when you're trying to
name the color
of the ink in which the word is printed
and that the reading of the word
gets in the way
volvo
of the color name
and what they did was to compare
a bunch of all the residents who had
gone through it uh... uh... transit over
meditation course
another group of residents would gone
through not the cold that'll mindfulness
of the training
all of that was attended would tend to
be kind of a a placebo control
here or subjects were just want to
relaxed
and control subjects who didn't want to
get anything
there was a reduction instru pinter
appearance
uh... in the yucky i'm of group
but it was not statistically significant
didn't make it
for the kind of thing work
they've just one maybe fifteen or twenty
more subjects that might have had no
power to detect
but you can see the idea here
that present double meditation
at least there's a trend here for
reducing most group
float the strip interference
all here's another study done on uh...
a little bit later this a bike lady
winks or madison suite or doctoral
dissertation at yale university
and what dole blanks farm as did was to
pickled or group of
college students basically
and give them one passed through
a fifteen minute long
reading
meditation
exercise in which there is simply
supposed to focus on their breeding
for
for fifteen minutes
this is a centrally what we now know as
mindfulness meditation all talk about
that
in more detail
but among the arm
among the many tasks that
that uh...
wank home
she was wank than she is downplaying
storm as o winkle administered to her
subjects was a strip task
she measured stroop interference before
and after
or the meditation exercise
and also had a control condition in
which subjects
just uh... just rested
and what you can see here appears
thus a standard way of doing the home
the the strippers
there's a baseline religious reading
color patches
that this may mean color patches
then there is a
congruent ask where there's a word and
the word is the same as god culver in
which it's printed so it's the word blue
printed in blue image
and then there is
the a critical
incongruity condition
the name of the word of the color of the
uconn which it's printed
is uh... different and what subject just
posted it was simply maine the color of
the work
member stroop interference
interference with
name of the word
the um...
with the color navy
and what you think this is pretest
before anybody
all they've got any meditation
and you can see here
very nice stroop interference effects
indian congruent condition of takes you
a lot more eager to made the colors
that in the baseline
the congress condition
the republican four groups who don't
have to go into details
there are also showing stroop
interference
on the post test
what dog
what what what what i found to make a
long story short
on is reduced stroop interference but
there was still stroop interference
there just wasn't as much
as there was before
and there was more change
more reduction in stroop interference in
the meditation group
then there was
in the argument to control groups
or passes back in
kind of see this
so for the meditation group incongruity
condition
stroop interference starts out
the pretest about
on seven hundred milliseconds
the name of color
and drops down to or five hundred
seventy five
that's a pretty substantial
home so here
brought this has change in stroop
interference
and you can see that there's much more
of a reduction in stroop interference in
the meditation group than the reason the
other two groups yes
ads just that's just our it's an
accident
are because in fact in the in the wake
study archie randomly assigned subjects
the conditions that i just turned out
that way
so there are there are these baseline
problems it's not easy
that the other
to do this
all but the thing at the the thing here
is to really think about
if you just kind of
take each
group against its own baseline
you can see that there's
how much greater reduction
called for the meditation group
that's a problem
but it's not critical to the
interpretation of the experiment that
something you would like not to happen
you'd think with random assignment
everybody would start out equal
there are
failures of random ization
along the way it doesn't always work out
the way you'd like to work out
and you've got a turn in your doctoral
dissertation sometime so you can't keep
doing this
uh... in order to get it
absolute right
so
here's another condition she added
cellmark dad some of them some controls
again you can see on the pretest
ochoa quite a bit of stroop interference
and all the groups
now here
they look very comparable
and in the post test
yeah out there is some reduction here
and what you can see is that
in the meditation of the group
there is an actual reduction in stroop
interference
whereas
learning control group for the rest to
control group
there's a change
it's not a reduction
so again what
all twinks form as a study seems to
suggest that alexander's did not was
that at least with respect to the
breeding form of meditation
that uh... that she uh... uh...
but she started
meditation does seem to lead to deal
automatons ation of thought as measured
by the stroup at uh... that's that
that's what we're going to focus on
out uh... just to
just to
clarified that you had some other
measures as well she asked people to
categorize objects that you found that
after meditation
people
were more
easily able to it
categorize on usual objects
and so on
i'd you pointed out here
as opposed to
real yoga meditation
or perhaps even transit double
meditation there's some debate in the
literature about whether to young counts
as a religious
organization
or not
i want to get into that fight
for one thing we know for sure
is that
armed thugs
do you know
the the procedure used by weighing storm
as was completely secular
argues for college students randomly
assigned to these conditions
there was no nothing alike
or religious or philosophical overweight
uh... yet she got the use of she got
these really alone
interesting kind of a fax
recently there's been a spate of
interest in the yet another
secularized and to some extent from
modified version meditation
all known as mindfulness based rests on
the stress reduction
then all the buddhism
present origins long ago and far away
began to come to the attention of
people in the in america in eighteen
ninety three when the person's and
masters
or came to the united states offer this
big conference call world parliament of
religion
think about that for a second
sounds great
alm
and then our and that in the fifties on
board i said to that susan t uh... who
was a very paul prominent on a teacher
or bob or those of buddhism in japan not
exactly a zen priest itself
so we did study was at least came in
baidoa good middle lecture tor
of the united states and got abt a lot
of people
especially
the people of the beat generation
jack carol lack alan ginsberg william
burroughs all those guys who spent a lot
of time down in
eggs or
all vonnegut got dot god doug got
intrigue lives and meditation by virtue
of the lectures
di substances okie
and more recently john cabot zeran who's
all medical psychologist at university
of massachusetts medical school
or has developed
all of the basically based on his own
buddhism
what he calls a mindfulness based stress
reduction technique
which does four is then buddhism
what herbert benson is relaxing should
response did for yoga
take it completely out
of its religious and philosophical
couple of them context
and teach it to people
as essentially of stress reduction
technique
which is why it's called
mindful of the space
most of the stress reduction
also what we've got here is the
secularized all of the buddhist practice
some people are taught
ought to the trained too
hong engage with their world of what
cabins in cold
mormon from moment
non judgmental awareness
that's a cloud
over to clone
now that's a nice cloud or it's a fluffy
cloud or insult rain cloud it's not
quality
you have a pain
you just experience the pain
and let it go with static thinking about
the meaning of the pain
dot and so on
and covered soonest colleagues have
developed a strong operational
definition
operational definition in psychology
defines a construct by the
procedures
ployed
all these people were taught to sit
alba
you know meditative posture
and focus on their role
uh... plot only on the partly sensations
especially the the sensations of their
breeding
thoughts and feelings come into their
minds has posted just noticed some of
them but the go winston welling
dwelling on them return attention to
breathing
and then
in addition to the formal training say a
couple of hours of the couple of one
hour sessions a couple of times a week
all of these individuals were given
homework assignments asked the practices
right at home
as well and so as well as in the clinic
again palm called so agood this practice
is supposed to do two things
evolved in a mindfulness pay stress
reduction as opposed to enhance the self
regulation of the tensions with it
your controlling
uh... your attention
all but also is supposed to
or even reorient yourself to experience
so that you were experiencing things but
not thinking about that
or you're noticing things but not
judging
all there is no
psychologists have developed a
questionnaire to measure these things
the toronto
mindfulness kale
uh... was developed to measure are
people's responses to
uh... mindfulness based meditation
techniques
on this kayla soft on the lecture
supplements for this course of your
date's been
uh... kind of meditative practice at all
you might want to
fill it out after your next uh... at
your next session
and then there's this
wife acid mindfulness scale which is
more of a personality questionnaire
which measures
how wine before you are
of things in the ordinary course of
everyday living
to what extent can you just not react
to what's going on in your on your mind
and uh... and so on this saw scale is
also up on the lecture supplements
if you want to
if you want to fill it out
ads with transcendental meditation
most of the studies of mindfulness based
stress reduction
as its name suggests
have focused on
measures of stress
anxiety depression
measures of audit nomic nervous system
function
like heart rate
and uh...
mccarty of ordered from cardiovascular
are measures
but there are a couple of calm
there were a couple of oliver attempts
to look at
the effects of and bsr
mindfulness
cognitive processing
using our old friend the strip test
on
here's a word he resolved with early
boasts of study by by anderson and her
colleagues
measuring
the affects called mindfulness based
ross reduction on emotion
lots of nice changes more positive
affect less negative affect
she got nothin when she tried the
strippers
home they're just no changes in st coast
performance at all
unfortunately the strip test that you
use it was kind of all weird variant of
the stroop test
soul
more in malad ascii
pretty much the same on
the uh... the same experiment
looking at
of all although mindfulness pay stress
reduction
on stroup past performance
and what you can see here
small effects
so this is the number of items you
process okayed the number of colors you
can name
less interference were colors you can
name
and
completing a six-week course of them bsr
produced a signal significant increase
poem color navy performance
and a significant looks swollen it is
but it's a certain alone statistically
significant
of decrease endeavors
so here again we have
or somebody
are showing
the effects of the automatons ation
coming from bsr
here all
i gotta say
that's a small effect
and just to kind of
show ya how small it is
here is
a study by amir roslan cognitive
neuroscientist at mcgill university
for using our hypnotic suggestion
for all
ag knows you know or maybe alexia
looking at the effects of that on the
strip clubs
on here
on twenty twenty basically
gave highly of the faisal subjects
a suggestion that whenever they saw
these words would be jim burge to them
looked like words of a foreign language
but they didn't understand
in the control condition
when the suggestions not given
highly hypnotize ipl subjects show very
nice troop interference
when the planet
been given a suggestion that the words
are jabber ish like in a foreign
language
strip interferences eliminated
completely
or really
since these are in susceptible subjects
they show
all stroop interference in the control
condition
they don't respond to the suggestion
this they continued to show of strength
for the poor
so stroke interference is something that
can be abolished completely
in just a couple of
although they've been just a couple of
minutes fight all appropriate
suggestions the high we cut the price of
all subjects
six or eight weeks
fault meditation experience
and bsr experience anyway
i could have some
affects diminishing stroop interference
but doesn't do anything like
abolish it
why that is
we don't know
further research is required to try to
figure this out
but i suspect the reason they has
something to do with the fact
that and bsr is really focused on stress
and emotion
the autonomic nervous system
and not so much
on these on cognitive changes of your
compensation
still not all
the idea that as far as consciousness is
concerned
meditation are supposed to change
consciousness
three nos from automatic habitual
patterns of thought
we have ways of measuring this
in science
in psychology and cognitive science
so what scientific approach
premeditation is going to look at that
measures
the automata zation whether it's a
stroop task or something else
we've talked a lot of discourse about
what consciousness is and how we can
approach of scientifically
next week we'll finish off by talking
about
where consciousness comes from
thank you very much
we'll see you have a good weekend