came with store that was just a little
bit of housekeeping
which is to say that
sometime this week we ought to have been
waiting list of everything else
straightened out
we're going to do our best
for those who were still on a waiting
list for movie you watched waitlisted
into
enrollment in the class
palm again your chances of
getting off the waiting list of the
cluster better
if you're waitlisted for a discussion
section that has
available seats in it
whatever will do our best to difficult
all right
topic today for the next couple of
davis is the relationship between mind
and body
i suspect that roughly half of you got
interested in this course because he
thought we were going to talk about
drugs
we're not
and the other half of you
got interest in this christmas you
thought
you can watch me solve the mind-body
and i'm not
hall so just wanted everybody
understands
what's going to happen here
which is something else and firewood
mind-body problem i think has never been
better expressed penned by thomas nagel
loss for it and why you know
context of an essay it is about what
we've referred to a little bit what is
it like to be a batch
and to remember that naval starts out of
a a guard with that
the fact of the new organism has a
mental states that is conscious
experience of all
means that there's something it's like
to be that organism
there's something it's like to be a
cuban who's hungry or who sees chairs
there's something it's like who batches
flying around in finance tax and all
that
of one of the points that uh... that
made one star argue
there are lots of other ways to think
about behavior
but those are there ways none of which
really captured the idea that mental
life goes on as games put it
the first of all the uh... the person
point for a psychologist is that
thinking of some sort grows on it
and then they go goes on guard
argued the real mind-body problem comes
from the fact that
them
the experience of having conscious
mental states
doesn't seem to be
analyze the below into anything else
and uh... you can't have it
just inspections of systems of
functional states the cause
so various kinds of facts
because they're all sorts of functional
states that could be
work there
without giving rise to conscious
experience
so that's the real puzzle of or wrong
slow for naval and for many other
philosophers
as well
and so it comes to me i say that nagel
onto specifies what i think is
what really bothers people about the
relationship between my apartment
why the body
consciousness is what makes the
mind-body problem really intractable
without consciousness for mind-body
problem would be much less interesting
because of all i could think of it
quality i think that that is combining
is some set of structures and processes
that intervene between environmental
stimulus
and behavioral response
well because thermostats and computers
and all sorts of things that could do
that
and we don't ever asked a question about
whether or
whether their conscience
so without consciousness and they want
answers the mind-body problem would be
much less interesting because
frankly the money would be much less
interesting
with consciousness however
it seems hopeless
alternates trying to figure out why
evolve out of the consciousness makes
the mind-body problem all of the seem
hopeless
but i want to talk about today and that
will expand on over the next couple of
days
palm
the whitewater problem begins with a big
heart
alva where the course weekend a week ago
over back to him on and we keep coming
back to him from time to time
all who argued all four
altered
two things first on he argued that there
was a strict separation between
humans and animals
descartes
palm
said that he
came to us floss appeal is understanding
through a process of radical methodical
skepticism that is he tried to doubt
everything
and try to figure out
what he could go
but he actually did you do that
on a big part was there you know
faithful loyal and faithful fall over
all
sort of the uh... roman catholic church
he saw what had happened to people like
uh... galloway oh and you're going to
brood over there trying to
on a platform about things that seem to
contradict
the church doctrine
so right off the bat in my view anyway
descartes failed it is
alderdice philosophical program
because he's at work
human beings have souls
animals do not
animals are just or unconscious reflex
machines all they do is respond
reflexively too
of the end of the two stimulus of and
supporting the environment
but humans have consciousness
and that frees humans from reflex action
uh... we have reflexes but it frees us
from all from reliance on reflex action
take our target because
uh... we have minds by which they
cartman souls
file word which the decor thought
on gave us on gave us free will
so it's consciousness
defined really in terms of free will
or that separates home
human beings
from various animals
and then called
nordic are trying to figure out exactly
what he meant by undetected
animals have
bodies
humans have bodies and mines
and he came up with a philosophical
position that is
first known by the phrase substance
dualism
all by which is that what
mind and body are characterized by too
are composed of two quite different
substances
bodies are characterized by
substances that have a property known as
extension that is they take up
whereas
mind is in material it doesn't pick up
space
and it's characterized flying
so we've got this
or that don't do well with the martin
in the world mines composed of one kind
of substance
buddies composed of another
just as a footnote
from here
that we get on entire tradition from
descartes up into the nineteenth century
or philosophers arguing that psychology
could never be a science
a position that was adopted as recently
as well as a manual kant
in the late though
blvd century
and the position
against which does cycle physicist that
we talked about last week
rebels
really succinctly he says look
depends on measurement
condescension lien adopted the cartesian
position
mind wasn't characterized by
extension the didnt a company
at all
so so what we can measure mine
so you can't have a science of the line
psychology has to remain a philosophical
discipline
and it was only in the halted could be a
bit late in the nineteenth century
sometime after contra died
that braver and fact mirror at all and
held bolts out of the end of the
nineteenth century psychophysical
decided they're going to try to make
your mind anyway somebody else
public public did that
they did simply by us to be people
assigned numbers to their experience
the public polite is really bright given
an eight
if it's not so great
give it a lesser number and they found
that those numbers the people assigned
to their experiences
cold air raid waffling
physical stimulation withdraw activities
at bundy in the body and so on
and therefore begin to develop real
science in psychology broke all
comes as a reaction
octopus
okay now
okay so first we go body a mind-boggling
gold composed of two different kinds of
substances
but descartes wasn't eight dummy
he understood that mind and body
interrupted subha
he gave us this
after he saw fickle position
which is known as interactive dualism
which argued that mind and body
though they into other though they're
composed of different substances
nevertheless interact with each other
and descartes examples of this were
really gone quite cleary says in the
first place
we get a great deal of our knowledge
through our sensory organs
we see the world we hear about to the
world we smelled pace things
and all that happens by virtue of our
bodies
if you blind
some body he can see anymore he can't
have those kinds of mental state
if u deaf and somebody he can't hear
anymore
you can't have those kind
malval mental state
that's the first weight that mind and
body attract is that
some of our knowledge columns through
war of them
uh... is channeled through our bodies
ought to be other way that of mind and
body interact
is that our thoughts of fact our barnali
on actions if i say i would like to
raise my right hand
about raise my right hand
fought of raising my right hand
somehow causes me to raised my right
that's the real problem here which is
not just of mind and body or composed of
different substances which is bad now
but you've got to have some way hongkong
of
these two
completely different kinds of things
two completely different kinds of things
interact with each other and a card had
no idea how this happened
except
he had this idea
that material substances could affect
the material substances
there had to be some passageway that had
to be some point
where the tumor
uh... they collected
and descartes thought he found it
in the pineal gland
which is this
that sits
right there
all valid in the yard
in the brain
and while wide choose the pineal gland
might not choose something else
caldwell first location
all of them take are located the pineal
gland right in the exact center of the
brain
case with up at school
if you're going to have some place for
by the body that we read what better
place
for for that to be
that donald
amid a dent in the exact center of the
brain so that made sense
argued also thought that the pineal
gland was the only structuring the break
that there was only one up
you got to hamas fears of all that kind
of stuff
uh... two sets of spinal nerves and hold
on all of that
but there seem to
they tend to be only one
one pineal gland and said okay
all of that uh... that again makes sense
to pick up the center of this
saying this
homogeneous things right center
on the group of patients
and then finally of
the descartes thought that all the human
beings
pad pineal gland
your book theodore brains and cat
parades and things like that we didn't
find a pineal gland is that
or the humans have martins
solely humans had been some structure
where mind and body can come together
and here's a structure that only humans
have
all and so this must be it you can come
to see the reasoning
unfortunately
ficar dot
two i three wrong
all of the if you do your histology
called all of the it turns out that the
pineal gland is not a unitary clump of
matter
that they've got they've got different
kind of structure different kinds of
structures associated with it
and it turns out the pineal glands not
uniquely human either
small dogs and cats
birds have them it's like virtue of the
people and that
words for example
regulators sleep cycles
rest about animals to sleep
also that this could work out either
bucket seemed like a good idea at the
time
thought he'd had this way of solving
forces mind-body problem that's not the
same opinion planned this and important
it is the tube
it does it's important for a sleep cycle
but it's not exactly
pollute the place where mind and body
come together
so card gives us this
stalled that this idea of substance
dualism and this is even more
interesting idea of interactive dualism
and we're kinda been stuck with it ever
since
all of this although debit cards
duelist ic
intuition
that is that mind and body are somehow
different
is a position that is very appealing
the people
on a large numbers of groans
first there are lots of religious
doctrines
that part of that argue that something
like a school separates
all human beings from all of the local
from other animals
and all
tone of the world
since the enlightenment
there's been is kind of gradual trends
of the translation for first
hopes for into mind
so humans have mines in animals told
orion and minded the consciousness of
the humans have
the other animals killed this is an idea
that
that that pervades lots of
religious or the doctrines not just
uh...
the second thing is
that this this idea that mind and body
or somehow separate
appeals to what is known as folk
psychology
that is
all of the kind of intuitively informal
all understanding of mine
that people carry around in their heads
before they take psyc one
homework large so i won
although and discredited to it of
understanding of mine
basically says that we have parties and
we are mines
and bodies and minds are salmo how
different
that's what they card
that would cause that's what comes to a
sort of uh...
descartes so substance to elizabeth
there somehow different
and also that mind and body interact
somehow
that's where we get
creepy asian all interactive dualism
'cause it's obvious called that they do
and then finally
all in scientific psychology as it began
to develop in the nineteenth century
well into the twentieth century
uh... we have this idea
basic cartesian
dualism
is relative is preserved at what's known
as the doctrine of mental listen
and the dot doc about was the basically
says
that mental states part to action
as close to affect
that it's not the it's our mental states
or believe in something
or perceiving something or feeling
something or wanting something
that causes us
to do what we do that causes us to
behave of the world
when we do
somehow what's goin through our minds
causes us to behaved with our bodies
all of the way we do but what's
important
or mental state
that are causing behavior to to occur
and all this culminates basically
id william james definition of
psychology as well
as the science of mental life
stroll
descartes some
dualism or something like day cards to
elizabeth very very very appealing to
people on almost everybody in this room
i'm sure agrees that he or she has a
mind
james that what's important for the
weekend argue about right
palm
what you do with that mind is that or
what you think if you do with that
binder so that it was something
different
most people have this intuition
that mind and body or somehow different
when you start thinking about it
seriously as descartes with other people
did
you begin to think
heart that their that that that that
that
there's a real problem
this idea that mind and body or somehow
different
but still somehow interact
how could that possibly be
uh...
the case
people worried about this a lot
fall and this is not a course in the
history of philosophy were only going to
do this for one day with any luck will
do it for a little bit less than a day
are but just to try to give you an idea
about what people other how people try
to get out of what i called descartes
impasse
that's not through the two ritual
home uh... that is the idea of
mind about your somehow different than
the interact somehow we can figure out
what they do
so you get somebody like nicholas mala
branches as well here's the solution to
the problem
turns out
that paul causal power right looked like
a real resides with god
all and so what happens is that
when something moves in the world
that's the occasion for god to put into
the mind of the observer the perception
of the movies object
called and when are
when somebody archive thinks about
raising his right hand
that's the occasion for god to make the
right
all rate
that's not a particularly satisfactory
uh... the solution mind-body problem i
think
but it did get mala brushed tenure
and then aquila dot along all along the
way says those welded thereto brooks for
those who says look
all of the l minded body are very
different
all of their true dyed a different
properties of reality okayed two
different
features of reality
and all my dead body are connected
because
god says
that mind and body or connected
godward games this isomorphism sort of
whatever goes through your mind paul
although dissolved has its cover part of
what goes on
goes on the world and whatever goes on
in the world has withheld report
and something that goes on through your
mind
and then got for you don't know why this
articulates what
seems to be the favorite solution
or from a duelist at point of view
which is of the human element
psychophysical parallelism
which basically says
there's a relationship
that all about what goes on intervened
in the physical world
and what goes on in the all of that has
its parallel did what goes on in the
mind and vice versa
and that correlation is simply
established by god
so what
well why did basically says is work
there is a relationship
between mind and body
and on the way it works is god does it
that was no more satisfactory to anybody
that many of these other all of them
kinds of solution
than people realize that pretty quickly
and they tried some other ways pub
getting out
okay cards
palm
sulfur example george barkley bishop
barkley after who berkeley's name
uh... had this idea that workers
filled when the way to get out of doing
a lot of the problem of dualism said
there's only one thing
what part we did was to work hard
for mine
and he said well before the there's
really only reality as the law in
perceives that
there's no physical world out there
palm uh... that's
not of particularly
satisfactory solution either but that's
what the
that's when it came up with
and in the late nineteenth and early
twentieth centuries an american
or psychologists and psychiatrists
wharton prince
arca above the plugin solved
all of the problem of symbolism again
kind of like barkley
with what he called the mine stuff
theory
here's the relationship between mind and
body
all matter
containers
thing cold minus stuff
and if you get in
not for this matter
dogma clump together
then you've got a lot of mind stopping
to get a mine
if you don't have a lot of the stuff
clump together that you don't have
enough mine stuff to give rise to mind
so you don't have a life
he got tenure for this true
stalling
picked up the door directed the harvard
founded and directed the harvard
psychological clinic and establish the
journal of abnormal psychology which is
published to this day
with william james his best friend
arms are going to be really was a very
important on the guy
i mean who seems kinda silly to wants
now
though of if u reddog john swirls i'll
review of
david chalmers
on you'll see
now actually chalmers is an idea that
experience is a fundamental feature of
matter
is not all that different
for almost all of the of the word
princes idea that all better contains a
little bit of mine stuff
but any ways some people tried to escape
the problems of cartesian dualism
by going
or for mine
basically saying that you know there is
no of the matter doesn't matter
barkley said at one of them very clearly
on here that's the kind of a version of
what's known in
in materialist borders of that is is
only one kind of thing
and it's mine
where uh...
artwork princess at all matter contains
of somali someone so there's really no
difference between them
more popular were also at the center for
the heart of palm palm
with the philosophical views dot org
that
who've come to a says known as
materialist bonanza
previous guy say there is only one kind
of thing
and its matter
all of them mind is just kind of out of
the picture
get this in the eighteenth century in
france julia cooperate they love met re
all proposes what's known as the
automaton theory
that basically says
humans have consciousness
salem entry was a good divided humans
consciousness
but he says
consciousness really just doesn't matter
all up to behavior
we are automata joyous like all other
avenues
it's just that we happen to have
consciousness
song
and uh... so
the problem here
that this resolves the mind-body problem
chris you no longer have to worry about
howled thoughts affect behavior
you don't have to worry about how some
of them something like a mental state
the real physical world because it turns
out that consciousness has no effect
on the real physical world
automata over reflex machines just like
the rest of of metering
and then on thomas huxley
although it's not
basically put pulls us all together
with his doctrine of at the phenomenal
isn't
thomas huxley was darwin's cause and
uh... tubes called darwin's bulldog uses
really vigorous proponent
of the theory of evolution
uh... which is not a bad thing all but
u_s_-led uh... thought to articulate
this doctrine
that basically
did just like the elementary
we guess we have consciousness
but consciousness plays no haldol ruled
the world
all we have our brains
and brains receive stimulus inputs that
brains execute response outputs
and that's just the way it is
called consciousness is nothing more
this team of the whistle
alone
using a steam engine analogy
uh... it's not even the whistle of the
west's wants the scheme of the whistle
it just doesn't do anything
battle
so bizarre ways in which people
when none of us would have happened
really had ulm cargo descartes not
argued convincingly onto a lot of people
that in mind and body were somehow
different yet mind and body somehow
interacted
all these guys are trying to figure out
how to respond onto this
to this general position
james for his part
basically said that the booth at the end
of the nineteenth century all these
positions have been articulated
and james carville kind of looks at me
says
i really liked working a lot but the
buying stuff theory can't be right
right it's just not
finally takes an entire chapter of the
principles volvo arguing very gently
that it's just a coup
idea
on james james who trained as a position
on his very interested biology says look
materialism is right
there's only one kind of substance
in the world of those of the physical
substances all we know
rejected
what seemed to be the logical
consequence of that assumption
who rejected the automaton theories that
were not tommorow
already rejected up a phenomenal izumi
says
it's obvious that it was obvious to him
that mental states have allen had causal
efficacy so it would just have to
but with that
what what one must be the case
is that there is some kind of cycle
physical parallel
there must be some correspondence
between what goes on in our minds
and what goes through our brains
okay
it's not our correspondence that's
established by god it's a secular
version of psychophysical parallelism
all but uh... it's just that that's all
we can do
james says he just kind of throws up his
head
ensign says that's of that that's the
best i could do
or maybe
as psychology develops poem of the boys
will be able to do better than that will
be able to
i figure out exactly
how the psychophysical parallelism
occurs
but he says i can't do it
we just don't know what
so that takes us to the end of the
nineteenth century
and then what happens is people start
responding part two
to james
on john b watson
of founder of a also charter school in
psychology known as behavior resum
basically takes
the automaton theory and be although
that and the view of epa phenomenal ism
which came through blossom p
and in bed sit
in the heart in psychology about the
plots of actually dividing us
that psychology is the science of mental
life
he says look
covers right
you really can't have a science in
psychology if you're going to study the
mind
hongkong
for all of you probably do
is to have a science
that studies behavior
and the conditions
under which it occurs
because that's the whole you could
describe objectively
the only thing that you could
scientifically observe
the only thing you can scientifically
study on his behavior
which is publicly observable
and the environmental conditions under
which it occurred
which is publicly
uh... observable
and he says although
and the but then he goes what one step
further he says look
throughout these guys are right
mental states simply
have any causal efficacy they don't
do anything
we have them we understand we have them
all bob what really goes on here
is that all behaving organisms whether
your work for a cruel were more awful
leisure or wrong
wrapped worldwide or if you would be
all behaving organisms or simply
reacting
to informant told
uh... stimulus
newspaper stands
then you can have
a natural science in psychology
but as long as you know fault but that's
what you're going to let some kind of
metaphysical idea like bahrain
some kind of the material minders from
minded
somehow different
promo the full body into your size
you're never going to get anywhere
so what we want to do
is simply learn how we can predict
behavior
which is something that we can as we
were to predict behavior we advance
our scientific theories halt
about behaviors
not about the line
palm and week that we can use our
scientific knowledge
to promote human welfare
by controlling the behavior hall felt
people based on these kinds of
scientific principle
so what will be dealt with the
behaviorist revolution
really is fall an attempt to kind of
roldo mind out
of the discipline
and what you'll see if this becomes
very popular really fast
and in the nineteen twenties the
nineteen thirties and go back and you
won't you you well
start star reading
the old scientific journals and
psychology you see two things happening
very quickly
the first is federal references to
mental life dropped almost completely
out of the picture
pass on a psychologist dot don't the
don't talk about
memory and perception
uh... andy walker
all the talk about behavior
on the talk about stimulus control
behavior
and the other thing that happens
part of the at this time which really
hadn't happened before it looks like all
of the store to we've had a ball
research to the exclusion of human
research
on watson said lots ok word rust animals
so uh... all that you can take your rats
in your bookings of your cats in your
dogs that you could do perfectly good
psychology
uh... it doesn't matter that your
subjects could no longer tell you about
your about their mental state
cause their mental states don't mean
anything
all that means anything
his behavior
and the circumstances under which it
occurred
the third interesting thing
that happens about this time let's not
just like colleges for collect a lot
like this
by the way trouble what's himself pre
quickly dropped out of psychology
he had uh...
he had a romantic entanglements with a
graduate student and they didn't like
that at johns hopkins have
on the keep them out
uh... and he went to work for auto
advertising agency
great contribution to civilization
decides
the invention behavior as a
he invented the coffee break
he'd he divides the concept of the
mid-morning to mid afternoon coffee
break as a way of selling coffee
for our client was advertising agents
before john watson for job you want to
be did not have coffee breaks
after him
we have starbucks and everything that
goes with it right is all
called for the
considerable consequence
what's about the which he answer
okay but the other thing that happened
to your in fact called art
this same kind of of the same kind of
idea
all we really have his behavior and mind
width really doesn't play any kind of
role of the role of it
although it appears and all
but the appears in philosophy as well
you can see it and all of the famous saw
other treatise by gilbert rile british
philosopher called the concept of mine
in which he's three describes
although the mind is just the ghost in
the machine that's where though
please so i think it was got the title
of their album
home ando
it does look
it's just a mistake
to think about mind as somehow separate
on him it's you know that
it's even a mistake to think about mind
is a physical part of the body
blind dosent really exists
all that exists
for bodies
when we think about mind what we've
really mean
behavior
or at least disposition
the behavior
paula and that's really all we can say
about it because it's just out of his
writing
thirty years after john b watson
uh... and uh... just
tho exactly the same kind of idea
fizzled when we refer to
when we talk about
all mental states
we refer to we were really referring to
one of two different things
first were just referring to behavior
were referring to
the circumstances for using mental power
so what i say i m
hungry
what i really mean is it's been awhile
since breakfast and it's getting on
towards lunch
if i say i'm sleepy
what it really what i really mean is
it's been a little while since theater
and it's getting on towards
jay leno time or something like that
really i'm just referring to
all behavior in the circumstances
uh... under which it occurs
which is exactly what watson had said
psychology wada confine itself to
uh... as a deal
as a science of mental life
sobel begat
is in addition to the psychological
behavior ism
davis
a tradition
all philosophical behavior ism that
really translates mental blood that was
the terms
into arm into the behavior
you actually see these guys postal but
what do you mean by thinking
well what i mean by thinking is talking
to myself
okay that's behavior
and are there was a tradition of the man
putting electrode people for a
productive
think of thought
on the purity of that their vocal
apparatus moved while they
fought thoughtfully but go they were
thinking out loud to think that behavior
thinking particulates just behavior
if you believe something
that's not a mental state
wud believing something means is
behaving as if it's true
so quite believe in god i go to church
and behaving as if there's a god
if i believe it's raining outside i
carry an umbrella line behaving as if
it's raining outside and solid believing
doesn't mean anything are more than that
all the medical terms that we have
believing feeling knowing wanting all
that stuff
can be translated either into
something that refers to
overt behavior
for two the circumstances hall under
which
which it occurs
philosophical behavior ism
i think it all confines of the apex
caught in the hong denote viewpoint
within philosophy
that essentially denies the
consciousness
dogs exist all
loan there are floss words out there who
say they see it's a delusion
kind of a version of that the phenomenal
ism
with old even if you could be a puff
anomalous thought
the consciousness was really just that
part of the product id
but consciousness doesn't really exist
and the basis for this is a stance came
they came to be associated with
approval for suffers or at the end
who are conducted a stance known as
positivism
is worth watching cold logical part of
this
which basically said that nothing exists
that can't be publicly verified
okay that's what that's a
of positivism nothing exists that can't
be publicly verified if it exists
it can be publicly verified if it
doesn't exist it can't he publicly
verified
and of the idea of the idea here is of
course that
because consciousness been heralded
subjective
because it's inherently private
can't be publicly verified
and therefore it doesn't really exist
you will see
home strains of this
again and also a professor so roles
review of debt bennett's book
consciousness explained
or dented essentially takes us
first of all quali a
uh... and on the second about
consciousness in general
it basically says
well have to book it says consciousness
doesn't exist with
publicly verified
and in the other half of what he
identifies consciousness with certain
functions
the other aspect o behaviors
but all these guys
basically argue
that consciousness is irrelevant to
function we may have it
but it's basically up a phenomenal it
doesn't play and he called the wall
uh... in anything
all we've got is a brain
which operates as a kind of virtual
machine
all turn taken over from computer
science
that processes stimulus inputs
and generates response of with
basically
now some people like this viewpoint
most people to help like this viewpoint
are is i think that's just doesn't sound
right to be some out
reasoner doesn't celebrate you is
because were also you back at the cards
impasse
we all share this notion
blinded somehow special
somehow different from body
mind and body interacts
well we don't have the foggiest idea how
we do it
and the f_a_a_'s the reviews and the
responses to the reviews on the
responses to the responses of
uh... to the reviews
yeah better collected and all updated
professor sural orc i think if you are
really good
idea
hollow people are trying to grapple
forward with his idea
that comes to us from the car
that bind the body
or somehow difference
but somehow incorrect
and how that could possibly
were all sitting piping still one
hundred twenty years after james his
principles
city most of us anyway
mobile call james's conundrum
forces us to materialism
we all adopt a scientific worldview
now that there's no physical world out
there in it can be understood to be
cadavers science based on measurement
and public knowledge
and all of that kind of stuff
science forces osprey which will listen
of experience
nevertheless inclined to the student
will listen
which is the idea that somehow
mind is different
that body
and that's all some there's some kind of
mystery
about first
how bottle we process these could give
rise to mental states
but you know that's not so much of a
mystery but didn't bother the at the
phenomenal is in the nineteenth century
baba lee
start processes could give rise to
mental state
what really bothers people
is the idea
mental state
could play uphold the wall
world
so now what you see in though
boxgrove reviewed by several
there's a bunch of responses
onto the soul of the situation
some people just want to give up on
folks psychology
they are right
you know they're right let's not talk
about mind anymore
alm
or they go
for some kind of god reduction this
materialism
that basically denies that you could
org conscious states have a lot of pavel
material basis
but you can't reduced
consciousness
uh... material functions
or you get a blend of materialism and
dualism to get people to save the assets
right were all scientists now we're all
material is now
but still
palm
there because some people will really it
was just
three-day car got it right the first
time
are the okay to set aside the god part
are part of the basically got it right
um... we didn't bring some kind of
dualism
and then there are people who just say
i give up
i can't deal with us now
on and this is in fact the position
are cold mister realism
are that's associated with our colin
began
all who basically said
we've been trying for a long time to
solve the mind-body problem
nobody has helped
funniest idea how to solve the mind-body
problem
all and all that and a says
we just can't do it
we don't have the cognitive capacity to
solve the mind-body problem
all of these that we know
that materialism is right
science
inclined to storage
materialism ok are but we simply cannot
figure out
mahalo on top of the how it works
and we're never going to be able to
figure out
how it works
and that the note that this is not just
uh...
the kind of a accounts of the strange
idea for home
for rome
for permitting the basis of what
developmental psychology teaches us that
there were certain things that we're
simply not capable of understanding at a
particular time
beget all begin with actually base in
this idea on p o_j_'s notion that there
were stages of cognitive development
andy's of what
the result there are some things i don't
know that child with a pre operational
stage a cloud of development just can't
get
and you don't understand at all until
you move to the next stage of cognitive
development and is that what we're stuck
uh... at a particular staging trodden
uh... development that basically
prevents us from understanding
of uh... uh... the relationship between
mind and body
we are cut off by our very cognitive
constitution
from what she did a conception
of the psychophysical link
uh... so we don't worry about this what
we want
but nobody's ever gonna be able to
we're going to be able to solve it
and that we get people like
i'll put my professor's sorrow
hall who has this really interesting
waved at the those who've taken paula
paula dot of course from professors who
are already of his books
know that he has harvests or way of just
kind of
all allot of uh...
intellectual
detritus
these as well
the only reason we have a mind-body
problem is because
reread take heart
fog and descartes says that there are
minds and bodies at the paris somehow
different but they don't buy the but
they interact
and descartes just made this fundamental
mistake
which was to think of mind and body has
sold
how different is that they're just not
is that the way to solve the mind-body
problem
is to say
mind is what the brain dogs
consciousness is a causal property of
the parade that something that grill
tissue produces
in the same way that the stomach
produces digestion and stuff like that
is just really no different
all of them from that
at certain levels of anatomical
organization
we know
at the level represented by the human
brain
brahma believe primate brains
maybe other mammalian brains
maybe not
invertebrate brains but maybe
at certain levels about a public
organization
neural tissue gives rise
uh... that the consciousness
but only
when that
neural structure
isn't certain kinds of physiological
states so if you're
going in for surgery in your put under
our played of general anesthesia
you're not conscious anymore
along to fall asleep you're not
conscious anymore if somebody could to
over the head with a frying pan
xox about you're not conscious anymore
on menu somehow yukon your your
that physiology apartment comes back and
produces
that's alright
okay now what's not all that it's
because uh... so relax you pics of mind
is very important
the argues that the mind-body problem is
essentially
not a problem at all
there's a problem for better prepared to
was
only because we adopted this basic uh...
the space of cartesian step
and then finally
we get
people who are overly influenced
vault of the body of
find neuroscience
who want to who want to argue again as
walks and might have
as the philadelphia philosophical
behavior is sort of like
that are somehow all-girl sciences going
of themselves solve these problems
what what happens is
or real problem is that we insist on
talking about things like
all pauline patricia churchill and
all have argued for what about the
status of the call interfere rather
reduction which says basically but we
need to do is to get rid of folks like
ology
we always talk about all i believe in
this or i want that arrived i'd leave
that
the head of the people problem is that
you know we keep talking about
folks like a logical concepts that we
think explain our behavior but they
don't really explain her behavior
what explains our behavior
are brain processes
and they argue
organ for this position called interfere
reddick reduction
by which they said we really want to get
rid of all this folks psychology
and talk about the things that really
matters
when the proposition two principal of a
new theory
mirror the proposition two principles of
the board theory and the new theory
gives better explanation predictions of
the old one
the new theory contains the correct
description all reality
it is to be preferred
and their basic idea here is that brain
science
constitutes a new theory
that gives you better explanations have
better predictions
folks like ology
and that weren't we should start
all of them we should start doing that
never really very quite
white dog
quite serious about this lived alone
further folk psychology talks about
mental states of believing that wont
even
real science
term they use real science
talks about
physical states
therefore and here's a quote
psychology must be grounded in the real
world findings of girl's life
the implication being
the world of folk psychology the world
of consciousness the world of mental
life
is not some call the real world
the world on the line is the world of
hall of uh... non-existent things like
easter
uh... which we now know doesn't exist
largest on which we now know doesn't
exist
fairies which we know no don't exist
because we got up
because a better science now
here they are
palm
they are really quite serious about this
there was an article about them in the
new yorker couple years ago
of which uh... which showed that contain
both of them the following
the following episode polled pat comes
home o lived with her house for world
one bb
and she says to me
paul don't speak to me
by serotonin levels of hit bottom my
brain is awash in glucose steroids
by blood vessels are full of adrenaline
and if it weren't for my end dodging the
soviet side of driven the car into a
tree on the way home
my dopamine levels need lifting
this is the scientific language that
they want to substitute for poke
psychology
because this is grounded in the real
world findings of neuroscience
and not be in the
other worldly
although abuse all blown salvo folks
like ology
but noticed
they actually came
even even they can't pull this off
actually talk like that
don't speak to me okay
that's what don't speak to me means that
the real world
all about the cause of by means of
neuroscience right because this is now
how we know what speaking there is
physically
on them when she when she says poor
amiya chardonnay
what she really means is put some
ethanol in water hog at at at at at at
at a particular in a particular way
home and and all of that right but
that's a bit that's that's kind of where
this is going
what's happening here
is that
guys are kinda missing the point
this is a human interaction
that is being mediated by people's
mental state
wants something from pole
okay
she wants him to
feel a little solicitous and give her
some space and poruri chardonnay
not true bark choc
she wants a chardonnay
right why doesn't she just injected with
the both the boxing thomson or something
like that
why did she talk to him at all
in the real world of social interaction
you know do stuff like this right
i can talk to you right now forming a
glass of chardonnay i'm going to take a
bath and i'll be down in a little while
right
if it's an interaction that means
something
something like this just kind of strips
the whole thing of its meaning
unless you have your
video decoder ring
that'll tell you what it means for some
way to save my brain is awash in glucose
steroids what elements that name
from no wonder you know what that means
right
unless you can come in quick gota bhool
and and and and and and and what
happened with the wikipedia
what really needs to happen
is that we need to ground neuroscience
in the real world findings of psychology
okay
psychology columns
but neuroscience only makes sense once
we've got the psychology right and i can
give you more examples of this view
force me to all do it next week
it's really it's really true
that mural science is no
privileged
science
without
your own neuroscience you can still have
a science of mental life you can still
talk about perception memories and
thoughts and feelings and do all the
things that psychologist drew
without really goin inside the head to
find out how the brain does it
but if you think about it for a second
without psychology
all you've got for neuroscience
is the biology of neural function
you don't know anything about what the
brain is doing
you'd be a good weekend doing their own
science the way we want to do it now
hong kong dot unless you have some idea
about what's going on at the mental
level of analysis
okay another diatribe
next time we'll take up when i take to
be four different problems of the route
having to do with the relationship
between body and mind
thank you very much