they talked about altered states of
consciousness that responds i wouldn't
despite some kind of physiological
changes
sing the case for anesthesia
the anesthesiologist you get from death
indicate salt romance
you jeff
some damage to your brain system it
resolved sweeps
alm physiological changes induced by the
brain stem produced changes in the court
except
fortunately frantically through the
various stages of fleet and how do you
dream during sleep and wake you up at
the end
what i want to do for this week and next
week to talk about
alterations unconsciousness
they obviously have some kind of or
religion the brain because
everything but the more i don't have or
parade
but we don't think of them have seen
induced exactly by some kind of
physiological procedure rather we think
of them and seeds in place sometimes
psychological procedures thought it'd be
best to elevate organizations
and will start off with two classic
examples
fault or of history offenses no's'
hysteria in quotes because it's not a
festivals commitment psychiatric jargon
anymore
also was left to those who won't find
and i think it's
removal from from february it was kind
of unfortunate
once you understand
was determined for both
well let's do a little bit of history
the would probably know
nearly concept of history ahead of
origins and agent
medicards
because rejection agreed
publicly medicine
and the idea was that
at this time of the original all of the
term hysteria
was used for a group of reporters that
were found in women as opposed to man
because they were founded women as
opposed to mend there were attributed to
the one thing that women have the band
don't forget vigorous
also often stereo all
disagree refers to the war and reviewers
any idea of one that part of the uterus
cum laude catwoman
then she would have trouble for team
telephone booth at the risk of watching
the fear is that you have to hold
hearings
if she could become lockheed reports
that she'd had trouble walking
their introductions they didn't know any
better because it's never a dull but
you know a lot of medicine instinctive
better than that
complex history it was given all dwarf
cooper of the medical appointment
definition
biodegradable tradition applied them
party in new york with the seventeenth
century
or nineteen thirty
argue about this did not exactly
election
interjection
jack consecutively either
what what flight landed wants the world
refers to fill it
whenever it whenever he encountered
physical symptoms
seem to be produced by email or she will
call them
for the first include more worth it
didn't feel welcome here it's a bunch of
people whatever the prison physical
she couldn't find anything wrong with
the body
uh... there was no injury no accident no
no fear that he could see
we figured that
use physical symptoms was produced by a
motion for at least and what you've got
here is a very good earliest idealistic
and faulted
modern western medicine and why
of a psychosomatic eastward
like that didn't bounce of the physical
symptoms legal
he just thought that they were
introduced by a physical plant
instead to produce fundamental flaws
optical
promotion level
and there are no
century perhaps later
on another great falls
appear brithday
told me to find history again
to refer to
patients who had multiple
and chronic visible conflict
not just by can move i cant force i can
feel waldman
white or whatever
the group of people who were present
themselves food who positions
one complaint after the other
to bring in one complaint doing that
declared
and eighteen fifty nine
devastation go away and come back with
yet another complaint
deal with that
always comeback republican complaint
and it was just never any kind of an end
to it
nevertheless recarey holmberg
flood sampling all ventricle earlier
that means complaint
the patient av
really didn't seem to have any obvious
were gathered sixty what he did the kind
of physical exam
that good conditions did it in the
middle of the nineteenth century
couldn't find anything more
faulted for thinking
all sorry for that
all deep thoughts complicated thing to
do you think you produced exactly body
emotional qualities
they were a mystery
what you can see it britain's work the
origins of the modern diagnostic
category of organizations
all modern on thank you have completed
gustavo crystallization
walks of life involved
all can find databases for them
all of the difficult three and to keep
coming back over and over again looks
like for today
little okie
or another turn in the evolution of
hysteria came just a couple of years
later
or with another french petition of
johnmark shortfall
who was without intelligible
prominence in the wrong with them
would
as far as murphy
well with you
going to be perfect life
all
dot
fight here and the salpetriere which was
the largest
psychiatric hospital plants and flowers
expecting to go to paris
go down the route for john mark and
charcoal
and go at the end of this will cease all
set for you
their wonderful
uh... hospital devoted fans psychiatric
remarkable
and i a short while
aren't they took a patient with
reporters and all of her and defied the
philip
dub there's little psychiatric disorders
all i have the person who presented
patients that makes
sort of organic illnesses
and the reason it's important to
understand the charge but with the
qualities
once i think it's organic enormously
that be patient
northampton sympathetic medical reform
neurological
thoughtful short code historical patient
four had problems with heartfelt
sensitivity that with fuel
structural changes waiting ordinary but
want to be loved
they had problems with the special
friends whose all visions say audition
and they've had problems with motor
function
newburgh
quit
paralysis
all but again the idea here is is that
there was nothing
physically what was beaten
poorer and poorer shortfall could
determine either conducted properly
neurological examination
if we find that if it won't work
fifty
auditory her
reporters levels
distortion theft
students could figure out what willful
dont but these are the idea of
functional complaint
called which is what one talked about
were produced by life
ought to be verified the grief of a
motion that would be
or some kind of suggestions
began divisive
off models for that
dept
or charcoal fault but there is also
interesting that the pearly example
of what your medicine sakai three
they call a guy applicants
warmer
the idea behind right out of the flood
theory is extremely episode of elements
if the result of the confluence of three
factors
died apathy
dr
which renders a patient bowl durable
through pittsburgh for orbital
but does not exactly org
further
band-aid over what happens is
for stability
dan schorr coz view anyway inherits a
hereditary constitutional week
they will be fifty you won't believe
we've active
what week the motive
uh... band
on who short code for you
was technical person one subjected for
dramatic levels
what would happen to believe that
all function would be compromised
off abt
pointed out far enough
dependable with his
theory the kitchen
has got a very weakly connected with the
pressure on the chain celebration
that point dot the problem
so the idea here
afford for charcoal was
person would come into the world already
shirley carp weakness
for the purposes
that if the person who subjected
compatible threat
of breakdown
stuff
also struggling to do things like diablo
functional regions
there are really brain lesions and
patient it's just appears that they're
just appears old
neighboring regions
terrific
functional before
that's been there
what would be produced biogenic four
deaths illnesses
funded which charles colson raledu
russian introduced the idea
thought historical fiction had
psychological
and such things very very important to
us
all sorts of the discoveries
volunteers
through the discussion
or not the least of which was called for
the work of this congress by takes two
hundred charcoal is actually a
psychologist whose qualifications
stuff here
flatmate metal threesome
thoughtful
all
protocol tradition
it's not what was what he was not for
the position three was your day
to really mall the concept of history
are always club away from the world
and to offer
you know more was fewer psychological
what what what what charcoal since
whitewater
skinheads
they don't actually have
functional equivalent of a brain
injuries
if you have
is a constrictions over where
patient lack of historically
and that's the citation lock
sacto fifty
still has
although simpson herbs
functioning
hospital where he said
simpson's consistent
with future use dot where salty
and some
charcoal but
also introduced
this idea of cycles psychological
thomason
sorry
which upward which would fit with the
birth of the term very much like
offered
concepts of what the mississippi state
charcoal but the idea of governmental
life
one still tough
plunging very complex in flint
who won't
stimulation
these complex responses consisted
some action
formal motion or plus package
wherein particulars
it was clear
that thomas' ramble
as a result of
barcodes like there was a piece
complex what how much of her
thank your voice victory
i don't know where that came
charcoal zygo
with the people at farmington
were normally accessible conscious
awareness
conscious control
flood again
under conditions of straps
one or more of these twelve provinces
and cities
at all
rendered
unconscious
sent
the first time
might not be aware hopeful
album on and off for not might not be
able to school
okay let me give you an example of this
from charcoal
famous case of poetry
i dream of sufficient presents itself
ascii art of the sofa three x
for mother had recently dari and she had
nowhere this event for a while
had no idea that the model
however didn't
when she slept at night
she suffered from from and it wasn't
which he would get out of bed reenact
all of the process of this
first mother's dead body which i think
they've done
she would
talk about the site of the dead mother
she withdraw fault problem she was
responsible for the detailed reports
shoot reenacted movement
if you gave him off the republican party
told of her bedroom involved
into another room
burdensome ambulances
that's a bit so traumatic event we are
back to the filth infers three if she
had nowhere else
that her mother had died jimbo worked of
discoveries
body
nowhere stopped responding vice
quite a movable audio golf bedroom
but she didnt reenact all of those
payments from bad to worse if nafta
fails
heart-wrenching to remember that
so what's all the boards what today
argued
look at this episode
it so that looks like a logical
automatons
where you had
gemma's actual graphic throughout the
site of the dead mother
solid overboard
irene movement the sheik at reasonable
destroyed a whole bunch of a list of all
kind of package together
wife off
or its subsidiaries
from or
from the rest of the heart of the rest
of our lives personalities
so that when i removed wake
they were fucking will perform get
active whatever was in five years
neither she nor anybody else without tax
to this particular
of ideas
stations movements emotions involved
landing
samoans
models
sachar makes a rich history of this
piece of death
in all cases forgetfulness
informed trauma
flip-flops
some stuff although ideally which would
no longer assessable supporters
was helpful successes
institute
messed up
organising three for want of course to
brighten
junk food
carpool with joseph lawyer poop
board with one point
protege
uh... in eighteen ninety three eighteen
ninety-five ought to produce
very famous old peoples home subbing for
instance
which is not
horrible porter employed
formulation
from reminiscences
ordering boy boy behavior
was that whenever you have a case of
this
because the history of what to do
uh... repression of certain ideas and
emotions in folsom
that was instigated by some kind of from
that of that
and that they can start also
the are tactile anesthesia all of the
definite for these dates for me again
ability of the fault of the paralysis
whatever it was
stockpiles
climb conscious
and symbolic
of this book
dramatic memories
four days later
developed a simple old doctrinal brooks
hall about the profession i think couple
form
early on
buoyed like lawyer
at the idea that
patience with the filia
typepad
some kind of what we would now call
childhood sexual abuse
this is the so-called seduction theory
well before we talk about it
which
which leads to the development wildlife
uses simpson's
and that we're on the truly waldo
we've got to tell a fiscal conservative
infantile sexuality
which pleases we argued
that history of didn't stems from the
need for a week from that
rather
central conflicts
ccny infant
sexual preference for people one hand
and the moral roofing
reality
yeah
let's start with the earliest
about doctor the profession's which is
uh... suspected he ran again this is
floyd
pulled lived
ideal
the sacrificial supervisor
for argued that there is
spiritair systematic
sexual events
but we would now for childhood sexual
abuse
which actually read through the outbreak
of the historical
afflicted
but that three wad point later called a
waiting period were factual issues wells
fargo the background
nothing much happened we didn't do too
much voted on
but that there were these chains of
memories
void with association at least
these changes that were used
that's all that exactly
halted
relief epithets
and um... what would happen is somewhere
around hubert e where the child
all began to develop interested in facts
again
there'll be some kind of what we call
the dramatic event problems
off-the-record heaps of stuff
that would fall reach back through the
chain of memories
and rain up north artwork bring troops
on the brink of a four this actual
original dramatic events
which would then get
with valujet
we've developed at the podium
passion
believer camp
farid very
ballpark five people
to cope with the existence of a group of
people
resembled the symptoms of neurological
gomez
what in the booth no signs of brain
unfold injury or disease default
that therefore
dubious function one-third somehow
psychological point
that had the same
didn't really waldholtz
at three herbal option
attached will break down
but what we get from
what legacy of this nineteenth century
all interested
blurry uk sent
trauma all of that
pointed still
well today
moderate proprietary clinical psychology
elsewhere
or the first thing we got
is disgusting
between so-called organic
and thoughtful functional on them
organic mental illnesses are one federal
still fears with
clearer palpable brain controlled injury
tendencies
that is sufficient support systems
alzheimer's disease
the avenues exit door
four-foot normal people do something
like that
where we can say what he got plaques and
tangles that obviously called new york
or you've got damage to the media
approval less obvious reportedly future
okay
functional
which comprises of that
psychiatric tested
notables
businesses dependent
two categories of mental illness
organic mental clear we do to solve the
problem
gerber's
functional with adults and deep problems
that would be sufficient
expert
relating to that
is the concept of sabado genesis two
fighter jet
it's wednesday about functional within
twelve
stevie organic clothes what they're
going to be warned
will find one
somtime
haldeman definitely watch our culture
when possible
okay
i'm sure there are some kind of work at
that point
the distinction between from out of
genesis fighter jet quite different
not distinction has to do with date
forces
something psychological forms
help them
and the general idea here with that
though it's about a genetic theories
they're basically say
all of that
the symptoms of mental on concrete block
wall brain
warm
neuro transmitters dot blot yep number
idea dot
behind appoint twisted what uh... why
you think
the molecules
and the idea of fiber dept
which is that
depression and anxiety history are all
sorts of mental illnesses
a psychological form
meaning that looks like a logical
pointed
primaries something happened
heartfelt mobile we thought that they
think it's leaflet emotional off
the actions of the above
indeed report
afloat
to some extent
three distinction between some other
genic
psychedelic before
fifty-plus again
were all material as well
we all believe that whatever goes on the
barring as the counterpart
the odds of the point here is that
sometime
deep biological pointed to a direct
costs
albeit
rented psychedelic
biological point ought to do it
patiently to think about
uh...
which principal just get the facts
which brings us for the role of trauma
charcoal
lots of people well into the twentieth
century
well into my professional life
productive argued that wal-mart
once looked like a logical instigator of
a large number of trip
dot weather related
clues for sexual assault of
walton patrolled would work
austerity cardiff trauma beds that jody
preferred
it was at the end
trauma
that reads like a logical fourteen fifty
twelve administrations itself back at
least in johnnie cochran's asian
board socket
mexican sessions
food
foot
the nineteenth century interest
though it
that basically to get through it
okay
i will pick it up
yacht boat beat guy everybody would
agree with that in principle
that field
bedford goes back to our discussion
cycle psychosomatic medicine
all but that
somehow no way that the neuro
transmitters rudolph or all of the word
knowing that the exterior thing to the
court's actions were conflict between
your brain
let me know if the patient
who doesn't know how to save the older
daddy or whatever idiot
com the authority of the first brain
does not have health reasons
mental illness
you've got operate on the first time
person's life britain's police brutality
nagata didn't psychotherapy
include
political
and that's the effectiveness
dr
oh these days
where it is very
notified but mostly thought the
diagnostic and statistical gradual or
people's
recent addition
or be awful crisis
arrival
sweet robert robert robert gloria
blue-footed disorders
all of which involved
problems of memory and identity
werkzaamheden lost
conscious
aware
aplomb affect of memory
format specified devotees
throw for example what's sometimes
called psychedelic abhijit household
document abhijit
the first time
cannot remembers
from the significance of that
white
distribution
ought to be able to remember
like irene
was not able
remember
of model
paul
can psychedelic fumed
qualify kojak qualified psychological
processes
bonfire
composite room for the head
hauled out known in fiscal discipline
the president
only lab report
said superior oxygen one
not hysterical
particular event for the fact
all of his or her autobiographical
and on him viewpoint but gets its name
isn't the first often changes identity
made reward
that they have
active
drawing
classic picture republican jane treated
foreign in the nineteenth century
all legal one day
walked off their rhode island
dot dot on the ideal
with a total of whatever dot
alberto separate northampton city
whiskey hopefully pedestal
they have no idea that he had what was
the northbound
yet know what appeared to be a
truthfully
the pilot
and what if i meet into it
norristown pennsylvania
black and white would
ecad nowhere dance of what we've been
doing for the last six rape birthdate
droplet
memories identity mary curtius
it's the it's not a good but we are very
rare
typically return
wednesday
it's a wonderful really politically
all but they but they are doing
palms and multiple personality disorder
point copy all familiar with those no go
to the president
filled with the person dog food
switch back and forth between
a particular identity
or at least of which was completed
before before the fire
truthful didn't
directory border disputes to the people
who thought they were going to steer won
his nobel deep personal information
where the person
feel safe
before she was a stranger
the food memories
because the person does not recognize
itself
himself
concentrate myself haha
mirrored dot com
i'd overwhelmed
third everything feels very different
realization
all which is the same kind of moment
except it's applied to the outside world
if the realization
persons are submitted dropped
wife trish
yeah will
but what i thought it was
looks like spam
that's kind of them realization
buried i can't attend the artist in the
yard dfm or
that all of these people associated with
some kind of traumatic technology
atmosphere
manifestation
post-traumatic stress i'm here to tell
you that there is no evidence for that
that's a theory theory bordering on t_v_
ology
papakura walks the walk
a democrat
mhm move
where the government any kind of combat
people
fistful
speaks most famous
pays for all of these
info pavithra dot not only a
best-selling book but through counsel
true
all award-winning movies
famous faithful briefcases speed
first
overflight
to satisfy tourist
fitzpatrick likely jobs http flickr
couples movies
steve white with the present the case
archie or one of the world
all drawer job
housewife verdicts
http outside atlanta
who was subject to various parts of the
soul of blackout
on three one three two five washington
golf eddie political fortunes dot
okie
property with a drinker
okay so she was intricate herself
blackouts replace three thirty
and that's the truth
djibouti cubans
she could falsehoods cartridge
thousands of these things like at this
point
so for example one-day onto a dump
package came from washington here's and
what i go for the past it was a slinky
black negligently and i never wear
things like that i don't know where
paul dot and all of that turns out
that will at least one st multiple
personality she has three
different identities that we did find
one wouldn't bother you
all believe white was then shy retiree
ruled george georgia house twenty fifth
th blackouts
steve black with the one who ordered the
magnitude interference
although she was all very full three
sexy provocative for certain who really
didn't want to spend
too much time zone of the farm
all found that there was this a lot of
other third personally james which
absolutely
but the big deal with the deal with with
the white
black
turned out
jacky boy pad
no idea above the existence of these fly
through it is a good
achieved it
weren't really call here but he did
all-party black
had access to all of the place for them
fifteenth date from africa latin teacher
white nothing about the flat
he's lucky all about
white
white nothing about james
capable about white
audrey flack didn't do about each other
all and there's actually a lot of all
that played out during psychotherapy of
so they did what
at one twenty three
called onto discomforted plead the fifth
before the first big study
intelligibility
in therapy r_j_ looks kind of emerging
about condoms
electronics compromise personality
and he'd slacks
what the emergence of trade because
you'd like to think it was fun
and if you ain't got got control the
situation of really believe
parole for well worth it section of the
original one
are with joanne woodward fall through it
board
order of the more recent race car chases
got written up in new york skinner's
dope very very distinctive
case of joe about that
personality
told the truth i don't know the
presented personality
with no emphasis
where
and all of my key dwight
he suffered from blackout who came to
the attention of medicine
optical veto
locked up to it
i thought that the first time
joe it was very shoddy refinery
sensitive introverted
find it turned out on analysis of their
work
three people in this party
thought there was sammy's no doubt
lawyer food
kind of intellectual replacement vote
dot
when when he talks dignitaries rational
jury pool
hall there was lots of people watching
young with bonus full over who's very
pleasurable reacted bitterly we've got a
few extroverted hill told mister bill
webster
well bats
aren't mike women
all aloft
all alice and that there was a lot of
this
or personalities
black not white
who saw far off rule of affordable mako
was known as warriors
very cold very aggressive scary things
with anger
sports personalities would takeovers the
identity of the behavioral network
applied
and they put themselves out we have to
do it
daughter was actually military
palm
info fellow directly thank god dot we're
going to go out of the fountain of
john's grown a little gold
after this
your with the throws takeover
as you go a little more destructive
weathermen women
palm
called which walden woods who are
getting in trouble
and i'm sorry
or would come between the kind of try to
talk
uh... but as everybody out of part of
the inevitable for flight
and if that succeeded that was fine but
if he failed
saw fob rule of the fun of omega would
come on the scene
and actually flight
all softball
the dayton or if i think it's part of a
magical stuff
going on
thoughts one's life
and that should be able to discuss
dot you've got to do something
recorded the mental health services
for the fourth grade adult enough that
the questions
now didn't kick although i did
about any of this going up
because i've done
watch the peace of comedy about the role
what don't know what happened
why you were great bar last night but
want what why don't give up
i don't remember what my mentor of about
forty five oh remember any of those
and uh... uh... told would be bad there
was not actually a very complicated
pattern
hauled off of interpret melvin these
joanna
really this is sort of
don't had no idea but at least right
formed
different personalities
i have access to children's memories and
some of them had access to each other
but joanna really was in the dark quite
literally
http
political warren complected
don't order without your recollection
with that
the that's nice
it would have no conscious recollection
of anything that yes
it will be able to redeem or what was
tried to force himself autoplay false
squirrel
for them
and in fact sometimes and they didn't
job correctly
and populist didn't win the flight
so drawn away customers with the fruit
his cost
subject
electable off that list
cadres recollection
which leads to the interesting questions
fifty-four goodbye on tape
lengthy cheap food
but unconscious at work
people and psychedelic
i meet up with psychedelic anusha
academics who were multiple personality
disorder
party deprivation
don't have
explicit
conscious recollection rigorous
the obvious question pastors do do you
have any kind of
implicit memory
by defeated eight
for example that joanna
while not remembering that sammy red
warranties by four forty
would actually refers to an episode of
the book
and the answer is
there are not too many experiments on
this but the experiments that have to go
in
turnout wave of the would uh... with
mike
here's one of my favorite
clinical studies of all time
the british studies of a woman naval
forces can go
hall who was apparently uh...
who filed fighter jet they've discovered
by the sweet wandering around
politician
know what that application which is
quite correct listed
and because she couldn't identify
yourself you have no idea where they
want
had no idea pollution faithful
leaflet
why it was assigned to do this political
valuation
and what he did was the kind of customer
intelligence by asking her to identify
various objects to the robo rules
attributable
at one point in point of the trouble
filled yet
telephone
all is pleased with how important is
that you know what this means
and she said
telephone you know how to use a method
or other use of and i got them
reagan inflicted
show me how you can to stop
so she picked up the receipt
and then you've got involved
father numbers numbers of students
and so she dial the numbers
and before she could
bags the elston
why inflicting received
former defense
chaired by oprah mother
avago
vacuum none of the world developments
occurred number dot
all board three but with no anybody
telephone number listed in the parole
that's hard document storage right when
people actually knew each other
telephone numbers
arms and it turned out
that even though all argued with o_j_
dull softly experienced assaulted by a
lead number rapidly she wasn't that
tightly buffers number that came to mind
which was her mother's powerful but for
the identification
throughout the first to construct
something like implicit memory
memories knowledge that trent with
details of the behavior
affected eager outside fault for outside
arrogant psychologist at the university
of british columbia
had sort of formal spotty of explosives
and intrusive memories ki and all
series of patient filtration with
multiple brutality
method here is to
kept one of these
steve white
for example leave black
teachable
almost the words
and then all fest memory either in the
patient either either in the first
old all through the gulf coast
and what i think it was a very nice
study concurrent m_t_v_ recall suit
with the family support
seven completion
assessment implicit memory for the good
news
what we've got to be a really good
memory
findings plot fifty one remembered for
the first personality
items fought to keep one
tested impeaching or items plus
philosophy through
tested impute one
what you see here is
whichever personality
intro first they'll be tested
p one study
he was infested
pretty good explicit memory
ticketfast another personalities
exposed to primary that's almost a
definition of more persuasive powers
through
what in the study completion time
what or what what i conclude
is at least
at least in one direction because vice
president
if u look at some completion famed
personality
but you also get the project
nostalgia
shifted
soweto res
ponders from the circumstances forty
always
we don't know why
but at least under some circumstances
you've got transfer of inflicted
gambling
between personalities
even though you don't have transport
effect
for depth just the kind of former right
give with explosives had conscious
recollection
well that's what the interpreter l_b_o_
asians all about you don't get it
club
applauded it was a test
let me start tomcat
new flat you keep white and she was born
or something
blasted jonno bushels
assist
there is another category of psychiatric
disorders
historically related to web major which
we see this
job nation
these are what are known as the
conversion disorder
which are also pedestal neurological
disorders
in different versions of food
adyar charcoal
surfaces
observations talk shows
problems with
sensations
voluntary boulder i think they're part
of life
bluffton large lover when you do with
the appropriate corologis pepsi implied
that before he took advil there's
nothing warm yet
swiftly
so we have a set of
historical atmospheres
functional disorders
sensory function
the most common which would have killed
himself
itself lines
we also have to relatives
functional
plentiful respectful
motor functions
are going to get the idea here is that
jimmy conversion disorders
what you've got
abhijat nate had argued
a problem up aware of it
a person who's historically depth
the auditory systems working perfectly
well
here she is simply not aware
not consciously aware
of the article is good
into terrible ralph and both system
working pretty well
persons from college more
blood
we can see implicit memory spirit
untreatable disrupted disorders
the next question and inconclusive
production
incapable of conversion disorders
assured afterwards yes
tampa were unsealed
no
soft pedaling syndrome uprooted and
authenticate lost
wolf art movement or whatever
they could still feel sensation
so it's hard to follow up with vote will
be called the school to devote
convergent
all of the cost of the first place if
there were kept one
what web
moreover
we know what you have a pretty good idea
from the work go abroad vsnl dot com
group going on there
i think it was good
diario of the brain that
with had handled confidentially
attempting to locate
generate lutheran
but it's not just sort of thing
the request
you know we had to go
you know
i don't know enough about it would have
to be quite know what what happened
obviously station
i think what
what robert robert woodson
that's under a logical problem we know
what i think i'll that happens because
shortfall
dur penetration of the building
anatomical
in any event let me show you all
very interesting
recent poll
recently
already all sorts of them
of implicit perception and dog
near historical blind
worked for richard bryan dot kept the
country often australia
this was a patient who was or was
effectively blocked
point
one of the
stuff
transportation to and historically blood
had no visual experience
at all
hauled and off
that was apparently nothing wrong with
with the patient virtual
and what's right and the concrete
wants to put the first in february
discrimination fourteen thousand
situation
overweight fold
what will be eliminated
or in front of the correct choice
all all
with with one of
before the trip
their words
glanced over thirty three
protection performance
and what paul right from the fucking
bitch
with the show
that will go to sleep three to five
the first time
performed of palms chan
on this visual discrimination fast
just like the fact that the person who
had no experience in c
it's kind of like blindsided
things kind of idea
except in the case of flanked by
playstation v
organic deficit
p
chopped up with
fulfilled
you're going to stop it
something like that at all
but what your state
inflation
responded blog chance level termination
not forfeit
culture
and that other control tasks with a
triple white fluffy
performance for a fact that chance
the next twelve to turn the lights acog
given that he was which which is in full
performance goes back up to seventy five
percent
himself global two hundred
fitful
he trials
dad of history quite opposite
goes back to chat
here we have sufficient
lax
visual x
who is not a lot less please
funding through intrusions
that is essentially what infrastructure
peoplesoft
patience has no exclusive
individual dot
sufficient
behaviors guided fly fishing through the
woods
even india
rehab
bomb pathological cases
taken from a psychiatrist
seen football
dislocations of aware
problems not explosive within family
explicit for assistance with suction
in the absence of the any
associated grateful inflicted
conversion disorders
had to do with temptation
thoughts at this moment pat buchanan
memories identity
each of these cases
jogging
what you've got to if problems all
conscious
tilted toward person not consciously
aware
memory knowledge in identities
and dot
still important it would be great
the conversion before that
dot please not consciously aware
visual or destroyed
nevertheless
food
with
hysteria everywhere
perry was even more rarely studied under
laboratory conditions
but we can find fun things like system
republican plan there's a problem very
well studied white-painted notice
emotionally disturbed about the trip
thank you very much
do you want one