everything at berkeley takes longer than
it should
or clock is now fixed
that song
on the right time
let me just kind of wrap up on what we
talked about last time having to do with
the dissociate disorders
in modern psychiatric
taxonomy
there's a distinction made between
distorted disorders which
awareness of memory and identity
and the conversion disorders
which affect our wherein assaults
sensory perceptual functions
and all
phone fall winter and motor control
my own view is that that's a distinction
that we don't need to be uh... we don't
really need to be or making
because both the so-called associate
disorders and the so-called conversion
disorders involved the same underlying
pathology
which is a disruption in the five of the
monitoring or the controlling all
functions of consciousness
that's not attributable to any home
palpable bringing the unsold injury or
we're disease
and one of the young
interesting features of these disorders
is that they're reversible which is to
say they go away
eventually
on her usually quite temporary
and more important
all of the red of the reason why you we
should think of youths distorted
disorders
is that
the all
some but it was like a genic amnesia or
will show evidence of implicit memory
for things that he or she can't
consciously remember
and somebody with
so-called hysterical blindness
will show implicit perception for things
that he or she
uh... tent card catalogs
uh... cut the cc
so these two salsa disorders in fact
or very well name
because they involve
dissociation is
between explicit or conscious memory in
perception
and implicit or on conscious memory in
so just to make this clear who can say
that they're a bunch of different kinds
of the sosa disorders
there's somewhere the dissociation
effects conscious memory and identity
energetic and beautify the genic few
multiple personality disorder
there are
dispose of disorders that affect
conscious sensation and perception
these so-called hysterical blindness or
deafness or whatever
and then
there are all of the source of disorders
that affect not conscious awareness so
much as conscious control
all the so-called historical paralysis
where are the person is not able to
engage in
wonder another kind of voluntarily
home voluntary border behavior
such as finishes up from last time
what i want to do today is to turn to
any kind of paul
functional dissociation called as
witnesses said punctual associations
that we see
in the laboratory or as well as well as
well as in the clinic
and that's hypnosis
which we can define as a social
interaction involving two people
there is a subject and there is a
hypnotist
and what they had that this does is to
goa give to the subject of policy
gestures of various sorts all forum
adjective experiences all of which
involves some kind of alteration in
consciousness
either alterations in perception or
memory or the voluntary control of
action
in contrast to the usual kind of a magic
of experience where i say
imagine that your with your dog
okay and you imagine that your with your
dog but you know we're about to be with
your arbiter with recorded they're not
really there with your dog you're really
here
on
these fault suggested hypnotic
experiences already company dipped by
all uncut a degree of subjected
conviction that borders on delusion
all of the few giveth hypnotic subjects
a suggestion that
there with their dog they really think
they're with their dog
alm had a big reopened but all of
involuntary goes through the experience
of involuntary this that borders on
compulsion
if i ask you go back to be with your dog
take okay uh... see whereas my dog now
what does he look like he's got to do
all this deliberately
all over the effort
but in hypnosis
it's as if
though experience just happens
on has a kind of on didn
on quality to it
and since the late nineteenth century
since the time of shark owa engender a m
armpit knows this is going to be
interested not just because of the weird
thing people do with psychologists ought
to be able to explain it
but also because
in some respects
the phenomena of hypnosis
barest stronger phenotypic resemblance
to the symptoms of hysteria
leading various investigators to think
or hypnosis might serve as a laboratory
model
for the historical into solicit
disorders
we could figure out what goes on in
hypnosis
we might have a better handle
hall
what goes on
you know
in hysteria
so first thing to be said it is
that not everybody who gets a hypnotic
suggestion has a hypnotic experience
wayy too broad individual differences in
hypnotize ability or the ability to
experience hypnosis
and these can be objectively measured by
psychological tests that were developed
in the late nineteen fifties and early
nineteen sixties
still in use today somewhat analogous to
i_q_ test is at their performance tests
he'd taken i_q_ test the test though the
examiner asks you to do berries kinds of
things are supposed to reveal how smart
you are
you know hypnotized only scale
we don't just ask you to fill out a
questionnaire that's all i would like
no's' so right i think i get the pie
smaller whatever
we actually try to advertise you
all and see what happens so each of
these
standardized typifies ability scales
consist of an induction procedure that
contains suggestions for focused
attention
and all relax ation high closure
eventually a subject will close his or
her audience
and then the expert letter goes on to
give a series of tests suggestions
for various kinds of hypnotic
experiences the kinds of experiences
that hypnotized subjected sometimes have
and the subjects response to each of
these suggestions
is a value weighted by means of some
objective
behavioral criteria
go above the are most important of these
were of the bodies that stanford
university in the nineteen fifties and
nineteen sixties
stanford hypnotic susceptibility scale
all it is a very involved not devised by
a group of harvard
all for group id ministration
all the good actually
quality trial hold large number of
people
all for them
holdover
group of people through the soil
procedure once my personal record is
about five hundred
on huge classroom all above the one
place
uh... and then there are these also
called stamper profile skills which
allow us to measure
very fine individual differences among
the very highly
on at the participle
what kinds of suggestions
these are the kinds of suggestions that
are on the gold standard for the
measurement of hypnotize ability
stanford scale hall form cedars and a
empty
bom
so here's the are bringing nada
conduction there's a suggestion for ite
closure
and by the end of the induction most
subjects of close to rise that's the
behavioral criterion for passing that
item
on then subjects are asked to put out
their hans an experienced throughout
uh... and uh... magic that they're
holding on the phone aia heavyweight and
their hands and the weight is pushing
their hands and arms down and if they
had the moves down specified amount
in over a specified period of time
we record the subject is passing
that suggestion
then later on this uh... our suggestion
from the ski tow
on distance or that there's a mosquito
buzzing ongoing lee around your head of
the like to get rid of this mosquito
go ahead you're but if it if you want to
and we see whether the subject actually
waves his hand on toward this
mosquito or engages in some other kind
of along that activity
all
on here is a boy solicitation we tell
the subject of there's a lot of speaker
microphone combination over on the wall
next to his chair
and it's going to ask a missile solo
questions like go
do you have any brothers or sisters
and we dont
dirt determine the subjects response
by whether he actually engages in a
conversation
on one-sided conversation
with this all homes near the boys and so
on
towards the end we might test they are
post about x ingestion
set up a q that after the subject comes
out of hypnosis they'll respond to it
all and are very frequently
give a suggestion for post of nautica
amnesia
for a time they won't be able to
remember the things they did a
recurrence while they were multiple
times
so if you count this up there are twelve
items
and is so you can look at how all people
representative sample of the college
population scores on such a orson such a
scale
on this is work for a lot of fun
judge ordered historical guard stanford
who pioneered all of this work
all up and it turns out
about forty five percent of subjects
will cripple gault score
low on the scale all dawn
not very important
not very good for the price will but the
majority of subjects about fifty five
percent or at least moderately at the
participle
although
all about dot twenty percent or so
highly hypnotized blow by by the the
standards we usually measure
only a very small minority about five
percent of subjects
horrible be called hypnotic virtual
souls
uh... who seem to be able to do with
just about anything you ask him to do
all you know if it dose is desert
very very very
interesting subjects and
it's a real pleasure
it's a real pleasure to work with them
most of the stuff i'll be talking about
you today
are phenomena veteran served in this
group of subjects hypnotic virtual isos
found five maybe if you're lucky ten
percent all of the aisle of of the
population of college students
but you can see climbers
all these phenomena
in all or mere mortals if you will
club subjects who are of somewhat lower
or sid
hypnotized going
the usual contrast of hypnosis research
is between
subjects who are
low in hypnotize building who just don't
seem to experience of nosis at all but
are trying their best
on and these virtual os those who seem
to be able to do all sorts of malval
all sorts of things
so what do you think
well we see for example for example a
whole bunch of so-called associated
phenomena in hypnosis
in post of not i can be a show we see we
find subjects who can remember things
that they just did or experience
moderate at the time
on they respond to post about extra
justin's without realized without
remembering the suggestion consciously
or even knowing that they're responding
to the suggestion
all bilal responder suggestions for
sidearms
blindness or deafness
on bay yelled will do it
not be able to start the furor
for home
receiving the cell but when you
when he suggested there
blinder dot
on hypnotic analgesia
talk about quite a bit they don't seem
to experience very much pain
wilder the prize
and then there are a bunch of bomb
phenomena that we classifies hypnotic
hallucinations
on you karen home
i suggest to somebody that they're seen
something that's not their that's a
positive hallucination
you can suggest to somebody that they
can see some particular thing
that is right there bother them
that's in the uh... that's a negative
that's a negative hallucination the g_s_
size in section this week we're going to
play you about the uh... about video
rolled but would video
double demonstrate for most of these
from one of two u
i don't do classroom demonstrations of
hypnosis
or for that matter fraternity or
sorority demonstrations
of witnesses
now what do you make of all of this
people while you know they're they're
wrong
did you get some two subjects and
suggested they see something end up
that they can see something to say they
consider how do you know what they
really see
all often when people look at of the
problem of hypnosis
they react the same way as they do
through the phenomena hysteria
it's fake team it's saw third the that
that they conceive perfectly well
called
whereas what's interesting about this is
that nobody ever raises these questions
when somebody with actual brain damage
exactly the same thing
when age and came out of his surgery in
nineteen fifty three and couldn't
remember anything
nobody ever said yes you can
on nobody ever said that a gem was
faking
on his up his amnesia
ald with dvd the blind slight patient
study by widespread citizen so since
nobody ever claimed
that d_b_ really quincy
all of the things he said he couldn't
see
which leads into what i am sometimes
called the hysteria hypnosis paradox
which there's a group of the desert
there's arts school in psychology
that won't believe the self reports of
people unless their brain damaged
any kind of gotta wonder kind of what
the logic is arm behind that right
also of
look at this kind of
alicia leah some things that kind of
that i've got a hope will convince you a
little bit that the self reports the
beget forget the pie subject
do have some validity do seem to have
some truth elliott's but the whole idea
i mean
cognitive neuroscience and gunmen
cognitive neuropsychology is built on
accepting that face value the self
reports of people who were brain-damaged
right
also want to do it in other domains
old as well
here's a good example and that's with
ought hypnotic analgesia suggestions for
the hypnotic relief of pain
which since the eighteen forties before
the discovery of chemical analgesia
floyd and and anesthesia
have been used to all offer patients are
thought of substantial all of the
substantial pain relief
even in major surgeries like
appendectomy xenon caesarean sections
and off
orthopedic surgery and all sorts of oil
all sorts of things like that
now what's interesting about this
all about hypnotic analgesia
is that this is something that could be
studied both in the clinic with real
patients and real pain
and in the laboratory
with normal subjects people like you
would be
all who are having pain inflicted on
them by some kind of of laboratory all
of them procedure
here is a study bygone bernadette post
review actually bug-eyed montgomery in
his associates at the university of
connecticut
or meta-analysis is awful
analysis of various kinds of fell asleep
at the post
puts a whole bunch of studies together
all looking at the effectiveness of
hypnotic suggestions for analogies here
both across on what large number of
clinical studies
and across a large number of laboratory
studies
and what you can see here is
the overall effect size of hypnotic
suggestions for our parameters yet is a
very substantial
in social science research small effect
is about an effect ballpoint too
moderate size the factors that affect
orwell points of wellpoint dodo to two
point four so bigger facts are affects
salt with with with affect slices of
greater than point six
and that's exactly what we see here
these are substantial walking affects
on the are
on the perception of pain
both in the
kind of sterile artificial confines of
the psychological laboratory
and
in the applied
uh... confines of the clinic
this is called kind of uh... the echoes
the point that made before
the extent of obsolete of response to
suggestions for pain
is highly correlated with with with
hypnotic susceptibility
here we have people who score high on
all hypnotize abilities skills like that
standard form see that i told you about
before
and they're getting these wap in effect
sizes i mean these are nuclear physics
sized effect sizes right
alm
fear even subject some moderate
hypnotize ability can get substantial
pain relief
if i could tell you before you go into a
dental procedure we're going in for a
role
perot patient surgery
that by means of hypnosis i could reduce
your filled pain by one-third you take
it
alm and that's what we can get
in susceptible subjects
not so much
but even they can get a little bit of
pain relieving and susceptible subjects
get a little bit of pain relief
all promo from hypnotic suggestions
so what can you do here again bulb
because it will be to bring this
phenomenon into the laboratory in study
of under controlled conditions
he resolved research fight over argues
in a phenomenon called cold pressor
paying
you take a subjects forearm
and you
immersive circulating ice water
paul all about the water that sad zero
degrees centigrade and kept it but that
that uh... felt that uh...
of uh... printed return right
pause while on code kept it in there and
just take you're not going to feel any
pain
dawn record feeling your arms like
rubber you don't feel any pain at all
and the question is
or what kind of how much pain to
subjects experience organise and again
as in the clinical studies
you can see
that in susceptible subjects don't get
very much pain relief
subjects a medium hypnotize building get
more pain relief
ballpark at the price will be just
substantial amount of pain relief
all particular procedure
palm
here's all another very interesting
study by john started as associates at
washington university in saint louis
subjects called the beaver laboratory
subjects
through a whole bunch of different kinds
of the experimental procedures using
both
cold pressor pain that's the were seen
in arm often now in cold water
which in effect
and what's known as this gimmick muscle
pain this is a very interesting kind of
pain
where u
fallen use a blood pressure cough and a
clue dl flow of blood too though
forearm
and then u_s_ the person to do some work
with the forearm which exhausts the
oxygen
in waffles
and begins to or hurt like hell overall
very very very short criticizes on
believe oblique
best analog for clinical pain we've got
really are really great analog they'd
and your arm is turning technicolor
cousins dr dot the floods out of it in
all this kind of stuff
and so what they died they brought
subjects and fault though for this
although challenge the payment a whole
bunch of different kinds of treatments
hypnosis acupuncture placebo acupuncture
morphine aspirin all a bunch of other
drugs and all of that
and then looked at the comparative
effectiveness of these various kinds of
treatments
and the really interesting finding here
was that
of all these treatments
hypnosis gave the best
better then
true or placebo acupuncture better than
morphine workings not so good in the
laboratory for reasons that are not
completely clear it's great clinic but
it's not so good laboratory
aspirin halt world
or so on
although the compared to other kinds of
challenging agents
hypnosis is
pretty august frequent nala pick your
question
malcontent
there aren't any ethics issues because
there were informed consent
part of the procedures are we would
never ever do anything like this
well with subjects without them knowing
that we're going to do it
well when we do have nosis research in
my laboratory subjects know that there's
going to be hypnosis involved a
volunteer for it
so anybody does want to be hypnotized
will they get there
are keeping credit someplace else
song
diapering ever going to do anything
idon't think pain research myself
all but if we're ever going to do pain
research we would make sure that
subjects know what that's all
and no alright your arms turning
technicolor dot hurts like hell but
uh... goes away
all on the pretty fast is no there's no
organ damage or anything like that
all but
in this kind of research as in any kind
of research
informed consent is really important
it's absolutely critical
that subjects
nor what they're in for
before earth day well before they vote
tho before they
signed the contract as the world
uh... to super tuesday studies
or we have done
welcome dot typical under typical
induction of hypnosis will take about
fifteen min
yet they go to a whole procedure
so what we do is we could we know that
subjects are in susceptible to have no
sister highly hit the prize of all we
put all through the same procedure
on to see how good to see other respond
there are lots of their lots of design
issues in hypnosis researcher lots of
different ways to do it
all but the
that what i just described as the
standard basic paradigm for hypnosis
research
and the logic behind it is
on hypnotize will people ten experience
difficult since right
that but i think people can experience
opposes
all but otherwise
the nice thing is that
there aren't that there aren't serious
personality differences between high
above the proposal people so it's not as
if you're getting
or one kind of person and hypnosis
liberal mother kind of person
uh... otherwise
and there's really no way for us to
predict advisability of events either
onto the best
questionnaire coral of the fifth the
price ability of some fizzled
procedure called absorption
or subjects report all i get swept away
by sunset sore
i really get a group on what i'm
listening the in a ghada devito or
something like that
fallen and
those people tend to be a little bit
more highly of the prize of all than
everybody else
but the correlation is crumbling
it's point two oh
one point two oh if you're lucky
on and uh... that's just not enough to
service prediction
you all the way to know what somebody
said the price war
is to try to hit the tides and see if it
works
that's what the standard by skills were
all about
quick questions and then i gotta go on
iran never going to finish
it could certainly defer given the mood
and state of mind all because
performance on anything will be willed
it will be forgiven border state of mind
it could be the smartest person in the
world but if you don't
feel like it that day you're going to
flunk you're right cuteness
and it's exactly the same way
on here
on if you don't want to be hypnotize you
don't get hypnotize no matter what
no matter what the hypnotist does
in a very work in a very real sense of
all hypnosis is self hypnosis
and what they have the first really does
the doesn't put you in hypnosis
he tells you what to do it a put
yourself in
hypnosis
and uh... i've got to be in my career
i've done a lot of hypnosis research
i've worked with very experienced a
product subjects and i've become they've
become a one point right
i start my fifteen minutes hypnotic
induction patronizing
on people get myself in hypnosis and
on what you know what i'm ready and it
works just like
as i know what to do
thicket well here it's not a secure hit
over the head in hypnosis upon
you can give you can still talk about
forgive your suggestion that there can
speak anymore
you have some difficulty
mold ya
there but it's not just a difference of
allowing yourself or not
it's
it's like
it's really a skill
so you can view the greatest tennis
player in the world but if you don't
wanna play that day okay you're not
gonna play that day asking andrey agassi
all
if u our auction lumped like me
nothing in the world is going to make me
a world-class tennis player it's just
not going to happen
so it's not just a matter of ap of of
attitude or or or or wanting to do with
with all skilled performance
all all they cross the domain of
psychology
on performances of functional
interaction between
aptitude
you have the ability or not
and attitude
do ya wanna
palm
through and got out of both
and these subjects how both cause or
pain number they heard their interests
interested or whatever
but nothing in the world is going to
make somebody that the times more who's
not
it or more details about this there's a
lot of the lecture supplements i want to
strip club
the business about
how you get hypnotized more on and all
that and go right into on the berries
and very secure words
also okay that was all
doubles the cold pressor pain here is
the same kind of all fucking pattern of
findings
for all
for ischemic pain
and it turns out when you do psycho
physics to find out that there are
actually two components to the
experience of pain talked about this
election
earlier i think
there's what's known as sensory pain
which provides the person with
information about the location and
extent of some injury
and this will be call suffering
which has to do with the meanie
all the sensory
all pain these are just so civil
components of bald
of the pain experienced
and you might think well hypnosis
doesn't do anything to sensory pain the
pain still there
all somehow it doesn't bother
the patient all window or door or the
subject is much
on that turns out not to be true this is
work by jane oxfam queen's university in
canada
in which she collected
separate reports of sensory pain and of
suffering
from her subjects
and found the both of them were
substantially reduced so it's not just
operated on the so-called
psychological or emotional component of
pain
it's really operate on the pain
experienced
appoint all come back to on you know
okay so what do we make of this
aud dog john entails qatar surgeon
working in india are before the advent
of chemical are
anesthetics
all used to be nosis job with his
patience almost exclusively and had
quite a bit of success about it
and he kind of all of the big even he in
eighteen forty three eighteen forty four
faced what what i've called the hysteria
hypnosis paradox which is that people
just don't believe this
on and uh... as bill says you know
iv's i'd like to all the is reporting on
a whole series of volcanic ball
surgeries
major surgeries and which would knows
this was the only
analgesic agent
and he said the
i go least able to ways of accounting
for this
the first one you know all of my
patients also dob
well the the doctors an idiot
all he called me to pieces for twenty
minutes and i need to believe that i did
not
feel it at all
alm and and then kind of encouraging his
family members to go to
play the same joke on the doctor
all poor
they say they are
phone them for their brother sulfurous
look at me i've gotten rid of my carmike
burden
home uh...
while he didn't do this when i was about
a really didn't feel anything and that's
the experience
of subjects both in the clinic
laboratory
as dale
you can see what the date is here as
bill wrote this song monograph reporting
on problem hundreds of cases of surgery
successfully completed with the with
hypnosis is in full
unfold analgesic agent
right at exactly the same time as
was
demonstrating parental g flooded you
throughout the season for the first time
and uh... as i said there are big
individual differences responses nosis
but there are not big individual
differences in response to
onto easter another chemical island
anesthetic agents
and for that reason
i mean was crummy all pretty quickly or
hypnosis was kind of broad displaced
from the medical armament her room
small body home
by chemical anesthetics
but recently cards come back into along
from the comeback in the favor this is
work by our
workbook are weapons
all bio by relying
all was a dollop yard
on the position at harvard of harvard
medical school
who was not an anesthesiologist
uh... portable bunch of outpatient of
those surgeries
all of which employ conscious sedation
and patient controlled analgesia which i
described for you
a couple of weeks ago
and what lange did
was as an adjuncts as an add-on
party their days subjects of
idea of the giver patients on at the
uh... hypnotic induction and uh...
suggestions for analgesia reduced pain
or an attention manipulation basically
gave them a little distracting has and
looked at
added value might be of hypnosis
when you added to chemical
called chemical analgesia
and what you file found
was that the calm
uh... for that
did the added value nosis was all quite
quite great
here in black we see
all of them
uh... supplementation these are
conscious patients this is out patient
surgery conscious sedation
all to see that
all over the course of the procedure or
their reported pain
on goes up quite a bit
uh... when u
give the media attention the distracted
manipulation
all modulates
the pain somewhat bob when you add
hypnosis the pain actually goes down
over the course
of the arm of the midwest to again this
is clinical pain
usurpation real patients have been real
surgeries
or and off
hypnosis add something
on to well
to the procedure
dog lag is involved in a sort of what
we've done some
medical economic study showing
that hypnosis adding hypnosis out
actually cost effective
so do a little bit of extra charge for
the hypnotist
all by palm
that actually
that charge is compensated for
fewer side effects of the procedure on
uh...
less post-operative pain
wrong
vandals were two other things
that's exactly right so they get their
debt they're digging their drip
bulb although vault of bob ends up as a
painter of whatever
and they're going to go since with the
same time
exactly so
so you get this bill of this nice effect
so i don't want to do that
all get to get you to a brain imaging
studies i like your of them very quickly
all
altered which comes from pier rain bill
whose own neuroscientist at uh... about
at mcgill all university
he used a uh... this in the laboratory
study
palm
which archaea uh...
used at
different procedure too
put subjects in pain
which is not as hot presser remember
cool presser
you over some persons are banned
of circulating uh... circulate ice water
in hot presser you apply some electrodes
that paul
that heat to the skin won't damage the
skin
massively room on there for hours
but that they cats
it's painful
just like a kid touched off
very hostile or whatever
and then what he did was to give
subjects are hypnotic suggestions
that we're gearing simply to alter that
you call
that the plaza
you unpleasantness of the pain the sun's
the you know
the those suffering
component of pain and the nice thing is
that they did this inside a pet machine
so these are the subjects were we're all
of them
their brains were scanned
uh... at the uh...
at the time that they were going through
all this
and he looked at all i had to order for
regions of the brain
the primaries some out a sensory cortex
which is responsive to sensory pain
all records the location and the
intensity
of pain in various parts of body
and the anterior cingulate cortex
which moderates the of the suffering
component
volvo of pain
uh... it's a motion or on significance
and the first thing hard to be said here
is that
in terms of subjects self reports
you could actually see
telling people
they would prob have reduced suffering
from the pain
no-till reduction in the intensity of
the page
it's intended effect
and terms of self reports is a nice
reduction in
rated on pleasant us
no substantial reduction
and uh... in intensity
but the really interesting thing here
is what you see in the brain scan
let me see if i can
clothes off
and what you can see palms
on fears the enter rear of the dancing
itos cingulate cortex
you can see that there is essentially no
modification
called him the response was not a
sensory cortex between
height of the price of oil over to the
principal subjects
but there is a substantial
or reduction an activity in the anterior
cingulate cortex when these subjects
say they are
that those just doesn't bother them
so here you have one of these nice
little
home or in the brain
of the affects where the change in the
subjects experience
as a result of hypnotic suggestion does
seem to be reflected
in the changes in the subjects
or brain activity
there is reduced activity here
in the anterior in the interior single
cortex
there aren't that many brain imaging
studies that have no system to show you
another one
okay so
that's pain
here's another hypnotic phenomena is
what i've studied quite a bit called
posted nomic amnesia
where we kept the price subjects we
teach them a list of words during
hypnosis
give my suggestion that they will
remember the words that they've learned
that was
that there is any words
when the commodity nosis
until we give them a suggestion to
cancel the amnesia suggestion
now you can remember everything
so we do that
and then we give them a bunch of ball
of uh... memory test
here's all the rear of the results of
tests of
free recall
subjects are
low
medium height he's a virtual so subjects
and what you can see is
in susceptible subjects they don't
respond to the admission suggestion very
much the remember things perfectly well
sort of the subjects of medium at the
price billy
highly hypnotize ble subjects are
showing some degree caldwell of amnesia
here
alm and the virtual so subject
then i'll remember anything
then when you cancel the suggestion it
all comes back
these subjects
are now able to remember onwards
that they weren't able to remember
all of the previously
this is a test of free recall it's a
test of
explicit memory folding next question is
what would happen if you gave these
subjects attest of implicit memory
we did that
all here is with what we did was to give
subject supriya association fast
where the stimuli for the free
association coast
strongly associated
they were they were associated anyway
with the uh... with the yard target
words of the subjects of memorized three
nosis
so we give the stimulus boy
they had studied
words like girl
share flowers and short we gave the
stimulus boy
asking the people support for the came
to mind
the first were the came to mind
the first were the came to mind and
uh... and so on there were also some
control
of stimuli the day
before related words they hadn't studied
and what you can see here
is that
the in susceptible subjects who remember
the words that they had studied during
hypnosis perfectly well
showed a very nice primeval fact
so they're more likely to produce this
card as responses on the bundy board
association says
alternatives that they had studied
during hypnosis
but what you see here is
the same primate affect in the virtual
also subjects who were completely
amnesia then i'll remember the words
that they studied during hypnosis
yet they are
just as likely
as the in susceptible subjects to
produce on his words as well
and three associates
so again there's now a lot of evidence
this is the first of these studies
know a lot of evidence the suggestions
for post if not i can be shipped
impair
explicit memory or conscious
recollection
of things that happened during hypnosis
but they have no effect on implicit
memory these kind of unconscious
influences
of the
of the study experience
here as well
similar studies with with that we used
our own
uh... category
uh... numbers
in explicit memory when you reverse the
amnesia
all the memories come back
but in this particular experiment
the subject studied women's first name
is
body parts
for footed outils
on times
home and all we asked them
simply too
first woman's name it comes to mind
first body part the comes to mind first
animal
that that comes to mind and dot and so
on
what you see here teaches
very nice priming effect
for subjects are more likely
the ences apple subject to remember the
items perfectly well are more likely to
all produce
items from the study blisters free
associates
exactly the same priming effect
from the virtual so subject who dole
remember the list
again another demonstration
the dissociation between explicit
and implicitly
on skipping over this
for a second cousins
it'll take me to one
you can see the same kinds of
dissociation is
in the perceptual domain dissociation
between explicit and implicit perception
here is a study by richard bryant and
kevin mccarty than at macquarie
university and not in australia
on hypnotic blindness
took a bunch of virtual so hypnotic
subjects
gave them a suggestion that
for the time being
even though the rise rope and they
wouldn't be able to see things at work
that were all
over in front of them
on has had the subjects open their eyes
can you see this could be a little
frightening for subjects
all of these subjects were on word well
used to hypnotic procedures they that
they've been lots of other experiments
before so
they were able to
what's going on
and at what called the what they did
while they're always were open but they
said they couldn't see anything
albright in the country
who held up cards
that that don't work based on that bike
experiment hundai comic listening i
showed you before
that consisted of a printed hollow phone
plus a descent big you waiting for you
warren peace
toward us some of these words were
presented while the subject was hypnotic
we blind couldn't see them
said he couldn't see them
others were presented while the subject
was not could not agree blind you can
see them perfectly well
and then later on all day followed up
with a memory test
and that spelling test
in which they were presented with the
hubble phones
or hair
and asked
how they would spell it
obviously as in the eye can experiment i
showed you of earlier
on if u
actually process this did spell peace
p_d_a_s c_e_o_ supposed to p r_u_c_
if you all that you would actually
process the somehow
did spell hair h_ a_ r_ t_
which nobody ever does
as opposed to all as opposed to age a
high are
here is the all
pollen
the art of results
on wrote from rome
recall
all of this them subjects
didn't recall any all the words that
they had not seen
you don't consciously perceive something
you're not going to consciously remember
appalling either
but wasn't from what was interesting
here is that
the subjects showed
a big priming effect on the hubble phone
spelling test
so that
they were more likely
you would expect by chance
to show that had to spell peace
p_ a c_
forestville hair
h a already
showing that despite the fact that they
didn't have the conscious experience of
seeing nevertheless the visual stimulus
godin was processed was processed for
meaning and influence their performance
on this priming test
in the same way that posted melodic
engager
the star dissociate explicit an implicit
memory
conscious memory from unconscious
influences of memory
phenomenon like hypnotic blindness seems
to dissociate
explicit and implicit
perception
conscious perception is missing is
impaired
unconscious perception as revealed by
these priming effects
pretty much com
are pretty much spirit
okay we're not going to talk about post
a blog suggestions
instead
what we're going to do
hong
with all the really interesting study
called
the hypnotic alterations in color
perception workplace even cost money
on ben at harvard university's now back
at stanford worth of his p_h_d_
arm
that it's another one of these pet
imaging studies
he studies were done a little while ago
also too
mod will bother people don't do pet
imaging anymore but pet imaging has one
advantage over f_m_ arrive when you're
doing hypnosis research
and that is
that its client
the aftermarket she's on believable in
origin
and it's very difficult that there are
some studies of people sleeping and i'm
alright machines are
i don't know how they do it
my honest to god i don't know how to do
it
palm
but all
uh... it's just it's just not easy to
get in state at the price before that
bangin inclined going on but pat is
pretty quiet
and so that's actually the preferred
brain imaging procedure
offer these kinds of experiments anyway
what kozol unpaired wants to look at the
consequences for brain activity of
hypnotic suggestions for color blindness
and four color on them for a and for
colourful insulation
the employed
patterns like this in fact these are the
patrons he employed
all you can see this is a uh... but
uh... you know
that colored pattern
this is phone grayscale pattern
where different blocks and and and
rectangles
have exactly the same brightness and
intensity as the color blocks they're
just devoid of any color
uh... brandeis control
so all bloody what caused you and dad
was to take
hypnotic subjects is our again virtual
so subjects
and a custom under a couple of different
conditions
ald
he would present them with the colored
pattern
suggests of them that they're just seen
a ordinarily as uh... as it was in color
and than all later on
he would uh... present them with the
colored pattern
and give them a suggestion
that they'd they were that that they
have lost all color vision
and they're all the caller was draining
out of the stimulus
all so that they would put all these cdi
grayscale
anymore this practically and negative
hallucination
because you are
that since the suggestion is that you
won't be able to see something
that's right there
in front of you
so those are the first two conditions
in the third condition you presented
subject of the gray scale pattern and
ethnicity and grayscale
okay just see it the way you do
ordinarily see it
and in the last condition
he asked them presented the gray scale
pattern
now colorist
flowing into the started it into the
stimulus
the same colors that you can also a
before
that's technically a positive
hallucination subjects actually said
that they experienced these things
when he's asked me to see the color
pattern in color
they could name the colors
when u_s_ in ought to see the color
pattern in grayscale they couldn't
when you ask him to see the gray scale
pattern and color they pointed to
various colors or pumping even though
there was no colder in the stimulus
now that's their standard hypnotic a
fact
the question is what's going on with the
brain the reason we asked this question
is that there are certain
uh...
yes they work
hall died
dot on dot showed what
but but yes they were reduced wanted to
use one stimulus
they gave the important thing is alm
and that this is
perhaps above the small glitch in the
experiment
he counterbalance all these conditions
so across conditions the order a
presentation of these tests or was uh...
what what what what was different
we'll plan
the color was supposed to flow in
he didn't speak didn't specify any
particular color
out here
alone
and with great skill ups subjects were
experienced all with with the preschool
patterns and with that
this is
this
is what this pattern would look like if
you were totally colorblind
no because it's been so i think that
this was the first thing goes they would
have known what colors
there were but there was color
arsov subjects called and said that they
saw
blues and reds and yellows and greens
and all that kind of stuff and what's
interesting about this is
but there is not part called the brain
known as the fuse a form cholerae up for
those of you who got some neuroscience
frogman areas nineteen and thirty-seven
homes and also
rodman area twenty in the inferior
temporal region
that seems to be active wet
people art
involved with oradour seen colored
stimuli
that is princeton or that have some kind
of
and are what caused wind i've discovered
was that activity in these two
caller
areas all of the brain was modulated by
hypnotic suggestion
so that when subject stars showed
warsaw plug the colored pattern in color
these areas were active
when subjects or the colored pattern in
grayscale
activity was diminished in precisely
these areas
when subjects or the gray scale pattern
in grayscale
there was diminished activity in these
areas cause there is no colour in the
stimulus
and no colour in the experience
when the subject thought the gray scale
pattern
they hold loosening of the color
these brain areas got active uh... that
active again
so what's interesting about this study
as with the rain bill study
is that you can see
changes in the brain
that correspond to
the suggestions
ought to be given by the hypnotist
and be experiences the perceptual
experiences
better be reported
been reported by the subject
okay so there is actually just another
that way you
on them
presenting that uh...
kind of data
so what we can do now is to summarize in
the same way as we did for the decisive
disorders
what it is that altered
in hypnosis as an altered state of
consciousness
and what alter it is
conscious awareness
that the person with automatic and egypt
is not consciously aware of memories
that he's got
the person with hypnotic blindness or
hypnotic echoes is not consciously aware
of visual or auditory perception
what is
impaired by hypnotic suggestion is
explicit memory or explicit
of perception
what spared despite these suggestions is
what we now recognizes implicit memory
or implicit
implicit reception and again the nice
thing is part that when you can do it
our brain imaging hard shows
the brain
patter brain activity is changing
in a manner that correlated with these
suggestions and their reports
okay
hysteria and hypnosis or to
psychological alterations in
consciousness i suppose doctor michael
alterations and consciousness
next week will take up
on a couple more
with a focus on
meditation as an altered state of
consciousness and its consequences for
cognition
and brain activity
thank you very much
have a good weekend