okay one we begin
last time i talked about tried out of
life the mind-body
has to do with the relations between
mind and body
into four separate problems
and on wednesday i talked about the
first of these
which is
how we get from the body to the mind
the problem of the new role correlates
of consciousness
what parts of the nervous system
appeared to be implicated in various
kinds of conscious experiences
now look what i didn't talk about less
time with the distinction
that before through david chalmers makes
between
although would cause the easy problems
or maybe he's problems of consciousness
and the hard problems of consciousness
he characterizes the stuff i talked
about last wednesday essentially as a
newsy probable consciousness
it's easy to determine that the
reticular formation is associated with
consciousness or
that all
area of the one is associated with
conscious x or seen it
and uh... area of the four is associated
with
all the experience of seeing color
but then his points out that there are
that leaves completely on addressed
all problems which he calls the hard
problem of consciousness
uses the singular but
when you read his book to find figure
out
pretty quickly that there are actually
two of these
and of the first one always the one that
victims five actually talks about when
he clutches his head mauldin that
passage
how do brain processes produce
consciousness
how do the operations all nor on the
switches all we've got in the brain
five generate
conscious experiences mental states
farm
the idea that there is something that's
like to see red door be angry or
whatever
and
none of that
none of that material that i talked
about last time
dresses dot that mechanism problem
at all
we might be able to find out
what body parts are necessary for
consciousness
which is what the neural correlates of
problem for both
how we get
the operation of those brain parts
to conscious experiences isn't uh...
isn't at all clear
the second aspect of what robbers calls
the hard problem
is off
the problem of why
the brain processes
produce consciousness
it's pretty clear their brains process
information
that they take information from stimulus
inputs
walk around with them somehow
and then generate responses to those
stimulus simplex and that's pretty scott
clear
how all of that could happen in some
kind of mechanistic
on the mechanistic
although the west erasers
why
this consciousness associated with any
of this why does it at all just go on in
the dark
why don't we just operate
the weight we operate
processing stimuli and making responses
to them
without any kind of conscious experience
at all
this problem problem of mechanism how'd
of brain processes produce consciousness
i have to tell you does not keep me up
at night
farm
that's an interesting question i suppose
but it's a question for the girl
biologists who care
just album ilike have any interest in so
i don't talk about it all
wind a brain processes produce
consciousness is a little bit more
maybe metaphysical problem
why does it all just go on in the dark
palm it's probably flooded the intuition
here
is that being conscious has some kind of
adaptive function
it makes a difference
whether all goes on in the dark
all all that goes on unconsciously
or whether as somehow we have conscious
experiences associated with
the processing of stimulus inputs and
the generating of respond so please
maybe why doesn't hold just although all
go on in the dark
is a question we might be able to have
an answer for by the time the semester
ends
but before we can get their i think we
have to find out a little bit more about
what consciousness
what context does
so now let's turn to the second all of
these problems of consciousness with
sigmund freud called
the puzzling weep
from the minds of the body going the
other way
how do mental states and mental
processes
the functioning all the body
and in his up in this case study of the
rat man
all gone before you don't think the says
the same thing the victim stein was
saying accepting his act lee
the end of the freezing it presented
exactly the opposite way
from a mental process
to a simatic innervation the leap from a
mental state
to a bottle we change is something that
can never be fully comprehensible
all to us
nevertheless called we all have balm
we all share i think they cards notion
that somehow our mental states do cause
our bodies to be hate in various ways
for one a raise money or i said i want
to raise my arm in my arms build-up
there's something something there where
this has been all print all of the bell
but most interestingly i think
the problem of
the affect all of the mind on the body
is an area of the is in a medical
literature psychiatric literature
having to do with water called
psychosomatic contractions
and this has it's all about the idea
that somehow
mental states can affect disease
prophecies
that on that that in turn
affect the operation old-boy of the body
again in the earliest all of the in the
earliest history of this
alm the idea of psychosomatic
attractions comes to us mace basically
from
freudian psychoanalysis
famous song
uh... psychoanalyst frogs alexander
wrote a whole book all based on author
his ideas about the kinds of mental
states that produced various on
gregarious physical diseases
anorexia nervosa was supposed to be
caused by unconscious feelings of envy
and jealousy
and peptic ulcers were supposed to be
caused by unconscious infantile
dependency
uh... bronchial asthma
or excessive on resolved dependence on
one's mother
calm
hypertension high blood pressure
chronic inhibited aggressive impulses
and what our dive arthritis
called was all or was caused by
while rebellion of the conflict
that instant was when one rebels against
restrictive parental influences me can
kind of see how these kinds of
psychoanalytic stories
disciple of experience worked out
here is alexander's ward at all
all of them
uh...
detailed formulation for the yeti ology
a pair of peptic ulcer home
we've got this infantile dependency here
which leads inferiority feelings
which leads to norse assisted protest
and that over compensation to become a
big man where a big gone
all u_n_ delegation very aggressive
behaviors you feel guilty over that and
all that goes right to your stomach
and creates a whole that creates peptic
ulcers
that's the yacht that that's the classic
formulation
and at all
with infantile dependency and on resolve
oedipus complex is and all of that
palm
and all of that kind of stuff
more recently people have tried to
formulate all more modern
nonna psychoanalytic
fault of the idea of though
mental states could cause physical
diseases like alarm michaels
and what you might call modern
psychosomatic formulation
begins with something like the so-called
flights or flight reflex described by
the physiologist walter the famine
all you know it
in nineteen fifteen
we know that
when an organism and counters some kind
of stress
all the order of correct for the
environment
reacts through that threat
lagi thereby fleeing from the threat or
fighting against
and that calm about the threat
with all this is mediated the flight or
fight syndrome is mediated by the
autonomic nervous system
where threat
activates the sympathetic branch of the
autonomic nervous system and later on
the parasympathetic branch kicks into
marginally
though the sympathetic uh... arousal
and all the i don't know when you can
see it over here but
it's true anyway
palm that
for example all the synthetic nervous
system
for the sympathetic activation
has a whole bunch of
physiological or of that
physiological consequences one of which
is three and a hip
on digestive secretions
alm
uh... and dog that uh... if your
exposed to prolonged stress of course
that cat last very long you're starting
to consume blood sugars and things like
that
so your
starts working again start secretly
digestive
of on the fluids
to going to get more blood sugar into
the body
but there is nothing there to digest
and so gastric acids instead of eating
away at your hamburger rear speakers bar
eat away at you were at that that your
stomach lining instead
and that's what creates ulcers
so you don't have to have a whole new on
resolving dependencies on your mother to
get all service
all you got to do
is to be exposed
prolonged fred
and that's the general
one of the general all the way
most of these all modern psychosomatic
ideas or or college
so all of that can be summarized in what
sheldon cohen and others have called the
stress disease connection
where exposure
to psychological stress in one form or
another
all probably chronic psychological
stress may be a cute certainly chronic
sought
includes no no
to increase on people's risk
four various kinds of diseases
and some of these are
so-called mental illnesses like
depression
but also it turns out
that exposure to chronic stress
increases a person's risk for various
so-called physical diseases
like cardiovascular disease
extra chronic stress increases your risk
for proper car various kinds of
cardiovascular disease
all by about fifty percent
palm
there's actually a evidence now that
exposure to not everybody who has h_i_v_
infection
gets ames
all but it turns out that poem maybe if
you've got h_i_v_ infection and you are
exposed to to chronic stress
buster keaton increases by about fifty
percent
uh... the likelihood of progressing
from h_i_v_ aids and
increasing risk for all sorts of
complications
and there's even a little literature
on lovers not is convincing
all but there is a literature
that suggests that called old chronic
stress levels
or related to uh... increased risk for
cancer
the evidence for this don't do these
kinds of experiments in the laboratory
right we don't
expose people to chronic stress from an
infected with h_i_v_ and see if they get
a
all but
they resolve that
they're all you do is lots of evidence
for what you like all natural experiment
for beacon do have to be a logical
studies
measure stress levels in various ways
and then look at the correlation between
of the between stress levels
and various kinds of various aspects of
disease
either the onset of the disease
or the progression of the disease how it
develops
or the recurrence of the disease once
it's been treated complications from it
star stress seems to be involved in the
whole of these kinds of things
and we now know something about how this
is mediated now this is not a physiology
class so we got to go over this really
lightly
but it turns out
that there is what's known as the h_ p_
a_ axis the hypothalamic pituitary ugly
a portable
our taxes all seems to mediate a lot of
these are stressed disease connections
so that
when you're algo under under stress
the hype a palace releases are critical
problems releasing factor itself
probably substance
which affects the pituitary
uh... which releases the virus substance
which affects the adrenal glands which
supreme court us all and we know that
cortisol has a wide variety of
oval of affects
bodily function
similarly
there is yet another axis here known as
a sympathetic adrenal medullary axis
although the consequence of activation
of the sympathetic nervous system
although there are catecholamine summer
release
on that have hall all sorts of affects
on all sorts of barnali on the system to
the idea of your wrist
that it's either by virtue of the h_p_ a
axis
or by virtue of the essay on maxis
affects small
as medical effects on the body
and produces
produces the stress disease
so the physiology of this is beginning
to work a bid to be worked out
all what's not
always been claire unfortunately is what
is meant by stress
all walter buchanan that's him up there
island actually
the term stress you wouldn't know that's
the term stress is actually quite recent
on he didn't used rescues
all but they love the bug dog of the
cabins idea of the flight or fight
syndrome paula is really
really implies the concept of stress
though the idea of stress was first
introduced by all british all of the
position hans ellie
on nineteen thirty six
i need to find his any but in any event
the challenges on organisms current
level of physiological or psychological
adaptation
which sounds like a really good position
if we try to figure out what it means
physiological or psychological
adaptation
are celery all of the better for the
distinction between positive and
negative stress
distressed which is negative and you
stress
which is positive
and he makes the point
they're getting married
pretty much as stressful as getting
divorced
so i had a good bit adjusted just
because all sorts of good things are
happening to you
doesn't mean
uh... that europe that you're not under
stress
fall there all the even positive ads can
challenge your current level of
physiological or psychological
adaptation
sheldon cohen at carnegie mellon
university is really kind of the king of
stress of disease
these days
and he's defined all of the stress as
the
although the perception
that environmental demands tax
or exceed
the organisms adaptive capacity
probably as good at
twelve general conceptual definition
stress
as a as you can find
there's this whole literature out there
about stress and disease
fortunately on this is a literature that
drives most physicians crazy
all and they have been got got a gun to
some lengths to try to get rid of it
the idea that mental states could cause
bodily functions is not something that
modern medicine really likes very much
because they want to know all about
viruses and bacteria and all of that
kind of stuff
physical states that cause
uh... but close though
cause disease
home
and here's the good example of this
this is work by marshall and warren
or to australian oppositions they've won
the nobel prize for the first couple
years ago
who discovered
fog that at all people who had the
pollsters all were highly likely about
eighty eight percent
of patients with with law
all of that with all sorts
were infected with a particular
new form a bacterium
all called off helicobacter pylori light
age
uh... each pile or right
so this is all from there
or bridgeable study
eighty eighty eighty five ninety percent
of people with all service
had which by law right all over their
gods
people who just had gastric inflammation
much less likely
people of problems with called excessive
liver bile
a less likely
and patients who complained of
gastrointestinal problems but that prove
normal lung biopsy
hong
though again had
much reduced level called palm
became law right
infection leading all of them uh...
marshall and warren to conclude
that caught it's age high low right
infection that causes ulcers
okay so that's a physical condition
causing
a physical condition
leading
although steven hyman who was then the
director of the national institute of
mental health
an essay entitled another one bites the
dust
the time-honored attribution obsessed
symptomatic ulcers to stress alone
may result from a
theory driven retrospective
falsification
on that is one of those workers are
looking up the through the person
and you can always find some kind of
stress
getting married can be a stressful is
getting divorced than everybody's under
stress
all the time
applying to college can be stressful
getting into college can be stressful
graduating can be stressful all gone you
can always find stress
stress on the perception of stress are
notoriously difficult to define with any
precision
all basically goes on all your name in
this essay to say
that progress in psychiatry in the field
of mental health in general will will
occur
two of the expect that we get randolph
mental talk
and start talking about biological park
so what we want or we search for are the
biological basis of various mental
disorders
and develop all done at the biological
methods one brainstem brain damaging
form for diagnosis
and developing biological cures
like uh...
like medication
hyman's
or that's him or outright there'd be a
great after he left on their image
became the provost of harvard university
so visa guidance
pretty powerful
on you know
medical field
here's our good example all bottom of
all the historical trend of the
twentieth century that you might want to
call the biologists nation of mental
illness
which begins
with this wonderful quote from ralph
gerard zone uh... famous physiologist
behind every twisted fought there lies a
twisted molecule
plan dog thomas install boost the
current
director of n_r_a_ image
has no has written of recent paper in
melbourne inside of american
in which he says no row imaging has
opened up the black box for the brain
so that mental disorders
candies the studied for the first time
as abnormalities in brain connections
the idea that mental states comfort
nothing arbatov of the psyche counts for
nothing
that old mental illness is off
is brain disease
and we can see this
alm
we can see it all this solved but that
kind of thing towards buyers biology
station
lots of different aspects of the current
field of mental health
the idea of mental health mental illness
is construed as virological disorders
it's been it's gone now
so don't look for it
but it used to be there on the and i a m
age website
there was a off the headline that said
depression is a real nice
and the reason what they what they meant
by that was depression was a real
miller's because people with more
depressed
have brains to look different don brain
scans
people who don't have depression
as if the pression wasn't the real
illness before
frame images
so modern psychiatry ten super for
biological explanations over
psychological explanations for various
kinds of mental disorders
they tend to produce prefer biological
treatments over psychological treatments
all and in general
all positions of all times
tend to discount the role of
psycho-social factors
indices and its treatment and it's
precisely those kinds of psycho-social
factors
generate issue here but we want to talk
about
how the mind affects the body
the burial label psycho somatic illness
implies that somehow the person's mental
state
affects
on his or her
physiological
on function we're not talk about raising
your right arm anymore
we're talking about how your mental
state can affect
something interesting inside your body
so anyway all
the all of the discovery of h pile or i
seem to ah... put the last mail in the
coffin
of the psychosomatic account of all
service
ulcers are due to
bacterial infection
rather than to any kind of stress
until people started looking at this all
the
more closely herbert wider recently
deceased fellow long-time of
medical psychologist at u_c_l_a_
pointed out that yes it's true as
marshall and warren discovered
that virtually everybody who has peptic
ulcers is infected with age
by law right
but it turns out
everybody's in fact at the page five oh
right right
on and it's not the case that our word
that we all have also received resulted
not everybody is infected with h_i_v_ or
aids suffers from peptic ulcers
you can do survey of also free control
our people
not patients who had gastric problems
as warranted marshall did
what do all of population
all sort of a
and you can find or age by law right
infection in about eighty percent
halt all through
all free controls
on normal whiter in fact estimated the
roughly half the world
had are clinically significant levels of
infection
with each pyloric
suggesting that
age by lori infection might be necessary
for all sirs to occur
what it was insufficient
all and implying
that what you really paul need to have
is home
is often have something else may be of
some kind of psychological factors
here's the kind of data people talking
about this is a popular this is laid off
broom result of a random sample global
their patients
signed the world all
stations of gastric ulcers
and uh... thoda good carefully matched
controls
patience with the one lol ulcers
and carefully matched also free controls
and on
because did concede that
while it's true
that patients with ulcers are more
likely to have each part laura infection
the control patients are also extremely
likely
that had exploring infection
suggested again
appalled that this is that this is an
that they'd camel rides
may be necessary but isn't sufficient
all but one response this is all
bruce over my ripping university of
minnesota
and robert bristled at the university of
very good
and uh... in norway
all i have uh... produced of
evidence for what they call a nice
also called by apus the stress model
parole sirs
by apple so stressed models and and and
medicine
argued that any particular episode of
disease is a product of the interaction
of two factors
dialysis factor
which were renders a person former will
piss on disease
and a stress factor
which precipitates thank you
song
uh... that that the silk in but but only
in not invulnerable patients
and so they argue
that called
that over myron morrison argue that
stress
dot just as in the modern psychosomatic
model
secrete gastric acid into the stomach
amak gastric acid the roads to stomach
lining
and because all solution
h_ pylori infection increases a person's
vulnerability
to disarm rogen process
but doesn't create gastric ulcers hong
all all by itself
and if that's the case
then you have at least two different
ogle option
for treating
on gastric ulcers u_p_s_ give the person
an antibiotic like a rented ratcheting
which attacks age by were right
do something psychological
of like bom
put the person through what some kind of
stress reduction
so what's the evidence for this
all over myron morrison actually dug
developed evidence for this in a
i'll have a role model
all bolsters
they're not going to go out and pick a
random sample of college sophomores and
in fact there do you know i systems with
age pylori amend subject them to
lots and lots of stress
they did this and rats
are born and raised in the yard in in
the lab so they're either free image
pylori infection
or at least called
uh... that they were randomly assigned
to conditions
uh...
regardless of the rich for lawrence
and we know that there is a there's an
experimental technique
are called restraint and water
hard every water blueprint of produces
gastric ulceration
uh... in uh...
in rats
what you do is to put the all of them
put the out a little glass to
and then you stick the glass children
and the animal doesn't drone or anything
like that but they don't like it at all
and uh... what what what
when when you well and you wouldn't
either
farm
fala and dog but what happens is the
start their technique reliably produces
gastric ulceration
all of the day
substantial percentage of rats
who are treated with this restraining
they'll develop ulcers as a result of
that
and here's the first entry point
or we have to rack is conscious while
it's restrained in water
do you get up to do you get all sorts
that's a very cool fight
so if you anesthetize the rat
stick them in the tube stupid to water
over too well look at the rat
noel sort
but if the rats conscious while this
whole goes on that's when it gets
holsters
also wotol or immersed in bed
was to of the based on the heart of the
phenomena which some of you all of you
took psychology one and shorter familiar
with the phenomenon called learned
helplessness
which occurs when
organisms whether they're rats are cats
or dogs are recruitment
are exposed to uncontrollable
on shock
that is
they just get shocked that there's
nothing they can do about it that
induces a psychological state known as
word helpless
and what over myron morrison dead ones
before their animals were put in this
restraint of water treatment
they got prior stress treatment by being
exposed to both uncontrollable
and on predictable
all uh... for chuck in various
combinations
so they've got
exposed uncontrollable and unpredictable
for choc
them they were given the restraint of
water conditions
and papa and then all of you know that
they've looked at the whole ulceration
let me get results like this
here are animals
this is the amount of ulceration
so you've got out of those who just got
restraint and water
your animals several of exposed to
unprofor uncontrollable shock
bombardment of controllable shock
so there's a big increase and alteration
of the animals who had prior exposure
to one controllable shock
here's another experiment
restraint of water only
here are animals that were are exposed
to
uncontrollable and on predictable shock
big increase of ulceration
and your animals route response or
exposed to
uncontrollable both predictable shock
and also
a big increase
you know in northridge
here and you have clearer
evidence although causal effect of
stress
on all serbs this is not due to age pile
all right
press for the first place these rights
don't have aged by law right it even if
they did there's a random
of employment of animals to conditions
each per lori infection is spread across
all the young
hold the uh...
conditions of the experiment
so if you can if you except
an add'l model for human disease which
most biologists part of it
too
on here is
clear evidence floor causal affect of
stress
of them very nice
demonstration of the psychosomatic
effect
i'll skip those
the experiments like this give us a
followed by a very nice way to
operationally define
psychological stress if you look at
those classic definitions you know
perception of retin challenge though i
had to adaptation
they are as hyman point as hyman out of
the crash site
kind of a
but in these kinds of experiments
all redefine stress
as open as a sort of circumstance
where salient events or unpredictable
were on controllable
and think about these in terms of
kind of animal condition experiments
and classical conditioning animals are
trying to predict
the occurrence of up on condition
stimulus
based on the condition stimulus
instrumental conditioning animals are
trying to predict
the occurrence of reinforcement
based on a conditioned response
those so-called helplessness experiments
animals can do that
on condition stimulus for the
reinforcement
either unpredictable
or uncontrollable
and the point of all of this is where do
you think about it for a second
or unpredictability in on
controllability our mental states
they are beliefs about the world
i can't predict what's going to go along
i can't control or what's going on
they are about something although in the
world their mental states and to the
extent
called blood these mental states of
unpredictability and uh... on
controllability
all going to create a background against
with although against which ulcers can
occur here you have
these are the mental state
that is causing andy allen a cinematic
uh... the state
on mental state
possible this were disease
these classic psychosomatic affects
are one domain
in which we can study the effects of the
mind of of mental mental state
on the body
here's another one
all what's known as the placebo effect
all which is defined as
any treatment
forum illness which does not which is
not specifically affective for that
illness the so-called sugar pill
and we can to find the placebo effect is
arthur shapiro did
as the nonspecific
psychological or cycle physiological
effect produced by a placebo
and the placebo effects of sometimes
been called
the jewel in the crowd of psychosomatic
medicine
because everybody
uh... a things while that stuff
placebos song
have an effect various disease processes
placebos
always entail
bell boli
that person is that that the person is
taking
overdose on active
on kind of drug that's what that's worth
reported both start
and again becasue placebo effect this is
something that many many physicians want
to get rid of this quickly if they can
again because
physicians like to have biological
treatment
for physical illness they don't want to
have psychological treatments
for physical illness
and the two european our investigators
are probing arts and culture
uh... been a very provocative of the
study
a couple of years ago
in which they denied that in fact there
were any placebo effects
which is quite interesting
although and they've been hearing on
which which really
it is very important
all goes as follows
placebo effects they are going to come
up against the standard clinical trials
for drugs
if you're a drug manufacturer and you
want to do a drug or that you want to
show the f_d_a_ the food and drug
administration
ventured roadworks or what you want to
do is to take two groups of patients
give one random though randomly assigned
them to
the drug war to a placebo
phone
and all you can get your drug approved
on if
the june opec to the drug is greater
a placebo
and that's a fall
drug manufacturers usually do
they have to conditions of their
experiments
the active drug
and a placebo order that condition
called
and uh... there'd their content to show
and for that matter the f_d_a_ is
content for them to show
that of the drug
works better all of them in the uh...
than the placebo
but probably arts and got shipped all of
them said they did well
okay
and within three minutes talk alike that
you can see you can show that
the of the placebo all of the heart of
the has some affect on the disease
process
but you don't really know
the magnitude of the placebo effect
unless you include
eight third condition and your
experiment which is of no treatment
control condition
the placebo condition
it's a control freak a placebo effects
of the drug
but you don't know what the placebo
effect of the drug is unless you've got
another group of patients and don't get
anything
and nobody does that
in drug trial
why would you
all your asked although you're being
asked to show
is that your drug is better than a
placebo so you're not going to go to the
expense
volvo of the producing
no treatment control so what you really
need if you're going to show that you're
going out the all look at the magnitude
of placebo effect
you've got to be able to do three
analyses
comparing
the drug treatment for no treatment at
all
you get what's known as the drug effect
that is the advantage of the drug over
doing nothing
second
you want to look at the magnitude of the
drug affect
compared to the magnitude of the placebo
effect
that difference is known as the specific
aspect of the drug
whatever that is
but by the same logic if you want to
know what the
if you will the specific aspects of the
placebo is you want to be able to
compare
the placebo
what happens when people get a placebo
to what happens
when people
get nothing now why would you do that
well because the medicine we note that
there are lots of cases of spontaneous
remission you get a cold you wait long
enough to goes away
to get a pain to wait long enough it
might go away
hard to get high blood pressure rio
just sit there for a while and that
michael way through
you've got to know what happens when
people
so what robertson and got your dad
was to sunday p available medical
literature and find a couple of hundred
studies
which had all three conditions
a permit him to evaluate the drug a fact
the specific a fact
and the placebo effect
the postal the placebo effect being
the difference in outcome between
the group they've got the would put the
placebo
and the group that got nothing
and when you do that
they got nothing
here we have
for dichotomous endpoints our basic or
not
this is something called the relative
risk ratio you'll have to worry about
that
but basically
this point means that there is no
placebo effect at all
and what you can see is
at the values
or nicely normally distributed
around no effect
here for continuous endpoints how high
is your blood pressure what it whatever
here is
milan no effect and there's a little bit
of a fact but again you get this nice
kind of sort of normal distribution
uh... things
hundred fifty-six studies
leading are these guys to conclude
that in fact
the placebo effect
that their art
anne placebo effect
which is rape i'll tell ya about
conclusion that upset the whole bunch of
people in the same in the in the domain
on both psychosomatic medicine
for which is so increasingly accepted
fly alone
barnyard by people
medicines just not something we have to
worry about much less actively use
now it turns out
that there are all
there are some problems with although it
but with this analysis mostly having to
do with the kinds of studies that they
had to use they say they had use
anything that
had already been generated
uh... including all of the trial's that
had a nice sensible placebo condition
that really wasn't
audio placebo condition when you do
these kinds of meadow analyses reviews
of literature
you're basically stock with what you've
got
but there are experimental studies
web based studies not necessarily
clinical trials
which clearly show
all of that placebos can have an effect
are not on various kinds of medical
outcomes the place where you see that's
a lot
all use it and not is in pain
here it is a home
really interesting study done by
fred evans who was one of my teachers
graduate school
what evidence did was to review
of large number of laboratory studies
comparing the effects of
various
drugs
too
ordered to placebo
caught in the control of laboratory
paint this is pain
the wrote we have lots of ways of
laboratory to induce pain
below my favorite is cold cold pressor
game where you take somebody's forearm
in this ticketed circulating ice water
and after about thirty seconds forty
five seconds the pain gets really really
really unbearable
home or there's a better job
kind dot disconnect muscle pain report
of blood pressure cough
on the persons alone on the person's arm
had to do some work which involved with
exhaust the oxygen
and the uh... ultimately the blood down
here new blood can't get down here to
adapt to the forearm
and that pain
that is the best analog clinical paying
money can buy it
or just feels like somebody's
tearing your inside-out it's just
unbelievable
and really good
ought to do in the laboratory
there are some others that are less
palatable hall one of my ego but my
former colleagues was
was enamored of electrical stimulation
of truthful
and there are others
all but in any event solved
what might happen in these laboratory so
easily find a way to induce pain
you give one group
solidly yaar
i'm active drug like morphine or door
bonneville max or whatever
another group of placebo in men than for
notre dame control group
and what evan stand here
was through all of the plot but he
called placebo efficiency
how well all the placebo did
compared to the drug
and what he discovered was a placebo
efficiency is a constant across a wide
range of drugs
so that
if you think you're getting morphine
placebo as half as effective as morphing
if you think you're getting darbone
placebo as half as effective as dharwad
if you think you're getting coding
placebos happens affective as
if you think you're getting ronald
reagan but it does the lacks any more
so what that is
alm
if you think you're getting aspirin
placebos half as effective as asked for
that's a very interesting affect
but what's really interesting about it
and looked in the present context is
the placebo effect is modulated by the
persons
what date
thank they're getting
determines
how effective the placebo width
placebo aspirin is not nearly as
effective for pain relief is working
but placebo aspirin is happens affected
israel aspirin
drop to my knowledge
i mean gal boy i see where you're going
with that
yet you consider going to really you're
shooting up now and uh... they're not
shooting up
calm
allied but they still get half the high
that they would be i think that they did
that they did shoot up
there are placebo effects in drug
addiction
i'm told about this i've got no personal
experience with it
but it's well known
that just a slight of for injection drug
abusers for example just the sight of
the injection drug apparatus
is about to to reduce
withdrawal
drug created
now when you get a higher not out of
that isn't completely clear
but the fact of the matter is most drug
addicts don't get high anyway
appear addicted the whole noble goal
whole process of getting addicted
is that you don't get high anymore
you're still trying to stave off
withdrawal effects
so there are these kinds of placebo
effect
there are similar kinds of the simple
fact seemed chemotherapy
cancer
treatment this is very well known
that went on a cancer patients come in
to beyond student would be a triple room
and they're just exposed to the
apparatus already start feeling
nauseated
uh... so that there are headed
chemotherapy for the cancer chemotherapy
offered produce nauseous a side effect
but this compound be condition
harm as well
here you've got
something like a specific belief about
the drug
modulates effect of the placebo and
there i think is really really nice
evidence for a mental state
i got to do a couple more things quickly
but picked some questions
yeah i would have been cold and that's
the implication right
art youth you've you've you've got to
you've got a pain that you would
effectively tree with coding thing i'm
going to give you some more free time
all while i'm gonna get working
you get a defect that's happened with
his more free which is probably just
about what codeine does for you yet you
could do that
you could do that part as president
nixon used to say it would be wrong
the reason i would be wrong
is that
uh... under one interpretation medical
ethics
positions of us postal lied to their
patients
all and although there is a new
literature
although there's a guy had captured
pod at harvard
gould actually has evidence
suggesting that if you say the people
this is a placebo
and it'll be good for your irritable
bowel syndrome
that actually works
okay you tell people it's a placebo
palm
that's kind of weird
all but what
obama captured dogs actually
is he he's a big believer in placebo
effect sat in mind-body healing and
stuff like that he tells people
that uh... the before see both furs
mind-body healing stalin
consensus kind of list
special story
oh of what will the whole world around
us
let's do a little bit more uncle siebel
effects
all vote will forget this
all for now
look to the lecture supplements for that
okay because the more work by all by
fred evans
reviewing the effects of placebos and
pain
it turns out that palm
placebos are more effective if you've
got severe pain that if you got only
mild pain
awlbayes adults response curve onto what
to placebos
so placebos give you more pain relief
and one placebo
there's a time affect curve
if you've got a job you've got an active
agent
that's got to have to life was saved
four hours
the placebo will also have a half-life
of approximately
their adult dad evans was able to
the document additive effects
also that bob
drug of there are some people or real
placebo responders their individual
differences among medical patients
and the effects of algae that drugs are
much bigger in people who are known
to respond unstable which suggested a
placebo effect and the drug effect is
piled on top of that
there are also problems with patient
beliefs if you tell people they're going
to get a debit might get a placebo
you've got less of a placebo effect
on his uh... the studies that evans had
uh... had reviewed
barbara studies were done
poem board
people didn't know they were getting
pussy willows
and their physician practices
it turns out
that positions
huang
dot gupta dispense medications very
easily and very frequently
the tend to get bigger placebo fax then
positions who or much more
wary about to spend dispensing medicines
more about him
big placebo pills are more effective the
little placebo pills
colored placebo pills
far more effective than brightly-colored
placebo pills
placebo pills the taste bad far more
effective the placebo pills
that pays good
placebo delivered intravenously is more
effective than the placebo delivered
intramuscular lee which is more
effective than placebo delivered orally
no to my knowledge there is no study of
rectly delivered
all but because that's really a burst of
procedure you destruct ought to be
dynamite placebos
and dog
expensive placebos
far more effective
then chief placebos
heroes work all from all
almost a program for promoting a product
behavior like a economic flatbed m_i_t_
all this is all things people effect on
pain induced by electrical shock
on the study was done under the guidance
of a of a new drug trial
and in some subjects were told
they were getting called they're getting
video regular
operates drug
and others were told that they were
gettin cheap
generic
and you've got
more all data stable allsec
when subjects thought they were getting
the more expensive
solved other proprietary uh... agent
so again
there are a bunch of these kinds of a
fax
what's interesting about these placebo
effect is that day there well documented
they have a note rieben control attached
to them
and they show barry clearly
that it's the person's believe that is
producing the affect
is the belief subs mental state it's
what you think you're getting
is going to are perfect
all of the deal
niigata skip over a couple things here
comb i'll skip over this
here's all the beltway dot very
interesting a recent renders work by
altman benedetti in this group of the
grip of italian positions
gould compared
what they call open versus hidden
treatment
what they do in these experiments
is a bit surreal clinic patients who
were getting enough
fective treatment
for all of the poor for or what one
illness or another
one verbal patience is pulled out of
getting the treatment
other group of patients
gets the same treatment but are not
told they're getting it
open person couldn't read
here all we have all of this is all
effective died as a paramedic
for postoperative inviting infer trickle
patients
all of the open treatment
how is it not reason green and it turns
out
when you interrupt to treatment
and you but you don't tell people
directors just obey doesn't have dripped
that's going into
if you would drop the treatment but you
don't kill the patient you're
interrupting the treatment
or they still get
reduction of anxiety if u_n_ tour up the
delivery of value as a pen and you tell
the patient that you're stopping
but the others have delivery withdrawn
when you get an increase
and anxiety
here's another one this is all morphine
from post-operative pain
in surgical or other treatments
on again your interrupting the morphine
you're not delivering it and you wonder
if you tell people
experience more pain then if u on if you
don't kill people
and here's another one from benedetti
all of this is all response only in
parkinson's patients
to the delivery oval
of small electrical order current
to the home
to the paulus
and what you can see here is that this
is
movement velocity
what how much of a tremor you're getting
if you'd not telling the police
parkinson's patients are being
stimulated
and if you don't tell them you stopped
continue to get some traveling so here
again what you what we're seeing or the
effects of the patients police
about his or her
all effecting
the patients aren't part of the clinical
condition
so what we got here
are a whole bunch of psychosomatic
affects
where stress
has an effect on disease
suggestion and belief
has an effect on disease and its
treatment
patients expectations
about what's going to happen to them
all affect
all the better affect the reactions of
their bodies to various kinds of
treatments
the whole thing suggests
words and beliefs and expectations of
other kinds of mental state
can in fact have
of facts on disease
and arms industry
that's just a rough torque
i'll be psychosomatic effect
palm evidence that suggests that
mental status
an expectation
barnali prophecies
next time for talk about the last few
mine but nobody
and body without mine
thank you very much
see you wednesday