the last couple times we've talked
mostly about the distinction between
automatic and controlled processing
and the reason i want to do that
is to introduce you to any
body of literature on the so-called
unconscious mental life
which we're going to continue distrust
for the next couple weeks
automatic process eased at least in
principle or unconscious processes
in the strict sense of the term
because in the first place
we're not aware of these goes on these
processes as they operate
and second
their automatic
we don't have any control over these
processes
as they operate
and for that reason
fun car cause automatic process he's has
sometimes been characterized as the new
one conscious
freudian unconscious is the old
unconscious automatic prophecies of the
new unconscious for which there's some
kind of scientific evidence
now that's true so far as it goes
but i want to make a distinction between
a process dean automatic
and
on mental state
i've done for a process being on
conscious
and a mental state being unconscious
it's one thing
not to know hollow you would construct
some per sector memory or whatever
it's another thing for you not to know
what that percept or memory is
and that's
the subject
the next couple of lectures
i put this up to specific founded in the
scientific american
this is the best description of the best
depiction of now i know of the so-called
iceberg a metaphor
for the mind
the general idea of being
there's only a small part of mental life
that is
on the surface
accessible a consciousness
and a large part
of mental life
that is below the surface
donald side of conscious awareness
now as i pointed out i think last time
iceberg metaphors sometimes attributed
freud in fact freud net did not use it
on at least we didn't use it in writing
palm
but there is actually a worldwide
scholarly search
to discover who would was who actually
introduce the iceberg report for the
unconscious
if you can ever find that it documented
you might actually get your name in
lights
so what's the fallout
all immanuel kant put a very nicely all
more than two hundred years ago
when he called and talked about this
contradictory aspect on fall all those
of consciousness
all because
it seemed to him
we had no idea is even though we were
unconscious all of them and he thought
there was some kind of contradiction of
that
to have ideas that we had not be
conscious of them
there seems to be some conduct on cutler
contradiction on that
for how can we know that we have them
if we're not conscious of them
and the goal for the next
all lectures is to show you how in fact
we do know
that we have a unconscious ideas
even though were not
conscious of them
got it right all we know this although
it would weaken our because identify
these unconscious ideas
by looking
at their indirect effects
on our experience
and action
been able to show we actually have
unconscious ideas even though we're not
conscious of them
is important because uh... james himself
pointed out one hundred years ago
the distinction between the unconscious
on the conscious been of the mental
state is the sovereign means for
believing what one likes in psychology
and perjury what might become a science
into a tumbling grown
uh... frequencies
james's beautiful writer
but you can see what the problem is
when you think about kind of boulder
freudian ism
where a patient comes into our to a
psychoanalyst
and says i'm depressed i'm anxious and
this time that
and if i could live with those wealthy
the problem is you have this one
resolved oedipus complex
you want to have sex with your father in
the hague your mother or u wanna have
sex with your mother you hate your
father or whatever it is to do so
and the patient says
no i don't
and the third this says
yes you do
i know you do because i'm a
psychoanalyst and i know how the
unconscious operates and let me explain
to the concept of repression
the sovereign means for believing what
one white
what one likes
if you can just simply say you don't
know what you know
you don't know what you feel
you don't know what you want
what you want is really unconscious and
i'm going to tell you what it is
so what we want to have
is some objective way of determining
whether a person has
one consciously beers
and what those unconscious ideas all are
and on-site though that suggested before
this scientific approach to the nature
of our unconscious mental life
balm
well its approach but it is not fully
satisfied
by the idea that automatic process he's
all run conscious in the strict sense of
deal
of the term let me just skip over this
because i don't need it
the general idea here is that mental
processes can be
unconscious
if they're performed automatically or
pre attentively because if you think
about the earlier of theories of the
unconscious
but the implication although voted on
one of the custody
is it at some point
the mental state constructed by the
automatic process becomes conscious
you may not know exactly how it comes to
be
that you perceive some objects as more
distant
all they did to you that bothers albee
now know that that's
that happens by virtue of the automatic
application
of these so-called size distance rule
but at least the mental states that are
created by these automatic processes
barroom principle
that is their consciously accessible we
know what we see and what we remember
and all of that
even if we can know exactly how we see
all were exactly how we remember
alm
so what we want to know is now
trend these
mental states
the products of automatic processes
also
homes on the beat on
also be unconscious and that's the
question
all for the next couple of
or the lectures
can mental states the unconscious
those things like on talk about
uh... beliefs and knowledge and feelings
and desires and perception memories and
all of that
ten-day
influence
are ongoing experience thought and
action
in the absence
of conscious awareness
all these
and feelings
and desires
this is a controversy that's been in
psychology since before the time of
right
came to a head or when freud started
talking about unconscious mental life
and continues to be double its on today
so now just to set the rules here
what do we mean by mental states
we're not talking anymore about mental
processes
we're talking about
and feelings
desires and that's one of the reasons
why
a couple of lectures ago introduced
this term about intention ality
and brent autos idea that intention
elevate is the work of the mental james
talks about it to us a fortress had
and remember that in though
then the jargon on philosophers
intentionally doesn't really mean what
you intend to do or what you want to do
it means what the mental state is about
and the general idea of what that that
brent connell had
is ever or mental states or a boat
something else
we proceed
something in the world we remember
something that happened in the past
jane is put at the same way
mental states deal with objects
independent of themselves we don't just
have
we have thoughts about something
we don't just have
percept
we have percept about something that our
mental representations of something
and professor john searle says that
admit much the same way
that or mental states have content in
that they've referred us on the specific
feature of the world
if i have a memory
it's a memory that something happened
if i have a perception
on something that's off but that isn't
the perception
that something exists
all of them
the world
so now will be one analyst
you can have can you have
mental states
intent with intention now we that is
they represents something
all of the other than themselves
all of them that are themselves
unconscious
for all
inaccessible
conscious awareness
and of course the answer's going to be
yes
so let's start by looking at conscious
or unconscious mental states
in the cognitive domain
by which we mean
unconscious perceptions
on conscious memories
unconscious knowledge
unconscious
uh... thoughts
these are things that
when their conscience they clearly have
intention only if i say i know how to
try ones are not uh... ended in a
necktie
or i perceive that there's a podium over
there
or if i remember drivin off
to grow of two children park yesterday
those mental states all had intention
ality
and they're conscious mental states
and the challenge i think laid down
fall by uh... body a brent otto and
others is to try to figure out
whether we can have or unconscious
mental states
mental states that are perception
memories and four th
even though we're not consciously aware
of them
the earliest good evidence that this is
the case
comes from studies of the army's x
syndrome
of neurological syndrome sometimes
though incorrectly
that although uh...
labeled of course across syndrome
that occurs when people have bilateral
damage to one or the other
of to uh... of to bring structures
most commonly in the media llc from
medial portion of the temporal lobe
right about there
all affecting
structure that's right here in known as
the hippocampus
all four less commonly
all at the end of the uh... the sort of
co subcortical structures known as the
dyan stuff along
affecting especially the babbling bodies
battery positions here
uh... dear the you know new high
perfomance
and what happens is that
damage
bilateral damaged he got to with these
so if you're white gold both of them
all bilateral damage to
one or the other all of these
subcortical brain structures
are produces
what's known as a specific memory
deficit
which is to say
that the patience
problems with memory
but they don't have problems with
anything else
paid their language functions on
impaired their general intelligence is
on impaired they could perceive the
world they can think they can do all
sorts of things
they jospin remember
and the specific memory deficit what's
love the primary feature of the specific
memory deficit is what's known as a and
carol great amnesia
that covers memory for what our notes
host morbid a battle of the events
that's a medical term
that basically means events that occur
after an injury has occurred
so i don't wipe out the person's
hippocampus
fall bilaterally
on on both sides of the brain and what
happens is
the person can no longer remember
that have happened
more controversial e
the amazing syndrome can the sometimes
involve a retrograde amnesia as well
that is
it covers
pre morbid
events on vents that occurred
before
the injury occurred that parts
controversial i do want to get into it
that's for another course
all but we're going to do all the focus
on here
is he encouraged raid component of the
music syndrome
yet get the brain damage
and you could no longer remember new in
new information
news all things have happened
since the brain damage occurred
well beginning in the nineteen fifties
all carved some all of them
norrell psychologists
they'd weren't even call that badly
didn't have that label all began dust
began to use experimental techniques
drawn from the psychology laboratory
to study various patterns solve all of
the various effects or brain damage on
cognitive functioning
and among the earliest of these was
started by warrington whites crimes
elizabeth warrington and larry weiss
grounds
all published in the late nineteen
sixties
on memory in the air music syndrome and
they used up
fo familiar bramble learning procedure
to study what n_b_c_ patients couldn't
could not remember
so remember these are patients who have
documented brain damage
can remember
things and although that things have
happened to the recently
are and what more into the white scratch
that
bring these people into the laboratory
so that they could study they studied
worked on the world
more rigorously
okay so imagine what you do when one of
these standard verbal learning experince
is that you present the subject with
assault with a list of words the study
of that's why it's called verbal morning
all like these
and then after a while you take the list
away
and u_s_ the person what he or she
karen uh...
can remember
warrington away scratched did this with
a group called that music patients
and a group of controls
and if i mean was
the music patients remembered very
little
of this wordless sure variations third
gradations of amnesia
fault
whereas the control patients
home who didn't have this brain damage
we're able to but remember affair amount
of it this is the basic phenomenon
and her great amnesia
where these
uh... and music patience
perform very poorly on recall tests
of memory
are just a kind of off the ante a little
bit
or into the white scranton
sees all of the uh... subjects through
an area of the recognition test as well
they presented them with a long list of
words
fumble which
words from the study list
they're called targets
others were
costs of words
that word that did not appear in the
study list
alm and ask them something to say which
ones
all day of the recognized from the study
was
and
here you can see the performance
of the emusic patients they're they're
basically a chance to the two
alternative force choice recognition
fast
whereas
the our control on patients were doing
pretty well
on this test again the difference
between a nuisance and controls on this
recognition past
distros
onward even even more rigorous
uh... documentation
of their
memory deficit
as a general rule not always true but as
a general rule
performance on recognition persons
better than performance on reporters you
can see that
could see that here
so even if you give a pretty easy tess
they still
org remembering all very much
okay so experiments like this leading to
an initial characterization all of the
psychological deficit in the emusic
syndrome
as a kind some kind of learning all
failure
lots of memory or a waltz of new all
learning all leading neuro psychologist
to begin to ask a question as well
is there anything that these damn easy
patients come learn
thug that are they completely void of
the capacity to work
or is that there's something that
that they can learn
member how we define warning classically
alm and in order to study invest more
into the white scraps concoct are
concocted
on yet a third test which they presented
to the subjects as a guessing game
and discussing game
ka comes into basic forms
one is words stem completion
i'm thinking of the word that begins
with these three letters can you fill in
the blanks
and some pictures simply sposed to
the author with it and fill in the
blanks
with the first word all that comes to
mind
or edward fragment completion
you don't have a stem anymore you've got
a fragment
i'm thinking of a word that has these
letters and it
kenya filling the blanks
and star subjects were supposed to come
up
with the first word
that comes to mind
if you've been looking back
you noticed that these stems
actually are stems from words from the
study was
and these fragments
or fragments that can be completed
with words
from the study list
so the point of this guessing game
is to see
whether subjects will actually
although
uh... the about the complete
these these stems or fragments with
items from the study list
and the answer is
normal subjects
they tend to complete these were these
all of those stems and fragments with
items from the study list
they've been primed formal come back to
work
but the interesting thing was
that'd be amazing patients
performed in exactly the same way
they showed exactly the same tendency
as the control subjects
to complete the stems and fragments with
words from the study was
apparently
studyin the
although the words on the study list
being exposed to the words of the study
list
made those words come to mind were
easily on the stem
hall and uh... and and fragment
completion test
the avenues x
were able to perform
joseph as well as the control subjects
just opposed to control subjects that
this is all true dot reintroduce intern
we've talked about before
a phenomenon known as priming
priming his dog out of this is all a
defined
as they are job
and case where
the processing of one item
fault redeemed the word
ash can on the study list influences
processing of a rather write 'em
that is
completing the words stand a stage
with ash can as opposed to ashtray
and if you think about the conventional
definition of wording
has so much a relatively permanent
change in behavior that occurs as a
result of experience
this prime in effect
represents the morning and a very broad
a sense of the term
now just to tops allies in cross some
keys here
prime aim for a primary text take two
forms
positive priming affects
one task
facilitates
performance
on a subsequent ask
and there are negative priming effects
where the first test
in paris performance
on the subsequent tests
were not ever going to be talking about
negative priming effects or they're hard
to get
and they're not relevant for all for us
they're interesting
they're just not relevant in this
context
we're going to be talking exclusively
positive palm
posited prime in fact
and the point here is
and music's show the same amount of
priming as control subjects too
even though they can't consciously
remember the price
they don't recall the words list but it
was
they don't recognized
the words from the study was they have
as far as we can tell
no conscious recollection of the words
from the study was
yet they show these priming affects
there clearly influenced by of memory
that they're not
consciously aware of
there clearly influenced by something
that's been stored in memory
that they clamp
consciously
these kinds of affects which are now
pretty well documented lead band
schachter then a toronto now at harvard
ought to make a distinction between
all add up to expressions of memory
explicit memory and implicit memory
because identify explosive memory with
conscious recollection
as reflected for example in people's
performance on tests of recall
recognition
and we can define implicit memory
any aspect
followed of past experience
on the persons
subsequent
experience
thought or action
that's implicit memory because
if there is a fact of the past on
experience for action
there's a memory implied in their
something has to have been stored
paul and uh... filled memory is implicit
in the effect
so any effect on experience for
direction
that's attributable to a pass the bed
and the finding from studies like the
warrington aways cram study
was simply that all priming effects
can occur in in the absence of conscious
recollection they could be dissociated
from conscious recollection all if you
are or if you will
and only in this case
the fact the primary fax occur in the
absence of conscious recollection
is that these private effects
seemed to represent
memory
there a trace of some past experience
the study experience
but they're and unconscious
there are bad all their memory entrees
that people simply hard
all the people simply aren't aware of
that's the basic distinction between
explicit and implicit memory
it's going to store as the
model
jill doggone later discussions
of all unconscious mental life
and other domains like perception and
thinking and so and so on
but this
basic distinction
is the one we have to
we have to world
deal but
and all
priming effects of the sort that i just
showed you
exemplify implicit memory
that you can get them you don't have to
consciously remember anything
all you even get these primary facts
when you don't consciously remember
uh... anything
priming effects exemplified implicit or
unconscious
if you read this literature
you'll see lots of different hats
used to study
and all of the want to point out
i don't think i'll get to
i'll finish this dog
this part of
for this lecture today will see
all but
in all the cabinet rotate in the case i
just presented to you the warrington
aways krantz case
and in the basque majority of studies of
the implicit memory
dog investigators are studying
formal priming cold repetition priming
and it's all the defining feature of
repetition priming
that the item presented at the time of
testing
is
some kind of
re capitulation
all of the item that was presented at
the time of study
solo queria ask you to study the word
ashtray
a sage t_r_ a_w_ a good p_r_ a white
the item presented at the time of study
then i ask you to complete the words
stand a stage with the word
and you produce and trade supposed to
ask him
or something like that
item presented the pilot asked the stand
a sage
is a partial
recapitulate shin of the item presented
uh... at the time of study so here you
have
human sample of this or in terms of stem
completion
paul or ash can or whatever
a blank page point-blank
and that would also be a partial
we capitulation
of the word presented at the time of
study
in a perceptual identification procedure
you put the item up but the subject
studied but you make it difficult to
read
in one way or another
and you measure the amount of time it
takes a subject to identify the stimulus
and it turns out
by the subjects will identify
stimuli drawn from the study was
more rapidly more accurately then and
then they'll identified
stimuli that work
previously
and then finally
another good example of a repetition
priming or the test
is what's known as the lexical decision
task where you put the whole word
up there
and then what the subject has to do is
simply say
whether it's a legal english word
that's the old that's just the task
electrical decisions basketball you have
to do anna turns out that there are
prime interfax electrical decision
such that
all-star subjects will be global more
readily
identify
award from the study list as a legal
english word
then they will
or of the word that wasn't drawn
the study was
so they're all priming affects
presentation one item
on thought during the study phase of the
experiment
facilitates
processing of that item
uh... very various kinds of tests
so you can think about all these
examples of repetition priming
as represented a kind of
bias in information processing
your body s to complete the stem with
ash can
your bias to complete the fragment with
ash your bios to say ask them to word
all and all of that
is based on some kind of memory trace
so i was formed at the time of the study
session yes
in these kinds of experiments it's
usually a couple of minutes just because
we will want to do these experiments
fast
baat karna we're going with this
burmese let me say two things about that
as nixon would say
called the first thing is that
for a psychologist
anything
is at least thirty seconds ago counts as
long-term memory
that's the way we do it for a second the
distractions long-term memory
anything that's less than thirty seconds
of distractions probly short term memory
so it's always a role long-term memory
books
now we usually do these bug bees all
part of experiments
pretty much elect in
the prime spendable
of all laboratory our
but these kinds of private x have been
documented over days
months
and years
despite the fact that the subjects can
remember anything at all about them
also larry squire did the boast of halt
thumb
vote one car
longest term study
on he got significant priming and one of
his own music patients after a period of
two years
also anyway that's the basic goal
that's the basic goal of the phenomenon
here
and let me just say one more thing alba
about this that's kind of subtle
and all of this is a little bit
difficult to mess
in all of these studies
performance on the implicit test
priming performance
gore did
whereas performance on the test dog
recall or recognition
is with his vote is pretty bad
but if you think about it for a second
there's a kind of wierd kind file
if you're going to compare performance
on a priming test to performance on say
all free recall test
and that is
the price test provides the subjects
with a different kind of information
at the test
than the free recall test dot if i say
that if i give you a list of words to
study and i said what do you remember
not giving too much of the head about
what you're supposed to be remembering
if i didn't want to words the study and
i say is that she cannot word
well that's a lot of q information
and we know that memory is passed with
or what with all of it
memory improved
to the extent that we supply subject
with lots and lots of
q information at the time of retrieval
so you might argue
that what appears to be spirit priming
on off and on one of these past
is it really
something about
implicit a run conscious memory at all
but really has more to do with
well you just gave a more hands so they
perform better
for that reason
though a really good tests dissociation
between say implicit explicit memory
keep the q information the same as that
both
the explicit test and the implicit test
so for example
first m cued recall
it's a can you remember a word on the
list
that began with
the letters g_ all right
and for the stem completion press the
priming you'd say give me the first word
you can think of that begins with the
letters g_ r_ a_
you hold the cues constant
but you very what the subject has to do
with the q
whether they have to remember
consciously remember
something for the past or whether they
don't have to consciously remember of
something for the past
and when you do that
the same dissociation this is work by
peter graft maurice choir in george
mandarin u_c_ san diego
comparing stemmed cued recall
stem completion test
these around musics and controls and
what you can see is that the emmys
x_-two worse than the controls
stem cued recall
their rap music they can remember to
begin with
but in fact they do a little bit better
than the control subjects
on the pet on a test of stem completion
so here you have a nice demonstration
of the dissociation between explicit an
implicit memory
very tightly controlled experiment
or where the information presented to
the subjects at the time of test is held
constant
but what they have to do
what with that information or varies
between the explicit an implicit test
let me show you a couple more
all examples of this dissociation just
so you can see that
on its not confined to well
single kind of a brain damage
they're a bunch of studies in the
literature
all called balms called
priming the and cases of amnesia
of following of
deal administration of electra
compulsive terribly
yeah uncommon
for depression
and what happens in ec ten e
is that palm paid all of the whole day
gold electrical current is delivered
across the company for sometimes
from the defects to the head
onto just one cumple
and that dog that induces like
time don't
soto epileptic uh... seizure that
results and a loss of consciousness
and one of the patient called the hog
recovered be begins to recover
consciousness
although their own that show amnesia for
events that occurred around the time
that the electric convulsive shock was
delivered
they will
show and and terror grade amnesia
for events that occur
for a period of time
after
dec ke was delivered
and they'll also show
they retrograde amnesia
for events that occurred
in the period of time leading up to the
delivery
of the c_t_
on you get less of this with the
unilateral ec t where there is one
electrode on the temple of one electrode
the top of the head
you get more
of this and asia at the
you see people it would bilaterally
to be studies of bilateral
paul dot you see
but just to make a graphic
the point where
ke alm
easy to use delivered
immediately after the patient is in
what's known as the post bechtel
confusion allstate that is posed seizure
confusion allstate
there are any awareness
hall above what's going on
on their and then they begin to recover
all consciousness
but the entire agreat unusual
covers this period
after
the shock is the delivered
and after the subjects come out of this
post iqbal confusion allstate
the retrograde amnesia covers a period
of time
well uh... immediately prior to the
delivery of org
of the uh...
solaris choir
berkeley's on our channel moral all i'm
peter graph all working together at u_c_
san diego whenever there together
did all of a study of bought explicit
and implicit memory
vcd induced and terror grade amnesia
these patients
god
fall
but they are jolt of
ec t
and then
after they have recovered consciousness
all all squire is colleagues asked them
to study word list
and then after they were fully recovered
they donna did dog of the press of
memory and what you can see here is
the art of the patients who actually got
the e_c_ t
were densely and these are
for the items that they studied right
after they got the e_c_ p
compared to controls
chest performances of
three choice
recognition test
and they're doing pretty badly
on here
all but
the subjects are showing the n_b_a_ sick
patients are showing
uh... performance
primate affects
on uh...
announced on completion
at exactly the same rate
as the controls so here we have
explicit memory
severely impaired
implicit memory
completely spared
not imperative all another example all
of the home
uh... of the dissociation between
explicit an implicit memory
all here is a study by jennifer dorfman
and her friends
on all of them explicit in implicit
memory in the
club post bcp retrograde amnesia
what dorfman did was to have subjects
study a list of words
before
obesity
then she let the recover for a while
trust their memory
here is stem q performance on stem she
would recall
very bad performance on the part of the
and music patients
very densely and music
performance on stem cued completion at
least the equivalent
albee
non n_b_c_ patients and again
to some extent
if anything the mt sick patients
or performing
or performing better
so here's another example
called form
on board
the dissociation
the split
between explicit an implicit memory
we have explicit memory grossly impaired
and
implicit memory
priming effects essentially on impaired
essentially spared
here's another example rebel pork
yeah anesthesiologist that i worked with
uh... ffa sometime ago
here we were looking at medical patients
undergoing an office procedure
wonder what's known as conscious
sedation
some of you have had this maybe for all
the
knee surgery or something like that
where it you'd they don't get a general
anesthesia
what you're dead as a drug
this case we used to
of the drug called proper fault
which is the drug that killed michael
jackson
called but
then again you don't take it in doses
like michael jackson talk at
on you take it in carefully controlled
doses and under carefully controlled
of circumstances
hauled and uh... impact in these studies
all the patients were able to control
the delivery of the anesthesia called to
themselves they were given a little
button
and whenever they started feeling a
little bit of pain
they could give themselves
for all of the bullets
oval purple for make the pain go away
all but one of the consequences of this
is
you are rendered and music for
but time when you were
sedated by propyl probable
now what's interesting about this is you
are completely conscious during the
procedure
you're aware everything that's going on
you could talk to the medical team you
can watch tv you could read a book you
can job could you could do all sorts of
things
but you don't remember any of it
afterwards
okay just have been you'd just like of
anybody here is had this procedure notes
of that
on was about the case
so while they're conscious that or
anything better to do
so while these people were having
learned their procedure we gave them all
learning task
calm
chalte chalte the bug all paris o'shea
learning task
in which they simply studied pairs of
words like hello shouldn't water water
naive
and uh... and so on
and then after the uh... although the
anesthesia was terminated
the the conscious sedation was all
was terminated
palm
we what the recovery little bit
and that we don't prevent did some
memory test of the recovery room so here
we've got
fallen
and the other seizure
and it's a mentor great amnesia that
these
uh... the patients experience you don't
get you don't lose memory for anything
that happened in the past
on role but you do have
oh video and enter a great amnesia
for the events that occurred
while you're a sedated by proper fall
palm
this is for or did you have just be a
music patients
on stem cued recall we asked him to
distinguish
with after the complete
stems from the study list
and from the from a control list they
did very badly
we ask you a recognize
words from the study a list
verses the controllers
they did very badly
point here
under free association test it turns out
that the alone theo sedated patients
perform just as well as the on sedated
of uh... controls
at producing the items from the of
this buddy list
song himself
as free associations
so again
very bad
explicit memory here
apartment that at the same time as we
see spear priming
so just to kind of some up here
you can see these
of the descent pattern of resulted in a
walk-in variety all twelve phenomenal of
amnesia
i've shown you uh...
coupled examples from the n_b_a_'s x and
wrong
resulting from bilateral damage to the
at the campus and other structures in
the medial temporal lobe
show you two examples of patients who
are at music by virtue of electrical
book convulsive therapy
palm
uh... one example of both of this case
were uh... different music
by virtue of conscious sedation
and there are other examples
so for example that you can beer you can
do the same kind of experiment with
patients who are under general
anesthesia we did this to
uh... we went into the loaded into an
operating theater with patients who were
completely out
all because they were having major
of the major surgery
and all over earphones
read the more wordless
and then we're able to show
that they had priming
all four of those words later
even though they didn't remember
anything about it of show you that study
later
all you do the same thing with hypnosis
all hypnotized subjects can get a
suggestion for post about again major
when you come out of no since you will
remember the things you've done
also while you were at the time
on does not but all the time but highly
hypnotize will subjects will come out of
hypnosis
and they'll be on able to remember the
things they did while they worked with
the prize at these for a while
also in a bunch of experiments people
have
of given hypnotized subjects all
wordless to study
given given them in our nation
suggestion
bring about of hypnosis
recall that all recognize the words
but they do show
all they do show priming effects
all there even a couple of cases
although the public sperm inside genuine
cases of multiple personality disorder
so-called isos have identity disorder
like the three faces aviv if you've ever
seen that movie which was based on a
real case
one personality studies a list
and then you test the other
personalities memory for that list that
they don't remember
all that saddam would look
features of multiple personally disorder
the black and white didn't know what he
black was doing and uh... and so on
yet eve white will show prime interfax
uh... all for poem
material that was studied by euphoric
and that's again or in genuine cases
which there aren't that many of but you
can get it and lots and lots of
different
uh... kinds of cases
you can even get these kinds of
dissociation in
normal neurologically intact not
mentally ill
not hypnotized not sedated not
anesthetized of patients as well
all
here as well advice example using a
paradigm known as savings in relearning
uh... body all
like tom nelson university of washington
what nelson did was to have subjects
study modern honest paired associates
two words paired together
this case of two-digit number
and a familiar word like forty eight
book
and all thirty-six party
then to get to your question
after off
four-week retention interval
one month later he brought the subjects
back
for a series of memory tests
one of these was like you and recall
test
weary gave them these are big the q
forty-eight and ask them to recall the
associated word
another was a recognition test we redid
the majority's between forty eight book
and forty-eight party
and awsome to recognize which one they
have actually seen
all some subjects performed really badly
on both these tests old cued recall and
recognition they've really
did remember anything
and then what below what job nelson did
was to ask them to
perform mix permit all over again
to relearn on new although they did to
relearn north on the list of these
kurdistan tips
somewhat which
contain the original pairing
that they had seen four weeks
earlier
forty-eight book
father parrot associates involved the
repair evolved old stimuli and responses
like forty eight party
and what
dharwad nelson dog discovered
subjects showed savings in a real
warning
for a benz that that will prepare it
were in paris
that that they could neither consciously
a recall
nor consciously recognize
here we have calm
this is for all recalled items
former cold items that were recognized
their savings have been in mel
relearning
that make sense
but here our own recalled items
there were also unrecognized and you
still get savings
in relearning
savings and relearning is based on the
presence of these
memory trace of the old event i mean
that's what savings everybody knows it's
a measure of memory
the fact that subject can show savings
in relearning items
that they neither recall nor recognize
isn't association between explicit an
implicit memory
memory is there
affecting people's performance on the
rewarding task
i think it's a it's doing that
in the absence called ball
in the absence of conscious recollection
here's another example this is from lori
jacoby kaya problem talked about before
or here
subjects were given a list of words to
deal with they weren't even have to
remember the blue of the words all there
were asked to do was to make some
judgments
about the words
on one case
the judgment was a shallow
so-called shallow judgment about the
physical features of the word
the second paintball
uh... does it dot contained a letter he
that's all the subjects were asked to do
enough other caught all in other cases
the subjects were asked to make a
on judgment about the semantic
properties of the word
does this word mean the same as this
word is that a synonym or whatever
and then called jacoby in dallas of put
subjects through test of recognition
upon pesto
on explicit memory
and a perceptual identification test
this if we put those up though those
words up and that subjects all of them
behind a mask
and subject simply to identify
what the words work
and the finding of the experiment
this is a familiar
all result
hidden in the end of the memory
literature
recognition
is better for items that were processed
deeply
as opposed to items that were subject to
shallow processing
so if you make a judgment about the meat
of an item
you're going to remember it better than
if you just make a judgment about the
physical appearance all of the item
but here
what you see there's a promise of
significant russian effect here
but priming
is unaffected by level of processing
explicit memory has affected by level of
processing
implicit memory is not affected
by level of processing
you're getting
implicit memory
independently called ball
of explosives
forget their help
so now we have two different kinds of
evidence
for this dissociation between explicit
an implicit memory
but the the cases i showed you jody
before
we have what's known as a population
dissociation
where there is some population like
emusic patients
don't have explicit memory
but do have implicit memory
and then all in the case of the college
sophomores studied by nelson or door
door jacoby or whatever we have the what
are known as functional dissociation
experimental variable
like a level of processing or
forgot about something else
will affect performance on an explicit
memory task but won't affect the
on implicit memory test
experi no abhi implicit memory
in the face of impaired explicit memory
isn't confined to just a particular kind
of subject
isn't confined to simply to order simply
to a particular experimental
experimental paradigms
i'm going to see
this is what i want to show you
these dissociation
between explicit an implicit memory
call me in free
what you see mostly
in this literature our water known as
singled associations
where you've got some variable like
whether the patient is and music or not
or whether the item couple got deep
processing or not
that affects performance on an explosive
memory test
but doesn't affect
performance
the implicit memory test
this is the most common pattern of
results
in this literature and it's the one
most important for us
because what you're getting is
no conscious memory
but priming
or some other
paula evidence volvo of one conscious
mem
you will from time to time if you read
deeply enough
were broadly enough in the
neuropsychological literature
c claims for what's known as a double
dissociation
and in this context
a double dissociation whitaker if us
particular variable like whether you
read music were not
whether you processed the items deeply
would have opposite a fax
on
explicit and implicit memory so here you
have an example where you've got solved
independent variable doesn't matter what
it is
improve explicit memory
impair implicit memory
the double dissociation is in some
respects the gold standard of
neuropsychological work because
that tells you that explode that would
evidence like this would tell you that
for example that explicit in implicit
memory or mediated by very different
mental modules are very different bring
systems
it's the gold standard it's actually not
just the gold standard it is the holy
grail
uh... gov neuropsychological research
and precisely because it's the holy
grail these are very
rarely
instead
most investigators claim to have
discovered a double dissociation what
they've really discovered is what i
prefer to call a twin dissociation
where you've got true independent
variables eight and b
one of these independent variables
performance on explicit memory task
doesn't affect performance audit
implicit memory test
and a second independent variable
will affect performance on his implicit
memory test
of performance on an explicit memory
test as i say here beats beefed wind
associations are sometimes claimed is a
double dissociation
on double dissociation really has to do
with the affects the opposite effects of
a single
experimental variable on too
thong two different tasks
now i don't want to do this now all due
this wednesday that sings this is pretty
much more i wanted to get us to today
explicit memory is conscious
recollection
when people recall or recognize or
previously studied word they consciously
remember us dave retrieve that item from
memory of brought it in the conscious
awareness
priming effects and all other implicit
memory affects heart
fun conscious
effects of unconscious memory they kind
of current even when the person has no
conscious recollection
all the priming event
these dissociation speaking explicit an
implicit memory argun announced serve as
the model
for looking at
onto so see issues between conscious and
on conscious mental states in other
domains like perception
demotion motivation and so on
thanks very much for c_ one wednesday