ok but see if we can wrap things up
today
are
just a reminder we got a final exam
scheduled for tuesday the ten th of a
three to six p m
gymnasium
d_s_p_ students
volume should have heard from me by now
that they sent us
sent to reach a deal and email
along belcher accommodations to puke if
you get an accommodation
mall if you haven't heard from the heart
send me an email
what's going on
anyway the examiners formatted as until
exams which you've got three hours
first hours not cumulative total
covered material since
c_e_o_
since the midterm
the second hour is to know that they
will cover some material from
from the midterm
but also give you a chance to put some
things together
on next wednesday here
a regular class time
will have a q and a session if you've
got any questions at all
or bring them to the
flynn of the class
deal with my won't do any formal review
at that time
and the reason i won't do that
is that
the ought never to review that's all i
have to say about it
so you can get that kind of there was
some
people questions there
although previous exams are up and there
is now one newbies face forum dedicated
to the final exam if you've got
questions of the run-up to the final
on just fill
right here let me know
and again just a reminder than on killer
portions of the cover all the material
since the midterm
the to an abortion is going to cover
okay
last time we talked about the cause of
the hog to a different empirical
definitions of consciousness
that allow us to investigate the
question of
weather
non adults
nonverbal humans
don humans have something resembling
consciousness hello or not
the so-called
mirror self recognition test
pioneered by home
pioneered by with gordon gallup
and the so-called forcefully expressed
all of them
that is very popular developmental
psychology
and that you've noticed that there is an
apparent contradiction between the
findings of the saudis
if you define consciousness in terms of
behaviorally and terms of the ability to
pass of
the mirror self recognition test
then all normal human infants to this
pretty much all normal human infants to
this point needs to
but yet to define consciousness
in terms of the ability to pass the
forcefully stress
that doesn't happen for most kids until
bulb
until about the
hard so they resolved there's a gap
there
well what other reasons
why there's a gap there is that
little kids very little kids are very
verbal they don't have their they don't
have
property for the good linguistic skills
yet
and it's been suggested that the
operable nature of the standard false
belief task
gets in the way of young children
responding appropriately or the properly
into it
so for example clement supporter all but
all of them
on his noticed a small early on
putting two and three year-old kids
three of the through the uh...
through the forcefully expressed
they'd say that u_s_ ticket to see where
the popped it will work
state usually make a mistake they
identify the wrong location
but if you were asked the child to look
where the puppet will work
but the child will often do is to work
in the right place that is what where
the puppet believes called the yelling
georg so that the toys the bed
so it's possible
very young infants younger than age four
or five
have some understanding of the theory of
mine
but it's just not an understanding that
can be expressed holiday verbally
all for those of you who goes and what
developmental psychology
this is a wall problem developmental
psychology
the distinction between
on the child's competence of the child's
performance
if you work for example lead
so uh... children's song little rustic
of behavior
it's very clear that should that little
kids can all understand
a lot more language that they can
produce
because they have linguistic competence
that just doesn't necessarily translate
into home
one way to deal with this problem of
course
sister concoct
a non-verbal version called the force
police task
and this is what it would be she and
boulder here on
psychologist at the university of
illinois on did
all you know study pioneering study
really truly wonderful study
on involving fifteen on mon bold infants
all who were put into a totally
nonverbal version
called the forcefully fast
all of tested which
expectancies were set up
all for the children
and then
all of these are logs
targets behavior violates those
expectancies
as you look at philips yet at the
infants reaction to it
and there's a general idea in
developmental psychology let's go no
controversial
philosophic factions
but there is a general idea which is
that
infants even infants
will pay more attention two events that
violate their expectancies they'll look
at the law burger
so what you could do is you can measure
the amount of time the child looks at
some of them
or not
or two
should determine whether it's been
surprised by that or not
taken to the experiment because it is
the thing of beauty
partly because it's such a filter
something also want to do later uh...
leader of the lecture
the experiment begins with three
so-called the militarization trials
that are simply intended to
well a quake the infant missus these are
fifteen-month old parkinson's or justo
people bid over a year old
wild with this procedure
and what happens on trial one is that
there's this actor here
theirs is the old boxes there is a green
box so there's hope
all plastic watermelons whitefield
and there's a little stage
and what happens is that the doors on
the stage open kinda blindfolded actor
appears
all piled up on the stage
itself
well na playful discover
got a you know
vice around so you can see
or arise
she picks up
the law of the watermelon
and puts it into the green box
that's all it happens on on trial
and what happens then is that there are
two
on uh... or other familiar recession
trials
there's a yellow box and every box in
the actor appears
and she wishes
into the green box
and then she goes away
and then she comes back and she reaches
into the quickbooks argument goes away
again that's all the fifteen-month old
debts
five-way ultimately resumption
are with this large
with this experimental environment
then there are some trials
that are that would be sheehan violation
on call
all believe production trials there
four different conditions of this
experiment
the whole bunch of fifteen month old
urbana-champaign has a lot of infants
and so on they were able to do two types
while relatively large number of kids in
each of these conditions
so let me to disarm very briefly
there we've got the yellow box at the
green box of the actor again
and on and one condition which they call
true belief green
all of the all the new york
the actor
as by
result folsom strings of police
the yellow box
just moves toward reeboks
and then moves away
nothing happens about the location of
the watermelon
all that happens is that there's some
action
yellow box moves toward
three boxes
obviously a control condition
and then there is a real
second condition called true belief
yellow
in which the actor is here
the actor watches
as the watermelon again by virtue of
some strings and police moves
from the green box
into the yellow box
then there it is although doctor
condition known as forcefully grave
where there is no waktu present
at all
for what the infant that's to watch
the watermelon movin
between box
to began talks
and then there is a poor condition are
very complicated condition known as the
reportedly yellow condition where the
actor is present
as and watches as the watermelon moves
from the green box to the yellow box
then the actor goes away
the doors are closed
and by means of the school system
the watermelon slice moves back
from the yellow box with remarks but
uh... this is very cool
and uh...
and of obviously all these conditions
were done and thought that was a were
assigned randomly the subjects of all
that kind of stuff in
yes they cover balance the yellow in the
green boxes they did everything they
were supposed to do
and the question is
what now happens
on the test trial
the actor appears
and either reaches into the green box
yellow box
does the infant respond differently to
this
depending on
what do you know understands
the actor notes and uh... and hoa what
the bosnian serb understands about where
the watermelon
called is
obviously
if the actor is all
artful
reaching into a prickly into a
particular box which i was going to be
surprised
and in fact that's exactly what happened
so we're looking at looking times here
and we're looking at the amount of time
all of the the infant looks
when the halt when when the actor
reaches into the yellow box
where the watermelon
or reaches into the green box where the
actor thinks the watermelon is and here
in the true believe grain
when the actor
reaches into the yellow box
the infant surprised by that and spends
a lot of time looking
where the all
when the true belief is that the
watermelon is in the yellow box
the child is surprised
the actor vault gold
inspects
inspects the green box
now when
the forcefully the actor as the false
belief
that it soon
the green box
child a surprise when the actor reaches
into the autobots
the child is is that the child to say
epidemic
you don't think the watermelons of
yellow box right why are you doing this
right
and when
the hard the actor has the false belief
that the home
at the altered watermelons and yellow
box
the child appears to be surprised
when the actor regions of the green box
again these fifteen month old infants
seem to understand
what there is that the actor who knows
and they seem to have the expectation
that the actor will behave in accordance
with what he or she knows
or believes to be the case
even when that knowledge or belief is
faults
that's the theory of mind
and by the evidence of this sat down
several of the several other studies
have been done since then
or it appears
that mobile home
fifteen-month old kids have it
that's about as early as you can post
these kids though some experiments with
eight month old
vishal results
roughly the same collection
both apparent contradiction
between the results of the may result
recognition case
which suggests that
our kids
all i have
something like
all all
part art part over consciousness of self
by the by the time that the lord
community-based
doesn't contradict
all of the performance of the polls with
gus so long as you're giving the child
and honorable version all the polls
we've passed
one that doesn't tax his or her on his
or her cognitive
so the general idea here is that even
infants aged fifteen months
not quite fresh out of the wall but
but it's still pretty young
all have these are some some rudimentary
theory of mine
they have some sense of what other
people believe
people believe might be incorrect
or at least at what other people believe
they differ from what they believe
and
infants expect other people to blame
the trip to behave
in accordance with their beliefs
and when they're surprised when paul
went off dot other people behave
accordance with something that they
don't believe where they're not supposed
to believe
so here you can see
that even relatively young kids fifteen
month old
victims
what we would up now wonder staff
as theory of mine
you can see where we're going with this
now that we've got nonverbal test or the
theory of mine
that's something that could be
administered
dogs and cats and of course chimpanzees
our closest or
or closely primate of relative
all we know that should pansies pastor
marisol recognition does
on board that that scallops explode
research
and we have a very clear sense that own
she could do that
the question is
do chimpanzees had anything remotely
resembling
you're in the body
do they have a sense that
creatures beliefs
that those beliefs might differ from
there's do they have the expectation
that other creature
martin recordings along with the police
are there are
other chimpanzee experiments dealing
with other aspects of the theory of mine
all but i don't
someone spent part of that today let's
just look
part of the question of whether
chimpanzees
the theory of mind mechanism
tran date
reason
about other peoples
of the people's beliefs
joseph caller mike thomas l_ o_ calls a
british psychologist thomas celebs at
emory university
apartheid in new york the application
all-boys nonverbal version of false
belief task
hong kong wherefore with chimpanzees
using a paradigm that smelled she's
quite a bit
or what happens in these experiments but
sorry i don't have a picture of a thug
looking all over for on
have one once i just can't
an event
follow what happens here
is that there is a hotter old a lot of
the human
who's been working with the chimpanzees
add to this august this sort of that
this person's fighter
hybrid reward
in one of two containers are these
most brightly colored plastic buckets
all on yup
and at the at the high gear
hikes this treat fruit loops or
something like that
all in full view of another bom
pics for better known as the
communicator
and the communicator has
previously been shown to be
all reliable
source all the information about where
treats and food and other things art the
way the slope
waited so long
on expert is usually done is that the
communique will come out
to be two buckets
one on either side
and the fighter will point to the one
bucket
or the other bucket
chimpanzee will go
turn over the bucket and fight between
headed that way
previously
the communicator has been shown to be a
reliable source of inspiration
as to where
the treats or
so the higher hides a reward view of the
communicator
and them palm
the communicator
all leaves the room
and then the hiker comes back
and switches the pockets
case which is the reward
from one pocket farther to the other
full on
in full view orbited of the subject
and the communicator that comes back
into the room
and points
took one of the two
in fact if unit leader does
is to work
the all the box
as the correct bucket
the place where
the where the where the troops going to
be found
communicator things
the tree his over here
the chimpanzee
that the trees but moved
the other
all of the the other container
and the question is which box
was the chimpanzee shoot
does the chimpanzee have the idea that
but communicator
he treated someplace
the chimpanzee knows
but the treaties
someplace on someplace else
make a long story short
what calling thomas l a good was to test
four and five year old children
on this task
and it turned out
that typical four-year-old
didn't pass the theory of what that this
nonverbal theory of mine
all of the past
all but the typical five-year-old did
that's in line with the original results
we talked about
so at least by the standards of the five
year olds
they can kind of get this house
question is
what are the apes do
deviates
fail this
miserably
day they don't have though that they
don't have some sense
that the home that the communicator by
pure warned that the
communicators believes
by people's they don't seem to have
the same kind of theory of mine
five-year-old
that his five-year-old infants
now were recently there has been who's
been on this could calling thomas solo
studies stimulated a lot of interest to
work
part of a number of installed of
investigators at all
at no time spent a lot of time looking
at various aspects of primate cognition
especially alot especially chimpanzee
cognition
permanent his colleagues following up on
the colin thomas ella studies
or developed
what's known as the primate cognition
test battery it's like an i_q_ test for
checked baggage
got a whole bunch of subclass on at
looking at
you know that chimpanzees ability to
deal with physical objects
i want to deal with quantities relative
walk were relatively
on through all of them
who will be differences about causality
on and also or the toast of various
social skills
whether rome
logy pansies
or other project learn
by observing each other
all how good they are at
rather than communication
finally
permanent his colleagues employed me
home
or two-thirds of the theory of mine
the animals can in fact
follow somebody else's gays sola fide
point to something
out there
in the presence of a chimpanzee
if i do that to you
so for the fact that there would be
slight or look over there
you're going to turn your eyes
and follow
all the love of apollo by david because
you cannot i'm looking at something
and you want to see what i see okay
and you turn your gays in the direction
of mine or that or or or the direction
by pointing
because you have some sense
that if you look we're all i'm looking
you'll see what on c
that's the whole point
days following
and then there was alot of but were less
than truthful
moralist and ripples leave
why does show you this because i think
huge study
they press the board or a hundred
chimpanzees
it s a whole bunch of a rang at times
and of course they put a bunch of cuban
children through these tasks is exactly
the same tasks
kids who were pretty on
on average age
of two-and-a-half years old
skipping
lightly through most of the uh...
real results of this
the apes were asked to deal with special
problems
they did pretty well not quite as well
as the kids but they did pretty well
when they were asked to deal with
questions of quantity
all of the chance of your ranks again
did relatively well
are when they were even asked to make of
the causal inferences
or do you know nate seemed to do or
relatively shipment is horrendous acts
are pretty smart
in the laboratory
when they were appalled when they were
asked to learn from each other engage in
some social learning past their children
did this very reveille
but neither the chimpanzees
the all
nor the iran depends on did
kidded somewhat better on tasks are
involving over
communication
uh... we see each other
but again when we get to the critical
theory of mine passed
these children your average age
two-and-a-half years old years of age
manage to parents
alone yarn
nonverbal theory of mine passed
all but the chimpanzees
the around that time
mostly did
these three by mta zero into possible
answers
so you'd expect fifty percent by chance
and they're performing basically
so again based on this kind of
very systematic comparison
between the park
between barbara chimpanzees ragtime
very young children
chimpanzees
do pretty well as long as they're doing
with non social kinds of things
but as soon as you get into all of the
social aspects of cognition
especially when you get to the theory of
mine
or the chimpanzees and moran seemed to
pretty poorly
on here again this is just a little of
the breakdown of those three of my best
or they're not very good at following
the kiddies
over the experimenter
on and they're not
very good about it before
experiment
volumes
as the children
now there are some problems with all
these studies and it's important before
we go much further
that we kind of talk about the vocal
for a second
our first there were a bunch of on
public on phones here
on makes a difference it turns out
whether on the animals are tested these
are usually young of a fairly or gavel
makes a difference of the weather's
animals were kids
or whether they're tested with their
parents aware that the touch the below
system social context
pyramid
probably the most critical one i think
the bulls so no problem with all of
these or the chimpanzee theory of mind
on studies
is it it makes a difference
who the experimenter it
when the subject is or human
infant
or a child
the experimental there's another human
being
but when the subject as a chimpanzee
the experimenter is
not another chimpanzee
but another human being
so it kind of asking a chimpanzee to do
something that you're not asking the
children to do
you're asking the inference to reason
about what's going on in a con specifics
head
reasonable what they are
big brothers and sisters or their
parents at all
are trying to think about
but in these tests
were always asking
chimpanzees to reason about what's going
on in and other species
and that's different task entirely
uh... what you'd really like to do
is that train up a chimpanzee research
assistant
also that you could get a chimpanzee the
v_ the indicators
reliable reliably pointing
at one forty four of the or the or the
other and then see what happens
to my knowledge no bodies dot
but if any of you ever get into a
position where you've got a hundred and
sixteen pansies and contest
really encourage her to think about this
of moreover
frogs the wall and other all that and
other investigators who look at your
pansies in the wild have found plenty of
evidence for social learning
all oblong chimpanzee
on chimpanzees are
very good at warning from other
chimpanzees
provided that this morning takes place
wondered naturalistic conditions in the
wild
if they're not so good about so-called
learning from each other in the yard
in the laboratory
that may be a problem with the
laboratory projects
so again
context seems to matter here
and wall his organs
but you get plenty of evidence
intelligence and consciousness and
chimpanzees
so long as you look at their behavior on
the more or less natural
it may very well be
that chimpanzees veranda tags
have a theory of the chimpanzee mine
or the or or the around it and mine
it something else and firewood
to ask them that they have
of theory all blown
of the eight mark
seven this at all
of the bps
critical part of the father of the
comments aside
calling thomas l have remarkably that
you know
their chimpanzees don't password
the old
the various versions nonverbal
the forcefully expressed
shut there is a lot going on inside the
head of a chimpanzee
on chimpanzee cognition go way beyond
simple stimulus response were
goes way beyond
bindle kind of repetitive mindless
acquisition hopeful of various gender
roles
and they suggested that
in fact there is a psychology the
chimpanzees have
it's just not quite the same psychology
we've got
they suggested that
junction packages have papers what they
call a perception goal
all psychology
chimpanzees have the ability
to wonder stand orders
including other species
knowledge and beliefs or they have some
sense for example mister
or that their traders concede things of
bill clinton's about that
that they don't
and also chimpanzees have some although
some of the lease wonders there
other people's goals
and intentions
when the when they are with a keeper
comes then around on the hood
around food time
the apple start asking for food stuff
pointing towards habitat for the food is
kept of all that kind
add seem to have some sense
of what the art of what the
t principles do
what callin thomas l o
or argue chimpanzees don't have
is what we typically mean by kanda bug
bite by consciousness
but no which is
that they work
what he called
they call believed
desire psychology
that is they seem to be unable to
appreciate
therefore there are people have beliefs
about the world
that may differ
from bearers
and they seem not to have the ability to
appreciate
people's beliefs
determine what their behaviors satellite
that could be like
even when their beliefs are wrong
this is the companies are the kinds of
believes buttercup
by the so-called forcefully expressed
either and it's verbal
boards nonverbal manifestations
chimpanzees just don't seem to get
don't seem to get that for
so it's not the case
the chimpanzees
dot akansh
it's not the case that jim clancy's
don't have alone
don't have that kind of psychology
it's just not arts it's about the same
as lord
forms with dot
sort of info
so let's try to review the bidding here
for a second
we're going to define consciousness in
terms of having a theory of the mind
the idea that
or mental states represent objects that
her independent of themselves
at other people may have mental
representations of the world that differ
from ors
and that people are expected to be paid
in accordance with bare all
mental representations of the world
intention ality
the love that that it's pretty clear
but we've got a people in this room
we've all got it with old humans have it
turns out the children have a true even
very young children
or fifteen months old
or with the press their belief desire
psychology they seem
they seem to have it
or at least they have the beginnings of
a as manifested like young issued
dollars joon
although i don't have time to talk about
this talk about this more the social
cognition class for those of you who
stayed around long enough to take a
former offer a tax
there's also the doors quite a bit of
evidence around now that i love the
classically autistic children
all of the do very poorly on
or both verbal and honorable
all versions of the theory of mind
which suggests
that there's some kind of limitation
consciousness their but certainly for on
chimpanzees around the kinds of other
off of others of our primate relatives
they just don't seem to have it at all
part of these
as for as we could go so we've got a
human infants have
uh... it's don't seem to have it all
now let's turn
but very briefly
for the last question
have we always have it
when you think about
consciousness
or any other
human
mental characteristic
from a fight with all of the home from a
file a genetic
the figure well
some species have it
we don't have it
ordered ordered all the other species do
have a
we've got it we've always had it
if you think about the development of
salt
mental trade my consciousness from it
auto genetic
you said well you know we call them
become one of the wall that we might
have it then but we
you'd get it pretty quickly by fifteen
months of two years of three years
alike and we just kind of keep it
from our cultural point of view however
from a historical point of view
it seems reasonable or at least
provocative
whether human beings as a species
have always been conscious
in the way that we
today in or
society and culture
have been conscious
and the reasons for thinking that this
isn't a completely stupid question
this is a question about
but historical on or or or the cultural
development
of of the whole of consciousness
all and the question of whether
somehow
human consciousness
which seems to be unique to us
is something that develop
in the human species
not just as a product of evolution
but rather
forwarding cultural history
of our species
guy don't try to answer this question
all was well of of the princeton
psychologist named julian james his now
deceased
also wrote in nineteen seventy six and
cst railway provocative book
all which i recommend to all of you for
your summer reading this is really
beach reading money combined
the origins of consciousness in the
breakdown of the bicameral mine
uh... and i did it in this book
while james tries to make the case
human consciousness is not just and
pro byproduct of our own of our
revolution
something that came with us what we
became humans as a species
but rather the human consciousness that
is our cultural achievement
and that there was a point
in historical time where we didn't have
the same human consciousness
that we have kit
and james follow the rights very
movingly about law about the source of
this it's like he was sitting in one day
we homer's iliad
he was really a bit in greek
avijit
i did in the product of a classical
education and they're all such a lot on
him
then hollywood's iliad
nobody
nobody makes decisions
nobody interest faxed nobody looks into
his minded but don't try to figure out
what he's feeling
nobody talks about the past there's just
no
no i'm not all that interior mental life
in the characters all of the iliad
that we expect all of these days to find
ought in anything that anybody rights
rather what happens in the iliad
is a god's helm and what to do and them
and go out to do it
the only people who think immediately
so james argues
fall apart
that their gods
all but uh... love your morals just
don't do it at all
james his argument is
this very clear
from from the literary structure of the
iliad
and he argues that this is not merely a
poetic device
by the rather
that the way things goal
mentally
don't go mentally immediately
is kind of characteristic of
what we were wiped out a particular
point in our historical
and cultural evolution
and this is kind of a evident from the
very first lines all quality
i'll be away
hog here we have a good adopting all
support the translation of his love rage
products
saying the rage of pelli assad achilles
and blah blah blah blah blah blah
and the will of the worst was moving
towards its and
the whole propel portly it begins with
the will of the woods
our handout
and the other gods begin news when the
two nd first broken clashed our demand
on board of men and the brilliant
achilles
and the aliya picks up
or midway through the trojan war on it's
been going on for taking pictures
and dot and then some of the uh... and
that goes on to the to retail
various incidents of the uh... in the
trojan war
but what's interesting about them is
that when you look at those those
incidents
they don't send to stem from people's
desire
they don't uh... what goes on in the
elite does nothing to do with what
people believe what they wont or even or
even what they feel
think about the start of the trojan war
where parents kidnaps helen widest paris
kidnap helen
well course helen is the most beautiful
woman in the world the face the wards of
march two thousand shift
paris doesn't want
cially goddesses came to paris and said
which one of us is the most beautiful
and after a died he says if you say i
love the most beautiful person a little
although although you have a good barry
helen
the comparison all okay
and so can you are the most beautiful
one
how are you married
she is married a man always right that's
why the trojan war starts okay
paris doesn't know what to do about hell
is this guy is a very shepherd living on
the hills all doesn't had any idea
what's going on
funds all grilled patrolling
on pandemic occurring
let later on in the trojan war
there's a door between mandalay else
who's
husband
and paris who was helen's kidnapper
just about the metal as his throttling
paris
and just about the time middle ace is
about to kill paris what happens
one of god's comes down
text paris hoping dump some back behind
the walls of choice
so they've got to do when the stock
is logon standing on the walls of troy
looking down on the thousand ships of
the tens of thousands of men
and she feels and
absolutely no responsibility for what's
but what what what what's been going on
the move gee that's really pple
this is really something
although antibodies later chiles would
run kills factor because the sort of
king pre-order
and preempt comes out of the asks off of
that families for for actors bodies look
at the above the burial
and achille says no i don't wanna
uh... non-factor killed by my ya
mario
my friend and achilles
part of the bench league yes
hector is body to preempt
but not because he feels any kind of
sympathy for prayer
i tell his mother wrote pearson occurs
through agreements has given party
parts or did you think that will turn on
they're not loaded just kind of goes off
and
doesn't he doesn't
think about anything
nobody in the iliad
there's a judge in a paris there's
another one
depart james points out that all of the
whole language of the iliad which seems
at first glance to be suffused with
mentalist construct
doesn't really have the middle slightly
doesn't mean solar mind of the iliad
it means something close to the breath
or or blood
toward most which would not only visa
motion
doesn't mean emotion in the alluded
means motion
volvo
although the the the distinction between
buying the body doesn't seem to exist
uh... in the yard deal with it
or contrast that
the odyssey
the story although justice is returned
to ethical and his wife
developing
again here's how it began saying to me
if a man news
dumb and up twists and turns
many cities of men who fought and
learned their minds
odysseus is
always
he's always trying to figure stuff out
he's always plotting he's always
tricking people
he's always trying to figure out what's
going on in somebody else's life
he's with the calypso when the silence
right what is what what what what is a
disgusting
he has his men
taught him
the mast so he can hear the sirens call
but he feels his meds here's with work
so they won't
he has some sense
if they hear what he hears
that they'll do what he wants to do
he has some sense of what he'll want to
do with the sirens call so we have some
self tied to the ship's mast
thinking ahead he's planning he's a
badge name what's going to go on
on max
alderdice aerosol go out with a truck by
this like lots of policy-wise
argued with the people lines for cyclops
that so that the cyclops won't be able
to see him
on cycle of the policy was asks song
uh... what this is his name and he says
i have no body
imo
uh... united greek
then bulb
part of it as i would look a little
justices has his men escape
holding on to the bottoms
bellies are both or polity position so
that went on with the mist
tries to see if the better writing
although the sheep out of the cape
he won't dog
odd people dog all of them
the discover them
and then when they get out there kind of
justice has been a right to skate
apology was calls to insult cyclops
friends
mistake was hurting you polity missoni
says
nobody is hurting me
'cause that's what he thinks lazard
welcome nobody is hurting him sober dot
going to come to your rescue right
that's what goes on all the way through
the odyssey
home ought to do you think he's always
conscious of the way you were conscious
he's thinking he's thinking about what
other people are thinking he's trying to
plan arquivo around that
nothing like that happens in the phone
immediately
kalin there's not if you read the story
of jason the oregon dot so did you get
jason
very much like a business is somebody
who's thinking for himself
jason sat silent wary wants his eyes
fixed on the ground beef or is he
at a loss as to what to do with his
wretched situation
strong for a long time he turned over
and over what issues
thinking and await that
that uh...
the uh... than the characters in the
iliad
while you can see this in the hebrew
bible
the the said said the same distinction
the provoked a story about a minivan
the expulsion from the garden of eden
have been able to plop down the garden
of eden and god says
though eat the tree of the fruit of the
heart of the though the fruit of the
tree of knowledge of good we will miss
her okay
than the supper comes along and says to
you
etc might have the sample
okay
and so she hates the apple and then she
gives up a bit to uh... to uh...
they're going to welcome back to the
sentences to describe the okay
automatons that just
responding to whatever the last thing
was that happened to them
until they eat from that
the fruit of the tree of knowledge of
god evil
then there are teas are open
and there should be as gods they knew
that they were naked they had self
recognition that the ferry make about
never thought of that before
on but the birth they got consciousness
head up at that point it was a time in
the garden when they were conscious
and there's a time at the garden
they were conscious
look at some of the hebrew prophets this
is from the book of a mississippi of the
book of the starts
famous is a profit
what they've been critical of of the you
know
uh... opinion
israel right
he doesn't speak for himself
here all who care always rule but with
all of the what the lord says the lord
warrants from his lion
and orders invoices were beautiful
but says the lord and then it goes on
and on and on and on
and then the next at the next verses
boss says the lord that i got up
answers and walked in here
amos has just come out
piece for a full bore
docent
doesn't seem to have ideas
of his own
quite different from what you see in the
book of a clean csd is also part of the
orbiaz orbited revival
by the preacher had been came over
israel in jerusalem
and i applauded my mind to seek and the
search out by wisdom all that is going
on her heaven
and i said to myself i've acquired great
wisdom surprising or whatever
all all the world for two rooms for so
wonderful
the the right over clearview wesleyan
in a way that the writer
the book of business
on fiscal just doesn't seem to be
always what what what changes argued
go back here for a second
what changes argues that early creatures
were essentially creatures of
they were descends
automatons basically responding whatever
was going on
om on dot around them
all quality
whatever thoughts they had
were interpreted as instructions from
the gods
early early humans according to james
they just been realized that their
thoughts were their own
they thought that those thoughts
were essentially coming from the gods
who were actually on
actually controlling
james dates the origin of consciousness
roughly third century he's on the
millennium bc
fault that the beginnings of it
as human beings
shifted from their or the perform their
original hunter gathering mode
on into our agriculture and large cities
and what happened over what happened
then according to james
as soon as you begin to develop
civilization
fabric all true
city life and so on
or what you need all
is all in some way of controlling these
large groups of people
and at some point that at some point
or what happened was that
came to be constructed this kind of
are fairly rigid social hierarchy or
where
thank god
speaks to the tape
the king does when he's told
and the kings speaks of the people under
him
and date
what they're told
white concept comes from the tape
who was told to do what he does
called by god again
order following that goes
uh... goes from the top down
on you can see this again in the hebrew
bible
think about moses
on rather than on mount sinai
bozo sees all those horrible stuff going
on with the along with the with the
israel lights
but most as doesn't come down and say
hey you guys
i think that we shall not buying
neighbor not kill and don't covet your
wife of your neighbor's wife and all the
stuff
gets the ten commandments from god
all deep this was a blow sis's idea
there was something that was given him
what happens then
the beginning roughly in the first
millennium bc somewhere around on it
around there
you've got lots of people together
hearing lots of different voices lots of
disagreement about these voices and what
happens is
all of the band of the heart of the
begin people human beings
definitely are
they're actually thinking part for the
other for themselves
that the gods of no longer telling them
what to do the oracle's begin to
disappear of or around this time
and the whole thing
is consolidated
onto watching what was called the golden
age of grace
around six hundred b_c_
gets solon of with his prescription gold
i sell forget paris tunnel and
plato and socrates encouraging people
think for themselves
if you go elsewhere
targeted in india and china
you get the buddha
encouraging people to
think for themselves and to attribute
their problems to their
not gods
and you get
confucius and china
on both of them celebrating people's
capacity to think for themselves as well
james's arguing
that there was this
she huge
cognitive shift
that occurred
in historical time
from a cognitive stance in which people
experience themselves as more or less
what caught my plans to do in what they
were
holden
operating as creatures of habit
to point where
human beings experienced themselves
for themselves
and soon as
i'll blog
though that cubans experience themselves
get view themselves as thinking for
themselves
that is what james coles
jan's question origins of consciousness
and he sums us up at a later paper the
swarm of modern beautiful politics
all that is most human about us this
consciousness
this artificial space we have najib and
other people within ourselves
this living within our reminiscences
plans of imagining
all of this is indeed
only about three thousand years old
told me something
really merchants on the human singing
roughly one thousand
one thousand nancy
that ladies and gentlemen is less than
one hundred generations
and from that i think we can conclude
that we are all
only a hundred generations
james's view
separate us
separate or
consciousness
creatures who work joyce like rust
genetically
just like us in terms of brain structure
just like most in terms of having
language
but somehow
appears to have
the same kind of consciousness
james may or may not be right
there's a lot of that there's still a
lot of dispute about this it's kind of a
really
boggles the mind of think that human
consciousness was not something that he
was always had
but that's the whole point of writing a
provocative book
want to get people thinking
one thing we know
is that consciousness is a great gift
called pollution
we've got
a level of consciousness that the
weather creature has
consciousness is a great gift of human
development
the consciousness of adult humans
for the consciousness all or of human
infants
the changes right consciousness
and achievement of civilization
it's something
that we have choir over
the course of cultural time
slumping white an aspect
pop culture
or society
which means i guess
for all we sell about consciousness that
such arable thing to waste
ought to go to scotland
and you go visit the castle although i
don't
quarter castle dot where mcduff org
but that this instructor but had was at
the airport
you go
over the door the entrance of the castle
as though you know or the famous waters
of coat of arms
bottle up here
the mindful
never was there any
better advice that anybody could give
talk to us
we've got consciousness
there was a time when either we didn't
have consciousness or bigger no we have
consciousness
now we have consciousness it's good
to behave as if we did
so
be mindful
thank you very much
fight
had a very good time teaching this
course i always do this was one of the
one about what one of one of the better
classes along really good classes
although
look forward to was seeing you all of
the review session
at the final exam
wanted to know
thank you very much