okay what do we begin
and off
if there's anybody who was not here last
week in any of the syllabus there are
somewhat here you can pick them up
hector clouds
cornell
or you can download it from the course
website
again this week
although last week you should have gone
to your discussion section
and you should do that again this week
not just because discussions section of
the good thing
but because we might want need to make
sure that we know who's in the class
we apologize for the are confusions
about
those phantom discussion sections that's
what happens when you saw for
staffing cuts through the budget
fall bob will do our best to get all of
those
or all of you who registered for one of
phantom sections
onto the chorus
we'll do our best with that
okay
problem of consciousness was set
for fall off the field by rene descartes
who's trying to figure out what he could
believe what he couldn't believe all and
he dog discovered that the one thing he
couldn't on dot which was that he was
thinking
that he was doubting
and all point i'll make a little bit
later is set for descartes think he was
just a kind of umbrella term that
covered
all mental state solve all of all sorts
and consciousness was picked up as a
problem for psychology by william james
of who wrote in his pioneering solid
introductory psychology of the textbook
that the psychology was the science of
mental life
by which he meant
the science to takes it upon himself to
describe consciousness arms and to uh...
and to explain consciousness
in the principles of allah james alm
open
referred to
the relatively small experimental
literature on dan in psychology that was
available to him at the time
but janusz piano plus a for first time
foremost
all apart that dogged looked the best
place to start first look for oprah
scientific psychology
was with a technique that floss for
student had made famous for couple
thousand years which was so which was
introspection
and he argued that have all the methods
in psychology
introspection is what we have to rely on
first and foremost of all week
james is a wonderful writer
and that when we look into our minds
what we discovered there are states of
consciousness
yes echoing day cards as i thought one
thing you cannot doubt
you can doubt that those states of
consciousness mean anything
if you want
but you can't doubt that you have
these of uh...
the use of these states of consciousness
and then james goes on in a famous
chapter of the on on on the stream of
thought to analyze the characteristics
of consciousness
that he finds when he intro specs
when he turns his attention inward and
tries to analyze his own
on them to light
here are the five
our characters of consciousness of james
discovered all talk about each of the
briefly arm you know
in a second
first of these areas
although it
that consciousness is personal or is
james put it fought tends to personal
forum
and he says
when you think about
what you'll find when you introspective
don't just find thoughts
what you'll find our your own thoughts
you don't find somebody else's sports
you don't find thoughts that somebody
for a couple years ago or anything like
that
you find on you find your own thoughts
and then he goes on to our to assert
that the universal consciousness act is
not that
gov thoughts and feelings exist
but rather
is thinking or heat is feeling something
that's what james means
by thought tending to personal form
the second characteristic as i thought
is in constant change
alva
the general idea here is that
you can have a conscious mental state
because
think of something
and end on think of something else and
then think of that first thing again
and even that
second thought of the first thing again
is a different for the entirely
not least because
when you think of something the second
time
you're aware of having fought it part of
the first time there's no bottling
sensation or thought no feel we know
desired no nothing
all that you ever have to be exactly
the same way twice
is in constant change
and then fought is also sensibly
continuous
palm he argued that we don't just have
little pieces of consciousness to know
that there is a while when we're not
conscious of them all others while when
we're conscious again
but rather and this is what gives him
the the metaphor of the stream of
consciousness
called bed that there's a constant flow
of continuous flow of consciousness
yes it's true that consciousness appears
to be interrupted when were asleep
for what we've been hit on the head and
rendered unconscious
or when we've been given some kind of
anesthetic agent that renders us on
conscious
but when we wake up
james argued
we pick up where we left off
in that sense
consciousness is still altman sensibly
continuous
on your don't wake up this at all would
you you know you kind of wonder who i a
m er what i was thinking nor all import
duties are
on entirely hold new batch of fought so
i've got
we don't have that kind of experience
when we wake up in the morning
we experience ourselves as the same
person
as we
alone as we experienced when we went to
bed
on the night before
park here of one of the point that will
pick up on a couple of minutes
cuban flawed appears to deal with
objects independent of itself
which is to say
fought is always on bumps something you
don't just have a few
right like a cartoon character with are
kinda bubble over your head
called the hog attendees
oh or just that is thinking or whatever
and it you're always
the longer always thinking about
something
this is what he calls the cognitive
function on the line
the mind knows the things that appear
before it
and it knowles that it knows that
it's physical wearing those all
awareness of perceiving
uh... or or whatever
that's important
one piece of consciousness
and then
consciousness is always interested in
more in one part of its object
then in another
this is james is all a part of their own
but i think it is interested in the
phenomenon of attention
on the world out there is all good
things he characterized it
elsewhere
is a blue mean baatein confusion
until we begin to sort things out
by paying attention to some things
or saw aspects of things more that we
pay attention to other kinds of things
accentuate shannan emphasis or present
and every perception we have
we look at some things will calm or the
new work of others
look at some aspects of those things
more than the book
brothers yep
this is exactly about selective
attention the fact that i'm not aware of
everything going on in this room right
now i'm looking at you
and paid attention to u_n_ everybody
else kind of fades into the background
that's exactly right
ahir james's although the setting the
stage for some people talk about him
three weeks
which is the relationship between
consciousness
and uh... attention
consciousness welcomes and rejects or
chooses
all the while it
so that's kind of what
james talked about uncut consciousness
at the most abstract level
the next question is what kinds of
thoughts or their what kinds of mental
states all org are there
all that we find when we
looking into already
all of the most succinctly
answer to this question was actually
given to us not by a psychologist papaya
philosopher immanuel kant or writing in
the critique of judgement towards the
end of the eighteenth century
where cult simply a starts
forbearers
three
absolutely irreducible faculties of mine
knowledge
feeling
and desire
on this gives us the classical so-called
trilogy of mind what psychology is all
about cognitive states
that have to do with
on knowing and believing things
affect in-state for abortion will state
we have to do
feeling things
and the cognitive states are
motivational states
that have to do with desire read or
wanting things
and when khan says that
there are these three stalled
faculties knowledge
feeling and desire our absolutely
irreducible
what he says if you can't get one from
the other
are that there is something
qualitatively different
then there is about
wanting something or feeling something
they call it was a very good about
expressing exactly what those
qualitative differences are you simply
asserted uh... that they are uh...
that they're qualitatively different but
i think if you think
wanted to just kind of
reflect on your own mental states for a
moment
on think about when you were
feelings of a motion allstate door
desiring all hamburger or a snickers bar
or whatever it is to be divider
homework thinking about some of our
problem in calculus or whatever
that those
three different kinds of states knowing
feeling the desiring
have some qualitative differences all
about them
and we'll come back
to arkansas idea that these are your
reducible faculties of mine
column for the compliment
so now let's just kind of focus for a
moment
on various kinds of cognitive states
of which perhaps most of what bob dole
states home sensation on and perception
the force of a risk for developing
in terms of
palm harbor what what are known as
sensory quality out
one-for-one floss first talk about
quality of the refer to
the subjective qualities of various are
conscious experiences
and we can think about these subjective
qualities as differing in uh... in a
variety of ways
first with respect to the sensory
modalities
seen something
is that qualitatively different
experience than hearing something
smelling something as a qualitatively
different experience than tasting
something
on and and
and and so on
now maybe we can kind of
reduce
pasting them vision or something like
that
but that's not what the way we
experience things of at all
there are qualitatively different
states of consciousness associated with
these various instrumentality
and also within each sensory modality
there are qualitatively
qualities ok retrieved by the way of
thinking about quali up
or within vision
those are the difference between seen
red and seeing blue
within got station
the difference between peace team suite
and pasting sour this something that's
like
to see something that's red that's
different from what it's like to see
something
to see something that's flu
so has been a lot of interest in
promoting the flossie of mind especially
since descartes
in the nature of these all of these
quali abuse at the zone subjective
qualities of conscious experience
and although general philosophical
approach to quali a
is nicely summarized by loss for daniel
bennett actually doesn't policeman
quality
albany says what your believing quali
episode what you believe in
that the whole goal quali i have these
four properties
the first of which is the most important
for our purposes
which is that
followed by the quality are art
ineffable
all somehow that is
that it's difficult
it's impossible
to describe hall what
sensory experience is like
onto dot
to somebody else
if you think about it for a moment what
is that exactly is it like to
see something
well you know what it's like to see
something and you know that it's not
that different to see something
called on her that it that it is the
care something
but try to convey that
goes to different experiences to
somebody else
and you find yourself
quite literally apple loss for words
same thing goes when you tried to convey
to somebody else
what it's like to see red as opposed to
blue
how do you describe blue
ads not so easy act
art that's what we mean by quality of
our ineffable
the second property of quality of
is that they are intrinsic to various
kinds of states which is to say
that you can't really analyzed them into
something more basic you can reduce
these all
these qualitative song
that sent three states
to something else
if i put up walden
uh... if i put a whole
northwst waffle orange for example you
know i said
all you know that thing of our image
there that looks kinda or red and it
looks kind of yellow
alternate that's fine
it looks kind of red looks kind of
yelling out tell me what red looks like
alright there we go
orange maybe isn't
of of one of these basic sensory quali a
but red and yellow apparently are
for mug and that there comes a point
where you just can't have a lights and
the uh... any longer
quali are are held to be private
that is to say
i have an experience of bread
and you interview has an experience of
bread
but it's not going to be possible for me
to compare by experience of red to your
experience ret
there's some there's a barrier there
all uh... that prevents us from making
any kinds of comparisons
between one person's mental state
and another person's mental state
and the final property subclause first
talk about
when they talk about quality
the basically all qualities of sensory
experience
or directly apprehended
that is there not
mediated by anything else you don't say
all wat do u hav that's that must be
read
are you available speedo some words
raised his head back to us are tearing
straight
you're just experience it as what it is
you don't you're not making any kind of
judgment
all about it so
although when they believe in quality or
not
all of these are the properties
that quality of are supposed to happen
now let's illustrate this a little bit
are beginning with of with old problem
posed by another floss for frank jackson
all who focused on this quality of the
adaptability aryan is thought experiment
concerning marry the color blind
scientists to spot expert goes by
number of names
but they all have meri
colour blinded scientists
all in them
anne r dot jackson asks us to imagine
of all the problem in meri who's a are
visual neuroscientist
who has been raised her entire life in
eight chromatic chamber
all
gold
uh... the uh... what was to be a lawyer
or in shades of gray black and white
and uh... and shades of gray
so that she's had no experience of red
and green in all of that
nevertheless mary knows all there is
about the nervous system analyst in
particular she knows all there is to
know
about hong
about uh... of the visual science and
hong kong revision works and all that
kind of stuff
and jackson asks us to what magid
all-white
happens
when mary for the first time walks out
of this
fault though the a chromatic world that
you've been living in for her entire
life
into a world
room of the room like this
harbo she have any kind of new
experience
i'll
something i've never thought of before
so that i've never experienced before or
does she say that's right by knew all
along that that's what red looked like
because i know everything there is to
know
about the nervous system
jackson's intuition and most people's
intuition is that mary will have a new
experience
when she moves into this world
and uh... yet the ideas did she knows
all there is to know about coloring
color vision
madam eaters and odd lateral geniculate
nucleus and all that stuff
all but it's not enough
to give her another on or experience
all jackson also
of poses of pose a problem of
all which were will call the slightest
with supervision
or fred's a colleague of mary's home was
also a visual neuroscientist knows
everything there is to know
about home of them about the uh...
visual system
and in fact jackson s are stupid this
role
role so visual neuroscientist we know
everything there is general about the
visual system
but it turns out fred's kind of
interesting
he's got abou arrange on boggled a
vision that extends into the infrared or
into the oprah wire it verbal violence
home all wavelengths that most of us
park and see
and the jackson says what you've got an
observer here
who knows all the rest of the above the
river system
and then u_s_ good
well when fred looks at all true violet
light or infrared light one is ec
well if you knew everything that there
was no but the nervous system
well maybe you want to be able to answer
that question
and you really can't
answer that question
home
salarpuria again this is kind of inept
ability you can't
third-person description of salam
sensory system
to a first-person description of what
the hong
of what the experiences
now this is all lights these are the
kinds of things philosophers to us
right they make a living
on part of the hog
the conjuring up these kinds of things
what's interesting is
there's somebody like this
not nordiques
all who is a art of the food is in fact
a color scientist
who is in fact colorblind
arm
and he's written about his experiences
as what i got to know everything there
is the bowel about color vision
i know all the physics i know that all
the physiology of the colors system i
know all about receptors on
opponent prophecies of all that the
other kind of stuff
no by deal what these colors look like
on
and he knows all about golf
colour mixture and the metaphorical of
the implications of color and all that
kind of stuff
but he still has no idea what these
colors
so the point of this story is first
there is a philosophical challenge of
philosophical conundrum in wicker argue
about it all we want okay
but as we move towards the science of
consciousness
weekend actually begin to collect some
impure kal evidence
about various kinds of things there's
this one guy out there on god's green
earth
who happens to be
called the hoboken colors scientist who
knows everything there is to know about
color and whose nonetheless has no
experience
all ball of color
which suggests that jackson's intuition
uh... right
here's another case to case odd
described by oliver sacks
of the patient jayada
who was an artist of visual artist
who sustained a traumatic up all but the
injury to a part of his brain review for
right there
palm which all it would be now we know
is important for processing or color
experiences before is basically been
wiped out
on inpatient uh... jaaye
all and what's interesting is that
r_j_ ait no longer concede color at all
and he can't
imagine
what colors looked like he can do he
does a dream in color email dreams and
grayscale
all but he's retained
everything that
a trained artist knows about color the
color mixture of what color things are
and all that kind of business so we can
still do his work
but he joins
any longer have the experience of color
so here again is an empirical case
with more beat
which suggests that no wind
knowing all the wrist a dull
about the physics of the physiology of
color vision
isn't enough to give us the bong
give us the experience of color
we're going to take say more about quali
o a little bit later on
but let's take up on the other property
called bob consciousness that gets a lot
of attention in the philosophical
literature
and that is intention ality
a philosophical terms and this is
another thing the philosopher is due to
us with some are regularity they take a
permit has perfectly clear armenian and
english and they
turn it into something else
all when i say i intend to do something
like i am tend to feed my cat or uh...
or whatever
by declaring that i'm gonna love
engage in some kind of behavior
but that's not what intentionally means
and
philosophy
or rather of the
difficult philosophical term
intentionally comes from this latin term
in anzio
which refers to ideas
and the general ideas that intention
ality
has to do
palm
representations
of various kinds of objects
and this is for us for viennese
philosopher
german alternate
volvo prawns brent auto
who had this idea
that all of mental life
was characterized
by intention ality
as brent i don't put it
intention now will be is the more called
the mental
or by which he meant that all mental
states are intentional in nature
and all only mental states
are intentional inmates
and when he says intentionally as the
work of the mental what he says it
all mental states or about something
remember that character of consciousness
that james talked about
that all mental states are about
something or other than themselves
they represent something else
that's what friends connell uh... was
uh... was getting at
so the i did for the general idea here
is that consciousness is
representational or conscious mental
states or always about something else
yeah there's a connection between your
mental state and something in the
outside world
that's right for mental state
isn't just about itself it's about
display i'm
not know governmental stateful of you
palms and in a moment it's going to be
so now that's an interesting problem
alm bertrand russell english forsberg
kind of bald of
and added to our understanding of this
all by arguing that intention albee
really comes in the form of what russell
called
propositional additives
all which takes a formal or mental
states take the form of
john believes that it's raining outside
and russell argued
that intention alley
includes
some proposition about the world
that's the thing that my mental state is
about
solomon attitude which represents the
nature
my mental state
all propositions are statements that
have truth value it's either raining
outside or it's not raining outside
and then the added to
all it is equivalent to some state like
believe e north eighteen or no way
whatever
home
it's not the if somebody says it's
raining outside
fact that it's raining outside is not my
mental state that's a state of the world
my mental state is my belief that it's
raining outside or my perception that
it's raining outside or my knowledge
that it's raining outside
so all these mental states
actually take uh... victims for
now that take you a long way towards
thinking about intention ality and uh...
in consciousness
ust especially if you think about
consciousness in terms of so-called
cognitive states
states of knowledge or all or uh... or
believe
but when you start thinking about nam
cognitive states
you begin to get into a little bit of
trouble
ice right now have a mental state
on one sheet
not a serious mental state like to live
are by far the third level so that i
want to pizza
home and that is why emotional say on
light on it like pizza
on and i'd like to have a pizza sometime
soon
all of that so that so that's an
emotional state but if you think about
it for a second that is might
mental state at the moment the i could
tell you right now i'd like to use its
about the fact that i
dislike pizza
all i want to pizza it's not the fact
that i don't want a piece of but there
really isn't any propositional content
here where's the proposition
there is an attitude
an attitude of lighting or an attitude
of wanting
but there is a dead heat
uh... but there isn't any propositional
content
so there's a challenge here
which is if we're going to say
state some knowledge feeling then desire
our here we are doing some bull
faculties of mine
we know how to describe cognitive states
states of knowledge in terms of
propositional attitudes
but it's not entirely clear how we
should characterize or emotional or only
be emotional motivational states
now one
solution to this
that's been offered by psychologists
especially stanley schachter and his
colleagues were on the center
and a famous paper
all about uh... love them
or the by the motion published in
nineteen sixty two
brush actor and singer basically argued
that emotional and motivational states
really can be reduced a cognitive states
that is that kant was wrong
that states of fielding and desire are
irreducible this to uh...
two states of knowledge
they took the position that in fact
when you say that who'd web when john
says that he likes pizza
what john
really
means
john believes that he likes pizza
doesn't really like pizza he just thinks
he does
all
and when john once a pizza
what he reeled off his mental state
really is
although that the state of belief that
he believes he wants pizza
all but he doesn't uh... but
stop the case of the actually once that
he just thinks it does
and by this kind of gambit
you can add propositional content
he wants pizza if you like speed so
that's a perfectly fine proposition
and then you add the added to
volvo all believe to it
to get the emotion
schachter and server really quite
serious about this
all of
of the the bills
famous songs our theory of a motion
lasted for a good thirty forty years of
still around
those who took it provoked a recent
college e read about this theory in your
hard with a textbook part no
on emotion
and it's something that still with us
today there's a group of for new
philosophers
part of the new atheists
small who owns argue the people who
don't actually believe in god
they just believe they do
uh... an
had that struck the same kind of quality
to it
but what's going on here is that shocked
arresting or are in fact
dead body
and say look
we can always reduced
an emotional state to a cognitive state
we can always reduced motivational state
to some kind of car the state and there
are no fistfights
on professional meetings o about whether
this is the case
yep quick question
yahoo arguably be what you like or wont
but you don't really
or one
yet about your notice actor and singer
experiment
okay much actress ever did to make a
really brief i wasnt to do this but all
do it anyway
all what schachter a singer did was to
uh... take subjects and on
surreptitiously
inject them with a drug epitaph trend
that the audience that induces a state
of physiological arousal never mind how
they did this located at
palm and uh... o
heartburn
all later on in the experiment
are they put the person who was now in
the state of physiological arousal with
a
schachter actually characterizes the
person is ours
of school gym
ordered the confederate of the
experimenter
who within one condition was behaving in
a very dat happy matter
and another condition of the experiment
was behaved in a very hostile angry
manner
all and that's the important is
environment with this person you're
feeling physiologically aroused and then
schachter and singer asked you what you
were
okay and it turned out that subjects who
fought with the who were tested
in the presence of a happy confederate
said that they were happy
and subjects were tested
in the presence of
an angry confederate said that they were
angry
and what schachter answer your concluded
from this is that we interpret our state
official physiological arousal with
almost all states have in common
by looking to the environment and to
trying to determine
all broke from the environment accusers
to that that basically explains why were
around
so if i morale is in the context of a
happy person so i must be happy
and if i'm around in the context of an
angry person i'd say must be angry
that's the general idea here
visited exactly this way
you're reducing an emotional state
to will belief
emotional state
you're reducing an emotional state
to apartment
shell that's
really aleman osama
that
let's go to the forward their willingham
discussed three
the third all aspect all called the
consciousness of the force routes or
talk about allot
which is all which is the the
the aspect of subjectivity
alm which is
nowhere
federer at all of the decks preston by
of berkeley zone home
or flow through drugs for all
conscious states exist
all lee as they are experienced by like
human or animal subject
remember from last time wouldn't makes
is really interesting distinction
between
physics
and psychology that physics is the
science of experience without an
experience in subject
and psychology is the size of experience
with an experience in subject sorrel is
trying to get at
part of that at the
the same kind of thing
and all basically says the pope
conscious mental states
have a subjective mode of existence
flip-flops principle
hong kong on call on college e they
exist or waived by virtue of having
someone who actually experiences
if there's no one to experience some
that they don't exist at all
which is different from all other island
features of the world
in general
have existence is independent of the
observer
this table
on that wall the clouds and the skye
outside the trees and all that stuff
they exist whether the experience them
or not
but conscious states
only exist in so far
as of that as as they were experienced
by someone
and that gives harm
all unconscious mental states a spurt
come interesting quality hard for them
and also opposes the challenge for
a scientific approach to consciousness
which is
of the level from last time
science is supposed to be talking about
the objective and the public
consciousness is subjective in private
how can you possibly have
say they are
the about science of consciousness
kind of signed posters for you a little
bit sir also qual that's problem repeat
uh... that did if you want to do science
you gotta figure out haha do this and he
simply points out
that the fact
the subject matter is onto logically
subjective
doesn't necessarily preclude plus from
had been epistemic lee object to the
sites that has passed
objective knowledge
about uh... all of these kinds of things
an old chin trying on
towards the end of this what your
certainly on one st
to show you how really psychologist
tried to do just that
which was to have
and epistemic lee
objective science
all of them onto logically
subject re
but just to keep a couple of suffers
right now
this subjectivity ald part of the aspect
of consciousness
how was i think nowhere better hog tie
the character done by for another plus
for thomas naval at n_y_u_
all did a famous essay that you're going
to see references to
of the later on
what is it like to be a batch
and what naples point here is
if you have a consciousness perry mrs
then there is something that's like
to have them
if you have conscious experiences
there's something it's like to be an
organism that can have are conscious
spirit
fundamentally an organism has conscious
mental states if in oriya
there's something that it's like to be
that organism
something that it's like
that organism so it's something that's
very there's something it's like
for me to have the experience of red
all but when you hold a you already
object up in front of your cellphone
camera
completely obviously
there's something it's like for your
cellphone camera
you know that there's something it's
like for you
and what it's like is different from
what it's like when you see green
what it's like
when you smell bob woodward but when you
taste sweet
is different from what it's like
or when the parliament
when you can start work
hong and for that matter
since that you have
ultrasonic area
they could hear frequencies weekend here
there is something that's like to be a
bad
that's not what it's like to be arts
uh... they have different kinds of uh...
sensory
censored capacity
um... they steeple
sold now let's just try to take this the
philosophical background which is
aside from next monday just about all
the philosophy you're gonna get out of
me
cassettes just about all the force be
i'd have to give
let's take some of these questions and
use them to with some of these debates
and use them to re frames hobart
questions about conscious
first as we think we have conscious
mental states we we experience ourselves
as had been conscious mental state
but some psychologists have argued
that we also have off one conscious
mental states
that is states of knowledge
feeling that desire
that we have been that dog uh... that
influence or behavior
but which were not aware of having we
don't have time to six p reinstalled
so now we have a question about whether
things like waali up the redness of read
the saw weirdness of slower
or home argued would order for it
intentional states wanting the peace or
like in the pizza
can in any sense beyond conscious
this is a question mark hall
come up against
home later
the semester
harsh
another question
kenneth is a true
for example
that palm
whole conscious mental states are
qualitative states or all conscious
mental states are intentional states
ten-year have consciousness
without
intention ality
rent auto said no
that intention only is the work of the
mental
all mental states or intentional in
nature any statements intentional is
mental in nature
that swine
but there are quite people like
zen
meditate urs
who argued
that they have conscious mental states
once a year
get the santori for whatever it's called
hongkong
all of that they have
or conscious mental states
part about anything at all
europe you work
now that's an interesting point
haha we would know this is not
completely clear
it's at least a question about whether
you can actually have a conscious mental
state
that doesn't have any qualitative on
characteristics to it
or better yet
a conscious mental state that isn't
above which
anything
at all
trend nonhuman animals
have are going to have bob have
intentional states
all we know we can
our budget tenured auger my character or
somebody's chimpanzee or somebody's
earthworm or whatever
all have while
uh... have constantly states
in anything like the way that we can
have
conscious mental state
and just to get back to the cellphone
example
we can know them can machines
have intentional states
on your cell phone
thermostat
uh... really good computer
on does it had anything like
intentionally
intentionally attached to it
and there are floss first talk about the
briefly
next week that you'll read about them
who actually say yes
on david chalmers
or very prominent for thr is worth a lot
about consciousness
quite happy with the idea
that thermostat self-consciousness
it's pretty impoverished consciousness
apparently all blood
it's again
and then finally we get to the big one
which is
we know we have these things
descartes seven what whatnot i'm fifty
and i'm thinking about thinking there is
that i can doubt that
jane says as soon as we look into our
minds we find mental states
but now the question is
actually cause anything
do conscious states
a causal role in the world
for our date more or less the phenomenal
these are the kinds of things that uh...
that uh... but we could talk about
let's take a couple of minutes just to
develop a couple of these things in
terms of
in terms of inside
first let's return to the definition of
consciousness in terms of quality
that consciousness has to do
with various qualities of
all of experience
we have a sensory modalities like
hearing in vision and got station of all
faction
and there's something it's like to see
something
that somehow different from what it's
like the taste
and we have these various sensory
qualities within our
of various instrumentality
if there's something it's like to see
red
different from what it's like to see
blue
and so on and most we can now begin to
ask questions what
where it is it's come from
where does seeing and hearing come from
uh... where it is seen red vs the of
blue come from
this is a question that has been
addressed scientifically since the
beginning of of the nineteenth century
by people
who are involved in an to while
subfields of psychology and biology
known as sense recycle physics
and all
and sensory
sensory girl physiology
let's look at
the various instrumentality
how many different ways do we have
to sense the world
what different kinds of said three for
instance do we have
aristotle famously argued that there
were five
uh... senses
vision audition
bus station
or faction
and the tactile sensor sense volvo touch
see i shall renton an important or a
physiologist on in the sort of lectures
uh... earlier in the twentieth century
argued that aristotle was on the right
track that he didn't quite have count
right
of that and that we have at least uh...
that at least eight
sense river valleys
uh... aristotle's five
there's formal sense
that there were startled mister sense of
warm cold and hot
and bad there or are two hein so
appropriate sanctions
children called them
patroness basis the sense of movement
which are us total published justo
reducible to the sense of touch
uh... and equilibrium the sense of
balance which i think aristotle also
fought was reducible sense
harsh arijit also argued
that there are some other sensory
modalities
all of that clearly operate a center but
albee's but interestingly don't give
rise to conscious sensation
song recall these intro ception if you
think about it for a second
all hotmail static regulation
you experience that your body
experiences
your body
blood sugars levels dropped
and your hypothetical skaggs into
instigate eating behavior
right that's
there has to be some kind of sensory
mechanism
that the text changes and blood sugar
level
your hypertonic split exchanges and
although uh...
phone cell beaulieu
poland and instigate stringent behavior
so there has to be something like a
sensory mechanism
that all of that
protects that
palm
ocular cues to things like our motion
depth perception there's feedback from
your audience onto your visual system
that provides information about for you
know promotion distance of objects o
from you the observer
but you're not consciously aware of any
of these sensations
they do account
and sensations
you're not consciously aware of
so we can begin to think about
gave these four they did these eight
all modalities of sensation
different ways of sense in the world
each of them qualitatively different
from the other one
and the question is
where do these qualities come from
well we know from the work of people
like sharon could
that each sensory modality
is defined in terms of made more or less
unique
package all features
there it is playing
there's a proximal stimulus
song pattern of physical energy is
that's recreated from an object that
falls on
the sensor receptors
are there are the century sectors
themselves
the rods and combs in the eyes basilar
membrane and the uh... in the inner ear
or so on
on that takes most in your standard used
entrance to system to a neural impulse
there's a sense retract
the bundle of nerves
that carries that sensory impulses in
towards the in towards the brain
and there is a sensory projection oreo
somewhere in the brain
that is the final destination point for
the sensory impulses
gives rise to these various kinds of
conscious experiences
and the general idea here
is that you tried always eight sensory
modalities identified by sharon tan
confidently is defined by unique all
package of these features and just use
the example of white per second
the proximal stimulus revision is light
waves of a particular wavelength three
hundred eighty two seven hundred
eighteen animators
on wavelength
all lightwave stimulate rods and calls
on the rat know i'll be all right
which gave rise to honor roll impulse
was electrical signals
that are carried along the optic nerve
and a couple of other bundles of birds
to the op
the occipital cortex
almost out of the brain
which gives rise to the experience
orble
of vision
one of these are really important to me
that's the whole package of some bom bom
bom sensation
and of the sensory nineteenth-century
phone percent three song physiologist
began to identify all
these kinds of things we know about the
bells were membrane and the oracle
reader
report that
all joint johannes builder
thoughtful under a leader of the century
physiologist
also the port
sensory modality is associate with these
different packages
or both of properties
but the one that's most important
turns out
there's a specific
pathway
that underlies each home
each of the modalities
it turns out that you don't see
something because electromagnetic
radiation falls on the rods and columns
of the aisle
and the reason we know that is the close
your eyes
and become electrically stimulate the
rods and cones me still see stuff
see patterns alike
get behind it be alright
electrically stimulate your optic nerve
and you'll still
stuff even though your eyes are closed
and you're in a darkened room and all
that and then finally because drop
microelectrode stone into your hall into
your honor
on occipital lobe
and don't stimulate you and you'll still
love them something but you'll see
something
here's something
we put those electrodes in the old
auditory cortex of your temporal lobe
right about there
you'll hear something
you won't see something
so now we know
one of the reasons that these quality
that these that there are these
qualitative distinctions among various
sensory modalities is that he sensory
modality is associated with a different
part of the brain
that gives rise
two deeds on these various kinds of
conscious experiences
and so as we now know
somehow we could
the rods in cones and you're right
your temporal cortex
as opposed to your occipital cortex
you'd hear
is not
bergsten realistic gives rise to the
sensory experience to the conscious
experience and sensation
where the stimulus gold
uh... on
what the final para what the final
destination of that they're old and
pollsters
that tells us
what the various modalities of
sensational
now we've got this worked out really
well
four
and for hearing
and for go station and for all factions
the skin senses are pretty complicated
but we convert that with that picture is
or the developing
free monthly as well
but the general idea here is
that we can begin
through sensory physiology
paul did go to
to begin to
scientifically
the question of baja many quali are
there
starting with the question
of how many different
waves they're roar
for us to sends
aristotle's five
something closer charade
stamp that's not the final answer to
wall of this but it's not a bad place to
start on the second day of class
home so let's stop there
and on wednesday
another aspect
of the nineteenth century science of
consciousness which is the development
of sensory psycho physics
which tries to understand the
relationship
the physical properties of stimuli
and the psychological properties all be
conscious experiences which these
stimuli give arrives
thank you very much will see you on
wednesday