okay let's
pick up where we left off last time
and just reviewed of debating a bit
let's just
talk about what we did
last week
the general
identification of consciousness with
attention
lead psychologists or early on could be
interested in the various
forms that attention conflict in the
various process easy that on july
paying attention to something shifting
your attention to something to goering
something and so what
that led to an interest and how much
processing could take place at outside
all the focal attention
which is to say what the scope of pre
attentive or pre conscious processing is
that's led to the debate over between
fault early stage processing theories of
attention and waits a bit late selection
theories mobile of attention
which never got resolved
which led to people like daniel carmen
to propose that in fact i was a false
distinction and that we had to take that
we would we had to have carries
but take into account two different
kinds of processing
automatic processing
which doesn't consume attentional
capacity
and controlled processing
and where we left ourselves last
wednesday was with albans allergic obeys
processed association procedure
which uses what's known as the method of
opposition to estimate
how much follow
perforce how much of the performance of
any given task
is due to
unconscious automatic processing
and how much of past performance is due
to conscious controlled processing
that in turn led to the
elaboration
of a large number of water known as dual
process theories and psychology
the whole volume of these edited by
shelley che continue our cultural
or pauline on nineteen ninety nine
and a more recent take on this dual
process business
by elliot smith
and don't get me to call stir
but in general
the idea behind all these dual process
theories
is a performance on any task
remembering a phone number all vasc in
somebody to marry you bein toothpaste in
the drugstore choosing your classes
whatever it is that you're going to do
is performed by some combination
ald all volvo automatic and controlled
processing
as some of these dual process there is
put it
you basically have a choice in terms of
how you're going to do something you can
either go the automatic route
or you can go the control group
and character blow-dried frog very nice
paper by smith and the koster
or as a kind of general
characterization of what these two
different kinds of prostheses are alike
there are conscious
prophecies sometimes called effort for
prophesies are controlled prophecies
that are mediated by all symbolically
represented rules that is rules that are
somehow represented talking in language
home
and dog these aught conscious or ref
report control processes
are the kinds of things that are luring
single trial or just one trial
if all i see you're going near a
dangerous electrical socket they say
don't do that
you avoid it
you just stay away from it right
palm so that's that's something that's
under conscious control processes
and the general idea here
is that
taken a conscious room towards past
performance
is something that's on your our control
it's optional
we do it depending on
how much information processing
capacities available to us we do it
depending on our level of motivation but
the general idea is that on his effort
fuller controlled processing
all of the audit is conscious
in the sense that
your consciously aware called the steps
in the process
your consciously aware of how you get
from your starting point point eight
two-year goal point
all point b
and that's to be contrasted
with these processes that are performed
automatically or unconsciously
or smith and a koster suggest that these
are mediated by more cars so see the
kinds of uh... principles
the kind of thing that you might find it
and all of the dog traditional
all accounts of classical oradour
instrumental conditioning
all of these uh... or associate
relations are structured by
the similarity between
to things or the spacey o temporal kandi
geary all of the between two things
and they're the kinds of prophesies are
required over many trials if i don't
tell you anything about the electrical
outlet
they'll go over and you'll stick your
finger in it and you'll get shocked
and yelled go away and then you're kinda
move back towards the electrical outlet
daniel stick your finger in it and
you'll get rocket
pretty soon you'll come to associate
the electrical outlet was something very
painful and it won't go over there
anymore
and the general idea is that these all
associa process these are executed
automatically
all pre consciously
so that you're not or where of how
you're getting from point a to point b
all you're aware of is that directly
beat
okay that's the general idea behind all
of these kinds of things
now the relevance of this
is one lead up to on but when we move
away from
although analyses all cognitive
functions like perception memory and
thought processes and categorization and
all that and get into
something closer to a social behavior in
the real world
all and ordered or we're going to talk
today about how
this distinction between automatic and
control processes
has been carried over from cognitive
psychology and cognitive science
into social psychology and other kinds
of social sciences
and as a backdrop let me just fell apart
no summarize very very very briefly are
the traditional cognitive perspective in
social psychology
which basically says
that social interaction is cognitively
mediated
that is how we interact with each other
is determined by our perception of the
other person
by the goals that we have for the
interaction by the way we explain the
events that occur in the in that
interaction by memories of
past interactions with that person and
similar kinds of people
all-weather were engaged in
social interaction were not just trying
to
impressions of other people which is
what person perception is all about
but we're also trying to
control
how old they perceive oz
and then all of this is gone at least
the implication of traditional
on cognitive values and social of
direction is at all this is mediated by
conscious deliberate thought
on that what i need somebody for the
first time i'm consciously trying to
figure out what he or she is like and
i'm trying to control what he or she
thinks of me at all that kind of stuff
that traditional cognitive focus in
social interaction carried us along way
in social psychology
bob over and over the overtime
some resistance to it began to build up
resistance that really took the form
of too
different
on the different jack shins
one
they were both involved the kind of
reaction to this kind of pulled the
calculating
overly irrational view
of social interaction
all of the the idea that word of the
hallways than ever
call it the whole that everywhere trying
to perform some kind of rational cost
benefits calculation
or with with with everything we do and
some social psychologist began to make a
plea for
what they sometimes called hot cognition
uh... that is to say
that part of the very least our
cognitive processes are infused with
warm when wet stuff
are with the emotion that motivation
that all of that we have drives at once
and
needs them
feelings and affects
and that they're important the social
interaction
called the two
and one way they are important is that
are cognitions leave on for happy
weekend to see everything as positive
all week and remember positive things
and so one all and so forth
the other reaction to this cold
calculated rational view was more
relevant
art we're going to talk about alarm
in this course
and that is
the end but beyond that embraced by some
social psychologist all of this concept
although of autumn aka city
traditional social psychology
tends to focus on
the rule of the situation
in armed constraining or controlling
what people think and do in various
situations
and all of the uh... the uh... the the
the proponents of the sort of a custody
argument
basically argue
that these situational constraints
situational control operates
automatically
we're not aware
of the influence of the situation
on our thoughts and behavior and the
general model for this although i don't
like the idea of situational influenced
whose primary
something happens in the environment
and that corrine and so forth
and then that thought leads us
to act in a very busy and not you know
that they're in various ways
and what happened very quickly
as social psychology
in quality imported from cognitive
psychology the notion of autumn
intensity all some social although
psychologist
of the came to the idea
that art that's a fact of the matter was
that most social behavior
far from being deliberate then conscious
that voluntary in nature
is really automatic in nature most
social behavior
or personal
occurs automatically on their really
quite serious about this
this is our job barge bennett and why
you and i would be able to spend a we're
all in this group of people who are
making this argument
or writing in nineteen eighty four
all very lovely essay discovered great
pension for wonderful titles
on the automata city of everyday life
skinner argued so pointedly
the more we know about the situational
causes of psychological phenomenon
the lesson need we have
for postulated internal conscious
mediating
prophecies
to explain these phenomena
now they are a couple of things are
really interesting about the statement
the first is
we had a cognitive revolution in
psychology we found in cognitive sides
to get away from b_f_ skinner
onto all of the disrupt and and and and
through one of the defeat
behavior risen in psychology
and put the mind of back and i are at
the uh...
at the center of things
yet here's a guy who says he asked her
how to write the first time
are that the these are conscious guard
on cognitive processing really don't
have much to do with anything
you don't have to talk about internal
internal
conscious
mediating processes
are barges are cognitive social
psychologist
he says he s killer was wrong in that he
douglas can or didn't think that you had
to think about internal processes
mediating between stimulus and response
but otherwise he had it right
node none of those internal processes
are excessive bolta conscious awareness
they are all occur
consciously
leading
origin other people
to make a strong claim that social
behavior is essentially automatic in
nature
that what we think what we do
how we perceive
how we explain things
and how we act upon those cognitions
all is basically triggered all by the
environment
alm is a product of pre attentive or pre
conscious processing we have no idea
what's going on inside our heads
all of that that gets is from stimulus
on to respond
on yes
alm social behavior is guided by
internal
cognitive another mental representations
that's
standard
doctoring for cognitive social
psychology
but far disclaim that all these internal
but all representations of the situation
or constructed automatically
and then they're just kind of dumped
into awareness
all of the are basically the idea here
is that
on everything occurs
unconsciously
uh... one without any kind of conscious
mediation
now how do you get to that position when
you get to that position through
experiments like this
this is a classic experiment
by barge in the stall the colleagues
organ which
subjects were brought into the
laboratory
all for an expert meant a final language
processing
uh... that was the cover story social
psychologists are famous for concocting
sort of cover stories onto in an attempt
to prevent
of their subjects for almost all of them
figured out what's really going on for
successful that is as a matter of
controversy
all but i what type of my life
still have very very very close friend
identifies himself both as a cognitive
and social psychologist
and he once applied
one was interviewed for a job in social
psychology and he gave us talk about
memory and other information processing
of all this kind of stuff
and the first question that that is job
talk was what makes you a social
psychologist
and his answer was
i log into my subjects
have that's a little harsh
though it's not on true
but there's a budget tremendous nielsen
social psychology of deception and cover
stories and stuff like this in
recruiting subjects for a young
for a uh...
other experiment on language processing
was part of the experimental deception
so what does subjects task was they were
given a bunch of
word while the old were although no
words on finals
although they were scrambled
and they were supposed to
unscramble these words so was to make
complete sentences and there was an
experimental rooster there with a
stopwatch
but im along it took them to do these
kinds of
some of the sentences contain the words
that barge cold ruling primes
words like aggressively and rude and
bother in disturbing intrude which all
bear on the concept
of rudeness
other sentences
scrambled senses contain words that
barge calls
polite crimes
fall or words like respect and honor
inconsiderate and appreciate and all of
the holiday and patiently
all of which are related to the concept
of
politeness
and then there were neutral tribes what
would primes like exercising for most of
the cage italy
which are relevant neither to rudeness
politeness
so some subjects unscramble bunch of
senses that andrew crimes
other subjects on scrambled sentences
that had a bunch of polite crimes and
then there's a control group
that on scrambled sentences that had of
what should be snook brutal crimes and
you get the idea and that's all the task
what's
at the added obvious ferment
palm beyond
uh... the the subject was going to be
our page were given our booth is
experimental participation credits or
whatever it was
but the subject came out of the rome
and uh... the expert letter is possibly
dealing with was engaged in conversation
with another person who was
in fact a confederate of the
experimenter is part of the staging
of this experiment
and the experimenter
assiduously ignored the subject
who joins had to wait there
is payment
that's not polite just not
very flight
and actually built the b_ above the
script
called for the experimenter to
steadfastly ignore the subject
for ten minutes
just imagine for a second
if you're waiting for somebody for ten
minutes before they do what they're
supposed to go
you would be tempted to interrupt them
might take hate
give me a minute here give me my payment
and then you can go back your
conversation
well that was in fact the purpose of the
experiment
was the time how long the subjects in
each of these preconditions
would wait before interrupting the
experimenter
and the finding was
that subjects
the interruptions and sperm are over a
period of ten minutes
subjects on the plate condition
relatively or unlikely to interrupt the
expert matter
subjects
who unscramble senses containing rude
words
we're very unlikely to interrupt the
experimenter and subjects
who won scrambled sentences with neutral
words
phil alden
fell somewhere in between
the general idea here buga building on
the barges interpretation of the six
permit
just redeemer ruling words
prime do
think rules thoughts and gage in rude
behaviors
or maybe as an alternative
draws to remain broad words
prime due to precede the experimenter
as more rude then
otherwise would have been percy
similarly
just really
words related to politeness
makes if you came in a polite way or
interpret somebody's evolve of the
people somebody else's behavior as if
not exactly polite
at least not quite as rude as you might
have done otherwise and the argument is
that all of this happens unconsciously
after all subjects were instructed to
make the connection between the words on
the other event and the uh... behavior
of the experimenter
there was nothing about that the
experiment
it was just a thought on that would be
made barges solved view
this all happened automatically
re-enroll words you'd be calmer rude
person
reimer woodward's you interpret somebody
else's behavior as rude at all happens
automatically
all and uh... on consciously
without any kind of on without any kind
of intention
you never know what the baseline is for
something like this that's a good
question
the important point is
that the neutral guys are in the middle
and also these guys arlo
right there really are likely
these guys are high
now it's about fifty percent this kind
of in the middle
in these guys which permits you can
always
push the values around
a little bit but you would expect some
kind of work to read like this and
that's
that's what you get
that's all i can say
not my experiment
um...
so hard to so what what what what what
what god john barge does his so i look
all yes
aqua beginners controlled by the
situation then yes the kind of
psychologists are right that are
behaviors actually cool controlled by
the perception of the situation
but the perception of the situation is
itself constructed pre consciously
automatically
without any conscious mediating
processes in terms of
injury
ought all those kinds of situational
effects that you read about yen-dollar
in the uh... the uh... experimental
social psychology literature what the
bill burr mix permit
all of those all occur all automatically
social perceptions are perception of
other people as friendly your hostel or
whatever that's all constructed
automatically on
going from perception to behavior
proceeding somebody s hostile and
treating him as if he were hostile
that happens automatically
of valuating people as blue dart
battered by use or on nice
on that happens automatically
getting from a valuation behavior all
that happens automatically
on his metaphor is it social behavior
doesn't involve social cognition
so much as it involves social
ignition
there's a stimulus out there that
ignites things that primes something in
your mind and about and behavior has
kind of takes off
home from that
all barge expanded his view although a
little bit later
all people said well yeah that's all
true but still when people enter into a
social situation they have certain kinds
of goals that they want to all
part of the deal within those at least
or conscious
and parts is now that's not conscious
either
on he produces what he calls them
auto motive model for social behavior
where again the traditional way we think
that we thought about on social
interaction
when you come into a spin into a social
situation you have something you intend
to do
and your conscious of that
and then you are that now and then doll
maybe your configure your consciously
formulate your intentions
and maybe your behaviors automatically
executed on the basis of those
intentions but at least the intentions
themselves are consciously although
formulated
but no from his point of view
goals and motives are also automatically
invoke
it's automatic from beginning to and
and consciousness please
knoll role
and social behavior
on vault
alm actually that's not true
jon burge was once asked to give a young
than estimate
of how lol automatic social behavior was
and he said
ninety-nine
and forty four
one hundreds percent
people of a certain age will recognize
that phrase from ivory soap edsall lebow
told me you know
on nineteen sixties eighteen seventies
uh... but uh...
that's basically are the general idea
now this i'd this idea caught on
all producing what
i've called the autumn it has to be
juggernaut on in social psychology
a group of theorists
all michael dot about uh... john barge
who argue that human social behavior
is largely automatic in nature
that harper steps of the situation
or conscious perception of the situation
or relevant our conscience goals are
relevant to our conscious of motions are
relevant the whole shamir
is their relevance
because all of our
fought
and feelings and desires and behaviors
or alone apart over triggered
by a pre conscious
or analysis of the situation that takes
place automatically
outside conscious awareness
and conscious control
the implication here is a consciousness
is an afterthought
there is a stimulus
and we respond to would automatically
and only after we respond would
automatically do we give our reason for
the way we behave
and that reason has nothing to do with
why we actually behaved this weekend
know why we actually behaved
because not one of the pathway from
stimulus to response is completely
automatic an unconscious
when we give reasons for our behavior
what we're really doing is giving
plausible or acceptable reasons
for our behavior
but those reasons are entirely
orthogonal
the real reasons which are embedded
in these
automatic
called the processes abroad that that
are applied
uh... applied unconsciously
on to put it on put another way
in fact were all zombies after all
palm
and it's not bald before over all of the
four of the the usual kind of reasons if
you remember for your reading about
proponent of a dent bennett's of
orb response was on the argument
then it's a lot of argues
you can have an unconscious is i'll be
because of your physiologically
identical to humans and you've got
consciousness
all
so all of the world zombies after all
but it's not because were all big them
not because on these are conscious too
all of the the implication is here they
were all zombies after all
because in fact consciousness is at the
phenomenal
consciousness plays no causal role
all in
behavior and the proof of that
comes from experiments like
the xvi experimenter interruption
experiment
that shows
that babies affects of the situation on
behavior seem to be mediated
by unconscious home
called unconscious processes
okay so there we are also the more we
know about the situation will causes of
psychological phenomenon
the less need we have for pasta leading
internal conscious mediating processes
to explain these phenomena
and then barge goes on
is right in the nineteen ninety-seven
here
all of the making the forecast that
as knowledge progresses
there will be less of a role played by
free will were conscious choice in
accounting
for these psychological phenomenal and
then give so it's kind of this
kind of orwellian voice here
this trend has already begun
and it can do nothing but continue right
has kind of oracle about supplement
about psychology
and they're not all in the end of the
later on the same paper
all the business section public is
consciousness right into the sunset
or electricity pervades everyday life
i am statically push the point where she
writes this i emphatically push the
point
that automatic non conscious prostheses
purveyed all aspects of mental and
social life
all and he does that
in order to overcome
what i consider the dominant on even
implicit assumptions to the contrary
concedes so it's it's forcibly
alban
logon contradicting
this traditional view
are conscious uh... conscious that
conscious thought
all plays a role behavior
for those of you who are fans of all
uh... postwar czechoslovakian cinema
alone there is this
for the paper
the unbearable automata city of being
which kind of middle makes that makes
the same point most of a person persons
everyday life is determined not by their
conscious intention to deliver choices
but by mental processes
put in the motion
put into motion
by features of the environment
that operate outside conscious awareness
and guide so this is off this
preventable point of view here
that argues that
all social interaction
automatic including the social cognition
plays a role in social interaction
homes and conscious mental processes
really have nothing to do
with the case
now of course we've been here before
and barges quite aware of the heart of
the above the history of this plane
and he has explicitly put himself
are involve ought to be there in the
wind of what he calls
the progressive and naturalization
of alone of uh... logo of our
understanding of human nature
all this comes from all of the passage
in freud sun nineteen fifteen on new
introductory lectures or independence i
got up and sorry introductory
lectures and psychoanalysis
in which perot aide says
i'm here with what regret to tell you
something about use yourself
that you do not want to know
and i'm not the first person to say that
copernicus
told us dot all the broader showed us
that rear were not the center of the
universe
darwin
showed us that we were just another
animal
and
darwin thought we were a rational
animals
but i'm here to tell you
that we are irrational animals after all
of the recent gotten point said this was
because he had this idea that our
behavior was driven by these monsters
from the irs these unconscious
all sexual and aggressive or impulses
barge says
and that's not what's wrong traffic
barr says i'm here to complete
the trio
of naturalization this cooper nicholas
darwin n me
all and i'm here to tell you
that part of the social behavior is
automatic after all
that we who only think that conscious
thought plays a role in our behavior
were quite wrong about that
all our behavior
or at least ninety-nine and forty four
one hundreds percent of that on islam
is what the is automatic and on colleges
as i say
john call this the autumn intensely drug
or not because he is not the only guy
who thinks that's
palm uh... there's not there's now a
whole school
all social psychologists and other
social theorist
who have embraced
this view and the question is why would
you embrace this view
okay
let's go back here for a second
experiments of this kind
let's just assume
for one
for the vote for the purposes of
argument
barges interpretation of this palm of
this so that experiment or write that
somehow reedy words conceptually related
to rudeness
okay
lead people to behave in a rude way
water matically
and that reading
words conceptually related to play this
lead people to behave politely
failed a this is an automatically
no problem
just accept that for purposes of
argument
nothing about this experiment or any
other experiment in this line of
research shows that automatic
unconscious prostheses dominate behavior
much less
that they account for ninety nine ten
forty four one hundreds percent
all our behavior all experiment like
this shows you is that
certain things happen automatically
right automatic process these might play
some role
uh... in this behavior
nothing about this particular experiment
on tells us that automatic prostheses
dominate conscious
control processes
for that you need an entirely different
kind of experiment
and that's why i introduced you last
time for marriage a colby's method of
opposition
and is processed association procedure
setting aside the mechanics of the are
those of the mathematics which i would
never hold you responsible for
the whole idea all
the process dissociation procedure
is first
performance of every task
composed
every test is composed of
certain components that are performed
automatically
and certain components that are
performed
consciously
deliberately and that we can use the
auto the method of opposition
in the process dissociation procedure
to estimate
how much
of past performance is doing to
automatic process ease and how much of
past performance is due to control
processes
nothing like that
appears in this experiment or in any l
other experiments these can be followed
only as
demonstration experiments
demonstration experiments that suggest
that automata city plays a role and
social behavior
but do not by any means
how much of a role for that we're going
to need something else
we're going to need experiments
that actually use something like the
method of opposition
to do these estimates
there are three such experiments of the
social psychological literature west
time i worked which was
yesterday
their experiments are very revealing
called makes use of a phenomenon known
as the false fame a fact law officially
dogwood discovered by larry jacoby
all an experiment in which
subjects abreast to study a list of non
famous names just
names out of the phone book that don't
or dark the names of anybody famous
and all of them later on they're given
all of that will fit in judgment as to
which they're presented with another
list of names
i'm simply asking check off which ones
they think are famous and which ones
they think about that
customers
consists of
some famous names
and also some non famous names
and some of these none famously famous
names like a ronald reagan and margaret
thatcher
and then some other on don famous names
and some of the non tennis names were
non famous name studied twenty four
hours earlier
and the general finding here which is
why it's called the false benefactor is
that previously studied nonna famous
names
tend to be judged as
and the idea of their is
there when you read
non-fat do remain
that you remember
from before it would be certainty that
name seems familiar it must be famous
and the idea is that that paul g that
name seems familiar is mediated by a
kind of conscious of the mediator by
kinda primate effect
that operates on consciously and creates
this kind of conscious feeling called
bob dole familiarity
so the general idea behind the poll same
effect is that
the study the stunning phase
primes names on a judgment ask
and a private increases availability and
availability in and availability of
drugs to retrieval
and availability and influences on the
famed judgment
and that all of that happens
automatically
so now what you really want to know is
when you get wet when you get this poll
sabretech
hollow much of the fall same effect is
due to
controlled conscious processing and how
much of this false famous effect is to
do
uncontrolled automatic
unconscious processing
we won't go through the details cause
you'd rather put a fork in your ride and
see the details of these experiments
all but called here is the author is the
general result
all walked off you know this is by drew
colby himself
all be repeated the false fame
experiment
all under
dot three conditions
first young subjects performing a task
under full attention that was all they
had to do
was make fame judgments
second condition
for bomb-making fame judgments under
divided
attention also that they were actually
performing two tasks at once what was
the famed of the the pain judgment asked
one was a dance of destructor task that
was intended to consume to consume some
cognitive capacity and then on his
beaver studies of college students
then there was a group of the elderly
and we know from the study that i showed
your earlier
that elderly subjects tend to lose
cognitive capacities they get older
i've become more reliant on automatic
processes
what we've got here
is an estimate
all of the amount of initial ones
of controlled an automatic processing
on the false fail affect
in each of these three conditions
the first five years
under the the standard condition were
also objects are doing is making fame
judgments that stuff
full intention condition
conscious processes
dominate
unconscious automatic processes okay so
even that's not automatic
now
in a second condition where you consumed
cognitive capacity by engaging subjects
in a distract ur task while they're
making the famed judgments
the role palm
conscious processing
diminished
but even under those circumstances
yeah automatic processing has a little
bit more important but that's not
anywhere near a ninety nine and forty
four one hundreds percent automatic
and with the elderly
you get a little bit more influence of
automatic processing but there's still
welfare amount of conscious processing
involved even when old folks
are engaged in
bikinis fame judgments but in the
standard condition
where the false fame affect was uh...
was initially discovered
conscious processes
dominate
automatic processing
okay it's not the case
that this that this problem of effect
is mediated holy
or even in large part
whitewater matter processing
conscious processing is still played a
role
what the subject sir during the six
i remember this name
i remember this name from somewhere
don't remember i don't know where it
came from but i remember from somewhere
it must be
more famous than these other names yet
i'd just give you a sample barge
experiment
the barges experiments go back to
nineteen eighty two
that's the end of that answer
palm
now here's another argued the here's
another experiment
all by jim young woman car and his
colleagues at uh... at n_y_u_ on what
are known as spontaneous solid
or that the uh... the trade home of
uh... descriptions
indifference berman for different simply
ask to study photographs of people they
don't know
and each of these photographs is for his
sab paired with the behavioral
description
on here's a person
and he all in
wanted just remembered
here's another person and he uh... made
sandwiches and here's another person
and uh... on hwy of didn't understand
the t_v_ show or or whatever
later on
these saw that these subjects were
brought back to the laboratory
and they were shown a new set of
photographs and they were asked to make
trade judgments
of the personalities of the people
pictures and people do this you know you
look at somebody as a all that's a
friendly person and all that stuff
conscientious person or whatever you can
get people to do this because you do it
we're always doing that kind of thing
and what neelam unfounded deankl the
trend judgments were made with a mix of
these of all the photos of the subjects
unseen two days previously a bunch of
new photos
and what the finding was
when subjects made trade judgments of
the people in the old photos the photos
that they had studied
those stretch abuse shins
were made in line with the behaviors
that had been attached to the
photographs on the first day
and the interpretation of this was
well when the subject studied these
photographs on day one thing on pulled
the make trade attributions
they just did it automatically
they all hope of the they automatically
attach the behavior to the photograph
and then automatically mated inference
from the behavior to the corresponding
trait
the person didn't understand the daytime
television show must be stupid
all of the person although it didn't
study for exam
wasp bee
most lack conscientious notes or
something like that
and the general idea is
look at the read about the behaviors
primed irrelevant rates
stored and all of those are stored in
memory
that prime in increases availability
and that available early
on increased availability influenced
rate judgments
and that the whole thing is automatic
okay that's the general idea behind the
interpretation
of these spontaneous straight path
inferences that they occur automatically
you applied
the method of opposition
onto this kind of experiment again but
it's not going to the details that don't
have uh... or that i don't have a lot of
time to do this
but you know one of himself did this to
all the good tested is own hypothesis
i'm going to tell you had a minute
remember that the med jim kolbe is
method of opposition
allows us to argued to assess
the relative contributions of conscious
and all the matic processing
so testified
probably not the right term all except
before a posting
it's consciously automatic processing
so we did we do this is spontaneous
trade in print six permit
all under two conditions
first were subject to make the trade
judgments and we really after
studied the pictures
second twenty minutes after they study
the picture is giving time for conscious
memory to decay a little bit
and second
two days
after studying
palm all of these so that these pictures
giving
memory blocks of time
to evaporate
in the standard and in the immediate
condition
conscious processing
conscious processing dominates automatic
processing
twenty minutes later
there's a nice balance between
conscious and on conscious processing
even two days later which is how you'll
amended the experiment
in the first place
i mean it's mostly noise
the ms these values are very low
but the fact of the matter is
ghar ka just processing and automatic
processing are roughly evenly balanced
so in this case as well it's not the
case
that spontaneous inferences
despite his trait inferences are a
product of automatic unconscious
processing their product of a mix of
conscious
and unconscious processing
last experiment
this is known as the weapon bias palm
hog
uh...
richly documented by uh...
by paying
in a series of experiments
bogdan actually with leverage in kobe
this is an experiment in which subjects
are shown photographs or scenes of a
person with some object
and their ass simply to make a judgment
about whether the object is a weapon
for tool
i hadn't gone or a knife
versus or wrench or a screwdriver or
something
uh... like that
and the flying in the parking fine you
know what the defect
is that
these are white subjects
white subject
who are primed with pictures of black or
white people
that affects their judgment
if you're pretty cute they've white
subjects are primed with a
they're more likely to drugs with the
object is the weapon
if their pride with a white face they're
more likely to judge that the object is
the pool
and this is another unobtrusive index of
racial bias
okay that's carboplatin uh...
uh... what it is
also the general idea here is
that the that presentation of the face
primos
racial stereotypes
and the racial stereotypes prabhat all
of the prime related judgments and again
the the influence
of the priming is automatic
pain himself
did the experiment
using beyond using garden jacoby xo that
method of both
of opposition
and again we're looking at
type of processing
conscious versus unconscious
on the processing
and what you can see here is
in the standard condition
when there is no deadline in judgment to
take as much time as you want to decide
whether something as a weapon or a tool
conscious control processing
dominates unconscious
automatic processing it is not the case
that the weapons of fact is mediated
holy
or even a large part
by automatic processing
the only time
that you'll get
all automatic processing
dominating although uh... odd uh...
control processing
denoted in the weapon's affects only
is when you
force subjects to respond within five
hundred milliseconds within half a
second
under those circumstances
these red bars to show you the data from
above the from the last slide
funded and the under those circumstances
of bala responding is primarily
influenced by automatic processing
one of the chorus
responding within five hundred
milliseconds is mediated by automatic
processing right you can't do anything
else within five hundred milliseconds
economic blink your eyes with them
within five hundred milliseconds
this is the standard condition where the
weapons of fact
was discovered
it's dominated
by controlled processing
so the point here is
there's really no reason
to believe
that social behavior as it started in
the laboratory is dominated by
unconscious automatic processing
when you actually use something like the
method of opposition to do with the
comparison
you discover that
at the very worst
past performance is mediated by
a balance
of controlled and automatic processing
conscious and unconscious processing
and in many circumstances
conscious processing dominates automatic
processing there was a question or her
yeah priming itself is
prob partly conscious hall and not holy
automatic as we what might once and for
the past
despite these studies
okay and despite the fact
the evidentiary base before any studies
was relatively weak
the argued that the idea that human
behavior
for the human thought and action and
experience
was largely
altman mediated by unconscious processes
operator automatically has been very
very very seductive
or here's all the goodies park
or the whole stronghold issue
of american psychologist what's been
called the ladies home journal of the
psychological profession everybody gets
a everybody reads it
alm
the source of behavioral control comes
not from active awareness but from
mental activations of which we are all
aware
and environmental cues to which we are
not gonna consciously attending that
have a
found effect on our behavior
i don't see it
sandra blinks liens very good appalled
popular science writer is right in the
new york times
in navigating the world in deciding what
is rewarding humans are closer to some
bs
and censured beans
most of the time
there is no evidence for that
there's just
evidence all for that
here tim wilson professor of psychology
university of virginia
of riding in a in a book
freud's view of the unconscious was far
too limited
florence view of the unconscious
far too who committed robin when he said
bed consciousness is the tip of the
mental weisberg he was short of the mark
by quite a bit
consciousness may be more the size of us
mobile on top
i'll bet iceberg
two things have to be said about this
freud never once an old was written move
of god at all of my office
used the iceberg metaphor for
unconscious mental life that suburban
wedge in never ever used to be iceberg
metaphor
on in print
the second point is there is no evidence
the proposition
that poem
that's our
consciousness is just put the snowball
on the tour of the tip of the iceberg
much less on the tip of the iceberg
all the evidence we have
suggests that in fact
as to colby originally postulated
performed past performance tends to be
mediated by a balance of conscious and
unconscious prostheses
that differs
bone for one circumstance to another
like if you receive like if you require
fast response latencies they're going to
get performance dominated by unconscious
processes
if you let people take their time
they're going to get performance
dominated
there is no evidence or for any of this
many of you have read about if you have
and read malcolm gladwell lhs book blink
armed at all of the gladwell is one of
the finest popular science writers
working all of those working today
subtitled
the power of thinking without thinking
and the argument in blank is that we
don't really consciously think about
anything
ordered everything goes off
automatically at all
support of our brains of these different
closures
is colby adaptable unconscious
and the study of this kind of decision
making
fun conscious decision making
automatic decisionmaking is one of the
most important new fields of psychology
and global goes on motivated in the book
onto our group to kind of or repeat
the art though the work of barge and
others as evidence
for the dominant brawl
of one conscious processing in
psychology
home
one more
that wagner at home now professor at the
uh... at harvard
albeit in a book and internal delusion
of conscience will
the real causes of human action are all
unconscious
though real causes of human action or
so it is not surprising
that behavior could often arise as a
north of the custody experiments
without the person had been conscious
insight into qualities causation
this is what i refer to as well be the
autumn it has to be juggernaut
widespread acceptance by certain
although theorists
for the proposition
conscious processing plays no role in
social interaction
behavior at all
little word overall
that in fact
our experience
thought and action is a product of
unconscious processes
operating automatically
i don't have time to do this so bill
would put in the lecture
of one of the poem supplements
why would people believe such a thing
when in fact there is no evidence for
this
all we have for evidence of on of all
the role of automata city
is a bunch of demonstration experiments
but don't actually compare
the power of automatic unconscious
processing
whatever we do all those experiments
comparing
the power of automatic unconscious
processing
we all replied out
that in fact past performance is based
on a balanced
all i think there are all basically all
two reasons
the most important for our report
purposes
is what the philosopher colon flanagan
refers to as
conscious shyness
consciousness just makes people nervous
for abolish
of reasons
all i'm for it and and and uh... under
the bed and at one of those is
it makes apartments very hard for people
who understand
how conscious thinking l_a_ a rule in
the physical world
for that reason
long people can
this position
of pepper phenomenal ism
words on these moral behavior it's all
automatic
we're simply conscious of what we're
doin what we've done
in that sense were conscious on these
but consciousness plays no rule and what
we do
do i have to say it again and four
seconds
there's no reason to think this
it may be true that were conscious on
these
but the kind of evidence that underlies
the autumn it has to be juggernaut
gives us no reason to think it's true
okay
next week will pick up on new topic
they contrast between explicit and
implicit
cognition emotional motivation
thank you very much